1	Correction	NN	O	correction	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
3	Synergy	NN	O	synergy	dep	1	SENT_1	[p1l530t281r714b327],
4	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l729t290r776b317],
5	Independence	NN	O	independence	dep	1	SENT_1	[p1l794t280r1136b326],
6	?	.	O	?	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l794t280r1136b326],

1	Deciphering	VBG	O	decipher	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1156t280r1428b327],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_2	[p1l1446t280r1519b317],
3	Interaction	NN	MISC	interaction	dobj	1	SENT_2	[p1l1538t280r1781b317],
4	of	IN	MISC	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1800t279r1846b317],
5	HLA	NN	MISC	hlum	nn	6	SENT_2	[p1l1862t282r1952b316],
6	Class	NN	MISC	class	prep_of	3	SENT_2	[p1l1969t280r2081b317],
7	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	6	SENT_2	[p1l2101t282r2109b316],
8	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l2127t280r2210b317],
9	NK	NN	O	nk	nn	12	SENT_2	[p1l265t342r328b376],
10	Cell	NN	O	cell	nn	12	SENT_2	[p1l347t340r427b377],
11	KIR	NN	O	kir	nn	12	SENT_2	[p1l450t341r522b376],
12	Alleles	NNS	O	allele	dobj	1	SENT_2	[p1l541t340r689b377],
13	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l710t340r748b376],
14	Early	JJ	O	early	amod	17	SENT_2	[p1l771t340r881b387],
15	HIV-1	NN	O	hiv-1	nn	17	SENT_2	[p1l902t342r1016b376],
16	Disease	NN	O	disease	nn	17	SENT_2	[p1l1045t340r1215b377],
17	Progression	NN	O	progression	prep_in	12	SENT_2	[p1l1237t340r1501b387],
18	Jason	NNP	PERSON	Jason	nn	20	SENT_2	[p1l262t414r348b439],
19	D.	NNP	PERSON	D.	nn	20	SENT_2	[p1l365t414r394b439],
20	Barbour	NNP	PERSON	Barbour	dep	1	SENT_2	[p1l410t412r539b444],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l410t412r539b444],
22	Uma	NNP	PERSON	Uma	nn	23	SENT_2	[p1l555t414r624b439],
23	Sriram	NNP	PERSON	Sriram	appos	20	SENT_2	[p1l640t413r745b444],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l640t413r745b444],
25	Stacy	NNP	PERSON	Stacy	nn	27	SENT_2	[p1l760t413r841b447],
26	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	27	SENT_2	[p1l854t414r874b439],
27	Caillier	NNP	PERSON	Caillier	appos	20	SENT_2	[p1l889t412r999b444],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l889t412r999b444],
29	Jay	NNP	PERSON	Jay	nn	31	SENT_2	[p1l1013t414r1062b447],
30	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	31	SENT_2	[p1l1076t414r1104b439],
31	Levy	NNP	PERSON	Levy	appos	20	SENT_2	[p1l1121t414r1196b447],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1121t414r1196b447],
33	Frederick	NNP	PERSON	Frederick	nn	35	SENT_2	[p1l1213t412r1354b439],
34	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	35	SENT_2	[p1l1368t414r1402b439],
35	Hecht	NNP	PERSON	Hecht	appos	20	SENT_2	[p1l1419t412r1515b444],
36	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1419t412r1515b444],
37	Jorge	NNP	PERSON	Jorge	nn	39	SENT_2	[p1l1530t414r1614b447],
38	R.	NNP	PERSON	R.	nn	39	SENT_2	[p1l1631t414r1655b439],
39	Oksenberg	NNP	PERSON	Oksenberg	appos	20	SENT_2	[p1l1670t412r1836b447],

1	Correction	NN	O	correction	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l263t484r424b510],
2	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l439t483r489b510],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l439t483r489b510],
4	Barbour	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Barbour	nn	5	SENT_3	[p1l265t529r387b556],
5	JD	NNP	ORGANIZATION	JD	prep_for	1	SENT_3	[p1l400t531r445b561],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l400t531r445b561],
7	Sriram	NNP	PERSON	Sriram	nn	8	SENT_3	[p1l460t530r556b556],
8	U	NNP	PERSON	U	appos	5	SENT_3	[p1l574t531r602b561],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l574t531r602b561],
10	Caillier	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Caillier	nn	11	SENT_3	[p1l617t529r720b556],
11	SJ	NNP	ORGANIZATION	SJ	appos	5	SENT_3	[p1l734t530r771b561],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l734t530r771b561],
13	Levy	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Levy	nn	14	SENT_3	[p1l788t531r856b564],
14	JA	NNP	ORGANIZATION	JA	appos	5	SENT_3	[p1l869t531r913b561],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l869t531r913b561],
16	Hecht	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hecht	nn	17	SENT_3	[p1l929t529r1019b556],
17	FM	NNP	ORGANIZATION	FM	appos	5	SENT_3	[p1l1034t531r1086b561],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1034t531r1086b561],
19	et	FW	O	et	dep	5	SENT_3	[p1l1102t534r1131b556],
20	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	21	SENT_3	[p1l1145t529r1177b556],
21	(	FW	O	(	dep	5	SENT_3	[p1l1193t530r1286b561],
22	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	24	SENT_3	[p1l1193t530r1286b561],
23	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	24	SENT_3	[p1l1193t530r1286b561],
24	Synergy	NN	O	synergy	dep	21	SENT_3	[p1l1302t530r1425b564],
25	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1440t537r1471b556],
26	independence	NN	O	independence	prep_for	1	SENT_3	[p1l1485t529r1722b563],
27	?	.	O	?	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1485t529r1722b563],

1	Deciphering	VBG	O	decipher	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1739t529r1925b564],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_4	[p1l1941t529r1991b556],
3	putative	JJ	O	putative	amod	4	SENT_4	[p1l2007t530r2133b563],
4	interaction	NN	O	interaction	dobj	1	SENT_4	[p1l264t575r429b601],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l445t574r477b601],
6	HLA	NN	MISC	hlum	nn	7	SENT_4	[p1l490t576r552b601],
7	Class	NN	MISC	class	prep_of	4	SENT_4	[p1l566t574r642b601],
8	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	7	SENT_4	[p1l658t576r662b601],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l678t574r734b601],
10	NK	NN	O	nk	nn	12	SENT_4	[p1l752t576r794b601],
11	cell	NN	O	cell	nn	12	SENT_4	[p1l808t574r856b601],
12	KIR	NN	O	kir	dobj	1	SENT_4	[p1l874t576r919b601],
13	receptor	NN	O	receptor	nn	14	SENT_4	[p1l936t579r1065b608],
14	alleles	NNS	O	allele	dep	12	SENT_4	[p1l1079t574r1172b601],
15	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1188t582r1225b601],
16	early	JJ	O	early	amod	19	SENT_4	[p1l1241t574r1314b609],
17	HIV-1	NN	MISC	hiv-1	nn	19	SENT_4	[p1l1330t576r1405b601],
18	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	19	SENT_4	[p1l1426t574r1537b601],
19	progression	NN	O	progression	prep_on	1	SENT_4	[p1l1554t575r1743b609],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1554t575r1743b609],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_5	[p1l1759t575r1831b601],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1848t574r1955b609],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	4	SENT_5	[p1l1972t575r2036b606],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_5	[p1l1972t575r2036b606],
5	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	6	SENT_5	[p1l1972t575r2036b606],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_5	[p1l1972t575r2036b606],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1972t575r2036b606],
8	e43	NN	O	e43	dep	2	SENT_5	[p1l2051t576r2113b601],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l2051t576r2113b601],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l264t620r319b647],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l264t620r319b647],
3	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	dep	1	SENT_6	[p1l337t620r797b655],
4	/	:	O	/	punct	6	SENT_6	[p1l337t620r797b655],
5	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	6	SENT_6	[p1l337t620r797b655],
6	|	NN	O	|	dep	3	SENT_6	[p1l337t620r797b655],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l337t620r797b655],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l337t620r797b655],
2	.0030043	CD	NUMBER	.0030043	num	1	SENT_7	[p1l337t620r797b655],

1	In	IN	O	in	dep	9	SENT_8	[p1l265t692r289b717],
2	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	3	SENT_8	[p1l305t691r376b717],
3	Pathogens	NNS	O	pathogen	pobj	1	SENT_8	[p1l390t690r554b725],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l390t690r554b725],
5	volume	NN	O	volume	appos	3	SENT_8	[p1l569t690r685b717],
6	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	5	SENT_8	[p1l700t692r724b722],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l700t692r724b722],
8	issue	NN	O	issue	appos	5	SENT_8	[p1l740t691r814b717],
9	4	CD	NUMBER	4	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l828t693r853b717],
10	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l828t693r853b717],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_9	[p1l262t761r319b788],
2	funding	NN	O	funding	nn	3	SENT_9	[p1l333t761r453b796],
3	statement	NN	O	statement	nsubj	9	SENT_9	[p1l470t766r627b788],
4	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l640t761r683b788],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_9	[p1l697t761r747b788],
6	above	JJ	O	above	amod	7	SENT_9	[p1l761t761r855b788],
7	paper	NN	O	paper	prep_for	3	SENT_9	[p1l872t769r960b795],
8	was	VBD	O	be	cop	9	SENT_9	[p1l974t769r1032b788],
9	incomplete	JJ	O	incomplete	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1048t761r1229b795],
10	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1048t761r1229b795],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_10	[p1l1243t761r1300b788],
2	full	JJ	O	full	amod	4	SENT_10	[p1l1314t761r1360b788],
3	funding	NN	O	funding	nn	4	SENT_10	[p1l1375t761r1496b796],
4	statement	NN	O	statement	nsubj	5	SENT_10	[p1l1512t766r1669b788],
5	follows	VBZ	O	follow	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1683t761r1800b788],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1683t761r1800b788],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l339t996r480b1022],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l339t996r480b1022],
3	Barbour	NNP	PERSON	Barbour	nn	5	SENT_16	[p1l493t996r686b1031],
4	]	NN	O	]	nn	5	SENT_16	[p1l493t996r686b1031],
5	D	NN	O	d	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l493t996r686b1031],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l493t996r686b1031],
7	Sriram	NNP	PERSON	Sriram	nn	8	SENT_16	[p1l700t996r811b1022],
8	U	NNP	PERSON	U	conj_or	5	SENT_16	[p1l822t997r857b1027],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l822t997r857b1027],
10	Caillier	NNP	O	Caillier	nn	12	SENT_16	[p1l870t996r990b1022],
11	S	NNP	O	S	nn	12	SENT_16	[p1l1001t996r1039b1031],
12	]	NN	O	]	conj_or	5	SENT_16	[p1l1001t996r1039b1031],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1001t996r1039b1031],
14	Levy	NNP	PERSON	Levy	nn	16	SENT_16	[p1l1052t996r1183b1031],
15	]	NNP	O	]	nn	16	SENT_16	[p1l1052t996r1183b1031],
16	A	NNP	O	A	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l1052t996r1183b1031],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1052t996r1183b1031],
18	Hecht	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hecht	nn	19	SENT_16	[p1l1196t996r1295b1022],
19	FM	NNP	ORGANIZATION	FM	conj_or	5	SENT_16	[p1l1306t997r1366b1027],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1306t997r1366b1027],
21	et	FW	O	et	conj_or	5	SENT_16	[p1l1379t1002r1408b1022],
22	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	23	SENT_16	[p1l1420t996r1454b1022],
23	(	FW	O	(	dep	21	SENT_16	[p1l1468t994r1564b1028],
24	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	26	SENT_16	[p1l1468t994r1564b1028],
25	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	26	SENT_16	[p1l1468t994r1564b1028],
26	Correction	NN	O	correction	dep	21	SENT_16	[p1l1578t996r1764b1022],
27	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1578t996r1764b1022],
28	Synergy	NN	O	synergy	conj_or	5	SENT_16	[p1l1778t996r1906b1031],
29	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1918t1005r1954b1022],
30	Independence	NN	O	independence	conj_or	5	SENT_16	[p1l1964t996r2210b1031],
31	?	.	O	?	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1964t996r2210b1031],

1	Deciphering	VBG	O	decipher	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l338t1041r541b1076],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_17	[p1l558t1041r607b1067],
3	Putative	JJ	MISC	putative	amod	4	SENT_17	[p1l623t1042r756b1067],
4	Interaction	NN	MISC	interaction	dobj	1	SENT_17	[p1l771t1042r955b1067],
5	of	IN	MISC	of	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l972t1041r1006b1067],
6	HLA	NN	MISC	hlum	nn	7	SENT_17	[p1l1019t1041r1097b1066],
7	Class	NN	MISC	class	prep_of	4	SENT_17	[p1l1112t1041r1192b1067],
8	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	7	SENT_17	[p1l1208t1042r1219b1066],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1235t1041r1294b1067],
10	NK	NN	O	nk	nn	12	SENT_17	[p1l1310t1042r1364b1067],
11	Cell	NN	O	cell	nn	12	SENT_17	[p1l1379t1041r1441b1067],
12	KIR	NN	O	kir	dobj	1	SENT_17	[p1l1457t1042r1520b1066],
13	Receptor	NN	O	receptor	nn	14	SENT_17	[p1l1535t1042r1685b1076],
14	Alleles	NNS	O	allele	dep	12	SENT_17	[p1l1699t1041r1806b1067],
15	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1822t1050r1862b1067],
16	Early	JJ	O	early	amod	19	SENT_17	[p1l1878t1041r1961b1076],
17	HIV-1	NN	O	hiv-1	nn	19	SENT_17	[p1l1976t1041r2073b1067],
18	Disease	NN	O	disease	nn	19	SENT_17	[p1l2092t1042r2211b1067],
19	Progression	NN	O	progression	prep_on	1	SENT_17	[p1l338t1088r538b1122],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l338t1088r538b1122],

1	PLOS	NNP	O	PLOS	nn	2	SENT_18	[p1l554t1087r637b1113],
2	Pathog	NNP	O	Pathog	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l653t1087r766b1122],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	number	4	SENT_18	[p1l781t1087r866b1119],
4	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	2	SENT_18	[p1l781t1087r866b1119],
5	10	CD	NUMBER	10	num	6	SENT_18	[p1l781t1087r866b1119],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	4	SENT_18	[p1l781t1087r866b1119],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l781t1087r866b1119],
8	e154	NN	O	e154	dep	2	SENT_18	[p1l882t1087r963b1113],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l882t1087r963b1113],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l980t1087r1038b1113],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l980t1087r1038b1113],
3	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	num	4	SENT_19	[p1l1057t1085r1542b1122],
4	ﬁournal	NN	O	ﬁournal	dep	1	SENT_19	[p1l1057t1085r1542b1122],
5	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1057t1085r1542b1122],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1057t1085r1542b1122],
2	.0030	CD	NUMBER	.0030	num	3	SENT_20	[p1l1057t1085r1542b1122],
3	l54	NN	O	l54	dep	1	SENT_20	[p1l1057t1085r1542b1122],
4	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1057t1085r1542b1122],

1	Received	VBN	O	receive	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l338t1157r491b1183],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l338t1157r491b1183],
3	September	NNP	DATE	September	dep	1	SENT_21	[p1l507t1157r685b1192],
4	12	CD	DATE	12	num	3	SENT_21	[p1l702t1157r743b1188],
5	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l702t1157r743b1188],
6	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	3	SENT_21	[p1l759t1155r842b1188],
7	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l759t1155r842b1188],
8	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	dep	3	SENT_21	[p1l856t1157r1017b1192],
9	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l856t1157r1017b1192],
10	September	NNP	DATE	September	dep	8	SENT_21	[p1l1034t1157r1211b1192],
11	12	CD	DATE	12	num	10	SENT_21	[p1l1228t1157r1269b1188],
12	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1228t1157r1269b1188],
13	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	10	SENT_21	[p1l1286t1155r1369b1187],
14	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1286t1155r1369b1187],
15	Published	VBN	O	publish	partmod	3	SENT_21	[p1l1384t1157r1550b1183],
16	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1384t1157r1550b1183],
17	October	NNP	DATE	October	dep	3	SENT_21	[p1l1567t1157r1702b1183],
18	26	CD	DATE	26	num	17	SENT_21	[p1l1717t1157r1760b1188],
19	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1717t1157r1760b1188],
20	2007	CD	DATE	2007	appos	17	SENT_21	[p1l1777t1155r1859b1184],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1777t1155r1859b1184],

1	Copyright	NN	O	copyright	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l339t1228r510b1263],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l339t1228r510b1263],
3	©	CD	NUMBER	©	num	4	SENT_22	[p1l532t1228r558b1254],
4	2007	CD	DATE	2007	dep	1	SENT_22	[p1l579t1226r653b1255],
5	Barbour	NNP	O	Barbour	dep	4	SENT_22	[p1l673t1228r810b1254],
6	et	FW	O	et	nn	7	SENT_22	[p1l828t1233r858b1254],
7	al.	FW	O	al.	dep	4	SENT_22	[p1l878t1228r911b1254],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l878t1228r911b1254],

1	>	JJR	O	>	amod	3	SENT_24	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
2	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	3	SENT_24	[p1l288t3093r352b3116],
3	Pathogens	NNS	O	pathogen	nsubj	4	SENT_24	[p1l367t3092r511b3123],
4	|	VBP	O	|	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l526t3091r528b3124],
5	www	NN	O	www	dobj	4	SENT_24	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_25	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_25	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
4	1540	CD	DATE	1540	num	7	SENT_25	[p1l1207t3094r1270b3116],
5	October	NNP	DATE	October	nn	7	SENT_25	[p1l1690t3092r1803b3116],
6	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	7	SENT_25	[p1l1815t3094r1880b3116],
7	|	NNP	O	|	dep	3	SENT_25	[p1l1895t3091r1897b3124],
8	Volume	NN	O	volume	nn	11	SENT_25	[p1l1912t3092r2017b3116],
9	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	11	SENT_25	[p1l2031t3094r2044b3116],
10	|	NN	O	|	nn	11	SENT_25	[p1l2060t3091r2062b3124],
11	Issue	NN	O	issue	dep	7	SENT_25	[p1l2079t3093r2144b3116],
12	10	CD	NUMBER	10	num	14	SENT_25	[p1l2160t3094r2189b3116],
13	|	NN	O	|	nn	14	SENT_25	[p1l2204t3091r2206b3124],
14	e154	NN	O	e154	dep	3	SENT_25	[p1l2221t3094r2287b3116],

