1	OPEN	NN	MISC	open	nn	3	SENT_1	[p1l241t131r323b155],
2	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	3	SENT_1	[p1l333t112r365b162],
3	ACCESS	NNP	O	ACCESS	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l372t131r485b155],
4	Freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	3	SENT_1	[p1l501t130r590b162],
5	available	JJ	O	available	dep	6	SENT_1	[p1l597t130r731b155],
6	online	NN	O	online	dep	3	SENT_1	[p1l739t130r832b155],

1	PLOS	NNS	O	plo	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l2003t110r2118b154],
2	PATHOGENS	NNS	O	pathogen	dep	1	SENT_2	[p1l2129t130r2308b154],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_3	[p1l242t240r373b300],
2	Evolutionary	NNP	O	Evolutionary	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l409t240r862b317],
3	Genetics	NNP	O	Genetics	dep	2	SENT_3	[p1l894t240r1200b300],
4	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1233t240r1364b300],
5	Emergence	NNP	O	Emergence	dep	2	SENT_3	[p1l1403t243r1798b317],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1831t239r1904b300],
7	Avian	JJ	O	avian	amod	9	SENT_3	[p1l1932t240r2131b300],
8	Influenza	NNP	O	Influenza	nn	9	SENT_3	[p1l248t330r573b391],
9	Viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_of	3	SENT_3	[p1l606t331r864b391],
10	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l899t331r958b390],
11	Wild	NNP	O	Wild	nn	12	SENT_3	[p1l993t331r1150b391],
12	Birds	NNPS	O	Birds	prep_in	9	SENT_3	[p1l1188t331r1361b391],

1	Vivien	NNP	PERSON	Vivien	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l243t460r366b491],
2	G.	NNP	PERSON	G.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l384t462r424b491],
3	Dugan	NNP	PERSON	Dugan	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l441t453r599b499],
4	‘	NNP	O	‘	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l441t453r599b499],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l441t453r599b499],
6	Rubing	NNP	PERSON	Rubing	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l618t460r756b499],
7	Chenz	NNP	PERSON	Chenz	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l774t453r903b495],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l774t453r903b495],
9	David	NNP	PERSON	David	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l922t460r1034b491],
10	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1051t462r1080b491],
11	Spiro3	NNP	PERSON	Spiro3	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1097t453r1229b498],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1097t453r1229b498],
13	Naomi	NNP	PERSON	Naomi	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1247t460r1373b491],
14	Sengamalay3	NNP	PERSON	Sengamalay3	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1392t453r1661b499],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1392t453r1661b499],
16	Jennifer	NNP	PERSON	Jennifer	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1677t460r1838b491],
17	Zaborsky3	NNP	PERSON	Zaborsky3	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1854t453r2067b499],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1854t453r2067b499],
19	Elodie	NNP	PERSON	Elodie	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2085t460r2206b491],
20	Ghedin4	NNP	PERSON	Ghedin4	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l243t511r415b553],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l243t511r415b553],
22	Jacqueline	NNP	PERSON	Jacqueline	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l431t518r642b556],
23	Noltings	NNP	PERSON	Noltings	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l659t511r834b557],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l659t511r834b557],
25	David	NNP	PERSON	David	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l852t518r965b549],
26	E.	NNP	PERSON	E.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l983t520r1015b549],
27	Swaynes	NNP	PERSON	Swaynes	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1032t511r1212b557],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1032t511r1212b557],
29	Jonathan	NNP	PERSON	Jonathan	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1228t518r1410b549],
30	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1427t520r1466b549],
31	Runstadler7	NNP	PERSON	Runstadler7	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1484t511r1726b553],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1484t511r1726b553],
33	George	NNP	PERSON	George	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1742t520r1887b557],
34	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1904t520r1949b549],
35	Happ7	NNP	PERSON	Happ7	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1967t511r2100b556],
36	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1967t511r2100b556],
37	Dennis	NNP	PERSON	Dennis	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2118t518r2253b549],
38	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2269t520r2308b549],
39	Sennes	NNP	PERSON	Sennes	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l244t569r393b611],
40	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t569r393b611],
41	Ruixue	NNP	PERSON	Ruixue	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l412t576r545b607],
42	Wang	NNP	PERSON	Wang	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l561t569r703b615],
43	‘	NNP	O	‘	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l561t569r703b615],
44	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l561t569r703b615],
45	Richard	NNP	PERSON	Richard	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l722t576r869b607],
46	D.	NNP	PERSON	D.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l887t578r927b607],
47	Slemonss	NNP	PERSON	Slemonss	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l944t569r1139b611],
48	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l944t569r1139b611],
49	Edward	NNP	PERSON	Edward	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1158t576r1304b607],
50	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1322t577r1358b607],
51	Holmes	NNP	PERSON	Holmes	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1376t569r1579b611],
52	”	NNP	O	”	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1376t569r1579b611],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1376t569r1579b611],
54	Jeffery	NNP	PERSON	Jeffery	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1594t576r1730b615],
55	K.	NNP	PERSON	K.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1747t578r1782b607],
56	Taubenberger	NNP	PERSON	Taubenberger	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1797t569r2116b615],
57	‘	CD	NUMBER	‘	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1797t569r2116b615],
58	*	CD	NUMBER	*	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1797t569r2116b615],
59	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l245t645r254b664],
60	Laboratory	NN	O	laboratory	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l266t643r396b670],
61	of	IN	O	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l409t643r433b664],
62	Infectious	JJ	O	infectious	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l445t643r561b664],
63	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l576t644r682b668],
64	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l576t644r682b668],
65	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l696t643r795b664],
66	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l810t644r907b664],
67	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l920t643r945b664],
68	Allergy	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Allergy	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l956t643r1040b670],
69	and	CC	O	and	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1052t643r1096b664],
70	Infectious	JJ	O	infectious	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1111t643r1227b664],
71	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1241t644r1347b668],
72	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1241t644r1347b668],
73	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1362t643r1460b664],
74	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1475t644r1584b664],
75	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1598t643r1622b664],
76	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1634t643r1717b668],
77	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1634t643r1717b668],
78	Bethesda	NNP	LOCATION	Bethesda	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1731t643r1846b668],
79	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1731t643r1846b668],
80	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1861t643r1977b670],
81	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1861t643r1977b670],
82	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1992t643r2070b664],
83	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2084t644r2155b664],
84	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2169t643r2193b664],
85	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2204t644r2308b668],
86	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2204t644r2308b668],
87	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l243t686r258b705],
88	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l265t685r345b705],
89	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l353t684r386b705],
90	Infectious	JJ	ORGANIZATION	infectious	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l396t684r512b705],
91	Disease	NN	ORGANIZATION	disease	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l522t685r611b705],
92	Dynamics	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Dynamics	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l622t685r743b711],
93	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l622t685r743b711],
94	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l754t685r899b711],
95	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l908t684r933b705],
96	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l941t684r1035b711],
97	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l941t684r1035b711],
98	The	DT	O	the	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1043t684r1088b705],
99	Pennsylvania	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pennsylvania	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1098t684r1253b711],
100	State	NNP	ORGANIZATION	State	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1263t685r1323b705],
101	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1333t685r1457b711],
102	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1333t685r1457b711],
103	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1468t685r1586b711],
104	Park	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Park	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1596t684r1651b709],
105	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1596t684r1651b709],
106	Pennsylvania	NNP	LOCATION	Pennsylvania	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1662t684r1823b711],
107	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1662t684r1823b711],
108	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1834t684r1911b705],
109	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1922t685r1993b705],
110	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2003t684r2028b705],
111	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2035t685r2138b709],
112	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2035t685r2138b709],
113	3The	NNP	O	3The	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2148t684r2213b705],
114	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2222t685r2238b705],
115	Craig	NNP	PERSON	Craig	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2247t685r2307b711],
116	Venter	NNP	PERSON	Venter	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l242t727r322b747],
117	Institute	NNP	PERSON	Institute	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l333t727r437b751],
118	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l333t727r437b751],
119	Rockville	NNP	LOCATION	Rockville	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l449t726r559b751],
120	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l449t726r559b751],
121	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l570t726r687b753],
122	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l570t726r687b753],
123	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l699t726r777b747],
124	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l789t727r860b747],
125	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l871t726r896b747],
126	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l904t727r1008b751],
127	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l904t727r1008b751],
128	4Department	NN	O	4department	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1019t727r1187b753],
129	of	IN	O	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1198t726r1223b747],
130	Medicine	NNP	MISC	Medicine	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1232t726r1346b751],
131	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1232t726r1346b751],
132	School	NNP	ORGANIZATION	School	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1357t726r1436b747],
133	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1448t726r1472b747],
134	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1482t726r1596b751],
135	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1482t726r1596b751],
136	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1608t727r1727b753],
137	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1737t726r1761b747],
138	Pittsburgh	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pittsburgh	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1771t726r1901b753],
139	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1771t726r1901b753],
140	Pittsburgh	NNP	LOCATION	Pittsburgh	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1913t726r2044b753],
141	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1913t726r2044b753],
142	Pennsylvania	NNP	LOCATION	Pennsylvania	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2056t726r2217b753],
143	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2056t726r2217b753],
144	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2229t726r2307b747],
145	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l243t768r314b788],
146	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l326t767r350b788],
147	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l359t768r463b792],
148	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l359t768r463b792],
149	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l475t769r490b788],
150	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l498t768r643b794],
151	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l654t767r679b788],
152	Veterinary	JJ	ORGANIZATION	veterinary	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l687t768r811b794],
153	Preventive	JJ	ORGANIZATION	preventive	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l822t768r948b788],
154	Medicine	NN	ORGANIZATION	medicine	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l960t767r1074b792],
155	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l960t767r1074b792],
156	The	DT	O	the	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1085t767r1129b788],
157	Ohio	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Ohio	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1140t767r1196b788],
158	State	NNP	ORGANIZATION	State	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1208t768r1268b788],
159	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1280t768r1404b794],
160	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1280t768r1404b794],
161	Columbus	NNP	LOCATION	Columbus	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1415t767r1544b792],
162	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1415t767r1544b792],
163	Ohio	NNP	LOCATION	Ohio	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1555t767r1617b792],
164	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1555t767r1617b792],
165	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1630t767r1708b788],
166	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1721t768r1792b788],
167	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1803t767r1828b788],
168	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1837t768r1940b792],
169	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1837t768r1940b792],
170	6Southeast	NNP	ORGANIZATION	6Southeast	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1952t767r2094b788],
171	Poultry	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Poultry	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2106t767r2191b794],
172	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2202t767r2307b788],
173	Laboratory	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Laboratory	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l244t809r379b836],
174	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t809r379b836],
175	Agricultural	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Agricultural	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l392t809r531b836],
176	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l547t809r651b830],
177	Service	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Service	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l666t810r755b834],
178	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l666t810r755b834],
179	US	NNP	ORGANIZATION	US	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l770t810r800b830],
180	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l814t810r959b836],
181	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l972t809r997b830],
182	Agriculture	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Agriculture	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1007t809r1147b836],
183	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1007t809r1147b836],
184	Athens	NNP	LOCATION	Athens	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1160t809r1250b834],
185	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1160t809r1250b834],
186	Georgia	NNP	LOCATION	Georgia	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1263t810r1363b836],
187	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1263t810r1363b836],
188	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1377t809r1455b830],
189	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1470t810r1541b830],
190	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1554t809r1578b830],
191	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1589t810r1693b834],
192	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1589t810r1693b834],
193	7	CD	NUMBER	7	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1707t811r1721b830],
194	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1730t810r1827b830],
195	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1840t809r1865b830],
196	Arctic	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Arctic	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1876t810r1944b830],
197	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1958t809r2052b836],
198	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1958t809r2052b836],
199	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2066t810r2184b836],
200	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2197t809r2222b830],
201	Alaska	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Alaska	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2232t809r2307b830],
202	Fairbanks	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Fairbanks	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l244t850r363b875],
203	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t850r363b875],
204	Fairbanks	NNP	PERSON	Fairbanks	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l379t850r498b875],
205	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l379t850r498b875],
206	Alaska	NNP	LOCATION	Alaska	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l513t850r595b875],
207	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l513t850r595b875],
208	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l612t850r689b871],
209	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l706t851r777b871],
210	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l792t850r817b871],
211	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l830t851r933b875],
212	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l830t851r933b875],
213	8Nationa	NNP	ORGANIZATION	8Nationa	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l949t850r1070b871],
214	|	NNP	ORGANIZATION	|	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l949t850r1070b871],
215	Veterinary	JJ	ORGANIZATION	veterinary	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1086t851r1209b877],
216	Services	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Services	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1224t851r1319b871],
217	Laboratories	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Laboratories	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1336t850r1490b875],
218	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1336t850r1490b875],
219	Animal	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Animal	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1506t850r1588b871],
220	and	CC	ORGANIZATION	and	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1604t850r1648b871],
221	Plant	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Plant	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1665t850r1724b871],
222	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1740t850r1816b871],
223	Inspection	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Inspection	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1833t851r1956b877],
224	Service	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Service	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1973t851r2062b875],
225	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1973t851r2062b875],
226	US	NNP	ORGANIZATION	US	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2079t851r2109b871],
227	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2125t851r2270b877],
228	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2285t850r2310b871],
229	Agriculture	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Agriculture	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l243t892r383b919],
230	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l243t892r383b919],
231	Ames	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Ames	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l394t893r466b917],
232	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l394t893r466b917],
233	Iowa	NNP	LOCATION	Iowa	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l479t893r541b917],
234	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l479t893r541b917],
235	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l554t892r632b913],
236	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l645t893r716b913],
237	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l728t892r752b913],
238	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l762t893r865b917],
239	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l762t893r865b917],
240	9	CD	NUMBER	9	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l878t894r893b913],
241	Fogarty	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Fogarty	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l901t893r992b919],
242	International	NNP	ORGANIZATION	International	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1004t892r1156b913],
243	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1168t893r1253b917],
244	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1168t893r1253b917],
245	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1266t892r1365b913],
246	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1378t893r1487b913],
247	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1499t892r1524b913],
248	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1535t892r1617b917],
249	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1535t892r1617b917],
250	Bethesda	NNP	LOCATION	Bethesda	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1630t892r1745b917],
251	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1630t892r1745b917],
252	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1758t892r1874b919],
253	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1758t892r1874b919],
254	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1888t892r1966b913],
255	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l1979t893r2050b913],
256	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	257	SENT_4	[p1l2061t892r2086b913],
257	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2096t893r2193b913],

1	Abstract	JJ	O	abstract	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l308t1009r475b1040],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_6	[p1l308t1076r356b1101],
2	surveyed	VBD	O	survey	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l370t1074r508b1109],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_6	[p1l522t1074r572b1101],
4	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	5	SENT_6	[p1l585t1075r699b1109],
5	diversity	NN	O	diversity	dobj	2	SENT_6	[p1l713t1074r843b1109],
6	among	IN	O	among	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l855t1082r963b1109],
7	avian	JJ	O	avian	amod	12	SENT_6	[p1l978t1075r1057b1101],
8	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	12	SENT_6	[p1l1073t1074r1211b1101],
9	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	12	SENT_6	[p1l1224t1075r1296b1101],
10	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	12	SENT_6	[p1l1311t1075r1381b1106],
11	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nn	12	SENT_6	[p1l1311t1075r1381b1106],
12	)	NN	O	)	prep_among	2	SENT_6	[p1l1311t1075r1381b1106],
13	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1396t1075r1421b1101],
14	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	15	SENT_6	[p1l1435t1074r1498b1101],
15	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	12	SENT_6	[p1l1514t1074r1596b1106],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1514t1074r1596b1106],
17	comprising	VBG	O	comprise	partmod	2	SENT_6	[p1l1609t1075r1780b1109],
18	167	CD	NUMBER	167	num	21	SENT_6	[p1l1798t1076r1850b1101],
19	complete	JJ	O	complete	amod	21	SENT_6	[p1l1864t1074r2009b1108],
20	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	21	SENT_6	[p1l2022t1074r2084b1101],
21	genomes	NNS	O	genome	dobj	17	SENT_6	[p1l2099t1082r2242b1109],
22	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l308t1116r380b1143],
23	14	CD	NUMBER	14	num	25	SENT_6	[p1l396t1119r429b1143],
24	bird	NN	O	bird	nn	25	SENT_6	[p1l441t1116r500b1143],
25	species	NNS	O	species	prep_from	17	SENT_6	[p1l513t1117r624b1150],
26	sampled	VBN	O	sample	partmod	25	SENT_6	[p1l636t1116r765b1150],
27	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l779t1117r804b1143],
28	four	CD	NUMBER	four	num	29	SENT_6	[p1l816t1116r880b1143],
29	locations	NNS	O	location	prep_in	26	SENT_6	[p1l892t1116r1029b1143],
30	across	IN	O	across	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1041t1124r1135b1143],
31	the	DT	O	the	det	33	SENT_6	[p1l1146t1116r1196b1143],
32	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	33	SENT_6	[p1l1210t1116r1310b1143],
33	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	prep_across	29	SENT_6	[p1l1323t1117r1423b1143],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1323t1117r1423b1143],

1	These	DT	O	these	det	2	SENT_7	[p1l1433t1116r1524b1143],
2	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	nsubj	3	SENT_7	[p1l1536t1116r1649b1143],
3	represented	VBD	O	represent	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1662t1116r1847b1150],
4	29	CD	NUMBER	29	num	5	SENT_7	[p1l1860t1118r1895b1143],
5	type	NN	O	type	dobj	3	SENT_7	[p1l1906t1121r1975b1151],
6	A	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_7	[p1l1986t1118r2008b1143],
7	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	9	SENT_7	[p1l2020t1116r2158b1143],
8	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	9	SENT_7	[p1l2170t1117r2242b1143],
9	hemagglutinin	NN	O	hemagglutinin	dep	5	SENT_7	[p1l310t1157r535b1192],
10	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	11	SENT_7	[p1l551t1158r615b1189],
11	HA	NNP	O	HA	dep	5	SENT_7	[p1l551t1158r615b1189],
12	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	11	SENT_7	[p1l551t1158r615b1189],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l628t1157r684b1184],
14	neuraminidase	NN	O	neuraminidase	nn	17	SENT_7	[p1l699t1157r927b1184],
15	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	17	SENT_7	[p1l941t1158r1005b1189],
16	NA	NN	O	na	nn	17	SENT_7	[p1l941t1158r1005b1189],
17	)	NN	O	)	conj_and	5	SENT_7	[p1l941t1158r1005b1189],
18	subtype	NN	O	subtype	nn	19	SENT_7	[p1l1019t1157r1143b1192],
19	combinations	NNS	O	combination	dep	17	SENT_7	[p1l1156t1157r1375b1189],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1156t1157r1375b1189],
21	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1388t1157r1454b1184],
22	up	RB	O	up	advmod	28	SENT_7	[p1l1469t1165r1507b1191],
23	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1520t1161r1551b1184],
24	26	CD	PERCENT	26	num	25	SENT_7	[p1l1564t1159r1629b1185],
25	%	NN	PERCENT	%	prep_to	22	SENT_7	[p1l1564t1159r1629b1185],
26	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1642t1157r1674b1184],
27	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	prep_of	25	SENT_7	[p1l1685t1157r1798b1184],
28	showing	VBG	O	show	prepc_with	3	SENT_7	[p1l1811t1157r1941b1192],
29	evidence	NN	O	evidence	dobj	28	SENT_7	[p1l1955t1157r2093b1184],
30	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l2106t1157r2138b1184],
31	mixed	JJ	O	mixed	amod	33	SENT_7	[p1l2149t1157r2241b1184],
32	subtype	NN	O	subtype	nn	33	SENT_7	[p1l309t1198r433b1233],
33	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_of	29	SENT_7	[p1l447t1198r589b1225],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l447t1198r589b1225],

1	Through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l601t1198r733b1233],
2	a	DT	O	a	det	4	SENT_8	[p1l748t1206r762b1225],
3	phylogenetic	JJ	O	phylogenetic	amod	4	SENT_8	[p1l777t1198r979b1233],
4	analysis	NN	O	analysis	prep_through	19	SENT_8	[p1l992t1198r1110b1233],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1124t1198r1155b1225],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_8	[p1l1165t1198r1215b1225],
7	largest	JJS	O	largest	amod	9	SENT_8	[p1l1230t1198r1332b1233],
8	data	NNS	O	datum	nn	9	SENT_8	[p1l1345t1198r1411b1225],
9	set	NN	O	set	prep_of	4	SENT_8	[p1l1425t1203r1468b1225],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1481t1198r1513b1225],
11	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nn	12	SENT_8	[p1l1523t1200r1575b1225],
12	genomes	NNS	O	genome	prep_of	9	SENT_8	[p1l1587t1206r1730b1233],
13	compiled	VBN	O	compile	partmod	12	SENT_8	[p1l1744t1198r1886b1232],
14	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1900t1203r1931b1225],
15	date	NN	O	date	prep_to	13	SENT_8	[p1l1945t1198r2020b1230],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1945t1198r2020b1230],
17	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	19	SENT_8	[p1l2033t1206r2077b1225],
18	were	VBD	O	be	cop	19	SENT_8	[p1l2090t1206r2165b1225],
19	able	JJ	O	able	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2178t1198r2242b1225],
20	to	TO	O	to	aux	21	SENT_8	[p1l308t1245r339b1267],
21	document	VB	O	document	xcomp	19	SENT_8	[p1l357t1240r517b1267],
22	a	DT	O	a	det	25	SENT_8	[p1l534t1248r549b1267],
23	remarkably	RB	O	remarkably	advmod	24	SENT_8	[p1l569t1240r741b1275],
24	high	JJ	O	high	amod	25	SENT_8	[p1l759t1240r824b1275],
25	rate	NN	O	rate	dobj	21	SENT_8	[p1l844t1245r902b1267],
26	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l920t1240r952b1267],
27	genome	NN	O	genome	nn	28	SENT_8	[p1l967t1248r1095b1275],
28	reassortment	NN	O	reassortment	prep_of	25	SENT_8	[p1l1114t1245r1324b1272],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1114t1245r1324b1272],
30	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1341t1240r1407b1267],
31	no	DT	O	no	det	33	SENT_8	[p1l1427t1248r1465b1267],
32	clear	JJ	O	clear	amod	33	SENT_8	[p1l1483t1240r1555b1267],
33	pattern	NN	O	pattern	prep_with	21	SENT_8	[p1l1573t1245r1684b1274],
34	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1703t1240r1735b1267],
35	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	37	SENT_8	[p1l1750t1248r1826b1275],
36	segment	NN	O	segment	nn	37	SENT_8	[p1l1844t1245r1979b1275],
37	association	NN	O	association	prep_of	33	SENT_8	[p1l1996t1241r2166b1267],
38	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2185t1240r2241b1267],
39	occasional	JJ	O	occasional	amod	45	SENT_8	[p1l309t1282r468b1309],
40	inter	NN	O	inter	nn	45	SENT_8	[p1l483t1282r748b1316],
41	—	NN	O	—	nn	45	SENT_8	[p1l483t1282r748b1316],
42	hemisphere	NN	O	hemisphere	nn	45	SENT_8	[p1l483t1282r748b1316],
43	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	45	SENT_8	[p1l761t1290r837b1317],
44	segment	NN	O	segment	nn	45	SENT_8	[p1l850t1286r985b1317],
45	migration	NN	O	migration	conj_and	37	SENT_8	[p1l998t1283r1146b1317],
46	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1160t1282r1216b1309],
47	reassortment	NN	O	reassortment	conj_and	37	SENT_8	[p1l1231t1286r1441b1309],
48	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1231t1286r1441b1309],

1	From	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1455t1284r1532b1309],
2	this	DT	O	this	prep_from	5	SENT_9	[p1l1545t1282r1607b1314],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1545t1282r1607b1314],
4	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	5	SENT_9	[p1l1619t1290r1664b1309],
5	propose	VBP	O	propose	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1677t1290r1803b1316],
6	that	IN	O	that	complm	11	SENT_9	[p1l1815t1282r1877b1309],
7	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nsubj	11	SENT_9	[p1l1889t1284r1941b1309],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1953t1283r1978b1309],
9	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	10	SENT_9	[p1l1991t1282r2054b1309],
10	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	7	SENT_9	[p1l2068t1282r2142b1309],
11	forms	VBZ	O	form	ccomp	5	SENT_9	[p1l2154t1282r2242b1309],
12	transient	JJ	O	transient	amod	15	SENT_9	[p1l308t1324r445b1350],
13	”	NN	O	”	nn	15	SENT_9	[p1l457t1324r601b1358],
14	genome	NN	O	genome	nn	15	SENT_9	[p1l457t1324r601b1358],
15	constellations	NNS	O	constellation	dobj	11	SENT_9	[p1l614t1323r851b1355],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l614t1323r851b1355],
17	”	NN	O	”	appos	15	SENT_9	[p1l614t1323r851b1355],
18	continually	RB	O	continually	advmod	19	SENT_9	[p1l864t1323r1035b1358],
19	reshuffled	VBN	O	reshuffle	partmod	17	SENT_9	[p1l1048t1323r1200b1350],
20	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1216t1323r1252b1358],
21	reassortment	NN	O	reassortment	agent	19	SENT_9	[p1l1265t1327r1475b1355],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1265t1327r1475b1355],
23	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1489t1324r1514b1350],
24	contrast	NN	O	contrast	prep_in	11	SENT_9	[p1l1528t1328r1653b1350],
25	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1666t1328r1697b1350],
26	the	DT	O	the	det	27	SENT_9	[p1l1709t1323r1759b1350],
27	spread	NN	O	spread	prep_to	24	SENT_9	[p1l1772t1323r1874b1357],
28	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1888t1323r1920b1350],
29	a	DT	O	a	det	31	SENT_9	[p1l1930t1331r1945b1350],
30	limited	JJ	O	limited	amod	31	SENT_9	[p1l1960t1323r2064b1350],
31	number	NN	O	number	prep_of	27	SENT_9	[p1l2079t1323r2201b1350],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l2213t1323r2245b1350],
33	stable	JJ	O	stable	amod	35	SENT_9	[p1l309t1365r400b1392],
34	genome	NN	O	genome	nn	35	SENT_9	[p1l415t1373r543b1400],
35	constellations	NNS	O	constellation	prep_of	31	SENT_9	[p1l558t1365r771b1392],
36	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	37	SENT_9	[p1l786t1365r848b1392],
37	characterizes	VBZ	O	characterize	rcmod	27	SENT_9	[p1l863t1365r1063b1392],
38	the	DT	O	the	det	39	SENT_9	[p1l1077t1365r1127b1392],
39	evolution	NN	O	evolution	nsubj	45	SENT_9	[p1l1142t1365r1287b1392],
40	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1303t1365r1335b1392],
41	mamma	NN	O	mamma	nn	44	SENT_9	[p1l1348t1365r1670b1399],
42	|	NN	O	|	nn	44	SENT_9	[p1l1348t1365r1670b1399],
43	ian	NN	O	ian	nn	44	SENT_9	[p1l1348t1365r1670b1399],
44	—	NN	O	—	prep_of	39	SENT_9	[p1l1348t1365r1670b1399],
45	adapted	VBD	O	adapt	ccomp	37	SENT_9	[p1l1348t1365r1670b1399],
46	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nsubj	48	SENT_9	[p1l1687t1365r1825b1392],
47	A	DT	O	a	det	48	SENT_9	[p1l1840t1367r1862b1392],
48	viruses	NNS	O	virus	xcomp	45	SENT_9	[p1l1875t1366r1989b1392],
49	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1875t1366r1989b1392],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l278t1469r396b1490],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l278t1469r396b1490],
3	Dugan	NNP	PERSON	Dugan	nn	4	SENT_10	[p1l410t1470r487b1496],
4	VG	NNP	O	VG	dep	1	SENT_10	[p1l500t1470r540b1494],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l500t1470r540b1494],
6	Chen	NNP	PERSON	Chen	nn	7	SENT_10	[p1l553t1469r614b1490],
7	R	NNP	PERSON	R	appos	4	SENT_10	[p1l629t1470r647b1494],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l629t1470r647b1494],
9	Spiro	NNP	PERSON	Spiro	nn	10	SENT_10	[p1l661t1470r721b1496],
10	DJ	NNP	PERSON	DJ	appos	4	SENT_10	[p1l735t1470r768b1494],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l735t1470r768b1494],
12	Sengamalay	NNP	O	Sengamalay	nn	13	SENT_10	[p1l782t1469r928b1496],
13	N	NNP	O	N	appos	4	SENT_10	[p1l941t1470r963b1494],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l941t1470r963b1494],
15	Zaborsky	NNP	PERSON	Zaborsky	nn	16	SENT_10	[p1l975t1469r1085b1496],
16	J	NNP	PERSON	J	appos	4	SENT_10	[p1l1097t1470r1112b1494],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1097t1470r1112b1494],
18	et	FW	O	et	dep	4	SENT_10	[p1l1125t1473r1148b1490],
19	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	20	SENT_10	[p1l1160t1469r1185b1490],
20	(	FW	O	(	dep	4	SENT_10	[p1l1198t1470r1271b1494],
21	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	22	SENT_10	[p1l1198t1470r1271b1494],
22	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	20	SENT_10	[p1l1198t1470r1271b1494],
23	The	DT	O	the	det	25	SENT_10	[p1l1283t1469r1327b1490],
24	Evolutionaw	NNP	O	Evolutionaw	nn	25	SENT_10	[p1l1341t1469r1491b1496],
25	Genetics	NNP	O	Genetics	dep	20	SENT_10	[p1l1503t1470r1606b1490],
26	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1619t1469r1662b1490],
27	Emergence	NNP	O	Emergence	conj_and	4	SENT_10	[p1l1677t1470r1811b1496],
28	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1824t1469r1849b1490],
29	Avian	JJ	O	avian	amod	31	SENT_10	[p1l1859t1470r1925b1490],
30	Inﬂuenza	NNP	O	Inﬂuenza	nn	31	SENT_10	[p1l1940t1469r2047b1490],
31	Viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_of	27	SENT_10	[p1l2060t1470r2145b1490],
32	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2159t1470r2178b1490],
33	Wild	NNP	O	Wild	nn	34	SENT_10	[p1l2191t1469r2243b1490],
34	Birds	NNPS	O	Birds	prep_in	31	SENT_10	[p1l279t1503r342b1524],
35	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l279t1503r342b1524],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_11	[p1l355t1504r411b1524],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l424t1503r507b1530],
3	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	4	SENT_11	[p1l520t1504r570b1528],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_11	[p1l520t1504r570b1528],
5	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	6	SENT_11	[p1l520t1504r570b1528],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_11	[p1l520t1504r570b1528],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l520t1504r570b1528],
8	e1000076	NN	O	e1000076	dep	2	SENT_11	[p1l582t1505r704b1524],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l582t1505r704b1524],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	nn	2	SENT_12	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],
2	:10	FW	O	:10	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],

1	l371/journa	NN	O	l371/journa	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],
2	|	NN	O	|	dep	1	SENT_13	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],

1	l0O0076	NN	O	l0o0076	dep	16	SENT_15	[p1l716t1503r1123b1530],
2	Editor	NNP	O	Editor	dep	1	SENT_15	[p1l279t1555r370b1576],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l279t1555r370b1576],
4	Daniel	NNP	PERSON	Daniel	nn	8	SENT_15	[p1l382t1555r456b1576],
5	R.	NNP	PERSON	R.	nn	8	SENT_15	[p1l469t1556r488b1576],
6	Perez	NNP	PERSON	Perez	nn	8	SENT_15	[p1l501t1556r570b1580],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l501t1556r570b1580],
8	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	1	SENT_15	[p1l583t1556r702b1582],
9	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l712t1555r737b1576],
10	Maryland	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Maryland	prep_of	8	SENT_15	[p1l747t1555r864b1582],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l747t1555r864b1582],
12	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	nn	13	SENT_15	[p1l877t1555r955b1576],
13	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	nsubj	16	SENT_15	[p1l968t1556r1039b1576],
14	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1051t1555r1076b1576],
15	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	prep_of	13	SENT_15	[p1l1085t1556r1182b1576],
16	Received	VBD	O	receive	ccomp	67	SENT_15	[p1l279t1606r401b1627],
17	January	NNP	DATE	January	nsubj	28	SENT_15	[p1l413t1607r506b1633],
18	14	CD	DATE	14	num	17	SENT_15	[p1l519t1608r551b1631],
19	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l519t1608r551b1631],
20	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	17	SENT_15	[p1l563t1608r627b1631],
21	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l563t1608r627b1631],
22	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	amod	17	SENT_15	[p1l638t1606r766b1633],
23	April	NNP	DATE	April	tmod	22	SENT_15	[p1l779t1606r833b1633],
24	24	CD	DATE	24	num	23	SENT_15	[p1l846t1608r879b1631],
25	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l846t1608r879b1631],
26	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	23	SENT_15	[p1l891t1608r955b1631],
27	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l891t1608r955b1631],
28	Published	VBN	O	publish	dep	16	SENT_15	[p1l967t1606r1103b1627],
29	May	NNP	DATE	May	tmod	28	SENT_15	[p1l1116t1607r1165b1633],
30	30	CD	DATE	30	num	29	SENT_15	[p1l1176t1608r1209b1631],
31	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1176t1608r1209b1631],
32	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	29	SENT_15	[p1l1221t1608r1278b1627],
33	This	DT	O	this	nsubj	39	SENT_15	[p1l277t1658r325b1679],
34	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	39	SENT_15	[p1l337t1659r352b1679],
35	an	DT	O	a	det	39	SENT_15	[p1l363t1664r390b1679],
36	open	JJ	O	open	amod	39	SENT_15	[p1l402t1664r550b1685],
37	—	NN	O	—	nn	39	SENT_15	[p1l402t1664r550b1685],
38	access	NN	O	access	nn	39	SENT_15	[p1l402t1664r550b1685],
39	article	NN	O	article	ccomp	16	SENT_15	[p1l561t1658r633b1679],
40	distributed	VBN	O	distribute	partmod	39	SENT_15	[p1l644t1658r775b1679],
41	under	IN	O	under	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l788t1658r858b1679],
42	the	DT	O	the	det	43	SENT_15	[p1l868t1658r907b1679],
43	terms	NNS	O	term	prep_under	40	SENT_15	[p1l917t1662r985b1679],
44	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l996t1658r1021b1679],
45	the	DT	O	the	det	50	SENT_15	[p1l1029t1658r1068b1679],
46	Creative	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Creative	nn	50	SENT_15	[p1l1079t1659r1177b1679],
47	Commons	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Commons	nn	50	SENT_15	[p1l1188t1659r1311b1679],
48	Public	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Public	nn	50	SENT_15	[p1l1323t1658r1395b1679],
49	Domain	NN	ORGANIZATION	domain	nn	50	SENT_15	[p1l1407t1659r1499b1679],
50	declaration	NN	O	declaration	prep_of	43	SENT_15	[p1l1511t1658r1645b1679],
51	which	WDT	O	which	nsubj	52	SENT_15	[p1l1656t1658r1727b1679],
52	stipulates	VBZ	O	stipulate	rcmod	50	SENT_15	[p1l1740t1658r1854b1685],
53	that	IN	O	that	nsubj	56	SENT_15	[p1l1864t1658r1918b1683],
54	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1864t1658r1918b1683],
55	once	RB	DATE	once	advmod	56	SENT_15	[p1l1930t1664r1987b1679],
56	placed	VBN	O	place	ccomp	52	SENT_15	[p1l1999t1658r2077b1685],
57	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l2089t1659r2108b1679],
58	the	DT	O	the	det	60	SENT_15	[p1l2120t1658r2159b1679],
59	public	JJ	O	public	amod	60	SENT_15	[p1l2171t1658r2244b1685],
60	domain	NN	O	domain	prep_in	56	SENT_15	[p1l278t1692r375b1717],
61	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l278t1692r375b1717],
62	this	DT	O	this	det	63	SENT_15	[p1l387t1692r429b1713],
63	work	NN	O	work	nsubjpass	67	SENT_15	[p1l441t1692r501b1713],
64	may	MD	O	may	aux	67	SENT_15	[p1l512t1699r562b1719],
65	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	67	SENT_15	[p1l574t1692r602b1713],
66	freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	67	SENT_15	[p1l613t1692r680b1719],
67	reproduced	VBN	O	reproduce	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l692t1692r837b1719],
68	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l692t1692r837b1719],
69	distributed	VBN	O	distribute	conj_or	67	SENT_15	[p1l849t1692r986b1717],
70	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l849t1692r986b1717],
71	transmitted	VBN	O	transmit	conj_or	67	SENT_15	[p1l998t1692r1144b1717],
72	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l998t1692r1144b1717],
73	modiﬁed	VBN	O	modiﬁed	conj_or	67	SENT_15	[p1l1157t1692r1269b1717],
74	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1157t1692r1269b1717],
75	built	VBN	O	build	conj_or	67	SENT_15	[p1l1282t1692r1335b1713],
76	upon	IN	O	upon	prep	75	SENT_15	[p1l1347t1698r1415b1719],
77	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1347t1698r1415b1719],
78	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1427t1699r1451b1713],
79	otherwise	RB	O	otherwise	advmod	80	SENT_15	[p1l1462t1692r1580b1713],
80	used	VBN	O	use	conj_or	67	SENT_15	[p1l1593t1692r1647b1713],
81	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1661t1692r1689b1719],
82	anyone	NN	O	anyone	prep_by	80	SENT_15	[p1l1700t1698r1788b1719],
83	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1799t1692r1833b1713],
84	any	DT	O	any	det	86	SENT_15	[p1l1844t1698r1886b1719],
85	lawful	JJ	O	lawful	amod	86	SENT_15	[p1l1898t1692r1968b1713],
86	purpose	NN	O	purpose	prep_for	82	SENT_15	[p1l1981t1698r2085b1719],
87	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1981t1698r2085b1719],

1	Funding	NNP	O	Funding	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l279t1743r401b1770],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l279t1743r401b1770],
3	This	DT	O	this	det	4	SENT_16	[p1l411t1743r459b1764],
4	research	NN	O	research	nsubjpass	6	SENT_16	[p1l472t1743r570b1764],
5	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_16	[p1l583t1749r628b1764],
6	supported	VBN	O	support	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l640t1743r764b1770],
7	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l777t1744r796b1764],
8	part	NN	O	part	prep_in	6	SENT_16	[p1l810t1747r857b1770],
9	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l869t1743r897b1770],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_16	[p1l908t1743r947b1764],
11	Intramural	NNP	O	Intramural	nn	13	SENT_16	[p1l959t1743r1082b1764],
12	Research	NNP	O	Research	nn	13	SENT_16	[p1l1095t1743r1200b1764],
13	Program	NNP	O	Program	agent	6	SENT_16	[p1l1214t1744r1315b1770],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1327t1743r1352b1764],
15	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_16	[p1l1361t1743r1400b1764],
16	NIH	NNP	ORGANIZATION	NIH	prep_of	13	SENT_16	[p1l1413t1744r1461b1768],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1413t1744r1461b1768],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1472t1743r1516b1764],
19	the	DT	O	the	det	20	SENT_16	[p1l1528t1743r1567b1764],
20	NIAID	NNP	ORGANIZATION	NIAID	agent	6	SENT_16	[p1l1580t1744r1653b1764],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1580t1744r1653b1764],

1	Competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	2	SENT_17	[p1l278t1795r431b1822],
2	Interests	NNS	O	interest	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l444t1796r571b1816],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l444t1796r571b1816],
4	The	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_17	[p1l581t1795r626b1816],
5	authors	NNS	O	author	nsubj	7	SENT_17	[p1l637t1795r728b1816],
6	have	VBP	O	have	aux	7	SENT_17	[p1l741t1795r796b1816],
7	declared	VBN	O	declare	dep	2	SENT_17	[p1l808t1795r910b1816],
8	that	IN	O	that	complm	12	SENT_17	[p1l922t1795r970b1816],
9	no	DT	O	no	det	11	SENT_17	[p1l982t1801r1011b1816],
10	competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	11	SENT_17	[p1l1023t1796r1153b1822],
11	interests	NNS	O	interest	nsubj	12	SENT_17	[p1l1167t1796r1268b1816],
12	exist	VBP	O	exist	ccomp	7	SENT_17	[p1l1279t1796r1339b1816],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1279t1796r1339b1816],

1	*	NN	O	*	nn	2	SENT_18	[p1l278t1848r289b1858],
2	E	NN	O	e	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l301t1847r379b1868],
3	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	2	SENT_18	[p1l301t1847r379b1868],
4	mai	FW	O	mai	nn	5	SENT_18	[p1l301t1847r379b1868],
5	|	FW	O	|	dep	3	SENT_18	[p1l301t1847r379b1868],
6	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l301t1847r379b1868],
7	taubenbergerj@niaid.nih.gov	NN	O	taubenbergerj@niaid.nih.gov	dep	3	SENT_18	[p1l390t1847r742b1874],

1	Introduction	NN	O	introduction	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l245t1976r490b2007],

1	Low	JJ	O	low	amod	5	SENT_20	[p1l280t2051r346b2077],
2	pathogenic	JJ	O	pathogenic	amod	5	SENT_20	[p1l360t2051r524b2085],
3	(	NN	O	(	nn	5	SENT_20	[p1l541t2051r608b2085],
4	LP	NN	O	lp	nn	5	SENT_20	[p1l541t2051r608b2085],
5	)	NN	O	)	nsubjpass	14	SENT_20	[p1l541t2051r608b2085],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l541t2051r608b2085],
7	antigenically	RB	O	antigenically	advmod	8	SENT_20	[p1l626t2051r814b2085],
8	diverse	JJ	O	diverse	amod	9	SENT_20	[p1l829t2051r931b2077],
9	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	appos	5	SENT_20	[p1l948t2051r1083b2077],
10	A	DT	O	a	det	11	SENT_20	[p1l1098t2051r1123b2076],
11	viruses	NNS	O	virus	dep	9	SENT_20	[p1l1137t2051r1237b2077],
12	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	14	SENT_20	[p1l243t2104r288b2121],
13	widely	RB	O	widely	advmod	14	SENT_20	[p1l308t2095r404b2129],
14	distributed	VBN	O	distribute	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l424t2095r583b2121],
15	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l603t2095r630b2120],
16	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	18	SENT_20	[p1l649t2095r712b2121],
17	avian	JJ	O	avian	amod	18	SENT_20	[p1l732t2095r811b2121],
18	species	NNS	O	species	prep_in	14	SENT_20	[p1l831t2095r931b2129],
19	around	IN	O	around	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l952t2095r1059b2121],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_20	[p1l1078t2095r1123b2121],
21	world	NN	O	world	prep_around	18	SENT_20	[p1l1143t2095r1235b2121],
22	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1143t2095r1235b2121],

1	They	PRP	O	they	nsubjpass	3	SENT_21	[p1l243t2139r321b2173],
2	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	3	SENT_21	[p1l334t2148r378b2165],
3	maintained	VBN	O	maintain	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l392t2139r560b2165],
4	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l573t2139r609b2173],
5	asymptomatic	JJ	O	asymptomatic	amod	6	SENT_21	[p1l621t2139r828b2173],
6	infections	NNS	O	infection	agent	3	SENT_21	[p1l841t2139r990b2171],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l841t2139r990b2171],
8	most	JJS	O	most	appos	6	SENT_21	[p1l1004t2145r1075b2165],
9	frequently	RB	O	frequently	advmod	10	SENT_21	[p1l1086t2139r1238b2173],
10	documented	VBN	O	document	partmod	8	SENT_21	[p1l243t2183r428b2209],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l451t2183r478b2208],
12	aquatic	JJ	O	aquatic	amod	13	SENT_21	[p1l502t2183r609b2217],
13	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	10	SENT_21	[p1l633t2183r705b2209],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l729t2183r761b2209],
15	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_21	[p1l779t2183r823b2209],
16	orders	NNS	O	order	prep_of	13	SENT_21	[p1l848t2183r939b2209],
17	Anseriformes	NNPS	O	Anseriformes	dep	16	SENT_21	[p1l962t2183r1159b2209],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1183t2183r1238b2209],
19	Charadriformes	NNPS	O	Charadriformes	conj_and	17	SENT_21	[p1l244t2227r487b2253],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l244t2227r487b2253],

1	As	IN	O	as	mark	6	SENT_22	[p1l513t2227r550b2253],
2	such	JJ	O	such	amod	5	SENT_22	[p1l575t2227r649b2259],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l575t2227r649b2259],
4	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	5	SENT_22	[p1l674t2227r736b2253],
5	birds	NNS	O	bird	nsubj	6	SENT_22	[p1l760t2227r833b2253],
6	represent	VBP	O	represent	csubj	14	SENT_22	[p1l858t2233r995b2261],
7	major	JJ	O	major	amod	9	SENT_22	[p1l1019t2227r1107b2261],
8	natural	JJ	O	natural	amod	9	SENT_22	[p1l1132t2227r1238b2253],
9	reservoirs	NNS	O	reservoir	dobj	6	SENT_22	[p1l243t2272r384b2298],
10	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l396t2272r438b2298],
11	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	13	SENT_22	[p1l449t2272r584b2298],
12	A	NN	O	a	nn	13	SENT_22	[p1l595t2272r620b2297],
13	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_for	9	SENT_22	[p1l630t2272r729b2298],
14	[	VBP	O	[	dep	42	SENT_22	[p1l745t2272r804b2306],
15	l	NN	O	l	tmod	36	SENT_22	[p1l745t2272r804b2306],
16	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	17	SENT_22	[p1l745t2272r804b2306],
17	l	NN	O	l	nsubjpass	36	SENT_22	[p1l745t2272r804b2306],
18	l	NN	O	l	nn	19	SENT_22	[p1l815t2272r836b2306],
19	]	NN	O	]	dep	17	SENT_22	[p1l815t2272r836b2306],
20	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l852t2272r907b2298],
21	at	IN	O	at	quantmod	23	SENT_22	[p1l919t2278r945b2298],
22	least	JJS	O	least	mwe	21	SENT_22	[p1l956t2272r1021b2298],
23	105	CD	NUMBER	105	num	24	SENT_22	[p1l1037t2272r1085b2298],
24	species	NNS	O	species	nsubjpass	36	SENT_22	[p1l1099t2272r1198b2306],
25	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1211t2272r1243b2298],
26	the	DT	O	the	det	30	SENT_22	[p1l243t2315r287b2341],
27	more	JJR	O	more	mwe	28	SENT_22	[p1l303t2324r379b2341],
28	than	IN	O	than	quantmod	29	SENT_22	[p1l395t2315r461b2341],
29	9000	CD	NUMBER	9000	num	30	SENT_22	[p1l477t2315r549b2341],
30	species	NNS	O	species	prep_of	24	SENT_22	[p1l565t2315r665b2349],
31	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l680t2315r712b2341],
32	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	33	SENT_22	[p1l721t2315r784b2341],
33	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_of	30	SENT_22	[p1l798t2315r871b2341],
34	have	VBP	O	have	aux	36	SENT_22	[p1l886t2315r954b2341],
35	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	36	SENT_22	[p1l970t2315r1040b2341],
36	identiﬁed	VBN	O	identiﬁed	ccomp	14	SENT_22	[p1l1056t2315r1194b2341],
37	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1210t2324r1237b2341],
38	harboring	VBG	O	harbor	prepc_as	36	SENT_22	[p1l243t2360r392b2394],
39	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	41	SENT_22	[p1l401t2360r537b2386],
40	A	NN	O	a	nn	41	SENT_22	[p1l547t2360r572b2385],
41	viruses	NNS	O	virus	dobj	38	SENT_22	[p1l581t2360r681b2386],
42	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l696t2360r730b2394],
43	8	CD	NUMBER	8	dobj	42	SENT_22	[p1l696t2360r730b2394],
44	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l696t2360r730b2394],
45	l	NN	O	l	appos	43	SENT_22	[p1l738t2361r746b2385],
46	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	45	SENT_22	[p1l753t2360r777b2392],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l753t2360r777b2392],
48	l	NN	O	l	tmod	43	SENT_22	[p1l784t2361r792b2385],
49	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	50	SENT_22	[p1l800t2360r835b2394],
50	]	NN	O	]	nsubj	42	SENT_22	[p1l800t2360r835b2394],
51	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l800t2360r835b2394],

1	These	DT	O	these	det	4	SENT_23	[p1l848t2360r937b2386],
2	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	4	SENT_23	[p1l948t2360r1084b2386],
3	A	NN	O	a	nn	4	SENT_23	[p1l1093t2360r1119b2385],
4	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	17	SENT_23	[p1l1128t2360r1236b2392],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1128t2360r1236b2392],
6	commonly	RB	O	commonly	advmod	7	SENT_23	[p1l243t2404r401b2438],
7	referred	VBN	O	refer	partmod	4	SENT_23	[p1l420t2404r538b2430],
8	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l557t2410r584b2430],
9	as	IN	O	as	mark	13	SENT_23	[p1l604t2413r632b2430],
10	avian	JJ	O	avian	amod	12	SENT_23	[p1l652t2404r731b2430],
11	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	12	SENT_23	[p1l751t2404r887b2430],
12	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	13	SENT_23	[p1l905t2404r1004b2430],
13	(	VBP	O	(	prepc_to	7	SENT_23	[p1l1025t2404r1114b2438],
14	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nn	15	SENT_23	[p1l1025t2404r1114b2438],
15	)	NN	O	)	dobj	13	SENT_23	[p1l1025t2404r1114b2438],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1025t2404r1114b2438],
17	possess	VBP	O	possess	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1134t2413r1237b2438],
18	antigenically	RB	O	antigenically	dep	22	SENT_23	[p1l243t2448r431b2482],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l444t2448r499b2474],
20	genetically	RB	O	genetically	advmod	21	SENT_23	[p1l511t2448r669b2482],
21	diverse	JJ	O	diverse	conj_and	18	SENT_23	[p1l681t2448r783b2474],
22	hemagglutinin	NN	O	hemagglutinin	nsubj	24	SENT_23	[p1l796t2448r1011b2482],
23	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	24	SENT_23	[p1l1025t2448r1094b2482],
24	HA	NNP	O	HA	xcomp	17	SENT_23	[p1l1025t2448r1094b2482],
25	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	24	SENT_23	[p1l1025t2448r1094b2482],
26	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	27	SENT_23	[p1l1112t2448r1166b2482],
27	14	CD	NUMBER	14	num	28	SENT_23	[p1l1112t2448r1166b2482],
28	]	NN	O	]	dep	24	SENT_23	[p1l1112t2448r1166b2482],
29	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1183t2448r1238b2474],
30	neuraminidase	NN	O	neuraminidase	xcomp	17	SENT_23	[p1l243t2492r461b2518],
31	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	34	SENT_23	[p1l476t2492r544b2526],
32	NA	NN	MISC	na	nn	34	SENT_23	[p1l476t2492r544b2526],
33	)	NN	O	)	nn	34	SENT_23	[p1l476t2492r544b2526],
34	subtypes	NNS	O	subtype	dep	30	SENT_23	[p1l559t2492r692b2526],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l559t2492r692b2526],
36	which	WDT	O	which	nsubj	37	SENT_23	[p1l706t2492r795b2518],
37	includes	VBZ	O	include	rcmod	30	SENT_23	[p1l809t2492r928b2518],
38	all	DT	O	all	nsubj	39	SENT_23	[p1l943t2492r976b2517],
39	known	JJ	O	known	ccomp	37	SENT_23	[p1l989t2492r1088b2518],
40	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	45	SENT_23	[p1l1102t2492r1238b2518],
41	A	NN	O	a	nn	45	SENT_23	[p1l242t2536r267b2561],
42	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	45	SENT_23	[p1l279t2536r350b2562],
43	HA	NNP	O	HA	nn	45	SENT_23	[p1l364t2536r418b2561],
44	(	NNP	O	(	nn	45	SENT_23	[p1l431t2536r580b2570],
45	Hl	NNP	O	Hl	dobj	39	SENT_23	[p1l431t2536r580b2570],
46	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l431t2536r580b2570],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l431t2536r580b2570],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l431t2536r580b2570],

1	Hl6	NN	O	hl6	nn	2	SENT_25	[p1l431t2536r580b2570],
2	)	NN	O	)	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l431t2536r580b2570],
3	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l594t2536r650b2562],
4	NA	NN	O	na	nn	5	SENT_25	[p1l662t2536r715b2562],
5	(	NN	O	(	conj_and	2	SENT_25	[p1l728t2536r855b2570],
6	Nl	NN	O	nl	dep	2	SENT_25	[p1l728t2536r855b2570],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l728t2536r855b2570],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l728t2536r855b2570],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l728t2536r855b2570],

1	N9	NN	O	n9	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l728t2536r855b2570],
2	)	NN	O	)	nn	3	SENT_27	[p1l728t2536r855b2570],
3	subtypes	NNS	O	subtype	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l869t2536r1002b2570],
4	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l869t2536r1002b2570],

1	At	IN	O	at	quantmod	3	SENT_28	[p1l1016t2536r1052b2562],
2	least	JJS	O	least	mwe	1	SENT_28	[p1l1065t2536r1130b2562],
3	103	CD	NUMBER	103	nsubj	21	SENT_28	[p1l1147t2536r1196b2562],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1211t2536r1243b2562],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_28	[p1l243t2580r287b2606],
6	possible	JJ	O	possible	amod	8	SENT_28	[p1l304t2580r419b2614],
7	144	CD	NUMBER	144	tmod	6	SENT_28	[p1l441t2580r490b2605],
8	type	NN	O	type	prep_of	3	SENT_28	[p1l506t2586r568b2614],
9	A	DT	O	a	det	12	SENT_28	[p1l584t2580r609b2605],
10	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	12	SENT_28	[p1l625t2580r760b2606],
11	A	NN	O	a	nn	12	SENT_28	[p1l775t2580r801b2605],
12	virus	NN	O	virus	dep	8	SENT_28	[p1l815t2580r886b2606],
13	HA-NA	JJ	O	ha-na	amod	14	SENT_28	[p1l903t2580r1022b2606],
14	combinations	NNS	O	combination	nsubjpass	17	SENT_28	[p1l1037t2580r1237b2606],
15	have	VBP	O	have	aux	17	SENT_28	[p1l243t2624r311b2650],
16	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	17	SENT_28	[p1l326t2624r396b2650],
17	found	VBN	O	find	rcmod	12	SENT_28	[p1l410t2624r497b2650],
18	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l511t2624r538b2649],
19	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	20	SENT_28	[p1l551t2624r614b2650],
20	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	17	SENT_28	[p1l628t2624r700b2650],
21	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l718t2624r811b2658],
22	8	CD	NUMBER	8	dobj	21	SENT_28	[p1l718t2624r811b2658],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l718t2624r811b2658],
24	l5	CD	NUMBER	l5	num	25	SENT_28	[p1l718t2624r811b2658],
25	]	NN	O	]	appos	22	SENT_28	[p1l718t2624r811b2658],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l718t2624r811b2658],

1	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nsubj	2	SENT_29	[p1l279t2669r345b2695],
2	maintained	VBD	O	maintain	dep	8	SENT_29	[p1l359t2669r527b2695],
3	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l541t2669r568b2694],
4	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	5	SENT_29	[p1l582t2669r644b2695],
5	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	2	SENT_29	[p1l658t2669r730b2695],
6	have	VBP	O	have	aux	8	SENT_29	[p1l745t2669r813b2695],
7	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	8	SENT_29	[p1l828t2669r898b2695],
8	associated	VBN	O	associate	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l913t2669r1062b2695],
9	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1075t2669r1139b2695],
10	stable	JJ	O	stable	amod	13	SENT_29	[p1l1154t2669r1236b2695],
11	host	NN	O	host	nn	13	SENT_29	[p1l243t2713r303b2739],
12	switch	NN	O	switch	nn	13	SENT_29	[p1l319t2713r410b2739],
13	events	NNS	O	event	prep_with	8	SENT_29	[p1l426t2719r516b2739],
14	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l532t2719r559b2739],
15	novel	JJ	O	novel	amod	16	SENT_29	[p1l575t2713r654b2739],
16	hosts	NNS	O	host	prep_to	8	SENT_29	[p1l669t2713r741b2739],
17	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l757t2713r896b2747],
18	domestic	JJ	O	domestic	amod	20	SENT_29	[p1l910t2713r1041b2739],
19	gallinaceous	JJ	O	gallinaceous	amod	20	SENT_29	[p1l1056t2713r1237b2747],
20	poultry	NN	O	poultry	prep_including	16	SENT_29	[p1l242t2757r357b2791],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l242t2757r357b2791],
22	horses	NNS	O	horse	prep_including	16	SENT_29	[p1l375t2757r475b2789],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l375t2757r475b2789],
24	swine	NNS	O	swine	prep_including	16	SENT_29	[p1l493t2757r582b2789],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l493t2757r582b2789],
26	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l600t2757r655b2783],
27	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_including	16	SENT_29	[p1l671t2757r788b2783],
28	leading	VBG	O	lead	partmod	16	SENT_29	[p1l804t2757r913b2791],
29	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l928t2763r955b2783],
30	the	DT	O	the	det	31	SENT_29	[p1l972t2757r1017b2783],
31	emergence	NN	O	emergence	prep_to	28	SENT_29	[p1l1034t2766r1193b2791],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1211t2757r1243b2783],
33	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	prep_of	31	SENT_29	[p1l243t2801r379b2827],
34	A	DT	O	a	det	35	SENT_29	[p1l392t2801r417b2826],
35	lineages	NNS	O	lineage	nsubjpass	8	SENT_29	[p1l431t2801r547b2835],
36	transmissible	JJ	O	transmissible	amod	35	SENT_29	[p1l562t2801r752b2827],
37	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l768t2801r795b2826],
38	the	DT	O	the	det	40	SENT_29	[p1l810t2801r854b2827],
39	new	JJ	O	new	amod	40	SENT_29	[p1l870t2810r930b2827],
40	host	NN	O	host	prep_in	36	SENT_29	[p1l944t2801r1011b2827],
41	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l944t2801r1011b2827],

1	Adaptation	NN	O	adaptation	nsubj	11	SENT_30	[p1l1027t2801r1195b2835],
2	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1209t2807r1237b2827],
3	domestic	JJ	O	domestic	amod	5	SENT_30	[p1l243t2845r374b2871],
4	poultry	NN	O	poultry	nn	5	SENT_30	[p1l391t2845r499b2879],
5	species	NNS	O	species	prep_to	1	SENT_30	[p1l516t2845r616b2879],
6	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	11	SENT_30	[p1l634t2845r654b2871],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_30	[p1l672t2845r717b2871],
8	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	9	SENT_30	[p1l735t2851r806b2871],
9	frequent	JJ	O	frequent	amod	11	SENT_30	[p1l822t2845r948b2879],
10	[	NN	O	[	nn	11	SENT_30	[p1l969t2845r1090b2879],
11	l6	NN	O	l6	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l969t2845r1090b2879],
12	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	14	SENT_30	[p1l969t2845r1090b2879],
13	26	CD	NUMBER	26	num	14	SENT_30	[p1l969t2845r1090b2879],
14	]	NN	O	]	dep	11	SENT_30	[p1l969t2845r1090b2879],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l969t2845r1090b2879],

1	Sporadically	RB	O	sporadically	advmod	10	SENT_31	[p1l1110t2845r1237b2879, p1l243t2889r318b2923],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1110t2845r1237b2879, p1l243t2889r318b2923],
3	strains	NNS	O	strain	nsubj	10	SENT_31	[p1l332t2889r426b2915],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l440t2889r471b2915],
5	poultry-adapted	JJ	O	poultry-adapted	amod	6	SENT_31	[p1l479t2889r718b2923],
6	H5	NN	O	h5	prep_of	3	SENT_31	[p1l731t2889r776b2915],
7	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l791t2898r822b2915],
8	H7	NN	O	h7	nn	9	SENT_31	[p1l834t2889r879b2915],
9	AIV	NN	O	aiv	prep_of	3	SENT_31	[p1l893t2889r958b2915],
10	evolve	VB	O	evolve	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l971t2889r1063b2915],
11	into	IN	O	into	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1077t2889r1133b2915],
12	highly	RB	O	highly	advmod	13	SENT_31	[p1l1146t2889r1238b2923],
13	pathogenic	JJ	O	pathogenic	amod	14	SENT_31	[p1l242t2933r406b2967],
14	(	NN	O	(	prep_into	10	SENT_31	[p1l420t2933r486b2967],
15	HP	NNP	O	HP	nn	17	SENT_31	[p1l420t2933r486b2967],
16	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	17	SENT_31	[p1l420t2933r486b2967],
17	AIV	NN	O	aiv	tmod	14	SENT_31	[p1l498t2933r563b2959],
18	usually	RB	O	usually	advmod	17	SENT_31	[p1l575t2933r679b2967],
19	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l690t2933r808b2967],
20	acquisition	NN	O	acquisition	prep_through	10	SENT_31	[p1l822t2933r981b2967],
21	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l995t2933r1027b2959],
22	an	DT	O	a	det	24	SENT_31	[p1l1034t2942r1069b2958],
23	insertional	JJ	O	insertional	amod	24	SENT_31	[p1l1082t2933r1237b2959],
24	mutation	NN	O	mutation	prep_of	20	SENT_31	[p1l243t2978r377b3004],
25	resulting	VBG	O	result	partmod	24	SENT_31	[p1l393t2978r520b3012],
26	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l534t2978r561b3003],
27	a	DT	O	a	det	32	SENT_31	[p1l577t2987r592b3003],
28	polybasic	JJ	O	polybasic	amod	32	SENT_31	[p1l606t2978r743b3012],
29	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	32	SENT_31	[p1l759t2978r852b3004],
30	acid	NN	O	acid	nn	32	SENT_31	[p1l867t2978r928b3004],
31	cleavage	NN	O	cleavage	nn	32	SENT_31	[p1l942t2978r1067b3012],
32	site	NN	O	site	prep_in	25	SENT_31	[p1l1083t2978r1129b3004],
33	within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1144t2978r1237b3004],
34	the	DT	O	the	det	35	SENT_31	[p1l243t3022r287b3048],
35	HA	NNP	O	HA	prep_within	25	SENT_31	[p1l299t3022r353b3047],
36	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	37	SENT_31	[p1l367t3022r478b3056],
37	15,25	CD	NUMBER	15,25	num	38	SENT_31	[p1l367t3022r478b3056],
38	]	NN	O	]	dep	25	SENT_31	[p1l367t3022r478b3056],
39	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l367t3022r478b3056],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_32	[p1l491t3022r551b3048],
2	current	JJ	DATE	current	amod	3	SENT_32	[p1l562t3028r670b3048],
3	panzootic	NN	O	panzootic	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l680t3022r825b3056],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l836t3022r868b3048],
5	Asian-lineage	JJ	O	asian-lineage	amod	7	SENT_32	[p1l872t3022r1073b3056],
6	HP	NNP	O	HP	nn	7	SENT_32	[p1l1084t3022r1134b3047],
7	H5Nl	NN	O	h5nl	prep_of	3	SENT_32	[p1l1144t3022r1233b3048],

1	0	CD	NUMBER	0	num	2	SENT_33	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
2	[	CD	NUMBER	[	nsubj	5	SENT_33	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
3	99	CD	NUMBER	99	num	4	SENT_33	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
4	PLoS	NN	O	plo	dep	2	SENT_33	[p1l344t3144r408b3167],
5	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l423t3143r567b3174],
6	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	7	SENT_33	[p1l587t3142r590b3175],
7	www	NN	O	www	dobj	5	SENT_33	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],

1	p	NN	O	p	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_34	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	dep	1	SENT_34	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],

1	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nsubj	2	SENT_35	[p1l1313t1975r1378b2001],
2	appears	VBZ	O	appear	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1390t1984r1504b2009],
3	to	TO	O	to	aux	5	SENT_35	[p1l1515t1981r1543b2001],
4	be	VB	O	be	cop	5	SENT_35	[p1l1555t1975r1588b2001],
5	unique	JJ	O	unique	xcomp	2	SENT_35	[p1l1600t1975r1702b2009],
6	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1714t1975r1741b2000],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_35	[p1l1753t1975r1797b2001],
8	era	NN	O	era	prep_in	5	SENT_35	[p1l1810t1984r1856b2001],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1867t1975r1899b2001],
10	modern	JJ	O	modern	amod	12	SENT_35	[p1l1905t1975r2021b2001],
11	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	12	SENT_35	[p1l2033t1975r2169b2001],
12	virology	NN	O	virology	prep_of	8	SENT_35	[p1l2179t1975r2307b2009],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l2179t1975r2307b2009],
14	resulting	VBG	O	result	partmod	8	SENT_35	[p1l1314t2018r1442b2052],
15	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1458t2018r1485b2043],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_35	[p1l1502t2018r1547b2044],
17	deaths	NNS	O	death	prep_in	14	SENT_35	[p1l1565t2018r1659b2044],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1677t2018r1709b2044],
19	millions	NNS	O	million	prep_of	17	SENT_35	[p1l1721t2018r1837b2044],
20	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1854t2018r1886b2044],
21	poultry	NN	O	poultry	prep_of	19	SENT_35	[p1l1898t2018r2006b2052],
22	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l2022t2018r2049b2043],
23	64	CD	NUMBER	64	num	24	SENT_35	[p1l2067t2018r2102b2044],
24	countries	NNS	O	country	prep_in	14	SENT_35	[p1l2120t2018r2254b2044],
25	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l2272t2027r2308b2044],
26	three	CD	NUMBER	three	num	27	SENT_35	[p1l1314t2062r1388b2088],
27	continents	NNS	O	continent	prep_on	24	SENT_35	[p1l1406t2062r1558b2088],
28	either	CC	O	either	dep	24	SENT_35	[p1l1576t2062r1661b2088],
29	from	IN	O	from	conj	24	SENT_35	[p1l1677t2062r1748b2088],
30	infection	NN	O	infection	pobj	29	SENT_35	[p1l1765t2062r1893b2088],
31	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1911t2071r1941b2088],
32	culling	NN	O	culling	pobj	29	SENT_35	[p1l1958t2062r2063b2096],
33	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1958t2062r2063b2096],

1	There	EX	O	there	expl	2	SENT_36	[p1l2082t2062r2172b2088],
2	are	VBP	O	be	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l2190t2071r2235b2088],
3	also	RB	O	also	advmod	2	SENT_36	[p1l2253t2062r2308b2088],
4	significant	JJ	O	significant	amod	6	SENT_36	[p1l1314t2105r1465b2139],
5	zoonotic	JJ	O	zoonotic	amod	6	SENT_36	[p1l1491t2105r1617b2131],
6	implications	NNS	O	implication	nsubj	2	SENT_36	[p1l1644t2105r1824b2139],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1852t2105r1884b2131],
8	this	DT	O	this	prep_of	6	SENT_36	[p1l1905t2105r1956b2131],
9	panzootic	JJ	O	panzootic	amod	6	SENT_36	[p1l1982t2105r2135b2139],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1982t2105r2135b2139],
11	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l2162t2105r2227b2131],
12	379	CD	NUMBER	379	num	14	SENT_36	[p1l2255t2105r2307b2131],
13	documented	VBN	O	document	amod	14	SENT_36	[p1l1314t2149r1499b2175],
14	cases	NNS	O	case	prep_with	6	SENT_36	[p1l1523t2158r1595b2175],
15	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1620t2149r1647b2174],
16	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_in	14	SENT_36	[p1l1671t2149r1797b2181],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1671t2149r1797b2181],
18	resulting	VBG	O	result	partmod	6	SENT_36	[p1l1822t2149r1950b2183],
19	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1973t2149r2000b2174],
20	239	CD	NUMBER	239	num	21	SENT_36	[p1l2025t2149r2078b2175],
21	deaths	NNS	O	death	prep_in	18	SENT_36	[p1l2102t2149r2197b2175],
22	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l2221t2149r2248b2174],
23	14	CD	NUMBER	14	num	24	SENT_36	[p1l2277t2149r2308b2174],
24	countries	NNS	O	country	prep_in	21	SENT_36	[p1l1314t2192r1448b2218],
25	since	IN	O	since	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1461t2192r1533b2218],
26	2003	CD	DATE	2003	num	27	SENT_36	[p1l1547t2192r1617b2219],
27	(	CD	NUMBER	(	prep_since	24	SENT_36	[p1l1632t2192r1668b2226],
28	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1632t2192r1668b2226],
29	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1681t2192r1713b2218],
30	April	NNP	DATE	April	conj_of	6	SENT_36	[p1l1719t2192r1795b2226],
31	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	30	SENT_36	[p1l1808t2192r1879b2218],
32	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	33	SENT_36	[p1l1896t2192r1970b2226],
33	27	CD	NUMBER	27	num	35	SENT_36	[p1l1896t2192r1970b2226],
34	]	NN	O	]	nn	35	SENT_36	[p1l1896t2192r1970b2226],
35	)	NN	O	)	dep	30	SENT_36	[p1l1896t2192r1970b2226],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1896t2192r1970b2226],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_37	[p1l1984t2192r2044b2218],
2	Asian	JJ	MISC	asian	amod	3	SENT_37	[p1l2056t2192r2140b2218],
3	lineages	NNS	O	lineage	nsubj	10	SENT_37	[p1l2152t2192r2268b2226],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l2282t2192r2314b2218],
5	HP	NNP	O	HP	nn	7	SENT_37	[p1l1314t2236r1364b2261],
6	H5Nl	NN	O	h5nl	nn	7	SENT_37	[p1l1389t2236r1478b2262],
7	AIV	NN	O	aiv	prep_of	3	SENT_37	[p1l1507t2236r1572b2262],
8	have	VBP	O	have	aux	10	SENT_37	[p1l1598t2236r1666b2262],
9	also	RB	O	also	advmod	10	SENT_37	[p1l1693t2236r1748b2262],
10	caused	VBN	O	cause	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1774t2236r1874b2262],
11	symptomatic	JJ	O	symptomatic	amod	14	SENT_37	[p1l1900t2236r2098b2270],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1900t2236r2098b2270],
13	even	RB	O	even	advmod	14	SENT_37	[p1l2125t2245r2192b2262],
14	lethal	JJ	O	lethal	amod	16	SENT_37	[p1l2218t2236r2307b2268],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l2218t2236r2307b2268],
16	infections	NNS	O	infection	dobj	10	SENT_37	[p1l1314t2280r1455b2306],
17	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1480t2280r1512b2306],
18	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	19	SENT_37	[p1l1530t2280r1593b2306],
19	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_of	16	SENT_37	[p1l1616t2280r1689b2306],
20	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1714t2280r1741b2305],
21	Asia	NNP	LOCATION	Asia	prep_in	10	SENT_37	[p1l1764t2280r1828b2306],
22	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1853t2280r1908b2306],
23	Europe	NNP	LOCATION	Europe	conj_and	21	SENT_37	[p1l1932t2280r2049b2314],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1932t2280r2049b2314],
25	suggesting	VBG	O	suggest	partmod	10	SENT_37	[p1l2075t2280r2227b2314],
26	that	IN	O	that	complm	32	SENT_37	[p1l2251t2280r2309b2306],
27	migratory	JJ	O	migratory	amod	29	SENT_37	[p1l1314t2323r1461b2357],
28	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	29	SENT_37	[p1l1473t2323r1536b2349],
29	birds	NNS	O	bird	nsubjpass	32	SENT_37	[p1l1548t2323r1621b2349],
30	could	MD	O	could	aux	32	SENT_37	[p1l1635t2323r1716b2349],
31	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	32	SENT_37	[p1l1728t2323r1762b2349],
32	involved	VBN	O	involve	ccomp	25	SENT_37	[p1l1776t2323r1901b2349],
33	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1914t2323r1942b2348],
34	the	DT	O	the	det	35	SENT_37	[p1l1955t2323r2000b2349],
35	spread	NN	O	spread	prep_in	32	SENT_37	[p1l2014t2323r2111b2357],
36	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l2125t2323r2157b2349],
37	this	DT	O	this	det	40	SENT_37	[p1l2165t2323r2215b2349],
38	avian	JJ	O	avian	amod	40	SENT_37	[p1l2229t2323r2308b2349],
39	panzootic	JJ	O	panzootic	amod	40	SENT_37	[p1l1313t2367r1458b2401],
40	[	NN	O	[	prep_of	35	SENT_37	[p1l1474t2367r1554b2401],
41	28	CD	NUMBER	28	num	42	SENT_37	[p1l1474t2367r1554b2401],
42	—	NN	O	—	dep	40	SENT_37	[p1l1474t2367r1554b2401],
43	3	CD	NUMBER	3	number	44	SENT_37	[p1l1474t2367r1554b2401],
44	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	45	SENT_37	[p1l1562t2367r1594b2401],
45	]	NN	O	]	dep	42	SENT_37	[p1l1562t2367r1594b2401],
46	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1562t2367r1594b2401],

1	Concern	NN	O	concern	nsubjpass	3	SENT_38	[p1l1609t2367r1737b2393],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	3	SENT_38	[p1l1749t2367r1768b2393],
3	heightened	VBN	O	heighten	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1780t2367r1944b2401],
4	since	IN	O	since	mark	9	SENT_38	[p1l1956t2367r2027b2393],
5	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	6	SENT_38	[p1l2038t2367r2100b2393],
6	birds	NNS	O	bird	nsubj	9	SENT_38	[p1l2111t2367r2184b2393],
7	are	VBP	O	be	cop	9	SENT_38	[p1l2196t2376r2240b2393],
8	also	RB	O	also	advmod	9	SENT_38	[p1l2253t2367r2308b2393],
9	likely	JJ	O	likely	advcl	3	SENT_38	[p1l1314t2410r1391b2444],
10	to	TO	O	to	aux	13	SENT_38	[p1l1406t2416r1433b2436],
11	be	VB	O	be	cop	13	SENT_38	[p1l1449t2410r1483b2436],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_38	[p1l1499t2410r1544b2436],
13	reservoir	NN	O	reservoir	xcomp	9	SENT_38	[p1l1561t2410r1691b2436],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1706t2410r1738b2436],
15	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	17	SENT_38	[p1l1749t2410r1885b2436],
16	A	NN	O	a	nn	17	SENT_38	[p1l1899t2410r1925b2435],
17	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_of	13	SENT_38	[p1l1939t2410r2038b2436],
18	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	19	SENT_38	[p1l2054t2410r2112b2436],
19	switch	VBP	O	switch	rcmod	13	SENT_38	[p1l2128t2410r2220b2436],
20	hosts	NNS	O	host	dobj	19	SENT_38	[p1l2236t2410r2308b2436],
21	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1314t2454r1369b2480],
22	stably	RB	O	stably	advmod	19	SENT_38	[p1l1380t2454r1465b2488],
23	adapt	VBP	O	adapt	conj_and	19	SENT_38	[p1l1476t2454r1559b2488],
24	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1569t2460r1596b2480],
25	mammals	NNS	O	mammal	prep_to	23	SENT_38	[p1l1608t2454r1752b2480],
26	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1763t2454r1902b2488],
27	horses	NNS	O	horse	prep_including	25	SENT_38	[p1l1912t2454r2011b2486],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1912t2454r2011b2486],
29	swine	NNS	O	swine	appos	27	SENT_38	[p1l2024t2454r2113b2486],
30	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l2024t2454r2113b2486],
31	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l2126t2454r2181b2480],
32	humans	NNS	O	human	nsubj	33	SENT_38	[p1l2191t2454r2308b2480],
33	[	VBP	O	[	conj_and	3	SENT_38	[p1l1318t2498r1364b2532],
34	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	35	SENT_38	[p1l1318t2498r1364b2532],
35	]	NN	O	]	dobj	33	SENT_38	[p1l1318t2498r1364b2532],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1318t2498r1364b2532],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_39	[p1l1396t2498r1456b2524],
2	last	JJ	O	last	amod	5	SENT_39	[p1l1486t2498r1535b2524],
3	three	CD	NUMBER	three	num	5	SENT_39	[p1l1564t2498r1639b2524],
4	human	JJ	O	human	amod	5	SENT_39	[p1l1669t2498r1774b2524],
5	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nsubj	25	SENT_39	[p1l1804t2498r1940b2524],
6	pandemic	JJ	O	pandemic	amod	7	SENT_39	[p1l1969t2498r2115b2532],
7	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	9	SENT_39	[p1l2145t2498r2244b2524],
8	all	DT	O	all	advmod	9	SENT_39	[p1l2275t2498r2309b2523],
9	contained	VBD	O	contain	rcmod	5	SENT_39	[p1l1314t2541r1460b2567],
10	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	14	SENT_39	[p1l1481t2547r1534b2567],
11	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1556t2550r1586b2567],
12	more	JJR	O	more	conj_or	10	SENT_39	[p1l1607t2550r1683b2567],
13	novel	JJ	O	novel	amod	14	SENT_39	[p1l1705t2541r1784b2567],
14	genes	NNS	O	gene	dobj	9	SENT_39	[p1l1805t2550r1886b2575],
15	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	18	SENT_39	[p1l1907t2541r1965b2567],
16	were	VBD	O	be	cop	18	SENT_39	[p1l1985t2550r2055b2567],
17	very	RB	O	very	advmod	18	SENT_39	[p1l2075t2550r2140b2575],
18	similar	JJ	O	similar	rcmod	14	SENT_39	[p1l2160t2541r2260b2567],
19	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l2280t2547r2308b2567],
20	those	DT	O	those	prep_to	18	SENT_39	[p1l1314t2585r1390b2611],
21	found	VBN	O	find	partmod	20	SENT_39	[p1l1404t2585r1491b2611],
22	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1505t2585r1532b2610],
23	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	24	SENT_39	[p1l1545t2585r1608b2611],
24	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	21	SENT_39	[p1l1622t2585r1694b2611],
25	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1712t2585r1917b2619],
26	l6	NN	O	l6	nn	28	SENT_39	[p1l1712t2585r1917b2619],
27	,20,32,33	CD	NUMBER	,20,32,33	num	28	SENT_39	[p1l1712t2585r1917b2619],
28	]	NN	O	]	dobj	25	SENT_39	[p1l1712t2585r1917b2619],
29	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1712t2585r1917b2619],

1	Despite	IN	O	despite	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1351t2629r1462b2663],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_40	[p1l1475t2629r1519b2655],
3	recent	JJ	O	recent	amod	4	SENT_40	[p1l1532t2635r1624b2655],
4	expansion	NN	O	expansion	prep_despite	17	SENT_40	[p1l1636t2629r1784b2663],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1797t2629r1829b2655],
6	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nn	7	SENT_40	[p1l1835t2629r1900b2655],
7	surveillance	NN	O	surveillance	prep_of	4	SENT_40	[p1l1912t2629r2085b2655],
8	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	9	SENT_40	[p1l2101t2629r2304b2663],
9	7,8	CD	NUMBER	7,8	num	7	SENT_40	[p1l2101t2629r2304b2663],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l2101t2629r2304b2663],
11	l0	NN	O	l0	nn	13	SENT_40	[p1l2101t2629r2304b2663],
12	,34,35	CD	NUMBER	,34,35	num	13	SENT_40	[p1l2101t2629r2304b2663],
13	]	NN	O	]	nsubj	17	SENT_40	[p1l2101t2629r2304b2663],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1314t2673r1369b2699],
15	genomic	JJ	O	genomic	amod	16	SENT_40	[p1l1396t2673r1522b2707],
16	data	NNS	O	datum	conj_and	13	SENT_40	[p1l1550t2673r1614b2699],
17	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1645t2673r1794b2707],
18	5,36	CD	NUMBER	5,36	number	19	SENT_40	[p1l1645t2673r1794b2707],
19	—	CD	NUMBER	—	nsubj	25	SENT_40	[p1l1645t2673r1794b2707],
20	38	CD	NUMBER	38	num	21	SENT_40	[p1l1645t2673r1794b2707],
21	]	NN	O	]	dep	19	SENT_40	[p1l1645t2673r1794b2707],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1645t2673r1794b2707],
23	fundamental	JJ	O	fundamental	amod	24	SENT_40	[p1l1823t2673r2011b2699],
24	questions	NNS	O	question	appos	19	SENT_40	[p1l2039t2673r2176b2707],
25	remain	VBP	O	remain	ccomp	17	SENT_40	[p1l2204t2673r2308b2699],
26	concerning	VBG	O	concern	xcomp	25	SENT_40	[p1l1314t2717r1480b2751],
27	the	DT	O	the	det	28	SENT_40	[p1l1493t2717r1538b2743],
28	ecology	NN	O	ecology	dobj	26	SENT_40	[p1l1553t2717r1665b2751],
29	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1678t2717r1734b2743],
30	evolution	NN	O	evolution	dobj	26	SENT_40	[p1l1748t2717r1885b2743],
31	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1899t2717r1931b2743],
32	these	DT	O	these	det	33	SENT_40	[p1l1940t2717r2013b2743],
33	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_of	28	SENT_40	[p1l2027t2717r2134b2743],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l2027t2717r2134b2743],

1	Prominent	JJ	O	prominent	nsubj	6	SENT_41	[p1l2151t2717r2309b2743],
2	among	IN	O	among	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1314t2769r1417b2794],
3	these	DT	O	these	prep_among	1	SENT_41	[p1l1426t2760r1500b2786],
4	are	VBP	O	be	cop	6	SENT_41	[p1l1511t2769r1564b2786],
5	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1511t2769r1564b2786],
6	(	CD	NUMBER	(	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1577t2760r1601b2794],
7	i	FW	O	i	nn	8	SENT_41	[p1l1577t2760r1601b2794],
8	)	FW	O	)	nsubj	54	SENT_41	[p1l1577t2760r1601b2794],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_41	[p1l1612t2760r1657b2786],
10	structure	NN	O	structure	dep	8	SENT_41	[p1l1669t2766r1798b2786],
11	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1810t2760r1842b2786],
12	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	13	SENT_41	[p1l1847t2760r1952b2794],
13	diversity	NN	O	diversity	prep_of	10	SENT_41	[p1l1963t2760r2087b2794],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l2097t2760r2129b2786],
15	AIV	NN	O	aiv	prep_of	13	SENT_41	[p1l2133t2760r2199b2785],
16	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l2209t2760r2236b2785],
17	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	18	SENT_41	[p1l2246t2760r2309b2786],
18	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	15	SENT_41	[p1l1314t2804r1395b2836],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1314t2804r1395b2836],
20	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1407t2804r1546b2838],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_41	[p1l1556t2804r1601b2830],
22	role	NN	O	role	prep_including	8	SENT_41	[p1l1613t2804r1668b2830],
23	played	VBN	O	play	partmod	22	SENT_41	[p1l1679t2804r1777b2838],
24	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1788t2804r1824b2838],
25	inter-hemispheric	JJ	O	inter-hemispheric	amod	26	SENT_41	[p1l1834t2804r2096b2838],
26	migration	NN	O	migration	agent	23	SENT_41	[p1l2108t2804r2261b2838],
27	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l2108t2804r2261b2838],
28	(	CD	NUMBER	(	prep_including	8	SENT_41	[p1l2274t2804r2308b2838],
29	ii	LS	O	ii	dep	28	SENT_41	[p1l2274t2804r2308b2838],
30	)	IN	O	)	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l2274t2804r2308b2838],
31	the	DT	O	the	det	32	SENT_41	[p1l1314t2847r1359b2873],
32	frequency	NN	O	frequency	prep_)	28	SENT_41	[p1l1375t2847r1523b2881],
33	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1539t2847r1594b2873],
34	pattern	NN	O	pattern	conj_and	32	SENT_41	[p1l1609t2853r1716b2881],
35	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1734t2847r1765b2873],
36	segment	NN	O	segment	nn	37	SENT_41	[p1l1777t2853r1899b2881],
37	reassortment	NN	O	reassortment	prep_of	32	SENT_41	[p1l1915t2853r2113b2879],
38	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1915t2853r2113b2879],
39	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l2132t2847r2187b2873],
40	(	CD	NUMBER	(	conj_and	22	SENT_41	[p1l2203t2847r2246b2881],
41	iii	LS	O	iii	dep	40	SENT_41	[p1l2203t2847r2246b2881],
42	)	IN	O	)	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l2203t2847r2246b2881],
43	the	DT	O	the	det	45	SENT_41	[p1l2263t2847r2308b2873],
44	evolutionary	JJ	O	evolutionary	amod	45	SENT_41	[p1l1314t2891r1501b2925],
45	processes	NNS	O	process	prep_)	40	SENT_41	[p1l1517t2900r1653b2925],
46	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	47	SENT_41	[p1l1672t2891r1730b2917],
47	determine	VBP	O	determine	rcmod	45	SENT_41	[p1l1747t2891r1897b2917],
48	the	DT	O	the	det	50	SENT_41	[p1l1916t2891r1961b2917],
49	antigenic	JJ	O	antigenic	amod	50	SENT_41	[p1l1980t2891r2114b2925],
50	structure	NN	O	structure	dobj	47	SENT_41	[p1l2133t2897r2262b2917],
51	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l2282t2891r2314b2917],
52	AIV	NN	O	aiv	prep_of	50	SENT_41	[p1l1313t2935r1386b2967],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1313t2935r1386b2967],
54	maintained	VBD	O	maintain	rcmod	6	SENT_41	[p1l1405t2935r1574b2961],
55	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1592t2944r1620b2961],
56	discrete	JJ	O	discrete	amod	57	SENT_41	[p1l1639t2935r1750b2961],
57	HA	NNP	O	HA	prep_as	54	SENT_41	[p1l1769t2935r1823b2960],
58	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1841t2935r1896b2961],
59	NA	NNP	O	NA	nn	60	SENT_41	[p1l1914t2935r1966b2960],
60	subtypes	NNS	O	subtype	prep_as	54	SENT_41	[p1l1984t2935r2117b2969],
61	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1984t2935r2117b2969],

1	Herein	RB	O	herein	advmod	4	SENT_42	[p1l2138t2935r2249b2967],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l2138t2935r2249b2967],
3	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	4	SENT_42	[p1l2267t2944r2308b2961],
4	address	VBP	O	address	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l1314t2978r1423b3004],
5	these	DT	O	these	det	6	SENT_42	[p1l1436t2978r1510b3004],
6	questions	NNS	O	question	nsubj	7	SENT_42	[p1l1523t2978r1660b3012],
7	using	VBG	O	use	dep	4	SENT_42	[p1l1673t2978r1751b3012],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_42	[p1l1763t2978r1807b3004],
9	largest	JJS	O	largest	amod	11	SENT_42	[p1l1821t2978r1917b3012],
10	data	NNS	O	datum	nn	11	SENT_42	[p1l1930t2978r1993b3004],
11	set	NN	O	set	dobj	7	SENT_42	[p1l2006t2984r2044b3004],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l2057t2978r2089b3004],
13	complete	JJ	O	complete	amod	15	SENT_42	[p1l2097t2978r2231b3012],
14	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nn	15	SENT_42	[p1l2243t2978r2309b3004],
15	genomes	NNS	O	genome	prep_of	11	SENT_42	[p1l1314t3031r1443b3056],
16	compiled	VBN	O	compile	partmod	15	SENT_42	[p1l1458t3022r1594b3056],
17	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l1608t3028r1635b3048],
18	date	NN	O	date	prep_to	16	SENT_42	[p1l1650t3022r1720b3048],
19	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l1650t3022r1720b3048],

1	Author	NN	O	author	nn	2	SENT_43	[p2l280t269r419b300],
2	Summary	NN	O	summary	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l436t270r625b308],

1	Influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	3	SENT_44	[p2l282t338r420b365],
2	A	NN	O	a	nn	3	SENT_44	[p2l439t340r460b365],
3	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	8	SENT_44	[p2l478t339r583b365],
4	are	VBP	O	be	cop	8	SENT_44	[p2l602t346r648b365],
5	an	DT	O	a	det	8	SENT_44	[p2l666t346r701b365],
6	extremely	RB	O	extremely	advmod	7	SENT_44	[p2l721t338r874b373],
7	divergent	JJ	O	divergent	amod	8	SENT_44	[p2l892t338r1041b373],
8	group	NN	O	group	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l1059t346r1152b373],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l1171t338r1202b365],
10	RNA	NN	O	rna	nn	11	SENT_44	[p2l282t381r346b406],
11	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_of	8	SENT_44	[p2l370t380r475b406],
12	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	13	SENT_44	[p2l500t379r562b406],
13	infect	VBP	O	infect	rcmod	11	SENT_44	[p2l587t379r672b406],
14	in	IN	O	in	mark	22	SENT_44	[p2l698t380r722b406],
15	a	DT	O	a	det	16	SENT_44	[p2l748t387r763b406],
16	variety	NN	O	variety	nsubj	22	SENT_44	[p2l788t380r892b414],
17	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l916t379r948b406],
18	warm	JJ	O	warm	amod	21	SENT_44	[p2l970t379r1198b406],
19	—	NN	O	—	nn	21	SENT_44	[p2l970t379r1198b406],
20	b	NN	O	b	nn	21	SENT_44	[p2l970t379r1198b406],
21	|	NN	O	|	prep_of	16	SENT_44	[p2l970t379r1198b406],
22	ooded	VBD	O	ood	advcl	13	SENT_44	[p2l970t379r1198b406],
23	animals	NNS	O	animal	dobj	22	SENT_44	[p2l280t421r405b453],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l280t421r405b453],
25	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l424t421r565b456],
26	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_including	23	SENT_44	[p2l585t421r667b453],
27	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l585t421r667b453],
28	horses	NNS	O	horse	prep_including	23	SENT_44	[p2l685t421r791b453],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l685t421r791b453],
30	pigs	NNS	O	pig	prep_including	23	SENT_44	[p2l809t422r879b456],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l809t422r879b456],
32	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l896t421r952b448],
33	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_including	23	SENT_44	[p2l972t421r1102b448],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l972t421r1102b448],

1	Since	IN	O	since	mark	3	SENT_45	[p2l1119t422r1199b448],
2	they	PRP	O	they	nsubj	3	SENT_45	[p2l280t463r348b498],
3	contain	VBP	O	contain	advcl	12	SENT_45	[p2l364t464r478b490],
4	a	DT	O	a	det	7	SENT_45	[p2l496t471r510b490],
5	segmented	JJ	O	segmented	amod	7	SENT_45	[p2l528t463r701b498],
6	RNA	NN	MISC	rna	nn	7	SENT_45	[p2l720t465r785b490],
7	genome	NN	O	genome	dobj	3	SENT_45	[p2l801t471r937b498],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l801t471r937b498],
9	mixed	JJ	O	mixed	amod	10	SENT_45	[p2l955t463r1046b490],
10	infection	NN	O	infection	nsubj	12	SENT_45	[p2l1065t463r1198b490],
11	can	MD	O	can	aux	12	SENT_45	[p2l281t512r332b531],
12	lead	VB	O	lead	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l354t504r415b531],
13	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l434t509r465b531],
14	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	15	SENT_45	[p2l484t505r599b539],
15	reassortment	NN	O	reassortment	prep_to	12	SENT_45	[p2l619t509r829b531],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l619t509r829b531],

1	It	PRP	O	it	nsubjpass	3	SENT_46	[p2l849t506r867b531],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	3	SENT_46	[p2l887t505r907b531],
3	thought	VBN	O	think	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l925t504r1052b539],
4	that	IN	O	that	complm	16	SENT_46	[p2l1070t504r1132b531],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_46	[p2l1150t504r1200b531],
6	natural	JJ	O	natural	amod	7	SENT_46	[p2l282t546r387b573],
7	reservoir	NN	O	reservoir	nsubj	16	SENT_46	[p2l411t547r543b573],
8	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l564t546r595b573],
9	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	11	SENT_46	[p2l614t546r753b573],
10	A	NN	O	a	nn	11	SENT_46	[p2l774t548r795b573],
11	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_of	7	SENT_46	[p2l815t547r921b573],
12	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	16	SENT_46	[p2l943t547r963b573],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_46	[p2l983t546r1033b573],
14	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	16	SENT_46	[p2l1054t546r1117b573],
15	bird	NN	O	bird	nn	16	SENT_46	[p2l1140t546r1198b573],
16	population	NN	O	population	ccomp	3	SENT_46	[p2l282t587r458b621],
17	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l282t587r458b621],

1	Influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	3	SENT_47	[p2l472t587r611b614],
2	A	NN	O	a	nn	3	SENT_47	[p2l624t589r645b614],
3	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	5	SENT_47	[p2l656t588r762b614],
4	can	MD	O	can	aux	5	SENT_47	[p2l774t595r826b614],
5	switch	VB	O	switch	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l840t587r936b614],
6	hosts	NNS	O	host	dobj	5	SENT_47	[p2l952t587r1031b614],
7	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1044t587r1100b614],
8	cause	VB	O	cause	conj_and	5	SENT_47	[p2l1113t595r1199b614],
9	novel	JJ	O	novel	amod	10	SENT_47	[p2l282t629r363b656],
10	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	dobj	8	SENT_47	[p2l379t629r532b656],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l548t630r572b656],
12	new	JJ	O	new	amod	13	SENT_47	[p2l589t637r652b656],
13	species	NNS	O	species	prep_in	8	SENT_47	[p2l666t630r785b663],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l666t630r785b663],

1	Influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	2	SENT_48	[p2l801t629r939b656],
2	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	10	SENT_48	[p2l953t630r1059b656],
3	containing	VBG	O	contain	partmod	2	SENT_48	[p2l1073t630r1200b656, p2l281t671r327b705],
4	genes	NNS	O	gene	dobj	3	SENT_48	[p2l345t678r436b705],
5	derived	VBN	O	derive	partmod	4	SENT_48	[p2l452t670r566b697],
6	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l583t670r655b697],
7	bird	NN	O	bird	nn	9	SENT_48	[p2l674t670r732b697],
8	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	9	SENT_48	[p2l750t670r888b697],
9	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_from	5	SENT_48	[p2l905t671r1010b697],
10	caused	VBD	O	cause	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l1027t670r1133b697],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_48	[p2l1150t670r1200b697],
12	last	JJ	O	last	amod	15	SENT_48	[p2l282t712r332b739],
13	three	CD	NUMBER	three	num	15	SENT_48	[p2l343t712r423b739],
14	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	15	SENT_48	[p2l436t712r574b739],
15	pandemics	NNS	O	pandemic	dobj	10	SENT_48	[p2l588t712r755b746],
16	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l768t713r792b739],
17	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_in	15	SENT_48	[p2l807t712r936b739],
18	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l807t712r936b739],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l949t714r974b739],
2	this	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_49	[p2l986t712r1040b739],
3	study	NN	O	study	prep_in	6	SENT_49	[p2l1052t712r1144b747],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l1052t712r1144b747],
5	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	6	SENT_49	[p2l1155t720r1200b739],
6	surveyed	VBD	O	survey	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l281t753r418b788],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_49	[p2l435t753r485b780],
8	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	9	SENT_49	[p2l501t754r615b788],
9	diversity	NN	O	diversity	dobj	6	SENT_49	[p2l632t753r761b788],
10	among	IN	O	among	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l777t761r884b788],
11	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	13	SENT_49	[p2l903t753r1041b780],
12	A	NN	O	a	nn	13	SENT_49	[p2l1058t755r1079b780],
13	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_among	6	SENT_49	[p2l1094t754r1199b780],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l281t796r306b822],
15	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	16	SENT_49	[p2l332t795r394b822],
16	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	6	SENT_49	[p2l421t795r503b822],
17	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l421t795r503b822],

1	Through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l527t795r659b830],
2	a	DT	O	a	det	4	SENT_50	[p2l685t803r700b822],
3	phylogenetic	JJ	O	phylogenetic	amod	4	SENT_50	[p2l727t795r928b830],
4	analysis	NN	O	analysis	prep_through	21	SENT_50	[p2l953t795r1071b830],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l1096t795r1128b822],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_50	[p2l1150t795r1200b822],
7	largest	JJS	O	largest	amod	9	SENT_50	[p2l282t836r384b871],
8	data	NNS	O	datum	nn	9	SENT_50	[p2l399t836r465b863],
9	set	NN	O	set	prep_of	4	SENT_50	[p2l482t841r526b863],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l541t836r573b863],
11	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	14	SENT_50	[p2l585t836r648b863],
12	bird	NN	O	bird	nn	14	SENT_50	[p2l666t836r724b863],
13	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	14	SENT_50	[p2l742t836r880b863],
14	genomes	NNS	O	genome	prep_of	9	SENT_50	[p2l897t844r1040b871],
15	compiled	VBN	O	compile	partmod	14	SENT_50	[p2l1056t836r1198b870],
16	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l280t882r311b905],
17	date	NN	O	date	prep_to	15	SENT_50	[p2l324t878r399b910],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l324t878r399b910],
19	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	21	SENT_50	[p2l411t886r456b905],
20	were	VBD	O	be	cop	21	SENT_50	[p2l468t886r543b905],
21	able	JJ	O	able	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l555t878r619b905],
22	to	TO	O	to	aux	23	SENT_50	[p2l631t883r662b905],
23	document	VB	O	document	xcomp	21	SENT_50	[p2l675t878r835b905],
24	a	DT	O	a	det	27	SENT_50	[p2l847t886r862b905],
25	remarkably	RB	O	remarkably	advmod	26	SENT_50	[p2l876t878r1048b913],
26	high	JJ	O	high	amod	27	SENT_50	[p2l1061t878r1127b913],
27	rate	NN	O	rate	dobj	23	SENT_50	[p2l1142t883r1199b905],
28	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l281t919r312b946],
29	genome	NN	O	genome	nn	30	SENT_50	[p2l329t927r457b954],
30	reassortment	NN	O	reassortment	prep_of	27	SENT_50	[p2l478t924r688b951],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l478t924r688b951],
32	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l707t919r773b946],
33	no	DT	O	no	det	35	SENT_50	[p2l795t927r832b946],
34	clear	JJ	O	clear	amod	35	SENT_50	[p2l852t919r924b946],
35	pattern	NN	O	pattern	prep_with	23	SENT_50	[p2l943t923r1054b953],
36	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l1075t919r1107b946],
37	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	39	SENT_50	[p2l1123t927r1199b954],
38	segment	NN	O	segment	nn	39	SENT_50	[p2l281t966r416b996],
39	association	NN	O	association	prep_of	35	SENT_50	[p2l448t962r617b988],
40	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l651t961r707b988],
41	occasional	JJ	O	occasional	amod	47	SENT_50	[p2l740t961r900b988],
42	inter	NN	O	inter	nn	47	SENT_50	[p2l934t961r1199b995],
43	—	NN	O	—	nn	47	SENT_50	[p2l934t961r1199b995],
44	hemisphere	NN	O	hemisphere	nn	47	SENT_50	[p2l934t961r1199b995],
45	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	47	SENT_50	[p2l281t1010r357b1037],
46	segment	NN	O	segment	nn	47	SENT_50	[p2l382t1006r517b1037],
47	migration	NN	O	migration	conj_and	39	SENT_50	[p2l542t1003r690b1037],
48	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l716t1002r772b1029],
49	reassortment	NN	O	reassortment	conj_and	39	SENT_50	[p2l799t1007r1009b1029],
50	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l799t1007r1009b1029],

1	From	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l1035t1004r1112b1029],
2	this	DT	O	this	prep_from	5	SENT_51	[p2l1137t1002r1200b1034],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l1137t1002r1200b1034],
4	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	5	SENT_51	[p2l280t1052r324b1071],
5	propose	VBP	O	propose	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l349t1052r475b1078],
6	that	IN	O	that	complm	12	SENT_51	[p2l498t1044r560b1071],
7	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nn	8	SENT_51	[p2l585t1044r723b1071],
8	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	12	SENT_51	[p2l747t1045r852b1071],
9	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l877t1045r901b1071],
10	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	11	SENT_51	[p2l926t1044r989b1071],
11	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_in	8	SENT_51	[p2l1015t1044r1088b1071],
12	forms	VBZ	O	form	ccomp	5	SENT_51	[p2l1112t1044r1199b1071],
13	transient	JJ	O	transient	amod	16	SENT_51	[p2l280t1086r416b1112],
14	”	NN	O	”	nn	16	SENT_51	[p2l436t1086r579b1120],
15	genome	NN	O	genome	nn	16	SENT_51	[p2l436t1086r579b1120],
16	constellations	NNS	O	constellation	dobj	12	SENT_51	[p2l599t1085r836b1117],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l599t1085r836b1117],
18	”	NN	O	”	appos	16	SENT_51	[p2l599t1085r836b1117],
19	continually	RB	O	continually	advmod	20	SENT_51	[p2l855t1085r1027b1120],
20	reshuffled	VBN	O	reshuffle	partmod	18	SENT_51	[p2l1046t1085r1198b1112],
21	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l282t1127r318b1162],
22	reassortment	NN	O	reassortment	agent	20	SENT_51	[p2l339t1131r549b1159],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l339t1131r549b1159],
24	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l570t1128r595b1154],
25	contrast	NN	O	contrast	prep_in	12	SENT_51	[p2l617t1132r742b1154],
26	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l762t1131r793b1154],
27	the	DT	O	the	det	28	SENT_51	[p2l813t1127r863b1154],
28	spread	NN	O	spread	prep_to	25	SENT_51	[p2l884t1127r986b1161],
29	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l1008t1127r1039b1154],
30	a	DT	O	a	det	32	SENT_51	[p2l1057t1135r1072b1154],
31	limited	JJ	O	limited	amod	32	SENT_51	[p2l1094t1127r1198b1154],
32	number	NN	O	number	prep_of	28	SENT_51	[p2l282t1168r403b1195],
33	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l415t1168r447b1195],
34	stable	JJ	O	stable	amod	36	SENT_51	[p2l456t1168r547b1195],
35	genome	NN	O	genome	nn	36	SENT_51	[p2l560t1176r688b1203],
36	constellations	NNS	O	constellation	prep_of	32	SENT_51	[p2l700t1168r913b1195],
37	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	38	SENT_51	[p2l925t1168r987b1195],
38	characterizes	VBZ	O	characterize	rcmod	28	SENT_51	[p2l999t1168r1199b1195],
39	the	DT	O	the	det	40	SENT_51	[p2l280t1210r330b1237],
40	evolution	NN	O	evolution	nsubj	46	SENT_51	[p2l345t1210r490b1237],
41	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l506t1210r538b1237],
42	mamma	NN	O	mamma	nn	45	SENT_51	[p2l551t1210r872b1244],
43	|	NN	O	|	nn	45	SENT_51	[p2l551t1210r872b1244],
44	ian	NN	O	ian	nn	45	SENT_51	[p2l551t1210r872b1244],
45	—	NN	O	—	prep_of	40	SENT_51	[p2l551t1210r872b1244],
46	adapted	VBD	O	adapt	ccomp	38	SENT_51	[p2l551t1210r872b1244],
47	influenza	NN	O	influenza	nsubj	49	SENT_51	[p2l890t1210r1028b1237],
48	A	DT	O	a	det	49	SENT_51	[p2l1043t1212r1064b1237],
49	viruses	NNS	O	virus	xcomp	46	SENT_51	[p2l1078t1211r1191b1237],
50	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l1078t1211r1191b1237],

1	Results/Discussion	NN	O	results/discussion	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l245t1345r609b1377],

1	Global	JJ	O	global	amod	3	SENT_53	[p2l243t1421r352b1452],
2	Genome	NNP	O	Genome	nn	3	SENT_53	[p2l370t1423r516b1452],
3	Diversity	NN	O	diversity	nsubj	54	SENT_53	[p2l534t1422r682b1460],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l697t1421r732b1452],
5	AIV	NN	O	aiv	prep_of	3	SENT_53	[p2l746t1423r803b1451],
6	The	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_53	[p2l280t1471r340b1497],
7	complete	JJ	O	complete	amod	8	SENT_53	[p2l353t1471r487b1505],
8	genomes	NNS	O	genome	dep	5	SENT_53	[p2l500t1480r629b1505],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l642t1471r674b1497],
10	167	CD	NUMBER	167	num	11	SENT_53	[p2l686t1471r734b1497],
11	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	prep_of	8	SENT_53	[p2l748t1471r883b1497],
12	A	DT	O	a	det	13	SENT_53	[p2l894t1471r920b1496],
13	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	14	SENT_53	[p2l930t1471r1030b1497],
14	isolated	VBN	O	isolate	rcmod	11	SENT_53	[p2l1043t1471r1155b1497],
15	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l1166t1471r1237b1497],
16	14	CD	NUMBER	14	num	17	SENT_53	[p2l248t1515r278b1540],
17	species	NNS	O	species	prep_from	14	SENT_53	[p2l292t1515r392b1549],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l406t1515r438b1541],
19	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	20	SENT_53	[p2l444t1515r507b1541],
20	Anseriformes	NNS	O	anseriforme	prep_of	17	SENT_53	[p2l519t1515r716b1541],
21	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l730t1515r757b1540],
22	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	23	SENT_53	[p2l770t1516r787b1540],
23	locations	NNS	O	location	prep_in	14	SENT_53	[p2l800t1515r930b1541],
24	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l944t1515r971b1540],
25	the	DT	O	the	det	32	SENT_53	[p2l984t1515r1029b1541],
26	U.S.	NNP	LOCATION	U.S.	nn	32	SENT_53	[p2l1043t1515r1107b1541],
27	(	NN	O	(	nn	32	SENT_53	[p2l1123t1515r1236b1549],
28	Alaska	NNP	LOCATION	Alaska	nn	32	SENT_53	[p2l1123t1515r1236b1549],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l1123t1515r1236b1549],
30	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	appos	32	SENT_53	[p2l243t1560r398b1594],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l243t1560r398b1594],
32	Missouri	NNP	LOCATION	Missouri	prep_in	23	SENT_53	[p2l422t1560r558b1592],
33	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l422t1560r558b1592],
34	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l582t1560r637b1586],
35	Ohio	NNP	LOCATION	Ohio	nn	36	SENT_53	[p2l660t1560r744b1594],
36	)	NN	O	)	nsubjpass	38	SENT_53	[p2l660t1560r744b1594],
37	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	38	SENT_53	[p2l766t1569r836b1586],
38	sequenced	VBN	O	sequence	rcmod	11	SENT_53	[p2l860t1560r1021b1594],
39	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l860t1560r1021b1594],
40	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	41	SENT_53	[p2l1044t1560r1110b1586],
41	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	nsubj	42	SENT_53	[p2l1133t1560r1237b1586],
42	consisted	VBD	O	consist	parataxis	38	SENT_53	[p2l243t1604r377b1630],
43	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l399t1604r431b1630],
44	29	CD	NUMBER	29	num	45	SENT_53	[p2l450t1604r483b1631],
45	HA	NN	O	ha	prep_of	42	SENT_53	[p2l507t1604r561b1629],
46	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l583t1604r638b1630],
47	NA	NN	O	na	nn	48	SENT_53	[p2l659t1604r712b1629],
48	combinations	NNS	O	combination	prep_of	42	SENT_53	[p2l734t1604r942b1636],
49	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l734t1604r942b1636],
50	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l966t1604r1105b1638],
51	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	53	SENT_53	[p2l1130t1604r1157b1629],
52	HA	NN	O	ha	nn	53	SENT_53	[p2l1184t1604r1238b1629],
53	subtypes	NNS	O	subtype	prep_including	5	SENT_53	[p2l243t1648r368b1682],
54	(	VBP	O	(	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l387t1648r518b1682],
55	Hl	NN	O	hl	dobj	54	SENT_53	[p2l387t1648r518b1682],
56	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l387t1648r518b1682],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l387t1648r518b1682],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l387t1648r518b1682],

1	H8	NN	O	h8	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l387t1648r518b1682],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l387t1648r518b1682],
3	H10	NN	O	h10	appos	1	SENT_55	[p2l537t1648r697b1682],
4	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l537t1648r697b1682],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l537t1648r697b1682],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l537t1648r697b1682],

1	H12	NN	O	h12	nn	2	SENT_57	[p2l537t1648r697b1682],
2	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	8	SENT_57	[p2l537t1648r697b1682],
3	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l716t1648r771b1674],
4	all	DT	O	all	det	7	SENT_57	[p2l789t1648r822b1673],
5	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	7	SENT_57	[p2l840t1648r856b1674],
6	neuraminidase	NN	O	neuraminidase	nn	7	SENT_57	[p2l875t1648r1093b1674],
7	subtypes	NNS	O	subtype	nsubj	8	SENT_57	[p2l1112t1648r1237b1682],
8	(	VBP	O	(	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l244t1693r278b1727],
9	N	NN	O	n	dobj	8	SENT_57	[p2l244t1693r278b1727],
10	l	NN	O	l	tmod	8	SENT_57	[p2l284t1693r378b1727],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l284t1693r378b1727],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l284t1693r378b1727],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l284t1693r378b1727],

1	N9	NN	O	n9	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l284t1693r378b1727],
2	)	NN	O	)	dep	1	SENT_59	[p2l284t1693r378b1727],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l284t1693r378b1727],

1	These	DT	O	these	det	2	SENT_60	[p2l397t1693r486b1719],
2	sequences	NNS	O	sequence	nsubjpass	4	SENT_60	[p2l504t1702r650b1727],
3	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	4	SENT_60	[p2l666t1702r736b1719],
4	collected	VBN	O	collect	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l754t1693r884b1719],
5	as	IN	O	as	mark	23	SENT_60	[p2l900t1702r928b1719],
6	part	NN	O	part	nsubj	23	SENT_60	[p2l944t1699r1005b1727],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1022t1693r1054b1719],
8	an	DT	O	a	det	12	SENT_60	[p2l1066t1702r1101b1718],
9	ongoing	JJ	O	ongoing	amod	12	SENT_60	[p2l1118t1693r1238b1727],
10	AIV	NN	O	aiv	nn	12	SENT_60	[p2l242t1737r307b1763],
11	surveillance	NN	O	surveillance	nn	12	SENT_60	[p2l333t1737r506b1763],
12	project	NN	O	project	prep_of	6	SENT_60	[p2l532t1737r636b1771],
13	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l662t1743r689b1763],
14	The	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_60	[p2l714t1737r774b1763],
15	Ohio	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Ohio	nn	17	SENT_60	[p2l801t1737r877b1763],
16	State	NNP	ORGANIZATION	State	nn	17	SENT_60	[p2l904t1737r977b1763],
17	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	prep_at	12	SENT_60	[p2l1003t1737r1157b1771],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1183t1737r1238b1763],
19	collaborators	NNS	O	collaborator	conj_and	12	SENT_60	[p2l243t1781r436b1807],
20	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l470t1781r498b1806],
21	other	JJ	O	other	amod	22	SENT_60	[p2l532t1781r610b1807],
22	states	NNS	O	state	prep_in	19	SENT_60	[p2l644t1787r722b1807],
23	(	VBP	O	(	advcl	4	SENT_60	[p2l758t1781r941b1815],
24	1986	CD	DATE	1986	num	25	SENT_60	[p2l758t1781r941b1815],
25	—	CD	DATE	—	dobj	23	SENT_60	[p2l758t1781r941b1815],
26	2005	CD	DATE	2005	num	27	SENT_60	[p2l758t1781r941b1815],
27	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	32	SENT_60	[p2l758t1781r941b1815],
28	using	VBG	O	use	partmod	27	SENT_60	[p2l975t1781r1053b1815],
29	previously	RB	DATE	previously	advmod	30	SENT_60	[p2l1086t1781r1238b1815],
30	described	VBN	O	describe	ccomp	28	SENT_60	[p2l243t1825r384b1851],
31	protocols	NNS	O	protocol	dobj	30	SENT_60	[p2l401t1825r537b1859],
32	[	VBP	O	[	dep	23	SENT_60	[p2l559t1825r624b1859],
33	39	CD	NUMBER	39	num	34	SENT_60	[p2l559t1825r624b1859],
34	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	32	SENT_60	[p2l559t1825r624b1859],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l559t1825r624b1859],
36	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l643t1825r698b1851],
37	more	JJR	O	more	dep	38	SENT_60	[p2l716t1834r792b1851],
38	than	IN	O	than	advmod	4	SENT_60	[p2l810t1825r876b1851],
39	double	VB	O	double	conj_and	4	SENT_60	[p2l894t1825r994b1851],
40	the	DT	O	the	det	41	SENT_60	[p2l1013t1825r1057b1851],
41	number	NN	O	number	nsubj	49	SENT_60	[p2l1076t1825r1193b1851],
42	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1211t1825r1243b1851],
43	complete	JJ	O	complete	amod	48	SENT_60	[p2l243t1870r377b1904],
44	U.S.-origin	JJ	O	u.s.-origin	amod	48	SENT_60	[p2l395t1870r561b1904],
45	avian	JJ	O	avian	amod	48	SENT_60	[p2l578t1870r657b1895],
46	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	48	SENT_60	[p2l675t1870r811b1896],
47	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	48	SENT_60	[p2l827t1870r898b1896],
48	genomes	NNS	O	genome	prep_of	41	SENT_60	[p2l915t1879r1044b1904],
49	available	JJ	O	available	xcomp	39	SENT_60	[p2l1062t1870r1192b1896],
50	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1210t1870r1237b1895],
51	GenBank	NN	LOCATION	genbank	prep_in	49	SENT_60	[p2l244t1914r391b1940],
52	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l244t1914r391b1940],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l406t1914r437b1939],
2	total	NN	O	total	prep_in	9	SENT_61	[p2l451t1914r524b1946],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l451t1914r524b1946],
4	1340	CD	DATE	1340	num	8	SENT_61	[p2l544t1914r611b1940],
5	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	8	SENT_61	[p2l624t1914r690b1939],
6	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	8	SENT_61	[p2l704t1923r771b1948],
7	segment	NN	O	segment	nn	8	SENT_61	[p2l786t1920r907b1948],
8	sequences	NNS	O	sequence	nsubj	9	SENT_61	[p2l921t1923r1067b1948],
9	(	VBP	O	(	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l1081t1914r1236b1948],
10	2,226,085	CD	NUMBER	2,226,085	num	11	SENT_61	[p2l1081t1914r1236b1948],
11	nucleotides	NNS	O	nucleotide	dobj	9	SENT_61	[p2l243t1958r417b1992],
12	)	CD	NUMBER	)	nsubjpass	14	SENT_61	[p2l243t1958r417b1992],
13	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	14	SENT_61	[p2l437t1967r507b1984],
14	determined	VBN	O	determine	rcmod	11	SENT_61	[p2l528t1958r698b1984],
15	(	RB	O	(	advmod	14	SENT_61	[p2l718t1958r812b1992],
16	Table	NNP	O	Table	nn	18	SENT_61	[p2l718t1958r812b1992],
17	S1	NN	O	s1	nn	18	SENT_61	[p2l834t1958r878b1992],
18	)	NN	O	)	dobj	14	SENT_61	[p2l834t1958r878b1992],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l899t1958r954b1984],
20	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	21	SENT_61	[p2l974t1967r1019b1984],
21	listed	VBN	O	list	conj_and	14	SENT_61	[p2l1039t1958r1116b1984],
22	on	IN	O	on	prep	21	SENT_61	[p2l1136t1967r1172b1984],
23	the	DT	O	the	det	25	SENT_61	[p2l1192t1958r1237b1984],
24	Inﬂuenza	NNP	O	Inﬂuenza	nn	25	SENT_61	[p2l243t2002r383b2028],
25	Virus	NN	O	virus	dep	29	SENT_61	[p2l395t2002r476b2028],
26	Resource	NNP	O	Resource	dep	25	SENT_61	[p2l489t2002r627b2028],
27	website	NN	O	website	dep	29	SENT_61	[p2l640t2002r748b2028],
28	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	27	SENT_61	[p2l763t2002r1235b2036],
29	http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/	NN	O	http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/	dep	33	SENT_61	[p2l763t2002r1235b2036],
30	genomes	NNS	O	genome	dep	29	SENT_61	[p2l243t2047r390b2081],
31	/	:	O	/	punct	33	SENT_61	[p2l243t2047r390b2081],
32	F	NN	O	f	nn	33	SENT_61	[p2l393t2047r413b2072],
33	LU	NN	O	lu	dep	22	SENT_61	[p2l414t2047r481b2073],
34	/	:	O	/	punct	33	SENT_61	[p2l414t2047r481b2073],
35	Database	NN	O	database	dep	33	SENT_61	[p2l485t2047r641b2073],
36	/	:	O	/	punct	35	SENT_61	[p2l485t2047r641b2073],
37	shipment	NN	O	shipment	dep	35	SENT_61	[p2l644t2047r849b2081],
38	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l644t2047r849b2081],

1	cgi	NN	O	cgus	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l644t2047r849b2081],
2	)	NN	O	)	dep	1	SENT_62	[p2l644t2047r849b2081],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l644t2047r849b2081],

1	Cloacal	JJ	O	cloacal	amod	2	SENT_63	[p2l281t2092r393b2118],
2	samples	NNS	O	sample	nsubj	7	SENT_63	[p2l411t2092r526b2126],
3	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l544t2092r615b2118],
4	wild	JJ	O	wild	amod	5	SENT_63	[p2l632t2092r695b2118],
5	birds	NNS	O	bird	prep_from	2	SENT_63	[p2l712t2092r784b2118],
6	frequently	RB	O	frequently	advmod	7	SENT_63	[p2l802t2092r954b2126],
7	show	VBP	O	show	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l971t2092r1046b2118],
8	evidence	NN	O	evidence	dobj	7	SENT_63	[p2l1064t2092r1192b2118],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l1211t2092r1243b2118],
10	mixed	JJ	O	mixed	amod	11	SENT_63	[p2l243t2136r335b2162],
11	infections	NNS	O	infection	prep_of	8	SENT_63	[p2l353t2136r494b2162],
12	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l512t2136r576b2162],
13	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	14	SENT_63	[p2l596t2136r732b2162],
14	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_with	11	SENT_63	[p2l749t2136r849b2162],
15	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l869t2136r901b2162],
16	different	JJ	O	different	amod	17	SENT_63	[p2l915t2136r1039b2162],
17	subtypes	NNS	O	subtype	prep_of	14	SENT_63	[p2l1058t2136r1183b2170],
18	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l1202t2136r1238b2170],
19	serologic	JJ	O	serologic	amod	20	SENT_63	[p2l243t2181r372b2215],
20	analysis	NN	O	analysis	prep_by	7	SENT_63	[p2l398t2181r511b2215],
21	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	22	SENT_63	[p2l540t2181r660b2215],
22	39	CD	NUMBER	39	num	23	SENT_63	[p2l540t2181r660b2215],
23	—	NN	O	—	dep	20	SENT_63	[p2l540t2181r660b2215],
24	41	CD	NUMBER	41	num	25	SENT_63	[p2l540t2181r660b2215],
25	]	NN	O	]	dep	23	SENT_63	[p2l540t2181r660b2215],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l540t2181r660b2215],

1	Therefore	RB	O	therefore	advmod	10	SENT_64	[p2l687t2181r844b2213],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l687t2181r844b2213],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_64	[p2l871t2181r915b2207],
4	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	nsubjpass	10	SENT_64	[p2l941t2181r1045b2207],
5	chosen	VBN	O	choose	partmod	4	SENT_64	[p2l1071t2181r1172b2207],
6	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1196t2181r1238b2207],
7	sequence	NN	O	sequence	nn	8	SENT_64	[p2l243t2234r376b2259],
8	analysis	NN	O	analysis	prep_for	5	SENT_64	[p2l395t2225r508b2259],
9	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	10	SENT_64	[p2l524t2234r595b2251],
10	subjected	VBN	O	subject	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l613t2225r751b2259],
11	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l768t2231r796b2251],
12	sequential	JJ	O	sequential	prep_to	10	SENT_64	[p2l814t2225r962b2259],
13	limiting	VBG	O	limit	xcomp	10	SENT_64	[p2l979t2225r1094b2259],
14	dilutions	NNS	O	dilution	dobj	13	SENT_64	[p2l1111t2225r1237b2251],
15	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	16	SENT_64	[p2l244t2269r329b2303],
16	SLD	NN	ORGANIZATION	sld	dep	14	SENT_64	[p2l244t2269r329b2303],
17	)	CD	NUMBER	)	number	18	SENT_64	[p2l244t2269r329b2303],
18	[	CD	NUMBER	[	dep	16	SENT_64	[p2l348t2269r413b2303],
19	39	CD	NUMBER	39	num	20	SENT_64	[p2l348t2269r413b2303],
20	]	NN	O	]	dep	18	SENT_64	[p2l348t2269r413b2303],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l348t2269r413b2303],
