1	Correction	NN	O	correction	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
3	Stochastic	NNP	O	Stochastic	nn	4	SENT_1	[p1l533t280r762b317],
4	Processes	NNP	O	Processes	nsubj	7	SENT_1	[p1l783t281r1000b317],
5	Are	VBP	O	be	cop	7	SENT_1	[p1l1019t282r1096b317],
6	Key	NN	O	key	nn	7	SENT_1	[p1l1118t282r1199b327],
7	Determinants	NNS	O	determinant	dep	1	SENT_1	[p1l1220t280r1527b317],
8	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1547t279r1593b317],
9	Short-Term	NNP	O	Short-Term	nn	10	SENT_1	[p1l1611t280r1864b317],
10	Evolution	NNP	O	Evolution	prep_of	7	SENT_1	[p1l1888t280r2099b317],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t340r303b376],
12	Influenza	NNP	O	Influenza	nn	14	SENT_1	[p1l326t339r532b377],
13	A	NNP	O	A	nn	14	SENT_1	[p1l553t342r584b376],
14	Virus	NN	O	virus	prep_in	10	SENT_1	[p1l603t340r718b377],

1	Martha	NNP	PERSON	Martha	nn	3	SENT_2	[p1l264t412r371b439],
2	I.	NNP	PERSON	I.	nn	3	SENT_2	[p1l388t414r401b439],
3	Nelson	NNP	PERSON	Nelson	dep	54	SENT_2	[p1l417t412r529b444],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l417t412r529b444],
5	Lone	NNP	O	Lone	nn	6	SENT_2	[p1l545t414r619b439],
6	Simonsen	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Simonsen	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l634t413r792b444],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l634t413r792b444],
8	Cecile	NNP	PERSON	Cecile	nn	9	SENT_2	[p1l807t412r898b439],
9	Viboud	NNP	PERSON	Viboud	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l924t412r1044b444],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l924t412r1044b444],
11	Mark	NNP	PERSON	Mark	nn	13	SENT_2	[p1l1060t412r1135b439],
12	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	13	SENT_2	[p1l1148t414r1177b439],
13	Miller	NNP	PERSON	Miller	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1193t412r1283b444],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1193t412r1283b444],
15	Jill	NNP	PERSON	Jill	nn	16	SENT_2	[p1l1297t412r1334b439],
16	Taylor	NNP	PERSON	Taylor	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1349t412r1451b447],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1349t412r1451b447],
18	Kirsten	NNP	PERSON	Kirsten	nn	20	SENT_2	[p1l1467t413r1569b439],
19	St.	NNP	PERSON	St.	nn	20	SENT_2	[p1l1586t413r1622b439],
20	George	NNP	PERSON	George	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1637t413r1757b447],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1637t413r1757b447],
22	Sara	NNP	PERSON	Sara	nn	24	SENT_2	[p1l1773t413r1835b439],
23	B.	NNP	PERSON	B.	nn	24	SENT_2	[p1l1852t414r1876b439],
24	Griesemer	NNP	PERSON	Griesemer	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1891t413r2055b444],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1891t413r2055b444],
26	Elodie	NNP	PERSON	Elodie	nn	27	SENT_2	[p1l265t458r357b485],
27	Ghedin	NNP	PERSON	Ghedin	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l372t458r490b490],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l372t458r490b490],
29	Naomi	NNP	PERSON	Naomi	nn	31	SENT_2	[p1l507t459r605b485],
30	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	31	SENT_2	[p1l620t460r649b485],
31	Sengamalay	NNP	PERSON	Sengamalay	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l664t458r858b493],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l664t458r858b493],
33	David	NNP	PERSON	David	nn	35	SENT_2	[p1l875t458r960b485],
34	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	35	SENT_2	[p1l975t460r995b485],
35	Spiro	NNP	PERSON	Spiro	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1011t459r1096b492],
36	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1011t459r1096b492],
37	Igor	NNP	PERSON	Igor	nn	38	SENT_2	[p1l1113t460r1173b493],
38	Volkov	NNP	PERSON	Volkov	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1186t458r1298b490],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1186t458r1298b490],
40	Brian	NNP	PERSON	Brian	nn	42	SENT_2	[p1l1327t459r1401b485],
41	T.	NNP	PERSON	T.	nn	42	SENT_2	[p1l1416t460r1441b485],
42	Grenfell	NNP	PERSON	Grenfell	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1456t458r1583b490],
43	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1456t458r1583b490],
44	David	NNP	PERSON	David	nn	46	SENT_2	[p1l1600t458r1685b485],
45	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	46	SENT_2	[p1l1700t460r1721b485],
46	Lipman	NNP	PERSON	Lipman	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1737t459r1858b492],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1737t459r1858b492],
48	Jeffrey	NNP	PERSON	Jeffrey	nn	50	SENT_2	[p1l262t504r364b539],
49	K.	NNP	PERSON	K.	nn	50	SENT_2	[p1l380t506r404b531],
50	Taubenberger	NNP	PERSON	Taubenberger	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l418t504r646b539],
51	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l418t504r646b539],
52	Edward	NNP	PERSON	Edward	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l662t504r775b531],
53	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	dep	54	SENT_2	[p1l791t505r818b531],
54	Holmes	NNP	PERSON	Holmes	dep	57	SENT_2	[p1l835t504r949b531],
55	doi	FW	O	doi	dep	54	SENT_2	[p1l264t574r319b601],
56	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l264t574r319b601],
57	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l337t574r797b609],
58	/	:	O	/	punct	57	SENT_2	[p1l337t574r797b609],
59	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	60	SENT_2	[p1l337t574r797b609],
60	|	NN	O	|	dep	57	SENT_2	[p1l337t574r797b609],
61	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l337t574r797b609],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l337t574r797b609],
2	.0020	CD	NUMBER	.0020	num	3	SENT_3	[p1l337t574r797b609],
3	l25	NN	O	l25	dep	1	SENT_3	[p1l337t574r797b609],

1	In	IN	O	in	dep	9	SENT_4	[p1l265t647r289b672],
2	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	3	SENT_4	[p1l305t646r376b672],
3	Pathogens	NNS	O	pathogen	pobj	1	SENT_4	[p1l390t645r554b680],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l390t645r554b680],
5	volume	NN	O	volume	appos	3	SENT_4	[p1l569t645r685b672],
6	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	5	SENT_4	[p1l700t647r724b677],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l700t647r724b677],
8	issue	NN	O	issue	appos	5	SENT_4	[p1l740t646r814b672],
9	12	CD	NUMBER	12	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l832t647r872b672],
10	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l832t647r872b672],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_5	[p1l262t715r319b742],
2	spelling	NN	O	spelling	nsubj	9	SENT_5	[p1l334t715r452b750],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l469t715r500b742],
4	author	NN	O	author	nn	7	SENT_5	[p1l512t715r615b742],
5	name	NN	O	name	nn	7	SENT_5	[p1l630t723r715b742],
6	Elodie	NNP	PERSON	Elodie	nn	7	SENT_5	[p1l731t715r823b742],
7	Ghedi	NNP	PERSON	Ghedi	prep_of	2	SENT_5	[p1l838t715r928b742],
8	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	9	SENT_5	[p1l944t716r964b742],
9	incorrect	JJ	O	incorrect	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l980t716r1123b747],
10	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l980t716r1123b747],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_5	[p1l1137t715r1187b742],
12	correct	JJ	O	correct	amod	13	SENT_5	[p1l1202t720r1309b742],
13	name	NN	O	name	nsubj	16	SENT_5	[p1l1325t723r1410b742],
14	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	16	SENT_5	[p1l1426t716r1446b742],
15	Elodie	NNP	PERSON	Elodie	nn	16	SENT_5	[p1l1462t715r1554b742],
16	Ghedin	NNP	PERSON	Ghedin	parataxis	9	SENT_5	[p1l1569t715r1687b742],
17	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1569t715r1687b742],

1	This	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_6	[p1l338t781r395b802],
2	correction	NN	O	correction	nn	3	SENT_6	[p1l408t782r551b803],
3	note	NN	O	note	nsubjpass	6	SENT_6	[p1l565t786r623b803],
4	may	MD	O	may	aux	6	SENT_6	[p1l637t789r691b810],
5	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_6	[p1l703t781r734b802],
6	found	VBN	O	find	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l746t781r827b802],
7	online	NN	O	online	dep	6	SENT_6	[p1l839t781r925b802],
8	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l938t786r962b803],
9	doi	FW	O	doi	prep_at	6	SENT_6	[p1l975t779r1433b810],
10	:10.1371	FW	O	:10.1371	nn	11	SENT_6	[p1l975t779r1433b810],
11	ﬁourn	FW	O	ﬁourn	dep	9	SENT_6	[p1l975t779r1433b810],
12	:1	CD	NUMBER	:1	num	14	SENT_6	[p1l975t779r1433b810],
13	l.	NN	O	l.	nn	14	SENT_6	[p1l975t779r1433b810],
14	ppat	NN	O	ppat	dep	11	SENT_6	[p1l975t779r1433b810],
15	.0020138	CD	NUMBER	.0020138	dep	11	SENT_6	[p1l975t779r1433b810],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l975t779r1433b810],

1	Published	VBN	O	publish	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l338t817r471b838],
2	December	NNP	DATE	December	tmod	1	SENT_7	[p1l483t817r623b838],
3	29	CD	DATE	29	num	2	SENT_7	[p1l635t817r671b843],
4	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l635t817r671b843],
5	2006	CD	DATE	2006	num	2	SENT_7	[p1l685t817r753b840],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l685t817r753b840],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l338t852r456b874],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l338t852r456b874],
3	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	1	SENT_8	[p1l470t852r550b879],
4	2006	CD	DATE	2006	num	6	SENT_8	[p1l470t852r550b879],
5	)	NN	O	)	nn	6	SENT_8	[p1l470t852r550b879],
6	Correction	NN	O	correction	dep	3	SENT_8	[p1l563t852r719b874],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l563t852r719b874],
8	Stochastic	NNP	O	Stochastic	nn	9	SENT_8	[p1l732t852r868b874],
9	processes	NNS	O	process	nsubj	12	SENT_8	[p1l882t859r1008b881],
10	are	VBP	O	be	cop	12	SENT_8	[p1l1021t859r1062b873],
11	key	JJ	O	key	amod	12	SENT_8	[p1l1074t852r1119b881],
12	determinants	NNS	O	determinant	dep	1	SENT_8	[p1l1131t852r1312b874],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1324t852r1353b873],
14	short-term	JJ	O	short-term	amod	15	SENT_8	[p1l1363t852r1509b874],
15	evolution	NN	O	evolution	prep_of	12	SENT_8	[p1l1521t852r1649b874],
16	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1662t853r1687b873],
17	inﬂuenza	NN	O	inﬂuenza	nn	19	SENT_8	[p1l1700t852r1824b873],
18	A	NN	O	a	nn	19	SENT_8	[p1l1835t853r1856b873],
19	Virus	NN	O	virus	prep_in	15	SENT_8	[p1l1867t853r1938b873],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1867t853r1938b873],

1	PLOS	NNP	O	PLOS	dep	6	SENT_9	[p1l1951t852r2021b874],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	dep	1	SENT_9	[p1l2033t852r2128b881],
3	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	4	SENT_9	[p1l2140t852r2210b879],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	6	SENT_9	[p1l2140t852r2210b879],
5	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	6	SENT_9	[p1l2140t852r2210b879],
6	‘	NN	O	‘	dep	10	SENT_9	[p1l2140t852r2210b879],
7	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	8	SENT_9	[p1l2140t852r2210b879],
8	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	6	SENT_9	[p1l2140t852r2210b879],
9	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l2140t852r2210b879],
10	e138	CD	NUMBER	e138	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l338t887r406b908],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l338t887r406b908],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l420t885r872b916],
2	:10.1371	CD	NUMBER	:10.1371	number	3	SENT_10	[p1l420t885r872b916],
3	[	CD	NUMBER	[	dep	1	SENT_10	[p1l420t885r872b916],
4	journal/ppat	NN	O	journal/ppat	dep	3	SENT_10	[p1l420t885r872b916],
5	.0020138	CD	NUMBER	.0020138	num	4	SENT_10	[p1l420t885r872b916],

1	Pr	NN	O	pr	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
2	;	:	PERCENT	;	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
3	%	NN	PERCENT	%	nn	5	SENT_11	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
4	h	NN	O	h	nn	5	SENT_11	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
5	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	6	SENT_11	[p1l288t3093r352b3116],
6	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	dep	1	SENT_11	[p1l367t3092r511b3123],
7	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	8	SENT_11	[p1l526t3091r528b3124],
8	www	NN	O	www	dobj	6	SENT_11	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_12	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_12	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	dep	11	SENT_12	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
4	1194	CD	DATE	1194	num	7	SENT_12	[p1l1207t3094r1271b3116],
5	December	NNP	DATE	December	nn	7	SENT_12	[p1l1661t3092r1803b3116],
6	2006	CD	DATE	2006	num	7	SENT_12	[p1l1815t3094r1881b3116],
7	|	NNP	O	|	dep	3	SENT_12	[p1l1895t3091r1897b3124],
8	Volume	NN	O	volume	dep	11	SENT_12	[p1l1911t3092r2017b3116],
9	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	8	SENT_12	[p1l2031t3094r2045b3116],
10	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	11	SENT_12	[p1l2060t3091r2062b3124],
11	Issue	NN	O	issue	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l2079t3093r2144b3116],
12	12	CD	NUMBER	12	num	14	SENT_12	[p1l2160t3094r2189b3116],
13	|	NN	O	|	nn	14	SENT_12	[p1l2204t3091r2206b3124],
14	e138	NN	O	e138	dep	11	SENT_12	[p1l2221t3094r2286b3116],

