1	Correction	NN	O	correction	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
3	Structure	NN	O	structure	dep	1	SENT_1	[p1l533t281r742b317],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l761t279r807b317],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_1	[p1l824t280r897b317],
6	Malaria	NNP	O	Malaria	nn	8	SENT_1	[p1l918t280r1083b317],
7	Antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	8	SENT_1	[p1l1104t280r1282b327],
8	AMA1	NN	O	ama1	prep_of	3	SENT_1	[p1l1303t282r1431b316],
9	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1459t280r1497b316],
10	Complex	NN	O	complex	prep_in	8	SENT_1	[p1l1519t280r1717b326],
11	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1735t280r1832b317],
12	a	DT	O	a	det	14	SENT_1	[p1l1854t290r1877b317],
13	GrowthInhibitory	NNP	O	GrowthInhibitory	nn	14	SENT_1	[p1l1898t280r2081b317, p1l265t340r486b387],
14	Antibody	NN	O	antibody	prep_with	10	SENT_1	[p1l505t340r715b387],
15	Andrew	NNP	PERSON	Andrew	nn	17	SENT_1	[p1l263t412r384b439],
16	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	17	SENT_1	[p1l400t414r434b439],
17	Coley	NNP	PERSON	Coley	dep	42	SENT_1	[p1l449t412r541b447],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l449t412r541b447],
19	Aditi	NNP	PERSON	Aditi	nn	20	SENT_1	[p1l556t412r627b439],
20	Gupta	NNP	PERSON	Gupta	appos	17	SENT_1	[p1l642t413r744b446],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l642t413r744b446],
22	Vince	NNP	PERSON	Vince	nn	24	SENT_1	[p1l758t413r842b439],
23	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	24	SENT_1	[p1l856t414r876b439],
24	Murphy	NNP	PERSON	Murphy	appos	17	SENT_1	[p1l892t412r1019b447],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l892t412r1019b447],
26	Tao	NNP	PERSON	Tao	nn	27	SENT_1	[p1l1032t414r1088b439],
27	Bai	NNP	PERSON	Bai	appos	17	SENT_1	[p1l1105t413r1155b444],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1105t413r1155b444],
29	Hanna	NNP	PERSON	Hanna	nn	30	SENT_1	[p1l1172t414r1269b439],
30	Kim	NNP	PERSON	Kim	appos	17	SENT_1	[p1l1286t413r1349b444],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1286t413r1349b444],
32	Michael	NNP	PERSON	Michael	nn	33	SENT_1	[p1l1365t412r1482b439],
33	Foley	NNP	PERSON	Foley	appos	17	SENT_1	[p1l1499t412r1587b447],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1499t412r1587b447],
35	Robin	NNP	PERSON	Robin	nn	37	SENT_1	[p1l1603t412r1689b439],
36	F.	NNP	PERSON	F.	nn	37	SENT_1	[p1l1707t414r1729b439],
37	Anders	NNP	PERSON	Anders	appos	17	SENT_1	[p1l1744t412r1859b444],
38	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1744t412r1859b444],
39	Adrian	NNP	PERSON	Adrian	nn	40	SENT_1	[p1l1874t412r1974b439],
40	H.	NNP	PERSON	H.	appos	17	SENT_1	[p1l1991t414r2020b439],
41	Batchelor	NNP	PERSON	Batchelor	nn	42	SENT_1	[p1l2036t412r2181b439],
42	Correction	NNP	O	Correction	dep	1	SENT_1	[p1l263t484r424b510],
43	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l439t483r489b510],
44	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l439t483r489b510],
45	Coley	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Coley	nn	46	SENT_1	[p1l263t529r349b564],
46	AM	NNP	ORGANIZATION	AM	prep_for	42	SENT_1	[p1l363t531r421b561],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l363t531r421b561],
48	Gupta	NNP	PERSON	Gupta	nn	49	SENT_1	[p1l436t530r529b563],
49	A	NNP	O	A	appos	46	SENT_1	[p1l545t531r573b561],
50	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l545t531r573b561],
51	Murphy	NNP	PERSON	Murphy	nn	52	SENT_1	[p1l589t529r709b564],
52	VJ	NNP	O	VJ	appos	46	SENT_1	[p1l722t531r763b561],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l722t531r763b561],
54	Bai	NNP	PERSON	Bai	nn	55	SENT_1	[p1l779t530r822b556],
55	T	NN	O	t	appos	46	SENT_1	[p1l836t531r861b561],
56	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l836t531r861b561],
57	Kim	NNP	PERSON	Kim	nn	58	SENT_1	[p1l878t530r932b556],
58	H	NNP	PERSON	H	appos	46	SENT_1	[p1l950t531r978b561],
59	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l950t531r978b561],
60	et	FW	O	et	dep	46	SENT_1	[p1l993t534r1022b556],
61	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	62	SENT_1	[p1l1037t529r1069b556],
62	(	FW	O	(	dep	46	SENT_1	[p1l1085t530r1177b561],
63	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	65	SENT_1	[p1l1085t530r1177b561],
64	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	65	SENT_1	[p1l1085t530r1177b561],
65	Structure	NN	O	structure	dep	62	SENT_1	[p1l1194t530r1335b556],
66	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1350t529r1381b556],
67	the	DT	O	the	det	70	SENT_1	[p1l1393t529r1443b556],
68	malaria	NN	O	malaria	nn	70	SENT_1	[p1l1459t529r1569b556],
69	antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	70	SENT_1	[p1l1584t530r1700b564],
70	AMA1	NN	O	ama1	prep_of	46	SENT_1	[p1l1716t531r1803b556],
71	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1825t530r1849b556],
72	complex	NN	O	complex	prep_in	70	SENT_1	[p1l1866t529r1998b563],
73	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l2012t529r2078b556],
74	a	DT	O	a	det	78	SENT_1	[p1l2094t537r2109b556],
75	growth	NN	O	growth	npadvmod	77	SENT_1	[p1l264t574r538b609],
76	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	75	SENT_1	[p1l264t574r538b609],
77	inhibitory	JJ	O	inhibitory	amod	78	SENT_1	[p1l264t574r538b609],
78	antibody	NN	O	antibody	prep_with	72	SENT_1	[p1l552t574r698b609],
79	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l552t574r698b609],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_2	[p1l714t575r786b601],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l803t574r910b609],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	4	SENT_2	[p1l927t575r991b606],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_2	[p1l927t575r991b606],
5	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	6	SENT_2	[p1l927t575r991b606],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_2	[p1l927t575r991b606],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l927t575r991b606],
8	e138	NN	O	e138	dep	2	SENT_2	[p1l1006t576r1087b601],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1006t576r1087b601],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1102t574r1157b601],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1102t574r1157b601],
3	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	dep	1	SENT_3	[p1l1175t574r1644b609],
4	/	:	O	/	punct	6	SENT_3	[p1l1175t574r1644b609],
5	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	6	SENT_3	[p1l1175t574r1644b609],
6	|	NN	O	|	dep	3	SENT_3	[p1l1175t574r1644b609],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1175t574r1644b609],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1175t574r1644b609],
2	.0030138	CD	NUMBER	.0030138	dep	1	SENT_4	[p1l1175t574r1644b609],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1175t574r1644b609],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l265t647r289b672],
2	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	3	SENT_5	[p1l305t646r376b672],
3	Pathogens	NNS	O	pathogen	prep_in	22	SENT_5	[p1l390t645r554b680],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l390t645r554b680],
5	volume	NN	O	volume	nsubjpass	22	SENT_5	[p1l569t645r685b672],
6	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	5	SENT_5	[p1l700t647r724b677],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l700t647r724b677],
8	issue	NN	O	issue	dep	22	SENT_5	[p1l740t646r814b672],
9	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	8	SENT_5	[p1l829t647r853b672],
10	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l829t647r853b672],
11	In	IN	O	in	dep	8	SENT_5	[p1l265t717r289b742],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_5	[p1l305t715r355b742],
13	original	JJ	O	original	amod	14	SENT_5	[p1l370t715r484b750],
14	version	NN	O	version	pobj	11	SENT_5	[p1l500t716r610b742],
15	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l626t715r658b742],
16	this	DT	O	this	det	17	SENT_5	[p1l669t715r723b742],
17	paper	NN	O	paper	prep_of	14	SENT_5	[p1l740t723r828b749],
18	the	DT	O	the	det	20	SENT_5	[p1l842t715r892b742],
19	author	NN	O	author	nn	20	SENT_5	[p1l906t715r1009b742],
20	order	NN	O	order	nsubjpass	22	SENT_5	[p1l1023t715r1106b742],
21	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	22	SENT_5	[p1l1120t723r1178b742],
22	listed	VBN	O	list	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1194t715r1273b742],
23	incorrectly	RB	O	incorrectly	advmod	22	SENT_5	[p1l1290t715r1459b750],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1290t715r1459b750],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_6	[p1l1473t715r1530b742],
2	proper	JJ	O	proper	amod	3	SENT_6	[p1l1546t723r1649b749],
3	order	NN	O	order	nsubj	5	SENT_6	[p1l1663t715r1746b742],
4	should	MD	O	should	aux	5	SENT_6	[p1l1761t715r1863b742],
5	read	VB	O	read	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1880t715r1945b742],
6	as	IN	O	as	prep	5	SENT_6	[p1l1961t723r1991b742],
7	above	RB	O	above	dep	6	SENT_6	[p1l2006t715r2108b742],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2006t715r2108b742],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l339t788r480b814],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l339t788r480b814],
3	Coley	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Coley	nn	4	SENT_7	[p1l494t788r584b823],
4	AM	NNP	ORGANIZATION	AM	dep	1	SENT_7	[p1l596t788r661b819],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l596t788r661b819],
6	Gupta	NNP	PERSON	Gupta	nn	7	SENT_7	[p1l675t788r775b823],
7	A	NNP	O	A	appos	4	SENT_7	[p1l787t788r820b819],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l787t788r820b819],
9	Murphy	NNP	PERSON	Murphy	nn	11	SENT_7	[p1l833t788r962b823],
10	V	NNP	O	V	nn	11	SENT_7	[p1l973t789r1019b823],
11	]	NN	O	]	appos	4	SENT_7	[p1l973t789r1019b823],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l973t789r1019b823],
13	Bai	NNP	PERSON	Bai	nn	14	SENT_7	[p1l1032t789r1084b814],
14	T	NN	O	t	appos	4	SENT_7	[p1l1096t789r1127b819],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1096t789r1127b819],
16	Kim	NNP	PERSON	Kim	nn	17	SENT_7	[p1l1140t789r1208b813],
17	H	NNP	PERSON	H	appos	4	SENT_7	[p1l1220t789r1256b819],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1220t789r1256b819],
19	et	FW	O	et	dep	4	SENT_7	[p1l1270t793r1299b814],
20	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	21	SENT_7	[p1l1312t788r1346b814],
21	(	FW	O	(	dep	4	SENT_7	[p1l1361t786r1457b820],
22	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	24	SENT_7	[p1l1361t786r1457b820],
23	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	24	SENT_7	[p1l1361t786r1457b820],
24	Correction	NN	O	correction	dep	21	SENT_7	[p1l1471t788r1657b814],
25	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1471t788r1657b814],
26	Structure	NN	O	structure	dep	1	SENT_7	[p1l1672t788r1826b814],
27	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1839t788r1874b814],
28	the	DT	O	the	det	31	SENT_7	[p1l1884t788r1933b814],
29	Malaria	NNP	O	Malaria	nn	31	SENT_7	[p1l1947t788r2069b814],
30	Antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	31	SENT_7	[p1l2081t788r2211b823],
31	AMA1	NN	O	ama1	prep_of	26	SENT_7	[p1l337t834r437b859],
32	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l464t835r494b859],
33	Complex	NN	O	complex	prep_in	31	SENT_7	[p1l518t834r664b869],
34	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l686t834r756b860],
35	a	DT	O	a	det	37	SENT_7	[p1l779t843r795b860],
36	Growth-Inhibitory	JJ	O	growth-inhibitory	amod	37	SENT_7	[p1l818t834r1121b869],
37	Antibody	NN	O	antibody	prep_with	33	SENT_7	[p1l1143t834r1303b869],
38	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1143t834r1303b869],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_8	[p1l1327t834r1410b860],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1434t834r1547b869],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	5	SENT_8	[p1l1570t834r1655b866],
4	(	NN	O	(	nn	5	SENT_8	[p1l1570t834r1655b866],
5	1l	NN	O	1l	dep	2	SENT_8	[p1l1570t834r1655b866],
6	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	2	SENT_8	[p1l1570t834r1655b866],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1570t834r1655b866],
8	e172	NN	O	e172	dep	2	SENT_8	[p1l1679t832r1761b861],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1679t832r1761b861],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1785t834r1844b860],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1785t834r1844b860],
3	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	dep	1	SENT_9	[p1l1870t832r2210b869],
4	/	:	O	/	punct	5	SENT_9	[p1l1870t832r2210b869],
5	journalppat	NN	O	journalppat	dep	3	SENT_9	[p1l1870t832r2210b869],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1870t832r2210b869],

1	0030172	CD	NUMBER	0030172	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l339t877r479b906],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l339t877r479b906],

1	Received	VBN	O	receive	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l338t958r491b984],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l338t958r491b984],
3	October	NNP	DATE	October	dep	1	SENT_11	[p1l507t958r643b984],
4	1	CD	DATE	1	num	3	SENT_11	[p1l660t959r682b989],
5	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l660t959r682b989],
6	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	3	SENT_11	[p1l698t956r781b988],
7	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l698t956r781b988],
8	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	dep	3	SENT_11	[p1l795t958r956b993],
9	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l795t958r956b993],
10	October	NNP	DATE	October	dep	8	SENT_11	[p1l972t958r1108b984],
11	1	CD	DATE	1	num	10	SENT_11	[p1l1124t959r1146b989],
12	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1124t959r1146b989],
13	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	10	SENT_11	[p1l1163t956r1246b988],
14	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1163t956r1246b988],
15	Published	VBN	O	publish	partmod	3	SENT_11	[p1l1261t958r1427b984],
16	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1261t958r1427b984],
17	November	NNP	DATE	November	dep	3	SENT_11	[p1l1443t958r1614b984],
18	30	CD	DATE	30	num	17	SENT_11	[p1l1629t958r1672b989],
19	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1629t958r1672b989],
20	2007	CD	DATE	2007	appos	17	SENT_11	[p1l1689t956r1771b985],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1689t956r1771b985],

1	Copyright	NN	O	copyright	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l339t1037r510b1072],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l339t1037r510b1072],
3	©	CD	NUMBER	©	num	4	SENT_12	[p1l524t1037r550b1063],
4	2007	CD	DATE	2007	dep	1	SENT_12	[p1l563t1035r637b1064],
5	Coley	NNP	PERSON	Coley	dep	4	SENT_12	[p1l650t1037r741b1072],
6	et	FW	O	et	nn	7	SENT_12	[p1l753t1043r782b1063],
7	al.	FW	O	al.	dep	4	SENT_12	[p1l794t1037r827b1063],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l794t1037r827b1063],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	2	SENT_14	[p1l288t3093r352b3116],
2	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l367t3092r511b3123],
3	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	4	SENT_14	[p1l526t3091r528b3124],
4	www	NN	O	www	dobj	2	SENT_14	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
5	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_15	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_15	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
4	1827	CD	DATE	1827	num	7	SENT_15	[p1l1207t3094r1270b3116],
5	November	NNP	DATE	November	nn	7	SENT_15	[p1l1659t3092r1803b3116],
6	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	7	SENT_15	[p1l1815t3094r1880b3116],
7	|	NNP	O	|	dep	3	SENT_15	[p1l1895t3091r1897b3124],
8	Volume	NN	O	volume	nn	11	SENT_15	[p1l1911t3092r2017b3116],
9	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	11	SENT_15	[p1l2031t3094r2044b3116],
10	|	NN	O	|	nn	11	SENT_15	[p1l2060t3091r2062b3124],
11	Issue	NN	O	issue	dep	7	SENT_15	[p1l2079t3093r2144b3116],
12	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	14	SENT_15	[p1l2160t3094r2184b3116],
13	|	NN	O	|	nn	14	SENT_15	[p1l2204t3091r2206b3124],
14	e172	NN	O	e172	dep	3	SENT_15	[p1l2221t3094r2286b3116],

