1	OPEN	NN	MISC	open	nn	3	SENT_1	[p1l242t131r323b155],
2	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	3	SENT_1	[p1l333t112r365b162],
3	ACCESS	NNP	O	ACCESS	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l372t131r484b155],
4	Freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	5	SENT_1	[p1l501t130r590b162],
5	available	JJ	O	available	amod	3	SENT_1	[p1l597t130r731b155],
6	online	NN	O	online	prep	3	SENT_1	[p1l739t130r832b155],
7	0	CD	NUMBER	0	num	9	SENT_1	[p1l2003t110r2118b154],
8	9R	NN	O	9r	nn	9	SENT_1	[p1l2003t110r2118b154],
9	PATHOGENS	NNS	O	pathogen	dep	6	SENT_1	[p1l2129t130r2308b154],

1	Positive	JJ	O	positive	amod	3	SENT_2	[p1l248t240r525b300],
2	Selection	NN	O	selection	nn	3	SENT_2	[p1l559t240r884b300],
3	Results	NNS	O	result	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l923t240r1173b300],
4	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1208t240r1268b299],
5	Frequent	JJ	O	frequent	amod	9	SENT_2	[p1l1307t243r1630b316],
6	Reversible	JJ	O	reversible	amod	9	SENT_2	[p1l1666t240r2032b300],
7	Amino	NN	O	amino	nn	9	SENT_2	[p1l2065t240r2299b300],
8	Acid	NN	O	acid	nn	9	SENT_2	[p1l244t331r397b391],
9	Replacements	NNS	O	replacement	prep_in	3	SENT_2	[p1l435t331r935b407],
10	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l970t331r1030b390],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_2	[p1l1064t331r1180b391],
12	G	NN	O	g	nn	14	SENT_2	[p1l1214t333r1262b391],
13	Protein	NN	O	protein	nn	14	SENT_2	[p1l1300t331r1554b391],
14	Gene	NN	O	gene	prep_in	3	SENT_2	[p1l1589t333r1773b391],
15	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1806t330r1879b391],
16	Human	JJ	O	human	amod	19	SENT_2	[p1l1911t334r2163b391],
17	Respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	19	SENT_2	[p1l248t422r655b499],
18	Syncytial	JJ	O	syncytial	amod	19	SENT_2	[p1l687t422r1005b499],
19	Virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	14	SENT_2	[p1l1039t422r1218b482],

1	Viviane	NNP	PERSON	Viviane	nn	4	SENT_3	[p1l243t551r391b582],
2	F.	NNP	PERSON	F.	nn	4	SENT_3	[p1l405t553r436b582],
3	Botosso	NNP	PERSON	Botosso	nn	4	SENT_3	[p1l450t544r635b586],
4	‘	NN	O	‘	dep	71	SENT_3	[p1l450t544r635b586],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l450t544r635b586],
6	Paolo	NNP	PERSON	Paolo	nn	11	SENT_3	[p1l650t551r759b582],
7	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	11	SENT_3	[p1l773t553r819b582],
8	de	NNP	PERSON	de	nn	11	SENT_3	[p1l832t551r880b582],
9	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	11	SENT_3	[p1l892t553r931b582],
10	Zanotto2	NNP	O	Zanotto2	nn	11	SENT_3	[p1l944t544r1148b586],
11	*	NNP	O	*	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l944t544r1148b586],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l944t544r1148b586],
13	Mirthes	NNP	O	Mirthes	nn	14	SENT_3	[p1l1162t551r1310b582],
14	Ueda3	NNP	O	Ueda3	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l1325t544r1454b586],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1325t544r1454b586],
16	Eurico	NNP	PERSON	Eurico	nn	18	SENT_3	[p1l1469t551r1591b582],
17	Arruda	NNP	PERSON	Arruda	nn	18	SENT_3	[p1l1603t544r1770b586],
18	‘	NNP	O	‘	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l1603t544r1770b586],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1603t544r1770b586],
20	Alfredo	NNP	PERSON	Alfredo	nn	22	SENT_3	[p1l1783t551r1931b582],
21	E.	NNP	PERSON	E.	nn	22	SENT_3	[p1l1946t553r1977b582],
22	Gilios	NNP	PERSON	Gilios	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l1990t544r2110b586],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1990t544r2110b586],
24	Sandra	NNP	PERSON	Sandra	nn	26	SENT_3	[p1l2124t551r2261b582],
25	E.	NNP	PERSON	E.	nn	26	SENT_3	[p1l2276t553r2308b582],
26	Vieiras	NNP	PERSON	Vieiras	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l243t603r387b644],
27	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l243t603r387b644],
28	Klaus	NNP	PERSON	Klaus	nn	30	SENT_3	[p1l401t609r506b640],
29	E.	NNP	PERSON	E.	nn	30	SENT_3	[p1l520t611r552b640],
30	Stewienz	NNP	PERSON	Stewienz	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l565t603r750b644],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l565t603r750b644],
32	Teresa	NNP	PERSON	Teresa	nn	35	SENT_3	[p1l763t611r892b640],
33	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	nn	35	SENT_3	[p1l906t610r942b640],
34	T.	NNP	PERSON	T.	nn	35	SENT_3	[p1l954t611r989b640],
35	Peret6	NNP	PERSON	Peret6	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l1003t603r1134b644],
36	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1003t603r1134b644],
37	Leda	NNP	PERSON	Leda	nn	40	SENT_3	[p1l1148t609r1240b640],
38	F.	NNP	PERSON	F.	nn	40	SENT_3	[p1l1255t611r1286b640],
39	Jamal	NNP	PERSON	Jamal	nn	40	SENT_3	[p1l1298t603r1441b644],
40	’	NNP	O	’	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l1298t603r1441b644],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1298t603r1441b644],
42	Maria	NNP	PERSON	Maria	nn	47	SENT_3	[p1l1455t609r1565b640],
43	I.	NNP	PERSON	I.	nn	47	SENT_3	[p1l1580t611r1600b640],
44	de	NNP	PERSON	de	nn	47	SENT_3	[p1l1612t609r1660b640],
45	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	47	SENT_3	[p1l1674t611r1720b640],
46	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	nn	47	SENT_3	[p1l1732t610r1769b640],
47	Pardinis	NNP	PERSON	Pardinis	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l1783t603r1952b644],
48	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1783t603r1952b644],
49	Joao	NNP	PERSON	Joao	nn	52	SENT_3	[p1l1964t609r2056b640],
50	R.	NNP	PERSON	R.	nn	52	SENT_3	[p1l2070t611r2104b640],
51	R.	NNP	PERSON	R.	nn	52	SENT_3	[p1l2118t611r2152b640],
52	Pinho9	NNP	PERSON	Pinho9	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l2166t603r2307b644],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2166t603r2307b644],
54	Eduardo	NNP	PERSON	Eduardo	nn	55	SENT_3	[p1l245t667r411b698],
55	Massad	NNP	PERSON	Massad	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l429t661r623b702],
56	‘	CD	NUMBER	‘	number	57	SENT_3	[p1l429t661r623b702],
57	°	CD	NUMBER	°	num	55	SENT_3	[p1l429t661r623b702],
58	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l429t661r623b702],
59	Osvaldo	NNP	PERSON	Osvaldo	nn	63	SENT_3	[p1l640t667r802b698],
60	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	63	SENT_3	[p1l818t669r857b698],
61	Sant	NNP	PERSON	Sant	nn	63	SENT_3	[p1l874t661r1107b702],
62	’	NNP	O	’	nn	63	SENT_3	[p1l874t661r1107b702],
63	Anna	NNP	PERSON	Anna	appos	55	SENT_3	[p1l874t661r1107b702],
64	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l874t661r1107b702],
65	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l874t661r1107b702],
66	Eddie	NNP	PERSON	Eddie	nn	68	SENT_3	[p1l1126t667r1236b698],
67	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	nn	68	SENT_3	[p1l1252t668r1288b698],
68	Holmes	NNP	PERSON	Holmes	appos	4	SENT_3	[p1l1306t661r1546b702],
69	“	CD	NUMBER	“	dep	71	SENT_3	[p1l1306t661r1546b702],
70	"	``	O	"	punct	71	SENT_3	[p1l1306t661r1546b702],
71	2	CD	NUMBER	2	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1306t661r1546b702],
72	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1306t661r1546b702],
73	Edison	NNP	PERSON	Edison	nn	76	SENT_3	[p1l1564t667r1693b698],
74	L.	NNP	PERSON	L.	nn	76	SENT_3	[p1l1712t669r1743b698],
75	Durigon	NNP	PERSON	Durigon	nn	76	SENT_3	[p1l1760t661r1969b706],
76	”	NN	O	”	conj_and	71	SENT_3	[p1l1760t661r1969b706],
77	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1760t661r1969b706],
78	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1986t667r2058b698],
79	the	DT	O	the	det	81	SENT_3	[p1l2075t667r2139b698],
80	VGDN	NNP	O	VGDN	nn	81	SENT_3	[p1l2154t669r2274b697],
81	Consortium	NNP	O	Consortium	conj_and	71	SENT_3	[p1l243t725r474b756],

1	1Butantan	NNP	O	1Butantan	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l245t793r373b813],
2	Institute	NNP	O	Institute	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l391t793r494b817],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l391t793r494b817],
4	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l509t792r610b819],
5	Branch	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Branch	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l625t792r712b817],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l625t792r712b817],
7	Butanta	NNP	PERSON	Butanta	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l729t793r827b817],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l729t793r827b817],
9	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l843t793r884b813],
10	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l901t792r972b817],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l901t792r972b817],
12	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l989t792r1056b817],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l989t792r1056b817],
14	2Laboratory	NN	O	2laboratory	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1072t792r1225b819],
15	of	IN	O	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1239t792r1264b813],
16	Molecular	JJ	O	molecular	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1278t792r1396b813],
17	Evolution	NN	O	evolution	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1411t792r1523b813],
18	and	CC	O	and	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1539t792r1582b813],
19	Bioinformatics	NNS	O	bioinformatic	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1600t792r1777b817],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1600t792r1777b817],
21	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1793t793r1938b819],
22	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1953t792r1978b813],
23	Microbiology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Microbiology	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1992t792r2156b819],
24	,	,	ORGANIZATION	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1992t792r2156b819],
25	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2172t793r2270b813],
26	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2285t792r2310b813],
27	Biomedical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biomedical	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l244t834r374b855],
28	Sciences	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Sciences	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l385t835r492b859],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l385t835r492b859],
30	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l504t835r622b861],
31	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l632t834r657b855],
32	Sao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l665t835r707b855],
33	Paulo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l718t834r789b859],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l718t834r789b859],
35	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l800t835r841b855],
36	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l853t834r923b859],
37	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l853t834r923b859],
38	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l935t834r1002b859],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l935t834r1002b859],
40	3	CD	NUMBER	3	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1013t836r1028b855],
41	Division	NN	O	division	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1036t835r1129b855],
42	of	IN	O	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1140t834r1164b855],
43	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1173t834r1264b855],
44	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1276t834r1370b861],
45	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1276t834r1370b861],
46	Adolfo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Adolfo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1380t834r1460b855],
47	Lutz	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Lutz	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1471t835r1520b855],
48	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1531t835r1635b859],
49	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1531t835r1635b859],
50	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1645t835r1687b855],
51	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1698t834r1769b859],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1698t834r1769b859],
53	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1781t834r1848b859],
54	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1781t834r1848b859],
55	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1858t836r1874b855],
56	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1882t835r2027b861],
57	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2037t834r2062b855],
58	Cell	NN	ORGANIZATION	cell	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2070t834r2112b855],
59	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2124t834r2218b861],
60	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2124t834r2218b861],
61	School	NNP	O	School	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2228t834r2307b855],
62	of	IN	O	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l243t875r268b896],
63	Medicine	NNP	O	Medicine	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l277t875r385b896],
64	of	IN	O	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l396t875r420b896],
65	Ribeirao	NNP	LOCATION	Ribeirao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l430t875r526b896],
66	Preto	NNP	LOCATION	Preto	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l538t876r606b900],
67	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l538t876r606b900],
68	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l618t876r736b902],
69	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l746t875r771b896],
70	Sao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l779t876r821b896],
71	Paulo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l833t875r904b900],
72	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l833t875r904b900],
73	Ribeirao	NNP	PERSON	Ribeirao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l916t875r1012b896],
74	Preto	NNP	PERSON	Preto	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1024t876r1092b900],
75	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1024t876r1092b900],
76	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1103t876r1144b896],
77	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1156t875r1227b900],
78	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1156t875r1227b900],
79	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1239t875r1307b900],
80	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1239t875r1307b900],
81	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1318t877r1332b896],
82	Pediatric	NNP	O	Pediatric	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1341t875r1443b896],
83	Division	NNP	O	Division	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1455t876r1554b900],
84	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1455t876r1554b900],
85	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1566t876r1685b902],
86	Hospital	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hospital	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1696t875r1792b902],
87	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1803t875r1828b896],
88	the	DT	ORGANIZATION	the	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1836t875r1875b896],
89	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1886t876r2005b902],
90	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2015t875r2039b896],
91	Sao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2048t876r2090b896],
92	Paulo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2102t875r2172b900],
93	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2102t875r2172b900],
94	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2184t876r2225b896],
95	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2237t875r2308b900],
96	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2237t875r2308b900],
97	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l244t917r311b942],
98	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t917r311b942],
99	6Gastroenteritis	NN	O	6gastroenteritis	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l324t918r522b938],
100	and	CC	O	and	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l534t917r577b938],
101	Respiratory	JJ	ORGANIZATION	respiratory	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l591t918r726b944],
102	Viruses	NNS	ORGANIZATION	virus	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l737t918r821b938],
103	Laboratory	NN	ORGANIZATION	laboratory	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l835t917r964b944],
104	Branch	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Branch	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l977t917r1064b942],
105	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l977t917r1064b942],
106	Division	NNP	O	Division	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1077t918r1170b938],
107	of	IN	O	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1183t917r1208b938],
108	Viral	JJ	O	viral	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1217t917r1268b938],
109	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1282t918r1388b942],
110	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1282t918r1388b942],
111	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1401t917r1499b938],
112	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1512t918r1592b938],
113	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1603t917r1636b938],
114	Immunization	NN	ORGANIZATION	immunization	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1648t918r1813b938],
115	and	CC	O	and	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1826t917r1870b938],
116	Respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1884t918r2018b944],
117	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2031t918r2137b942],
118	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2031t918r2137b942],
119	Coordinating	VBG	O	coordinate	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2150t917r2307b944],
120	Center	NNP	O	Center	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l243t959r323b979],
121	for	IN	O	for	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l333t958r367b979],
122	Infectious	JJ	O	infectious	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l379t958r495b979],
123	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l508t959r614b983],
124	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l508t959r614b983],
125	Centers	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Centers	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l627t959r717b979],
126	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l729t958r762b979],
127	Disease	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Disease	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l774t959r863b979],
128	Control	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Control	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l875t958r963b979],
129	and	CC	ORGANIZATION	and	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l976t958r1020b979],
130	Prevention	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Prevention	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1034t959r1169b983],
131	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1034t959r1169b983],
132	Atlanta	NNP	LOCATION	Atlanta	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1181t958r1273b983],
133	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1181t958r1273b983],
134	Georgia	NNP	LOCATION	Georgia	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1285t959r1385b985],
135	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1285t959r1385b985],
136	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1398t958r1476b979],
137	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1489t959r1560b979],
138	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1572t958r1597b979],
139	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1607t959r1710b983],
140	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1607t959r1710b983],
141	7STD/AIDS	NNP	O	7STD/AIDS	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1723t959r1860b980],
142	Reference	NNP	O	Reference	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1873t958r1991b979],
143	and	CC	O	and	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2003t958r2046b979],
144	Training	NNP	O	Training	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2058t959r2155b985],
145	Centre	NNP	O	Centre	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2169t959r2254b983],
146	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2169t959r2254b983],
147	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2266t959r2308b979],
148	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l244t1000r315b1025],
149	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t1000r315b1025],
150	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l326t1001r368b1021],
151	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l379t1000r450b1025],
152	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l379t1000r450b1025],
153	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l462t1000r529b1025],
154	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l462t1000r529b1025],
155	8State	NNP	O	8State	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l539t1001r622b1021],
156	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l633t1001r752b1027],
157	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l761t1000r786b1021],
158	Sao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l794t1001r836b1021],
159	Paulo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l848t1000r919b1025],
160	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l848t1000r919b1025],
161	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l929t1001r971b1021],
162	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l983t1000r1054b1025],
163	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l983t1000r1054b1025],
164	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1065t1000r1133b1025],
165	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1065t1000r1133b1025],
166	9Tropica	NNP	O	9Tropica	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1143t1000r1259b1027],
167	|	NNP	O	|	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1143t1000r1259b1027],
168	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1271t1000r1380b1021],
169	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1391t1001r1495b1025],
170	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1391t1001r1495b1025],
171	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1506t1001r1625b1027],
172	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1634t1000r1659b1021],
173	Sao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1668t1001r1709b1021],
174	Paulo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1721t1000r1792b1025],
175	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1721t1000r1792b1025],
176	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1803t1001r1844b1021],
177	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1856t1000r1927b1025],
178	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1856t1000r1927b1025],
179	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1938t1000r2006b1025],
180	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1938t1000r2006b1025],
181	10	CD	NUMBER	10	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2018t1002r2049b1021],
182	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2057t1001r2202b1027],
183	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2212t1000r2237b1021],
184	Legal	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Legal	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2246t1000r2307b1027],
185	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l244t1041r358b1066],
186	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t1041r358b1066],
187	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l369t1042r488b1068],
188	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l497t1041r522b1062],
189	Sao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l530t1042r572b1062],
190	Paulo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l583t1041r648b1062],
191	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l659t1041r750b1062],
192	School	NNP	ORGANIZATION	School	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l761t1041r846b1066],
193	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l761t1041r846b1066],
194	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l857t1042r899b1062],
195	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l910t1041r981b1066],
196	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l910t1041r981b1066],
197	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l992t1041r1059b1066],
198	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l992t1041r1059b1066],
199	11	CD	NUMBER	11	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1072t1043r1098b1062],
200	Center	NNP	O	Center	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1109t1042r1189b1062],
201	for	IN	O	for	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1198t1041r1231b1062],
202	Infectious	JJ	MISC	infectious	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1241t1041r1357b1062],
203	Disease	NN	MISC	disease	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1368t1042r1457b1062],
204	Dynamics	NNP	MISC	Dynamics	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1468t1042r1589b1068],
205	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1468t1042r1589b1068],
206	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1601t1042r1746b1068],
207	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1756t1041r1780b1062],
208	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1790t1041r1883b1068],
209	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1790t1041r1883b1068],
210	The	DT	O	the	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1892t1041r1937b1062],
211	Pennsylvania	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pennsylvania	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1948t1041r2102b1068],
212	State	NNP	ORGANIZATION	State	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2113t1042r2173b1062],
213	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2184t1042r2308b1068],
214	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2184t1042r2308b1068],
215	Mueller	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Mueller	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l244t1083r333b1104],
216	Laboratory	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Laboratory	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l346t1083r481b1110],
217	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l346t1083r481b1110],
218	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l495t1084r613b1110],
219	Park	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Park	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l626t1083r681b1108],
220	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l626t1083r681b1108],
221	Pennsylvania	NNP	LOCATION	Pennsylvania	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l695t1083r856b1110],
222	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l695t1083r856b1110],
223	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l869t1083r947b1104],
224	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l961t1084r1032b1104],
225	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1045t1083r1069b1104],
226	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1080t1084r1183b1108],
227	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1080t1084r1183b1108],
228	12Fogarty	NNP	O	12Fogarty	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1198t1084r1327b1110],
229	International	NNP	ORGANIZATION	International	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1340t1083r1492b1104],
230	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1505t1084r1590b1108],
231	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1505t1084r1590b1108],
232	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1604t1083r1702b1104],
233	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1716t1084r1826b1104],
234	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1838t1083r1863b1104],
235	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1874t1083r1957b1108],
236	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1874t1083r1957b1108],
237	Bethesda	NNP	LOCATION	Bethesda	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1970t1083r2085b1108],
238	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1970t1083r2085b1108],
239	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2099t1083r2215b1110],
240	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2099t1083r2215b1110],
241	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2229t1083r2307b1104],
242	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l243t1125r314b1145],
243	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l326t1124r351b1145],
244	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l360t1125r464b1149],
245	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l360t1125r464b1149],
246	13	CD	NUMBER	13	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l478t1126r508b1145],
247	Laboratory	NN	O	laboratory	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l517t1124r646b1151],
248	of	IN	O	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l658t1124r682b1145],
249	Clinical	JJ	O	clinical	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l692t1124r776b1145],
250	Virology	NNP	O	Virology	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l788t1124r893b1151],
251	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l788t1124r893b1151],
252	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l906t1125r1051b1151],
253	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1063t1124r1088b1145],
254	Microbiology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Microbiology	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1098t1124r1262b1151],
255	,	,	ORGANIZATION	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1098t1124r1262b1151],
256	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1275t1125r1372b1145],
257	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1384t1124r1409b1145],
258	Biomedical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biomedical	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1420t1124r1550b1145],
259	Sciences	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Sciences	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1563t1125r1670b1149],
260	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1563t1125r1670b1149],
261	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1683t1125r1801b1151],
262	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1812t1124r1837b1145],
263	Sao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1847t1125r1889b1145],
264	Paulo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1902t1124r1973b1149],
265	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1902t1124r1973b1149],
266	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l1985t1125r2027b1145],
267	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	dep	269	SENT_4	[p1l2040t1124r2110b1149],
268	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2040t1124r2110b1149],
269	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2124t1124r2184b1145],

1	Abstract	JJ	O	abstract	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l308t1241r475b1272],

1	Human	JJ	O	human	amod	3	SENT_6	[p1l310t1308r420b1333],
2	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	3	SENT_6	[p1l435t1307r600b1341],
3	syncytial	NN	O	syncytial	nsubj	11	SENT_6	[p1l612t1306r743b1341],
4	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	7	SENT_6	[p1l756t1307r828b1333],
5	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	7	SENT_6	[p1l842t1307r943b1338],
6	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	7	SENT_6	[p1l842t1307r943b1338],
7	)	NN	O	)	dep	3	SENT_6	[p1l842t1307r943b1338],
8	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	11	SENT_6	[p1l957t1307r977b1333],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_6	[p1l989t1306r1039b1333],
10	major	JJ	O	major	amod	11	SENT_6	[p1l1053t1307r1141b1341],
11	cause	NN	O	cause	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1152t1314r1238b1333],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1251t1306r1283b1333],
13	lower	JJR	O	lower	amod	16	SENT_6	[p1l1294t1306r1379b1333],
14	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	16	SENT_6	[p1l1392t1307r1557b1341],
15	tract	NN	O	tract	nn	16	SENT_6	[p1l1568t1311r1638b1333],
16	infections	NNS	O	infection	prep_of	11	SENT_6	[p1l1651t1306r1800b1333],
17	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1814t1307r1839b1333],
18	children	NNS	O	child	prep_in	16	SENT_6	[p1l1853t1306r1976b1333],
19	under	IN	O	under	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1991t1306r2081b1333],
20	5	CD	DURATION	5	num	21	SENT_6	[p1l2093t1309r2108b1333],
21	years	NNS	NUMBER	year	prep_under	18	SENT_6	[p1l2121t1314r2200b1341],
22	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2213t1306r2245b1333],
23	age	NN	O	age	prep_of	21	SENT_6	[p1l309t1356r364b1383],
24	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l376t1348r432b1375],
25	the	DT	O	the	det	26	SENT_6	[p1l444t1348r494b1375],
26	elderly	JJ	O	elderly	prep_of	21	SENT_6	[p1l506t1348r616b1383],
27	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l506t1348r616b1383],
28	causing	VBG	O	cause	partmod	11	SENT_6	[p1l628t1349r744b1383],
29	annual	JJ	SET	annual	amod	31	SENT_6	[p1l757t1348r860b1375],
30	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	31	SENT_6	[p1l873t1348r985b1375],
31	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	dobj	28	SENT_6	[p1l997t1348r1150b1375],
32	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1162t1348r1262b1383],
33	the	DT	O	the	det	34	SENT_6	[p1l1274t1348r1324b1375],
34	fall	NN	DATE	fall	prep_during	28	SENT_6	[p1l1335t1348r1378b1375],
35	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1391t1348r1447b1375],
36	winter	NN	DATE	winter	conj_and	34	SENT_6	[p1l1459t1349r1565b1375],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1459t1349r1565b1375],

1	Multiple	JJ	O	multiple	amod	2	SENT_7	[p1l1578t1348r1703b1382],
2	lineages	NNS	O	lineage	nsubj	15	SENT_7	[p1l1717t1348r1841b1383],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1853t1348r1885b1375],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_7	[p1l1894t1348r1943b1375],
5	HRSVA	NN	O	hrsva	nn	8	SENT_7	[p1l1957t1349r2060b1375],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l2071t1348r2127b1375],
7	HRSVB	NN	O	hrsvb	nn	8	SENT_7	[p1l2142t1349r2242b1375],
8	serotypes	NNS	O	serotype	prep_of	2	SENT_7	[p1l309t1395r457b1425],
9	co-circulate	VBP	O	co-circulate	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l479t1390r657b1417],
10	within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l678t1390r773b1417],
11	a	DT	O	a	det	13	SENT_7	[p1l795t1398r810b1417],
12	single	JJ	O	single	amod	13	SENT_7	[p1l833t1390r922b1425],
13	outbreak	NN	O	outbreak	prep_within	9	SENT_7	[p1l944t1390r1083b1417],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1103t1390r1159b1417],
15	display	VBP	O	display	conj_and	9	SENT_7	[p1l1182t1390r1290b1425],
16	a	DT	O	a	det	19	SENT_7	[p1l1310t1398r1325b1417],
17	strongly	RB	O	strongly	advmod	18	SENT_7	[p1l1347t1390r1473b1425],
18	temporal	JJ	O	temporal	amod	19	SENT_7	[p1l1493t1390r1633b1424],
19	pattern	NN	O	pattern	dobj	15	SENT_7	[p1l1656t1395r1767b1424],
20	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1790t1390r1821b1417],
21	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	22	SENT_7	[p1l1840t1391r1954b1425],
22	variation	NN	O	variation	prep_of	19	SENT_7	[p1l1975t1391r2117b1422],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1975t1391r2117b1422],
24	with	IN	O	with	conj_and	9	SENT_7	[p1l2138t1390r2204b1417],
25	a	DT	O	a	det	26	SENT_7	[p1l2227t1398r2241b1417],
26	replacement	NN	O	replacement	pobj	24	SENT_7	[p1l310t1431r504b1465],
27	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l521t1431r552b1458],
28	dominant	JJ	O	dominant	amod	29	SENT_7	[p1l567t1431r718b1458],
29	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	prep_of	26	SENT_7	[p1l735t1436r898b1466],
30	occurring	VBG	O	occur	partmod	29	SENT_7	[p1l915t1432r1060b1466],
31	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1079t1431r1179b1466],
32	consecutive	JJ	O	consecutive	amod	33	SENT_7	[p1l1198t1432r1382b1458],
33	years	NNS	DURATION	year	prep_during	30	SENT_7	[p1l1398t1439r1485b1466],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1398t1439r1485b1466],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1504t1433r1529b1458],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_8	[p1l1547t1431r1597b1458],
3	present	JJ	DATE	present	amod	4	SENT_8	[p1l1615t1436r1731b1465],
4	study	NN	O	study	prep_in	6	SENT_8	[p1l1748t1431r1832b1466],
5	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	6	SENT_8	[p1l1848t1439r1893b1458],
6	utilized	VBD	O	utilize	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1911t1431r2021b1458],
7	phylogenetic	JJ	O	phylogenetic	amod	8	SENT_8	[p1l2040t1431r2242b1466],
8	methods	NNS	O	method	dobj	6	SENT_8	[p1l310t1472r445b1499],
9	to	TO	O	to	aux	10	SENT_8	[p1l458t1477r489b1499],
10	detect	VB	O	detect	xcomp	6	SENT_8	[p1l502t1472r600b1499],
11	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l612t1472r668b1499],
12	map	VB	O	map	conj_and	10	SENT_8	[p1l684t1480r750b1506],
13	sites	NNS	O	site	dobj	10	SENT_8	[p1l764t1473r830b1499],
14	subject	JJ	O	subject	amod	13	SENT_8	[p1l844t1472r955b1507],
15	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l967t1477r998b1499],
16	adaptive	JJ	O	adaptive	amod	17	SENT_8	[p1l1011t1472r1144b1506],
17	evolution	NN	O	evolution	prep_to	14	SENT_8	[p1l1157t1472r1302b1499],
18	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1317t1473r1342b1499],
19	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_8	[p1l1355t1472r1405b1499],
20	G	NN	O	g	nn	21	SENT_8	[p1l1418t1473r1439b1499],
21	protein	NN	O	protein	prep_in	10	SENT_8	[p1l1454t1473r1563b1506],
22	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1578t1472r1610b1499],
23	HRSVA	NN	O	hrsva	prep_of	21	SENT_8	[p1l1621t1473r1725b1499],
24	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1737t1472r1793b1499],
25	HRSVB	NN	O	hrsvb	prep_of	21	SENT_8	[p1l1809t1473r1917b1499],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1809t1473r1917b1499],

1	A	DT	O	a	det	2	SENT_9	[p1l1930t1474r1951b1499],
2	total	NN	O	total	nsubjpass	11	SENT_9	[p1l1963t1472r2032b1499],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l2046t1472r2078b1499],
4	29	CD	NUMBER	29	nn	9	SENT_9	[p1l2088t1474r2123b1499],
5	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l2136t1472r2192b1499],
6	23	CD	NUMBER	23	nn	9	SENT_9	[p1l2207t1474r2241b1499],
7	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	9	SENT_9	[p1l309t1515r405b1541],
8	acid	NN	O	acid	nn	9	SENT_9	[p1l420t1514r481b1541],
9	sites	NNS	O	site	prep_of	2	SENT_9	[p1l497t1515r563b1541],
10	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	11	SENT_9	[p1l578t1522r653b1541],
11	found	VBN	O	find	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l667t1514r758b1541],
12	to	TO	O	to	aux	16	SENT_9	[p1l774t1519r805b1541],
13	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	16	SENT_9	[p1l821t1514r858b1541],
14	putatively	RB	O	putatively	advmod	16	SENT_9	[p1l874t1514r1027b1549],
15	positively	RB	O	positively	advmod	16	SENT_9	[p1l1042t1514r1189b1549],
16	selected	VBN	O	select	xcomp	11	SENT_9	[p1l1203t1514r1329b1541],
17	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1346t1515r1370b1541],
18	HRSVA	NN	O	hrsva	prep_in	16	SENT_9	[p1l1388t1515r1491b1541],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1506t1514r1562b1541],
20	HRSVB	NN	O	hrsvb	conj_and	18	SENT_9	[p1l1579t1515r1687b1546],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1579t1515r1687b1546],
22	respectively	RB	O	respectively	advmod	16	SENT_9	[p1l1704t1514r1894b1549],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1704t1514r1894b1549],

1	Several	JJ	O	several	nsubj	16	SENT_10	[p1l1909t1514r2017b1541],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2034t1514r2065b1541],
3	these	DT	O	these	det	4	SENT_10	[p1l2077t1514r2160b1541],
4	sites	NNS	O	site	prep_of	1	SENT_10	[p1l2176t1515r2242b1541],
5	deﬁned	VBD	O	deﬁned	ccomp	32	SENT_10	[p1l309t1556r425b1583],
6	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	dobj	5	SENT_10	[p1l437t1561r600b1591],
7	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l612t1556r668b1583],
8	lineages	NNS	O	lineage	dobj	5	SENT_10	[p1l682t1556r807b1591],
9	within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l818t1556r913b1583],
10	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	prep_within	5	SENT_10	[p1l926t1561r1089b1591],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1102t1557r1126b1583],
12	both	DT	O	both	det	13	SENT_10	[p1l1140t1556r1211b1583],
13	groups	NNS	O	group	prep_in	10	SENT_10	[p1l1223t1564r1339b1591],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1223t1564r1339b1591],
15	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1351t1556r1407b1583],
16	correlated	VBD	O	correlate	conj_and	5	SENT_10	[p1l1419t1556r1574b1583],
17	well	RB	O	well	advmod	16	SENT_10	[p1l1587t1556r1647b1583],
18	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1659t1556r1725b1583],
19	epitopes	NNS	O	epitope	prep_with	16	SENT_10	[p1l1738t1557r1872b1590],
20	previously	RB	DATE	previously	advmod	21	SENT_10	[p1l1885t1556r2043b1591],
21	described	VBN	O	describe	partmod	19	SENT_10	[p1l2054t1556r2203b1583],
22	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2216t1557r2241b1583],
23	group	NN	O	group	nn	24	SENT_10	[p1l309t1605r402b1632],
24	A.	NN	O	a.	prep_in	21	SENT_10	[p1l415t1599r444b1624],
25	Remarkably	RB	O	remarkably	advmod	21	SENT_10	[p1l459t1597r645b1632],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l459t1597r645b1632],
27	18	CD	NUMBER	18	nsubj	32	SENT_10	[p1l662t1599r695b1624],
28	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l709t1597r740b1624],
29	these	DT	O	these	prep_of	27	SENT_10	[p1l750t1597r834b1624],
30	positively	RB	O	positively	advmod	31	SENT_10	[p1l848t1597r995b1632],
31	selected	VBN	O	select	partmod	29	SENT_10	[p1l1008t1597r1133b1624],
32	tended	VBD	O	tend	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1147t1597r1257b1624],
33	to	TO	O	to	aux	34	SENT_10	[p1l1271t1602r1302b1624],
34	revert	VB	O	revert	xcomp	32	SENT_10	[p1l1317t1602r1406b1624],
35	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1420t1598r1444b1624],
36	time	NN	O	time	prep_in	34	SENT_10	[p1l1458t1598r1527b1624],
37	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1540t1602r1571b1624],
38	a	DT	O	a	det	41	SENT_10	[p1l1585t1605r1600b1624],
39	previous	JJ	O	previous	amod	41	SENT_10	[p1l1615t1598r1746b1631],
40	codon	NN	O	codon	nn	41	SENT_10	[p1l1760t1597r1856b1624],
41	state	NN	O	state	prep_to	34	SENT_10	[p1l1871t1602r1952b1629],
42	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1871t1602r1952b1629],
43	producing	VBG	O	produce	xcomp	32	SENT_10	[p1l1967t1597r2124b1632],
44	a	DT	O	a	det	48	SENT_10	[p1l2139t1605r2154b1624],
45	’’	CD	NUMBER	’’	num	48	SENT_10	[p1l2168t1597r2242b1631],
46	flip	JJ	O	flip	amod	48	SENT_10	[p1l2168t1597r2242b1631],
47	—	NN	O	—	nn	48	SENT_10	[p1l2168t1597r2242b1631],
48	flop	NN	O	flop	nsubj	51	SENT_10	[p1l308t1639r384b1673],
49	’’	CD	NUMBER	’’	num	51	SENT_10	[p1l308t1639r384b1673],
50	phylogenetic	JJ	O	phylogenetic	amod	51	SENT_10	[p1l404t1639r606b1674],
51	pattern	NN	O	pattern	xcomp	43	SENT_10	[p1l627t1644r746b1673],
52	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l627t1644r746b1673],

1	Such	JJ	O	such	amod	4	SENT_11	[p1l767t1639r839b1666],
2	frequent	JJ	O	frequent	amod	4	SENT_11	[p1l859t1639r993b1673],
3	evolutionary	JJ	O	evolutionary	amod	4	SENT_11	[p1l1013t1639r1207b1674],
4	reversals	NNS	O	reversal	nsubj	17	SENT_11	[p1l1227t1639r1358b1666],
5	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1379t1640r1404b1666],
6	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	prep_in	4	SENT_11	[p1l1426t1640r1507b1666],
7	are	VBP	O	be	cop	17	SENT_11	[p1l1526t1647r1572b1666],
8	indicative	JJ	O	indicative	acomp	17	SENT_11	[p1l1593t1639r1740b1666],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1761t1639r1792b1666],
10	a	DT	O	a	det	11	SENT_11	[p1l1809t1647r1824b1666],
11	combination	NN	O	combination	prep_of	17	SENT_11	[p1l1844t1639r2040b1666],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l2061t1639r2093b1666],
13	frequent	JJ	O	frequent	amod	15	SENT_11	[p1l2109t1639r2242b1673],
14	positive	JJ	O	positive	amod	15	SENT_11	[p1l310t1681r429b1714],
15	selection	NN	O	selection	prep_of	11	SENT_11	[p1l442t1680r587b1712],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l442t1680r587b1712],
17	reflecting	VBG	O	reflect	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l601t1680r744b1715],
18	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_11	[p1l757t1680r807b1707],
19	changing	VBG	O	change	amod	21	SENT_11	[p1l820t1680r963b1715],
20	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	21	SENT_11	[p1l978t1681r1105b1707],
21	status	NN	O	status	dobj	17	SENT_11	[p1l1119t1685r1209b1707],
22	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1222t1680r1253b1707],
23	the	DT	O	the	det	25	SENT_11	[p1l1262t1680r1312b1707],
24	human	JJ	O	human	amod	25	SENT_11	[p1l1327t1680r1432b1707],
25	population	NN	O	population	prep_of	21	SENT_11	[p1l1447t1680r1624b1714],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1447t1680r1624b1714],
27	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1637t1680r1693b1707],
28	a	DT	O	a	det	30	SENT_11	[p1l1706t1688r1721b1707],
29	limited	JJ	O	limited	amod	30	SENT_11	[p1l1736t1680r1840b1707],
30	repertoire	NN	O	repertoire	conj_and	21	SENT_11	[p1l1855t1681r2007b1714],
31	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l2019t1680r2051b1707],
32	functionally	RB	O	functionally	advmod	33	SENT_11	[p1l2060t1680r2243b1715],
33	viable	JJ	O	viable	amod	35	SENT_11	[p1l308t1721r399b1748],
34	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	35	SENT_11	[p1l414t1722r510b1748],
35	acids	NNS	O	acid	prep_of	30	SENT_11	[p1l525t1721r602b1748],
36	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l617t1726r645b1748],
37	specific	JJ	O	specific	amod	40	SENT_11	[p1l660t1721r774b1755],
38	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	40	SENT_11	[p1l788t1722r885b1748],
39	acid	NN	O	acid	nn	40	SENT_11	[p1l900t1721r960b1748],
40	sites	NNS	O	site	prep_at	35	SENT_11	[p1l977t1722r1051b1748],
41	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l977t1722r1051b1748],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l278t1826r396b1847],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l278t1826r396b1847],
3	Botosso	NNP	O	Botosso	nn	4	SENT_12	[p1l406t1827r500b1847],
4	VF	NNP	O	VF	dep	1	SENT_12	[p1l508t1827r544b1851],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l508t1827r544b1851],
6	Zanotto	NNP	O	Zanotto	nn	7	SENT_12	[p1l553t1827r649b1847],
7	PMdA	NNP	O	PMdA	appos	4	SENT_12	[p1l659t1826r735b1851],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l659t1826r735b1851],
9	Ueda	NNP	PERSON	Ueda	nn	10	SENT_12	[p1l746t1826r806b1847],
10	M	NNP	O	M	appos	4	SENT_12	[p1l816t1827r843b1851],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l816t1827r843b1851],
12	Arruda	NNP	PERSON	Arruda	nn	13	SENT_12	[p1l852t1826r933b1847],
13	E	NNP	O	E	appos	4	SENT_12	[p1l944t1827r961b1851],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l944t1827r961b1851],
15	Gilio	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Gilio	nn	16	SENT_12	[p1l970t1826r1023b1847],
16	AE	NNP	ORGANIZATION	AE	appos	4	SENT_12	[p1l1032t1827r1068b1851],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1032t1827r1068b1851],
18	et	FW	O	et	dep	4	SENT_12	[p1l1078t1830r1100b1847],
19	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	20	SENT_12	[p1l1110t1826r1134b1847],
20	(	FW	O	(	dep	4	SENT_12	[p1l1144t1827r1217b1851],
21	2008	CD	DATE	2008	dep	20	SENT_12	[p1l1144t1827r1217b1851],
22	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	25	SENT_12	[p1l1144t1827r1217b1851],
23	Positive	JJ	O	positive	amod	25	SENT_12	[p1l1228t1827r1319b1847],
24	Selection	NN	O	selection	nn	25	SENT_12	[p1l1329t1826r1437b1847],
25	Results	NNS	O	result	dep	1	SENT_12	[p1l1449t1826r1531b1847],
26	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1541t1827r1561b1847],
27	Frequent	JJ	O	frequent	amod	31	SENT_12	[p1l1572t1827r1680b1853],
28	Reversible	JJ	O	reversible	amod	31	SENT_12	[p1l1690t1826r1811b1847],
29	Amino	NN	O	amino	nn	31	SENT_12	[p1l1821t1827r1899b1847],
30	Acid	NN	O	acid	nn	31	SENT_12	[p1l1909t1826r1960b1847],
31	Replacements	NNS	O	replacement	prep_in	25	SENT_12	[p1l1971t1826r2139b1853],
32	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l2150t1827r2169b1847],
33	the	DT	O	the	det	36	SENT_12	[p1l2179t1826r2217b1847],
34	6	CD	NUMBER	6	num	36	SENT_12	[p1l2227t1827r2243b1847],
35	Protein	NN	O	protein	nn	36	SENT_12	[p1l279t1861r363b1881],
36	Gene	NN	O	gene	prep_in	25	SENT_12	[p1l376t1861r438b1881],
37	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l449t1860r474b1881],
38	Human	JJ	O	human	amod	41	SENT_12	[p1l485t1861r570b1881],
39	Respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	41	SENT_12	[p1l584t1861r719b1887],
40	Syncytial	JJ	O	syncytial	amod	41	SENT_12	[p1l730t1860r834b1887],
41	Virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	36	SENT_12	[p1l846t1861r911b1881],
42	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l846t1861r911b1881],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_13	[p1l924t1861r980b1881],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l993t1860r1076b1887],
3	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	4	SENT_13	[p1l1090t1861r1139b1885],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_13	[p1l1090t1861r1139b1885],
5	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	6	SENT_13	[p1l1090t1861r1139b1885],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_13	[p1l1090t1861r1139b1885],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1090t1861r1139b1885],
8	el000254	NN	O	el000254	dep	2	SENT_13	[p1l1151t1862r1273b1881],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1151t1862r1273b1881],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
3	l0	NN	O	l0	dep	1	SENT_14	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
4	.1371	CD	NUMBER	.1371	num	3	SENT_14	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
5	/	:	O	/	punct	7	SENT_14	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
6	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	7	SENT_14	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
7	|	NN	O	|	dep	3	SENT_14	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],

1	lO00254	NN	O	lo00254	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1285t1860r1692b1887],
2	Editor	NNP	O	Editor	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l279t1911r370b1932],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l279t1911r370b1932],
4	Ron	NNP	PERSON	Ron	nn	7	SENT_16	[p1l382t1912r426b1932],
5	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	7	SENT_16	[p1l439t1912r461b1932],
6	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	7	SENT_16	[p1l473t1912r500b1932],
7	Fouchier	NNP	PERSON	Fouchier	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l513t1911r621b1936],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l513t1911r621b1936],
9	Erasmus	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Erasmus	nn	11	SENT_16	[p1l634t1912r732b1932],
10	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	nn	11	SENT_16	[p1l745t1911r836b1932],
11	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	appos	7	SENT_16	[p1l848t1912r933b1936],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l848t1912r933b1936],
13	The	DT	LOCATION	the	det	14	SENT_16	[p1l944t1911r988b1932],
14	Netherlands	NNP	LOCATION	Netherlands	appos	7	SENT_16	[p1l1001t1911r1146b1932],
15	Received	VBD	O	receive	rcmod	14	SENT_16	[p1l279t1963r401b1984],
16	June	NNP	DATE	June	nsubj	27	SENT_16	[p1l413t1964r470b1984],
17	20	CD	DATE	20	num	16	SENT_16	[p1l481t1965r514b1988],
18	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l481t1965r514b1988],
19	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	16	SENT_16	[p1l527t1965r590b1988],
20	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l527t1965r590b1988],
21	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	amod	16	SENT_16	[p1l601t1963r730b1990],
22	December	NNP	DATE	December	tmod	21	SENT_16	[p1l743t1963r867b1984],
23	4	CD	DATE	4	num	22	SENT_16	[p1l878t1965r897b1988],
24	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l878t1965r897b1988],
25	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	22	SENT_16	[p1l909t1965r973b1988],
26	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l909t1965r973b1988],
27	Published	VBN	O	publish	dep	15	SENT_16	[p1l985t1963r1121b1984],
28	January	NNP	DATE	January	tmod	27	SENT_16	[p1l1132t1964r1226b1990],
29	2	CD	DATE	2	num	28	SENT_16	[p1l1237t1965r1255b1988],
30	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1237t1965r1255b1988],
31	2009	CD	DATE	2009	num	28	SENT_16	[p1l1267t1965r1325b1984],
32	This	DT	O	this	nsubj	38	SENT_16	[p1l277t2015r325b2036],
33	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	38	SENT_16	[p1l337t2016r352b2036],
34	an	DT	O	a	det	38	SENT_16	[p1l363t2021r390b2036],
35	open	JJ	O	open	amod	38	SENT_16	[p1l402t2021r550b2042],
36	—	NN	O	—	nn	38	SENT_16	[p1l402t2021r550b2042],
37	access	NN	O	access	nn	38	SENT_16	[p1l402t2021r550b2042],
38	article	NN	O	article	ccomp	15	SENT_16	[p1l561t2015r633b2036],
39	distributed	VBN	O	distribute	partmod	38	SENT_16	[p1l644t2015r775b2036],
40	under	IN	O	under	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l788t2015r858b2036],
41	the	DT	O	the	det	42	SENT_16	[p1l868t2015r907b2036],
42	terms	NNS	O	term	prep_under	39	SENT_16	[p1l917t2019r985b2036],
43	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l996t2015r1021b2036],
44	the	DT	O	the	det	49	SENT_16	[p1l1029t2015r1068b2036],
45	Creative	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Creative	nn	49	SENT_16	[p1l1079t2016r1177b2036],
46	Commons	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Commons	nn	49	SENT_16	[p1l1188t2016r1311b2036],
47	Public	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Public	nn	49	SENT_16	[p1l1323t2015r1395b2036],
48	Domain	NN	ORGANIZATION	domain	nn	49	SENT_16	[p1l1407t2016r1499b2036],
49	declaration	NN	O	declaration	prep_of	42	SENT_16	[p1l1511t2015r1645b2036],
50	which	WDT	O	which	nsubj	51	SENT_16	[p1l1656t2015r1727b2036],
51	stipulates	VBZ	O	stipulate	rcmod	49	SENT_16	[p1l1740t2015r1854b2042],
52	that	IN	O	that	nsubj	55	SENT_16	[p1l1864t2015r1918b2040],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1864t2015r1918b2040],
54	once	RB	DATE	once	advmod	55	SENT_16	[p1l1930t2021r1987b2036],
55	placed	VBN	O	place	ccomp	51	SENT_16	[p1l1999t2015r2077b2042],
56	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l2089t2016r2108b2036],
57	the	DT	O	the	det	59	SENT_16	[p1l2120t2015r2159b2036],
58	public	JJ	O	public	amod	59	SENT_16	[p1l2171t2015r2244b2042],
59	domain	NN	O	domain	prep_in	55	SENT_16	[p1l278t2048r375b2073],
60	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l278t2048r375b2073],
61	this	DT	O	this	det	62	SENT_16	[p1l387t2048r429b2069],
62	work	NN	O	work	nsubjpass	66	SENT_16	[p1l441t2048r501b2069],
63	may	MD	O	may	aux	66	SENT_16	[p1l512t2055r562b2075],
64	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	66	SENT_16	[p1l574t2048r602b2069],
65	freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	66	SENT_16	[p1l613t2048r680b2075],
66	reproduced	VBN	O	reproduce	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l692t2048r837b2075],
67	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l692t2048r837b2075],
68	distributed	VBN	O	distribute	partmod	1	SENT_16	[p1l849t2048r986b2073],
69	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l849t2048r986b2073],
70	transmitted	VBN	O	transmit	partmod	1	SENT_16	[p1l998t2048r1144b2073],
71	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l998t2048r1144b2073],
72	modiﬁed	VBN	O	modiﬁed	partmod	1	SENT_16	[p1l1157t2048r1269b2073],
73	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1157t2048r1269b2073],
74	built	VBN	O	build	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l1282t2048r1335b2069],
75	upon	IN	O	upon	prep	74	SENT_16	[p1l1347t2054r1415b2075],
76	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1347t2054r1415b2075],
77	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1427t2055r1451b2069],
78	otherwise	RB	O	otherwise	advmod	74	SENT_16	[p1l1462t2048r1580b2069],
79	used	VBN	O	use	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l1593t2048r1647b2069],
80	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1661t2048r1689b2075],
81	anyone	NN	O	anyone	prep_by	79	SENT_16	[p1l1700t2054r1788b2075],
82	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1799t2048r1833b2069],
83	any	DT	O	any	det	85	SENT_16	[p1l1844t2054r1886b2075],
84	lawful	JJ	O	lawful	amod	85	SENT_16	[p1l1898t2048r1968b2069],
85	purpose	NN	O	purpose	prep_for	81	SENT_16	[p1l1981t2054r2085b2075],
86	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1981t2054r2085b2075],

1	Funding	NNP	O	Funding	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l279t2100r401b2127],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l279t2100r401b2127],
3	This	DT	O	this	det	4	SENT_17	[p1l411t2100r459b2121],
4	project	NN	O	project	nsubjpass	6	SENT_17	[p1l472t2101r555b2127],
5	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_17	[p1l567t2106r612b2121],
6	made	VBN	O	make	dep	1	SENT_17	[p1l625t2100r691b2121],
7	possible	JJ	O	possible	acomp	6	SENT_17	[p1l703t2100r801b2127],
8	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l813t2100r842b2127],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_17	[p1l852t2100r891b2121],
10	VGDN	NNP	ORGANIZATION	VGDN	nn	11	SENT_17	[p1l902t2101r973b2121],
11	program	NN	O	program	agent	6	SENT_17	[p1l987t2106r1089b2127],
12	funded	VBN	O	fund	partmod	11	SENT_17	[p1l1101t2100r1186b2121],
13	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1200t2100r1228b2127],
14	FAPESP	NNP	ORGANIZATION	FAPESP	nn	15	SENT_17	[p1l1240t2101r1328b2121],
15	project	NN	O	project	agent	12	SENT_17	[p1l1341t2101r1425b2127],
16	#	#	MONEY	#	number	18	SENT_17	[p1l1437t2101r1597b2127],
17	00/04205	CD	MONEY	00/04205	number	18	SENT_17	[p1l1437t2101r1597b2127],
18	-6	CD	MONEY	-6	dep	15	SENT_17	[p1l1437t2101r1597b2127],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1608t2100r1651b2121],
20	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1665t2100r1693b2127],
21	CNPq	NN	O	cnpq	agent	12	SENT_17	[p1l1704t2101r1775b2127],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1704t2101r1775b2127],
23	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	appos	21	SENT_17	[p1l1789t2100r1857b2121],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1789t2100r1857b2121],

1	Competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	2	SENT_18	[p1l278t2152r431b2179],
2	Interests	NNS	O	interest	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l444t2153r571b2173],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l444t2153r571b2173],
4	The	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_18	[p1l581t2152r626b2173],
5	authors	NNS	O	author	nsubj	7	SENT_18	[p1l637t2152r728b2173],
6	have	VBP	O	have	aux	7	SENT_18	[p1l741t2152r796b2173],
7	declared	VBN	O	declare	dep	2	SENT_18	[p1l808t2152r910b2173],
8	that	IN	O	that	complm	12	SENT_18	[p1l922t2152r970b2173],
9	no	DT	O	no	det	11	SENT_18	[p1l982t2158r1011b2173],
10	competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	11	SENT_18	[p1l1023t2153r1153b2179],
11	interests	NNS	O	interest	nsubj	12	SENT_18	[p1l1167t2153r1268b2173],
12	exist	VBP	O	exist	ccomp	7	SENT_18	[p1l1279t2153r1339b2173],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1279t2153r1339b2173],

1	*	NN	O	*	nn	2	SENT_19	[p1l278t2205r289b2215],
2	E	NN	O	e	nsubj	26	SENT_19	[p1l301t2204r379b2225],
3	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	2	SENT_19	[p1l301t2204r379b2225],
4	mai	FW	O	mai	nn	5	SENT_19	[p1l301t2204r379b2225],
5	|	FW	O	|	dep	2	SENT_19	[p1l301t2204r379b2225],
6	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l301t2204r379b2225],
7	pzanotto@usp.br	NN	O	pzanotto@usp.br	dep	2	SENT_19	[p1l391t2204r598b2231],
8	containing	VBG	O	contain	partmod	7	SENT_19	[p1l1314t2323r1472b2357],
9	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	11	SENT_19	[p1l1491t2329r1544b2349],
10	hyper-variable	JJ	O	hyper-variable	amod	11	SENT_19	[p1l1564t2323r1780b2357],
11	segments	NNS	O	segment	dobj	8	SENT_19	[p1l1801t2329r1943b2357],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1801t2329r1943b2357],
13	separated	VBN	O	separate	partmod	2	SENT_19	[p1l1965t2323r2106b2357],
14	by	IN	O	by	prep	13	SENT_19	[p1l2126t2323r2162b2357],
15	a	DT	O	a	det	16	SENT_19	[p1l2182t2332r2198b2348],
16	highly	RB	O	highly	pobj	14	SENT_19	[p1l2217t2323r2309b2357],
17	conserved	VBN	O	conserve	dep	16	SENT_19	[p1l1314t2367r1462b2393],
18	region	NN	O	region	dobj	17	SENT_19	[p1l1477t2367r1570b2401],
19	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1586t2367r1708b2393],
20	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	21	SENT_19	[p1l1724t2367r1817b2393],
21	acids	NNS	O	acid	prep_between	18	SENT_19	[p1l1833t2367r1905b2393],
22	164	CD	NUMBER	164	num	16	SENT_19	[p1l1926t2367r1975b2393],
23	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1991t2367r2046b2393],
24	176	CD	NUMBER	176	num	16	SENT_19	[p1l2065t2367r2123b2399],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2065t2367r2123b2399],
26	assumed	VBD	O	assume	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2140t2367r2266b2393],
27	to	TO	O	to	aux	28	SENT_19	[p1l2280t2373r2308b2393],
28	represent	VB	O	represent	xcomp	26	SENT_19	[p1l1314t2417r1451b2445],
29	a	DT	O	a	det	34	SENT_19	[p1l1471t2420r1486b2436],
30	receptor-binding	JJ	O	receptor-binding	amod	34	SENT_19	[p1l1505t2411r1756b2445],
31	site	NN	O	site	nn	34	SENT_19	[p1l1774t2411r1821b2437],
32	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	33	SENT_19	[p1l1844t2411r1909b2445],
33	15	CD	NUMBER	15	num	34	SENT_19	[p1l1844t2411r1909b2445],
34	]	NN	O	]	dobj	28	SENT_19	[p1l1844t2411r1909b2445],
35	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1844t2411r1909b2445],

1	Experimental	JJ	O	experimental	amod	2	SENT_20	[p1l1931t2411r2132b2445],
2	data	NNS	O	datum	nsubj	3	SENT_20	[p1l2151t2411r2215b2437],
3	show	VBP	O	show	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l2234t2411r2309b2437],

1	Introduction	NN	O	introduction	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l245t2325r490b2356],

1	Human	JJ	O	human	amod	3	SENT_22	[p1l281t2400r393b2426],
2	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	3	SENT_22	[p1l408t2400r565b2434],
3	syncytial	NN	O	syncytial	nsubj	11	SENT_22	[p1l579t2400r702b2434],
4	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	7	SENT_22	[p1l716t2400r785b2426],
5	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	7	SENT_22	[p1l801t2400r918b2434],
6	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	7	SENT_22	[p1l801t2400r918b2434],
7	)	NN	O	)	dep	3	SENT_22	[p1l801t2400r918b2434],
8	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	11	SENT_22	[p1l934t2400r953b2426],
9	a	DT	O	a	det	11	SENT_22	[p1l969t2409r984b2425],
10	leading	VBG	O	lead	amod	11	SENT_22	[p1l999t2400r1104b2434],
11	cause	NN	O	cause	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1118t2409r1195b2426],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1211t2400r1243b2426],
13	severe	JJ	O	severe	amod	16	SENT_22	[p1l243t2453r330b2470],
14	acute	JJ	O	acute	amod	16	SENT_22	[p1l342t2450r417b2470],
15	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	16	SENT_22	[p1l429t2444r585b2478],
16	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_of	11	SENT_22	[p1l595t2444r719b2470],
17	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l731t2444r758b2469],
18	childhood	NN	O	childhood	nn	20	SENT_22	[p1l769t2444r913b2470],
19	worldwide	JJ	O	worldwide	amod	20	SENT_22	[p1l922t2444r1073b2470],
20	[	NN	O	[	prep_in	16	SENT_22	[p1l1089t2444r1122b2478],
21	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	22	SENT_22	[p1l1089t2444r1122b2478],
22	]	NN	O	]	dep	20	SENT_22	[p1l1089t2444r1122b2478],
23	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1138t2444r1192b2470],
24	an	DT	O	a	det	26	SENT_22	[p1l1203t2453r1237b2469],
25	important	JJ	O	important	amod	26	SENT_22	[p1l243t2489r387b2523],
26	agent	NN	O	agent	conj_and	20	SENT_22	[p1l406t2495r484b2523],
27	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l503t2489r535b2515],
28	acute	JJ	O	acute	amod	30	SENT_22	[p1l548t2495r624b2515],
29	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	30	SENT_22	[p1l643t2489r800b2523],
30	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_of	26	SENT_22	[p1l817t2489r941b2515],
31	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l960t2489r987b2514],
32	the	DT	O	the	det	38	SENT_22	[p1l1006t2489r1049b2515],
33	elderly	JJ	O	elderly	amod	38	SENT_22	[p1l1069t2489r1166b2523],
34	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1184t2489r1238b2515],
35	immunocompromised	JJ	O	immunocompromised	amod	38	SENT_22	[p1l243t2533r564b2567],
36	[	NN	O	[	nn	38	SENT_22	[p1l578t2533r649b2567],
37	2,3	CD	NUMBER	2,3	num	38	SENT_22	[p1l578t2533r649b2567],
38	]	NN	O	]	prep_in	30	SENT_22	[p1l578t2533r649b2567],
39	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l578t2533r649b2567],

1	Initial	JJ	O	initial	amod	2	SENT_23	[p1l662t2533r746b2559],
2	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	20	SENT_23	[p1l757t2533r852b2559],
3	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l862t2533r924b2559],
4	monoclonal	JJ	O	monoclonal	amod	5	SENT_23	[p1l935t2533r1106b2559],
5	antibodies	NNS	O	antibody	prep_with	2	SENT_23	[p1l1117t2533r1237b2559, p1l243t2577r278b2603],
6	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l291t2583r317b2603],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_23	[p1l330t2577r374b2603],
8	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	9	SENT_23	[p1l387t2577r489b2603],
9	F	NN	O	f	prep_to	5	SENT_23	[p1l501t2577r520b2602],
10	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l532t2577r586b2603],
11	G	NN	O	g	nn	12	SENT_23	[p1l599t2577r625b2603],
12	proteins	NNS	O	protein	conj_and	5	SENT_23	[p1l637t2577r753b2611],
13	divided	VBN	O	divide	partmod	12	SENT_23	[p1l765t2577r871b2603],
14	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_23	[p1l883t2577r927b2603],
15	virus	NN	O	virus	dobj	13	SENT_23	[p1l939t2577r1008b2603],
16	into	IN	O	into	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1020t2577r1075b2603],
17	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	19	SENT_23	[p1l1088t2583r1139b2603],
18	major	JJ	O	major	amod	19	SENT_23	[p1l1152t2577r1238b2611],
19	groups	NNS	O	group	prep_into	13	SENT_23	[p1l243t2631r339b2656],
20	(	VBP	O	(	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l353t2622r385b2656],
21	A	NN	O	a	dobj	20	SENT_23	[p1l353t2622r385b2656],
22	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l397t2622r451b2648],
23	B	NN	O	b	conj_and	21	SENT_23	[p1l464t2622r492b2656],
24	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	23	SENT_23	[p1l464t2622r492b2656],
25	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	26	SENT_23	[p1l509t2622r581b2656],
26	4,5	CD	NUMBER	4,5	num	27	SENT_23	[p1l509t2622r581b2656],
27	]	NN	O	]	dep	23	SENT_23	[p1l509t2622r581b2656],
28	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l509t2622r581b2656],

1	Sequencing	NN	O	sequencing	nn	2	SENT_24	[p1l597t2622r764b2656],
2	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	9	SENT_24	[p1l776t2622r871b2648],
3	based	VBN	O	base	prep	2	SENT_24	[p1l883t2622r965b2648],
4	on	IN	O	on	pcomp	3	SENT_24	[p1l978t2631r1013b2648],
5	several	JJ	O	several	amod	7	SENT_24	[p1l1027t2622r1124b2648],
6	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	7	SENT_24	[p1l1136t2622r1238b2648],
7	genes	NNS	O	gene	pobj	4	SENT_24	[p1l243t2675r321b2700],
8	have	VBP	O	have	aux	9	SENT_24	[p1l330t2666r397b2692],
9	supported	VBN	O	support	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l408t2666r551b2700],
10	this	DT	O	this	det	12	SENT_24	[p1l560t2666r609b2692],
11	major	JJ	O	major	amod	12	SENT_24	[p1l618t2666r704b2700],
12	subdivision	NN	O	subdivision	dobj	9	SENT_24	[p1l713t2666r872b2692],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l882t2666r936b2692],
14	lead	VB	O	lead	conj_and	9	SENT_24	[p1l944t2666r1004b2692],
15	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1012t2672r1039b2692],
16	an	DT	O	a	det	19	SENT_24	[p1l1050t2675r1084b2691],
17	additional	JJ	O	additional	amod	19	SENT_24	[p1l1094t2666r1238b2692],
18	genotypic	JJ	O	genotypic	amod	19	SENT_24	[p1l243t2710r381b2744],
19	classiﬁcation	NN	O	classiﬁcation	prep_to	14	SENT_24	[p1l400t2710r587b2742],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l400t2710r587b2742],
21	mainly	RB	O	mainly	advmod	22	SENT_24	[p1l606t2710r705b2744],
22	based	VBN	O	base	partmod	19	SENT_24	[p1l722t2710r804b2736],
23	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l822t2719r858b2736],
24	the	DT	O	the	det	27	SENT_24	[p1l876t2710r919b2736],
25	G	NN	O	g	nn	27	SENT_24	[p1l939t2710r965b2736],
26	protein	NN	O	protein	nn	27	SENT_24	[p1l983t2710r1086b2744],
27	gene	NN	O	gene	prep_on	22	SENT_24	[p1l1104t2719r1178b2744],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1104t2719r1178b2744],
29	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1197t2710r1238b2736],
30	epidemiological	JJ	O	epidemiological	amod	31	SENT_24	[p1l243t2755r469b2789],
31	studies	NNS	O	study	prep_for	14	SENT_24	[p1l481t2755r576b2781],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l589t2755r620b2781],
33	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	prep_of	31	SENT_24	[p1l627t2755r735b2781],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l627t2755r735b2781],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_25	[p1l749t2755r807b2781],
2	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	nsubj	7	SENT_25	[p1l820t2761r962b2789],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l975t2755r1006b2781],
4	HRSVA	NN	O	hrsva	prep_of	2	SENT_25	[p1l1013t2755r1139b2781],
5	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1151t2755r1205b2781],
6	B	NN	O	b	prep_of	2	SENT_25	[p1l1217t2755r1237b2780],
7	show	VBP	O	show	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l243t2799r317b2825],
8	complex	JJ	O	complex	amod	10	SENT_25	[p1l336t2799r459b2833],
9	ﬂuctuating	VBG	O	ﬂuctuating	amod	10	SENT_25	[p1l478t2799r632b2833],
10	dynamics	NNS	O	dynamics	dobj	7	SENT_25	[p1l652t2799r795b2833],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l652t2799r795b2833],
12	since	IN	O	since	mark	15	SENT_25	[p1l817t2799r886b2825],
13	they	PRP	O	they	nsubj	15	SENT_25	[p1l907t2799r969b2833],
14	may	MD	O	may	aux	15	SENT_25	[p1l989t2808r1051b2833],
15	co-circulate	VB	O	co-circulate	advcl	7	SENT_25	[p1l1071t2799r1237b2825],
16	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l243t2843r339b2877],
17	a	DT	O	a	det	19	SENT_25	[p1l350t2852r365b2868],
18	given	VBN	O	give	amod	19	SENT_25	[p1l376t2843r453b2877],
19	season	NN	O	season	prep_during	15	SENT_25	[p1l465t2852r565b2875],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l465t2852r565b2875],
21	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l577t2843r639b2869],
22	one	CD	NUMBER	one	prep_with	15	SENT_25	[p1l652t2852r703b2869],
23	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l715t2852r745b2869],
24	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	26	SENT_25	[p1l757t2849r808b2869],
25	dominant	JJ	O	dominant	amod	26	SENT_25	[p1l820t2843r961b2869],
26	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	nsubj	34	SENT_25	[p1l972t2849r1114b2877],
27	that	WDT	O	that	nsubjpass	30	SENT_25	[p1l1126t2843r1182b2869],
28	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	30	SENT_25	[p1l1194t2852r1237b2869],
29	then	RB	O	then	advmod	30	SENT_25	[p1l243t2888r306b2914],
30	replaced	VBN	O	replace	rcmod	26	SENT_25	[p1l319t2888r441b2922],
31	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l453t2888r480b2913],
32	consecutive	JJ	O	consecutive	amod	33	SENT_25	[p1l493t2888r657b2914],
33	years	NNS	DURATION	year	prep_in	30	SENT_25	[p1l669t2897r743b2922],
34	[	VBP	O	[	advcl	7	SENT_25	[p1l759t2888r974b2922],
35	6,7,8,9,10,11	CD	NUMBER	6,7,8,9,10,11	number	36	SENT_25	[p1l759t2888r974b2922],
36	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	34	SENT_25	[p1l759t2888r974b2922],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l759t2888r974b2922],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_26	[p1l280t2933r340b2959],
2	G	NN	O	g	nn	3	SENT_26	[p1l357t2933r383b2959],
3	protein	NN	O	protein	nsubj	6	SENT_26	[p1l398t2933r505b2967],
4	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	6	SENT_26	[p1l521t2933r540b2959],
5	a	DT	O	a	det	6	SENT_26	[p1l556t2942r572b2958],
6	target	NN	O	target	ccomp	11	SENT_26	[p1l587t2939r673b2967],
7	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l687t2933r729b2959],
8	neutralizing	VBG	O	neutralize	amod	9	SENT_26	[p1l744t2933r921b2967],
9	antibodies	NNS	O	antibody	prep_for	6	SENT_26	[p1l936t2933r1095b2965],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l936t2933r1095b2965],
11	interacts	VBZ	O	interact	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1112t2933r1237b2959],
12	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l242t2977r306b3003],
13	host	NN	O	host	nn	15	SENT_26	[p1l320t2977r380b3003],
14	cell	NN	O	cell	nn	15	SENT_26	[p1l393t2977r441b3003],
15	receptors	NNS	O	receptor	prep_with	11	SENT_26	[p1l454t2983r589b3011],
16	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l603t2977r658b3003],
17	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	19	SENT_26	[p1l671t2977r691b3003],
18	highly	RB	O	highly	advmod	19	SENT_26	[p1l704t2977r796b3011],
19	variable	JJ	O	variable	conj_and	11	SENT_26	[p1l806t2977r925b3003],
20	[	NN	O	[	dobj	11	SENT_26	[p1l943t2977r1147b3011],
21	12,13,14,15	CD	NUMBER	12,13,14,15	num	22	SENT_26	[p1l943t2977r1147b3011],
22	]	NN	O	]	nsubj	19	SENT_26	[p1l943t2977r1147b3011],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l943t2977r1147b3011],

1	Most	JJS	O	most	amod	2	SENT_27	[p1l1162t2977r1238b3003],
2	changes	NNS	O	change	nsubj	8	SENT_27	[p1l243t3022r360b3056],
3	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l389t3022r417b3047],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_27	[p1l445t3022r490b3048],
5	G	NN	O	g	nn	6	SENT_27	[p1l520t3022r546b3048],
6	protein	NN	O	protein	prep_in	2	SENT_27	[p1l575t3022r681b3056],
7	are	VBP	O	be	cop	8	SENT_27	[p1l711t3031r755b3048],
8	localized	JJ	O	localized	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l784t3022r914b3048],
9	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l943t3028r970b3048],
10	an	DT	O	a	det	11	SENT_27	[p1l999t3031r1034b3047],
11	ectodomain	NN	O	ectodomain	prep_at	8	SENT_27	[p1l1063t3022r1237b3048],

1	Q	NNP	O	Q	nn	2	SENT_28	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
2	PLoS	NNP	O	PLoS	nsubj	3	SENT_28	[p1l344t3144r408b3167],
3	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l423t3143r567b3174],
4	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	5	SENT_28	[p1l587t3142r590b3175],
5	www	NN	O	www	dobj	3	SENT_28	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_29	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_29	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	nsubj	30	SENT_29	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
4	that	IN	O	that	complm	10	SENT_29	[p1l1314t2454r1372b2480],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_29	[p1l1385t2454r1429b2480],
6	G	NN	O	g	nn	7	SENT_29	[p1l1444t2454r1470b2480],
7	protein	NN	O	protein	nsubj	22	SENT_29	[p1l1483t2454r1590b2488],
8	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	10	SENT_29	[p1l1604t2454r1624b2480],
9	not	RB	O	not	neg	10	SENT_29	[p1l1637t2460r1685b2480],
10	required	VBN	O	require	dep	3	SENT_29	[p1l1699t2454r1825b2488],
11	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1837t2454r1879b2480],
12	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	13	SENT_29	[p1l1891t2454r1962b2480],
13	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_for	10	SENT_29	[p1l1976t2454r2104b2480],
14	in	FW	O	in	nn	15	SENT_29	[p1l2118t2454r2141b2480],
15	vitro	FW	O	vitro	advmod	10	SENT_29	[p1l2155t2454r2208b2480],
16	under	IN	O	under	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2221t2454r2309b2480],
17	appropriate	JJ	O	appropriate	amod	18	SENT_29	[p1l1314t2498r1487b2532],
18	conditions	NNS	O	condition	prep_under	10	SENT_29	[p1l1505t2498r1666b2530],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1505t2498r1666b2530],
20	but	CC	O	but	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1684t2498r1733b2524],
21	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	22	SENT_29	[p1l1750t2498r1769b2524],
22	necessary	JJ	O	necessary	conj_but	10	SENT_29	[p1l1787t2507r1928b2532],
23	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1943t2498r1985b2524],
24	efficient	JJ	O	efficient	amod	25	SENT_29	[p1l2002t2498r2118b2524],
25	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_for	22	SENT_29	[p1l2135t2498r2263b2524],
26	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2281t2498r2308b2523],
27	mice	NNS	O	mouse	prep_in	22	SENT_29	[p1l1314t2541r1383b2567],
28	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1404t2541r1459b2567],
29	humans	NNS	O	human	conj_and	27	SENT_29	[p1l1479t2541r1596b2567],
30	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1620t2541r1685b2575],
31	16	CD	NUMBER	16	num	32	SENT_29	[p1l1620t2541r1685b2575],
32	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	30	SENT_29	[p1l1620t2541r1685b2575],
33	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1620t2541r1685b2575],

1	It	PRP	O	it	nsubjpass	4	SENT_30	[p1l1707t2541r1730b2567],
2	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	4	SENT_30	[p1l1750t2541r1797b2567],
3	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	4	SENT_30	[p1l1818t2541r1888b2567],
4	argued	VBN	O	argue	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1909t2541r2011b2575],
5	that	IN	O	that	complm	13	SENT_30	[p1l2030t2541r2088b2567],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_30	[p1l2108t2541r2153b2567],
7	antigenic	JJ	O	antigenic	amod	8	SENT_30	[p1l2174t2541r2308b2575],
8	variability	NN	O	variability	nsubj	13	SENT_30	[p1l1313t2585r1463b2619],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1476t2585r1508b2611],
10	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	11	SENT_30	[p1l1516t2585r1619b2611],
11	strains	NNS	O	strain	prep_of	8	SENT_30	[p1l1632t2585r1725b2611],
12	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	13	SENT_30	[p1l1738t2585r1758b2611],
13	one	CD	NUMBER	one	ccomp	4	SENT_30	[p1l1772t2594r1824b2611],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1838t2585r1870b2611],
15	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_30	[p1l1877t2585r1922b2611],
16	key	JJ	O	key	amod	17	SENT_30	[p1l1935t2585r1985b2619],
17	features	NNS	O	feature	prep_of	13	SENT_30	[p1l1997t2585r2112b2611],
18	contributing	VBG	O	contribute	partmod	17	SENT_30	[p1l2125t2585r2309b2619],
19	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1314t2635r1341b2655],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_30	[p1l1355t2629r1400b2655],
21	ability	NN	O	ability	prep_to	18	SENT_30	[p1l1415t2629r1506b2663],
22	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1519t2629r1551b2655],
23	the	DT	O	the	det	24	SENT_30	[p1l1559t2629r1604b2655],
24	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	21	SENT_30	[p1l1617t2629r1688b2655],
25	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1702t2635r1730b2655],
26	re-infect	JJ	O	re-infect	amod	27	SENT_30	[p1l1744t2629r1867b2655],
27	people	NNS	O	people	prep_to	18	SENT_30	[p1l1879t2629r1977b2663],
28	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1991t2629r2047b2655],
29	cause	VB	O	cause	conj_and	4	SENT_30	[p1l2060t2638r2139b2655],
30	large-scale	JJ	O	large-scale	amod	32	SENT_30	[p1l2153t2629r2307b2663],
31	yearly	JJ	SET	yearly	amod	32	SENT_30	[p1l1313t2673r1404b2707],
32	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	nsubj	33	SENT_30	[p1l1418t2673r1560b2699],
33	[	VBP	O	[	ccomp	29	SENT_30	[p1l1579t2673r1644b2707],
34	17	CD	NUMBER	17	num	35	SENT_30	[p1l1579t2673r1644b2707],
35	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	33	SENT_30	[p1l1579t2673r1644b2707],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1579t2673r1644b2707],

1	Moreover	RB	O	moreover	advmod	6	SENT_31	[p1l1660t2673r1815b2705],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1660t2673r1815b2705],
3	several	JJ	O	several	amod	4	SENT_31	[p1l1832t2673r1932b2699],
4	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	6	SENT_31	[p1l1946t2673r2044b2699],
5	have	VBP	O	have	aux	6	SENT_31	[p1l2059t2673r2127b2699],
6	shown	VBN	O	show	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l2143t2673r2236b2699],
7	that	IN	O	that	complm	18	SENT_31	[p1l2251t2673r2309b2699],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_31	[p1l1314t2716r1359b2742],
9	C-terminal	JJ	O	c-terminal	amod	11	SENT_31	[p1l1371t2716r1534b2742],
10	hyper-variable	JJ	O	hyper-variable	amod	11	SENT_31	[p1l1545t2716r1760b2750],
11	region	NN	O	region	nsubj	20	SENT_31	[p1l1772t2716r1865b2750],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1877t2716r1909b2742],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_31	[p1l1914t2716r1959b2742],
14	surface	NN	O	surface	nn	16	SENT_31	[p1l1971t2716r2074b2742],
15	G	NN	O	g	nn	16	SENT_31	[p1l2086t2716r2112b2742],
16	glycoprotein	NN	O	glycoprotein	prep_of	11	SENT_31	[p1l2124t2716r2308b2750],
17	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	18	SENT_31	[p1l1314t2760r1334b2786],
18	immunogenic	JJ	O	immunogenic	ccomp	6	SENT_31	[p1l1345t2760r1549b2794],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1560t2760r1615b2786],
20	contains	VBZ	O	contain	conj_and	18	SENT_31	[p1l1626t2760r1748b2786],
21	multiple	JJ	O	multiple	amod	22	SENT_31	[p1l1759t2760r1879b2794],
22	epitopes	NNS	O	epitope	dobj	20	SENT_31	[p1l1891t2760r2012b2794],
23	that	WDT	O	that	nsubjpass	25	SENT_31	[p1l2023t2760r2081b2786],
24	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	25	SENT_31	[p1l2091t2769r2136b2786],
25	recognized	VBN	O	recognize	rcmod	22	SENT_31	[p1l2147t2760r2309b2794],
26	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1314t2803r1350b2837],
27	both	CC	O	both	preconj	30	SENT_31	[p1l1365t2803r1432b2829],
28	murine	JJ	O	murine	amod	30	SENT_31	[p1l1447t2803r1554b2829],
29	monoclonal	JJ	O	monoclonal	amod	30	SENT_31	[p1l1570t2803r1746b2829],
30	antibodies	NNS	O	antibody	agent	25	SENT_31	[p1l1762t2803r1912b2829],
31	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1929t2803r1984b2829],
32	human	JJ	O	human	amod	34	SENT_31	[p1l1999t2803r2104b2829],
33	convalescent	NN	O	convalescent	nn	34	SENT_31	[p1l2120t2803r2309b2829],
34	sera	NN	O	serum	agent	25	SENT_31	[p1l1314t2856r1372b2873],
35	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	36	SENT_31	[p1l1388t2847r1453b2881],
36	18	CD	NUMBER	18	num	37	SENT_31	[p1l1388t2847r1453b2881],
37	]	NN	O	]	dobj	18	SENT_31	[p1l1388t2847r1453b2881],
38	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1388t2847r1453b2881],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1467t2847r1498b2872],
2	addition	NN	O	addition	prep_in	15	SENT_32	[p1l1510t2847r1641b2879],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1510t2847r1641b2879],
4	the	DT	O	the	nsubj	15	SENT_32	[p1l1654t2847r1699b2873],
5	deduced	VBN	O	deduce	partmod	4	SENT_32	[p1l1712t2847r1836b2873],
6	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	8	SENT_32	[p1l1849t2847r1941b2873],
7	acid	NN	O	acid	nn	8	SENT_32	[p1l1954t2847r2014b2873],
8	sequences	NNS	O	sequence	dobj	5	SENT_32	[p1l2026t2856r2172b2881],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l2185t2847r2217b2873],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_32	[p1l2224t2847r2269b2873],
11	G	NN	O	g	nn	12	SENT_32	[p1l2282t2847r2308b2873],
12	protein	NN	O	protein	prep_of	8	SENT_32	[p1l1313t2891r1420b2925],
13	are	VBP	O	be	cop	15	SENT_32	[p1l1452t2900r1497b2917],
14	highly	RB	O	highly	advmod	15	SENT_32	[p1l1529t2891r1621b2925],
15	divergent	JJ	O	divergent	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1651t2891r1798b2925],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1651t2891r1798b2925],
17	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1829t2891r1894b2917],
18	a	DT	O	a	det	20	SENT_32	[p1l1926t2900r1942b2916],
19	sequence	NN	O	sequence	nn	20	SENT_32	[p1l1973t2900r2106b2925],
20	identity	NN	O	identity	prep_with	15	SENT_32	[p1l2139t2891r2251b2925],
21	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l2282t2891r2314b2917],
22	approximately	RB	O	approximately	quantmod	23	SENT_32	[p1l1314t2934r1530b2968],
23	53	CD	PERCENT	53	num	24	SENT_32	[p1l1541t2934r1606b2960],
24	%	NN	PERCENT	%	prep_of	20	SENT_32	[p1l1541t2934r1606b2960],
25	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1620t2934r1742b2960],
26	HRSVA	NNP	O	HRSVA	prep_between	24	SENT_32	[p1l1755t2934r1883b2960],
27	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1894t2934r1949b2960],
28	B	NNP	O	B	prep_between	24	SENT_32	[p1l1960t2934r1989b2966],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1960t2934r1989b2966],
30	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l2003t2934r2058b2960],
31	20	CD	PERCENT	20	number	32	SENT_32	[p1l2070t2934r2134b2961],
32	%	NN	PERCENT	%	amod	33	SENT_32	[p1l2070t2934r2134b2961],
33	divergence	NN	O	divergence	prep_of	20	SENT_32	[p1l2148t2934r2307b2968],
34	within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1313t2978r1406b3004],
35	the	DT	O	the	det	38	SENT_32	[p1l1418t2978r1463b3004],
36	same	JJ	O	same	amod	38	SENT_32	[p1l1475t2987r1549b3004],
37	antigenic	JJ	O	antigenic	amod	38	SENT_32	[p1l1561t2978r1695b3012],
38	group	NN	O	group	prep_within	33	SENT_32	[p1l1707t2987r1793b3012],
39	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	40	SENT_32	[p1l1809t2978r1920b3012],
40	14,19	CD	NUMBER	14,19	num	41	SENT_32	[p1l1809t2978r1920b3012],
41	]	NN	O	]	dep	33	SENT_32	[p1l1809t2978r1920b3012],
42	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1809t2978r1920b3012],

1	Despite	IN	O	despite	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1934t2978r2044b3012],
2	this	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_33	[p1l2056t2978r2107b3004],
3	diversity	NN	O	diversity	prep_despite	16	SENT_33	[p1l2119t2978r2250b3012],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l2119t2978r2250b3012],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_33	[p1l2263t2978r2308b3004],
6	nature	NN	O	nature	nsubj	16	SENT_33	[p1l1314t3028r1409b3048],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1423t3022r1455b3048],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_33	[p1l1463t3022r1508b3048],
9	selection	NN	O	selection	nn	10	SENT_33	[p1l1522t3022r1648b3048],
10	pressures	NNS	O	pressure	prep_of	6	SENT_33	[p1l1661t3031r1795b3056],
11	acting	VBG	O	act	partmod	10	SENT_33	[p1l1809t3022r1899b3056],
12	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1911t3031r1948b3048],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_33	[p1l1961t3022r2005b3048],
14	G	NN	O	g	nn	15	SENT_33	[p1l2020t3022r2046b3048],
15	protein	NN	O	protein	prep_on	11	SENT_33	[p1l2058t3022r2165b3056],
16	have	VBP	O	have	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l2178t3022r2247b3048],
17	not	RB	O	not	neg	16	SENT_33	[p1l2261t3028r2309b3048],

1	Author	NN	O	author	nn	2	SENT_34	[p2l279t269r418b300],
2	Summary	NN	O	summary	_	0	SENT_34	[p2l435t270r623b308],

1	As	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l279t344r314b369],
2	part	NN	O	part	prep_as	13	SENT_35	[p2l330t347r391b376],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l406t342r437b369],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_35	[p2l448t342r498b369],
5	Viral	JJ	ORGANIZATION	viral	amod	10	SENT_35	[p2l512t342r577b369],
6	Genetic	JJ	ORGANIZATION	genetic	amod	10	SENT_35	[p2l593t343r711b369],
7	Diversity	NN	ORGANIZATION	diversity	nn	10	SENT_35	[p2l727t343r860b377],
8	Network	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Network	nn	10	SENT_35	[p2l875t342r1006b369],
9	o/GDN	NNP	O	o/GDN	nn	10	SENT_35	[p2l1020t343r1140b374],
10	)	NNP	O	)	prep_of	2	SENT_35	[p2l1020t343r1140b374],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l1020t343r1140b374],
12	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	13	SENT_35	[p2l1154t350r1198b369],
13	sequenced	VBD	O	sequence	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l279t384r446b418],
14	the	DT	O	the	det	20	SENT_35	[p2l473t384r523b411],
15	second	JJ	ORDINAL	second	amod	20	SENT_35	[p2l550t384r658b411],
16	variable	JJ	O	variable	amod	20	SENT_35	[p2l685t384r806b411],
17	region	NN	O	region	nn	20	SENT_35	[p2l834t385r930b419],
18	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	20	SENT_35	[p2l959t385r1019b416],
19	G2	NN	O	g2	nn	20	SENT_35	[p2l959t385r1019b416],
20	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	45	SENT_35	[p2l959t385r1019b416],
21	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l1046t384r1077b411],
22	the	DT	O	the	det	24	SENT_35	[p2l1101t384r1150b411],
23	G	NN	O	g	nn	24	SENT_35	[p2l1176t385r1197b411],
24	protein	NN	O	protein	prep_of	20	SENT_35	[p2l280t426r390b459],
25	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l403t425r434b452],
26	human	JJ	O	human	amod	29	SENT_35	[p2l445t425r550b452],
27	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	29	SENT_35	[p2l564t426r729b460],
28	syncytial	NN	O	syncytial	nn	29	SENT_35	[p2l740t425r871b460],
29	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	24	SENT_35	[p2l883t426r955b452],
30	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	33	SENT_35	[p2l967t426r1068b457],
31	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	33	SENT_35	[p2l967t426r1068b457],
32	)	NN	O	)	nn	33	SENT_35	[p2l967t426r1068b457],
33	A	NN	O	a	dep	29	SENT_35	[p2l1080t427r1101b452],
34	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l1112t425r1168b452],
35	B	NN	O	b	conj_and	29	SENT_35	[p2l1182t427r1198b452],
36	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l278t467r350b494],
37	568	CD	NUMBER	568	num	38	SENT_35	[p2l371t469r425b494],
38	patients	NNS	O	patient	prep_from	35	SENT_35	[p2l446t468r569b501],
39	sampled	VBN	O	sample	partmod	38	SENT_35	[p2l588t467r718b501],
40	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l739t467r838b502],
41	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	44	SENT_35	[p2l862t470r889b494],
42	consecutive	JJ	O	consecutive	amod	44	SENT_35	[p2l914t468r1097b494],
43	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	44	SENT_35	[p2l1118t468r1199b494],
44	seasons	NNS	O	season	prep_during	39	SENT_35	[p2l279t516r399b535],
45	(	VBP	O	(	ccomp	13	SENT_35	[p2l420t509r607b540],
46	1995-2005	CD	DATE	1995-2005	num	47	SENT_35	[p2l420t509r607b540],
47	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dobj	45	SENT_35	[p2l420t509r607b540],
48	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l629t509r653b535],
49	the	DT	O	the	det	50	SENT_35	[p2l673t508r723b535],
50	state	NN	O	state	prep_in	45	SENT_35	[p2l742t513r816b535],
51	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l836t508r867b535],
52	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	nn	53	SENT_35	[p2l884t509r938b535],
53	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	prep_of	50	SENT_35	[p2l959t508r1051b540],
54	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l959t508r1051b540],
55	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	appos	53	SENT_35	[p2l1071t508r1158b535],
56	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_35	[p2l1071t508r1158b535],

1	A	DT	O	a	det	2	SENT_36	[p2l1177t510r1199b535],
2	total	NN	O	total	nsubjpass	22	SENT_36	[p2l279t550r348b577],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l363t550r395b577],
4	933	CD	NUMBER	933	num	5	SENT_36	[p2l406t552r460b577],
5	HRSVA	NN	O	hrsva	prep_of	2	SENT_36	[p2l476t551r579b577],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l593t550r649b577],
7	673	CD	NUMBER	673	num	9	SENT_36	[p2l664t552r718b577],
8	HRSB	NN	O	hrsb	nn	9	SENT_36	[p2l734t551r813b577],
9	time	NN	O	time	conj_and	5	SENT_36	[p2l827t550r1043b584],
10	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	12	SENT_36	[p2l827t550r1043b584],
11	stamped	JJ	O	stamped	amod	12	SENT_36	[p2l827t550r1043b584],
12	sequences	NNS	O	sequence	dep	9	SENT_36	[p2l1059t558r1199b584, p2l279t599r318b623],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l1059t558r1199b584, p2l279t599r318b623],
14	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l336t591r478b626],
15	those	DT	O	those	prep_including	2	SENT_36	[p2l495t591r581b618],
16	sampled	VBN	O	sample	partmod	15	SENT_36	[p2l598t591r727b625],
17	here	RB	O	here	advmod	16	SENT_36	[p2l747t591r813b618],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l830t591r886b618],
19	globally	RB	O	globally	conj_and	17	SENT_36	[p2l905t591r1034b626],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l905t591r1034b626],
21	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	22	SENT_36	[p2l1050t599r1109b618],
22	used	VBN	O	use	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l1127t591r1197b618],
23	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l278t633r321b660],
24	phylogenetic	JJ	O	phylogenetic	amod	25	SENT_36	[p2l342t633r544b668],
25	inference	NN	O	inference	prep_for	22	SENT_36	[p2l565t633r707b660],
26	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l727t633r783b660],
27	the	DT	O	the	det	28	SENT_36	[p2l803t633r853b660],
28	analysis	NN	O	analysis	conj_and	25	SENT_36	[p2l873t633r991b668],
29	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l1012t633r1044b660],
30	selection	NN	O	selection	nn	31	SENT_36	[p2l1061t633r1197b660],
31	pressures	NNS	O	pressure	prep_of	28	SENT_36	[p2l280t682r432b708],
32	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_36	[p2l280t682r432b708],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_37	[p2l444t676r492b701],
2	identified	VBD	O	identify	_	0	SENT_37	[p2l505t674r650b701],
3	18	CD	NUMBER	18	num	6	SENT_37	[p2l665t676r699b701],
4	positively	RB	O	positively	advmod	6	SENT_37	[p2l712t674r858b709],
5	selected	VBN	O	select	amod	6	SENT_37	[p2l869t674r995b701],
6	sites	NNS	O	site	nsubj	19	SENT_37	[p2l1008t675r1075b701],
7	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_37	[p2l1088t675r1112b701],
8	both	DT	O	both	det	9	SENT_37	[p2l1127t674r1197b701],
9	HRSVA	NN	O	hrsva	prep_in	6	SENT_37	[p2l281t717r384b743],
10	(	CD	NUMBER	(	number	11	SENT_37	[p2l397t717r423b748],
11	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	13	SENT_37	[p2l397t717r423b748],
12	sites	NNS	O	site	nn	13	SENT_37	[p2l435t717r511b748],
13	)	NN	O	)	dep	9	SENT_37	[p2l435t717r511b748],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_37	[p2l523t716r579b743],
15	HRSVB	NN	O	hrsvb	conj_and	9	SENT_37	[p2l594t717r694b743],
16	(	CD	NUMBER	(	number	17	SENT_37	[p2l707t717r733b748],
17	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	18	SENT_37	[p2l707t717r733b748],
18	sites	NNS	O	site	dep	15	SENT_37	[p2l745t717r821b748],
19	)	VBP	O	)	ccomp	2	SENT_37	[p2l745t717r821b748],
20	that	IN	O	that	complm	21	SENT_37	[p2l833t716r895b743],
21	tended	VBD	O	tend	ccomp	19	SENT_37	[p2l906t716r1015b743],
22	to	TO	O	to	aux	23	SENT_37	[p2l1028t721r1059b743],
23	revert	VB	O	revert	xcomp	21	SENT_37	[p2l1072t721r1160b743],
24	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_37	[p2l1172t717r1197b743],
25	time	NN	O	time	prep_in	23	SENT_37	[p2l279t758r348b784],
26	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_37	[p2l365t762r396b784],
27	their	PRP$	O	they	poss	30	SENT_37	[p2l414t757r485b784],
28	previous	JJ	O	previous	amod	30	SENT_37	[p2l503t758r634b791],
29	codon	NN	O	codon	nn	30	SENT_37	[p2l653t757r748b784],
30	state	NN	O	state	prep_to	25	SENT_37	[p2l768t761r841b784],
31	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dobj	23	SENT_37	[p2l861t758r910b789],
32	i.e.	FW	O	i.e.	nsubj	33	SENT_37	[p2l861t758r910b789],
33	exhibited	VBD	O	exhibit	rcmod	31	SENT_37	[p2l928t757r1072b784],
34	a	DT	O	a	det	35	SENT_37	[p2l1091t765r1106b784],
35	’’	NN	O	’’	nsubj	36	SENT_37	[p2l1125t757r1199b791],
36	flip	VB	O	flip	ccomp	33	SENT_37	[p2l1125t757r1199b791],
37	—	RB	O	—	advmod	36	SENT_37	[p2l1125t757r1199b791],
38	flop	JJ	O	flop	amod	41	SENT_37	[p2l278t799r354b833],
39	’’	NN	O	’’	nn	41	SENT_37	[p2l278t799r354b833],
40	pattern	NN	O	pattern	nn	41	SENT_37	[p2l370t800r500b833],
41	)	NN	O	)	dep	21	SENT_37	[p2l370t800r500b833],
42	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_37	[p2l370t800r500b833],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_38	[p2l514t801r562b826],
2	argue	VBP	O	argue	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l577t807r664b834],
3	that	IN	O	that	complm	15	SENT_38	[p2l678t799r740b826],
4	these	DT	O	these	det	7	SENT_38	[p2l754t799r837b826],
5	common	JJ	O	common	amod	7	SENT_38	[p2l852t807r989b826],
6	evolutionary	JJ	O	evolutionary	amod	7	SENT_38	[p2l1005t799r1199b834],
7	reversals	NNS	O	reversal	nsubj	15	SENT_38	[p2l280t840r412b867],
8	are	VBP	O	be	cop	15	SENT_38	[p2l440t848r486b867],
9	indicative	JJ	O	indicative	acomp	15	SENT_38	[p2l514t840r662b867],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l689t840r721b867],
11	frequent	JJ	O	frequent	amod	13	SENT_38	[p2l745t840r878b874],
12	positive	JJ	O	positive	amod	13	SENT_38	[p2l907t841r1026b874],
13	selection	NN	O	selection	prep_of	15	SENT_38	[p2l1053t840r1198b872],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l1053t840r1198b872],
15	reflecting	VBG	O	reflect	ccomp	2	SENT_38	[p2l280t882r424b917],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	19	SENT_38	[p2l449t882r499b909],
17	changing	VBG	O	change	amod	19	SENT_38	[p2l524t882r667b917],
18	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	19	SENT_38	[p2l694t883r822b909],
19	status	NN	O	status	dobj	15	SENT_38	[p2l847t886r937b909],
20	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l962t882r994b909],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	23	SENT_38	[p2l1015t882r1065b909],
22	human	JJ	O	human	amod	23	SENT_38	[p2l1091t882r1197b909],
23	population	NN	O	population	prep_of	19	SENT_38	[p2l280t923r457b957],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l280t923r457b957],
25	coupled	VBN	O	couple	partmod	23	SENT_38	[p2l470t923r594b957],
26	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l608t923r674b950],
27	a	DT	O	a	det	29	SENT_38	[p2l688t931r703b950],
28	limited	JJ	O	limited	amod	29	SENT_38	[p2l718t923r822b950],
29	repertoire	NN	O	repertoire	prep_with	25	SENT_38	[p2l837t924r988b957],
30	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l1001t923r1033b950],
31	functional	JJ	O	functional	amod	32	SENT_38	[p2l1042t923r1197b950],
32	viable	JJ	O	viable	amod	34	SENT_38	[p2l278t965r370b992],
33	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	34	SENT_38	[p2l386t966r482b992],
34	acids	NNS	O	acid	prep_of	29	SENT_38	[p2l499t965r575b992],
35	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l592t970r620b992],
36	specific	JJ	O	specific	amod	37	SENT_38	[p2l636t965r750b999],
37	sites	NNS	O	site	prep_at	25	SENT_38	[p2l767t966r841b992],
38	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_38	[p2l767t966r841b992],

1	This	DT	O	this	det	2	SENT_39	[p2l856t965r917b992],
2	information	NN	O	information	nsubj	3	SENT_39	[p2l935t965r1114b992],
3	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l1133t966r1153b992],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l1169t965r1201b992],
5	particular	JJ	O	particular	amod	6	SENT_39	[p2l280t1006r426b1040],
6	importance	NN	O	importance	prep_of	3	SENT_39	[p2l452t1007r629b1040],
7	since	IN	O	since	mark	18	SENT_39	[p2l655t1007r732b1033],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_39	[p2l758t1006r807b1033],
9	ectodomain	NN	O	ectodomain	nsubj	18	SENT_39	[p2l834t1006r1018b1033],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l1046t1006r1078b1033],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_39	[p2l1101t1006r1150b1033],
12	G	NN	O	g	nn	13	SENT_39	[p2l1176t1007r1197b1033],
13	protein	NN	O	protein	prep_of	9	SENT_39	[p2l280t1049r390b1082],
14	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	18	SENT_39	[p2l411t1049r431b1075],
15	also	RB	O	also	advmod	18	SENT_39	[p2l449t1048r509b1075],
16	a	DT	O	a	det	18	SENT_39	[p2l528t1056r542b1075],
17	target	NN	O	target	nn	18	SENT_39	[p2l561t1053r654b1083],
18	site	NN	O	site	dep	3	SENT_39	[p2l673t1049r725b1075],
19	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l745t1049r769b1075],
20	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	prep_in	18	SENT_39	[p2l788t1049r918b1075],
21	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	25	SENT_39	[p2l937t1048r999b1075],
22	have	VBP	O	have	aux	25	SENT_39	[p2l1018t1048r1089b1075],
23	so	RB	O	so	advmod	24	SENT_39	[p2l1108t1056r1141b1075],
24	far	RB	O	far	advmod	25	SENT_39	[p2l1159t1048r1199b1075],
25	proven	VBN	O	prove	rcmod	20	SENT_39	[p2l280t1097r387b1123],
26	unsuccessful	JJ	O	unsuccessful	acomp	25	SENT_39	[p2l407t1089r601b1116],
27	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l620t1089r676b1116],
28	because	IN	O	because	mark	30	SENT_39	[p2l696t1089r821b1116],
29	it	PRP	O	it	nsubj	30	SENT_39	[p2l840t1090r858b1116],
30	constitutes	VBZ	O	constitute	conj_and	18	SENT_39	[p2l875t1090r1045b1116],
31	a	DT	O	a	det	33	SENT_39	[p2l1063t1097r1078b1116],
32	significant	JJ	O	significant	amod	33	SENT_39	[p2l1097t1089r1199b1124, p2l279t1135r345b1158],
33	step	NN	O	step	dobj	30	SENT_39	[p2l373t1136r438b1165],
34	towards	IN	O	towards	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l465t1131r590b1158],
35	describing	VBG	O	describe	prepc_towards	30	SENT_39	[p2l619t1131r778b1166],
36	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l808t1131r864b1158],
37	understanding	VBG	O	understand	prepc_towards	30	SENT_39	[p2l894t1131r1119b1166],
38	the	DT	O	the	det	42	SENT_39	[p2l1148t1131r1198b1158],
39	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	42	SENT_39	[p2l280t1173r527b1206],
40	—	NN	O	—	nn	42	SENT_39	[p2l280t1173r527b1206],
41	escape	NN	O	escape	nn	42	SENT_39	[p2l280t1173r527b1206],
42	repertoire	NN	O	repertoire	dobj	35	SENT_39	[p2l542t1173r693b1206],
43	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l707t1172r738b1199],
44	this	DT	O	this	det	47	SENT_39	[p2l748t1172r803b1199],
45	major	JJ	O	major	amod	47	SENT_39	[p2l818t1173r906b1207],
46	human	JJ	O	human	amod	47	SENT_39	[p2l919t1172r1025b1199],
47	pathogen	NN	O	pathogen	prep_of	42	SENT_39	[p2l1041t1172r1198b1207],
48	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l1041t1172r1198b1207],

1	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	2	SENT_40	[p2l243t1346r313b1372],
2	explored	VBN	O	explore	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l328t1346r457b1380],
3	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l470t1346r498b1371],
4	detail	NN	O	detail	prep_in	2	SENT_40	[p2l512t1346r601b1378],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l512t1346r601b1378],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l616t1346r672b1372],
7	particularly	RB	O	particularly	advmod	2	SENT_40	[p2l684t1346r856b1380],
8	using	VBG	O	use	conj_and	2	SENT_40	[p2l869t1346r948b1380],
9	sequence	NN	O	sequence	nn	10	SENT_40	[p2l961t1355r1094b1380],
10	data	NNS	O	datum	nsubj	11	SENT_40	[p2l1109t1346r1173b1372],
11	sets	VBZ	O	set	ccomp	8	SENT_40	[p2l1187t1352r1237b1372],
12	that	DT	O	that	nsubj	13	SENT_40	[p2l243t1390r301b1416],
13	are	VBP	O	be	ccomp	11	SENT_40	[p2l314t1399r359b1416],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l373t1390r405b1416],
15	sufﬁcient	JJ	O	sufﬁcient	amod	16	SENT_40	[p2l414t1390r546b1416],
16	size	NN	O	size	prep_of	13	SENT_40	[p2l559t1390r611b1416],
17	to	TO	O	to	aux	18	SENT_40	[p2l625t1396r652b1416],
18	reveal	VB	O	reveal	conj_and	18	SENT_40	[p2l666t1390r754b1416],
19	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_40	[p2l767t1390r812b1416],
20	intricate	JJ	O	intricate	amod	21	SENT_40	[p2l826t1390r947b1416],
21	nature	NN	O	nature	dobj	18	SENT_40	[p2l962t1396r1057b1416],
22	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l1071t1390r1103b1416],
23	adaptive	JJ	O	adaptive	amod	24	SENT_40	[p2l1112t1390r1237b1424],
24	evolution	NN	O	evolution	prep_of	18	SENT_40	[p2l243t1434r380b1460],
25	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l395t1434r450b1460],
26	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l462t1434r526b1460],
27	restricted	JJ	O	restricted	amod	31	SENT_40	[p2l540t1434r678b1460],
28	spatial	JJ	O	spatial	amod	31	SENT_40	[p2l691t1434r785b1468],
29	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l799t1434r855b1460],
30	temporal	JJ	O	temporal	conj_and	28	SENT_40	[p2l868t1434r1002b1468],
31	sampling	NN	O	sampling	prep_with	18	SENT_40	[p2l1016t1434r1156b1468],
32	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l1016t1434r1156b1468],

1	This	DT	O	this	det	2	SENT_41	[p2l1171t1434r1237b1460],
2	information	NN	O	information	nsubj	3	SENT_41	[p2l243t1477r419b1503],
3	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l436t1477r456b1503],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l474t1477r506b1503],
5	particular	JJ	O	particular	amod	6	SENT_41	[p2l517t1477r662b1511],
6	importance	NN	O	importance	prep_of	3	SENT_41	[p2l680t1477r848b1511],
7	since	IN	O	since	mark	17	SENT_41	[p2l867t1477r938b1503],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_41	[p2l956t1477r1000b1503],
9	ectodomain	NN	O	ectodomain	nsubj	17	SENT_41	[p2l1019t1477r1193b1503],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l1211t1477r1243b1503],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_41	[p2l243t1521r287b1547],
12	G-protein	NN	O	g-protein	prep_of	9	SENT_41	[p2l303t1521r448b1555],
13	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	17	SENT_41	[p2l463t1521r482b1547],
14	also	RB	O	also	advmod	17	SENT_41	[p2l496t1521r551b1547],
15	a	DT	O	a	det	17	SENT_41	[p2l566t1530r582b1546],
16	target	NN	O	target	nn	17	SENT_41	[p2l595t1527r680b1555],
17	site	NN	O	site	advcl	3	SENT_41	[p2l694t1521r740b1547],
18	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l755t1521r782b1546],
19	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	prep_in	17	SENT_41	[p2l794t1521r918b1547],
20	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	24	SENT_41	[p2l932t1521r990b1547],
21	have	VBP	O	have	aux	24	SENT_41	[p2l1003t1521r1071b1547],
22	so	RB	O	so	advmod	23	SENT_41	[p2l1086t1530r1115b1547],
23	far	RB	O	far	advmod	24	SENT_41	[p2l1128t1521r1169b1546],
24	met	VBN	O	meet	rcmod	19	SENT_41	[p2l1182t1527r1238b1547],
25	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l242t1564r306b1590],
26	little	JJ	O	little	amod	27	SENT_41	[p2l320t1564r383b1590],
27	success	NN	O	success	prep_with	24	SENT_41	[p2l397t1573r507b1590],
28	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l397t1573r507b1590],

1	To	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l522t1564r565b1590],
2	addresses	NNS	O	address	prep_to	7	SENT_42	[p2l579t1564r716b1590],
3	these	DT	O	these	det	5	SENT_42	[p2l730t1564r803b1590],
4	key	JJ	O	key	amod	5	SENT_42	[p2l817t1564r867b1598],
5	issues	NNS	O	issue	dep	2	SENT_42	[p2l880t1564r960b1590],
6	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	7	SENT_42	[p2l972t1573r1013b1590],
7	undertook	VBD	O	undertake	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l1026t1564r1180b1590],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_42	[p2l1192t1564r1237b1590],
9	largest	JJS	O	largest	amod	10	SENT_42	[p2l243t1608r339b1642],
10	analysis	NN	O	analysis	dobj	7	SENT_42	[p2l373t1608r486b1642],
11	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l521t1608r553b1634],
12	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	13	SENT_42	[p2l582t1608r685b1634],
13	sequences	NNS	O	sequence	prep_of	10	SENT_42	[p2l720t1617r866b1642],
14	undertaken	VBN	O	undertake	partmod	13	SENT_42	[p2l900t1608r1069b1634],
15	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l1103t1614r1131b1634],
16	date	NN	O	date	prep_to	14	SENT_42	[p2l1166t1608r1236b1640],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l1166t1608r1236b1640],
18	comprising	VBG	O	comprise	dep	7	SENT_42	[p2l243t1652r408b1686],
19	both	CC	O	both	prep	18	SENT_42	[p2l429t1652r496b1678],
20	HRSVA	NN	O	hrsva	dep	19	SENT_42	[p2l519t1652r648b1678],
21	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l669t1652r724b1678],
22	HRSVB	NN	O	hrsvb	dep	19	SENT_42	[p2l746t1652r880b1684],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l746t1652r880b1684],
24	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l903t1652r958b1678],
25	utilizing	VBG	O	utilize	dep	7	SENT_42	[p2l980t1652r1100b1686],
26	detailed	JJ	O	detailed	amod	28	SENT_42	[p2l1121t1652r1238b1678],
27	temporal	JJ	O	temporal	amod	28	SENT_42	[p2l243t1695r377b1729],
28	information	NN	O	information	dobj	25	SENT_42	[p2l391t1695r574b1721],
29	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l391t1695r574b1721],

1	Methods	NNS	O	method	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l244t1786r416b1817],

1	Respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	2	SENT_44	[p2l245t1863r438b1901],
2	samples	NNS	O	sample	nsubjpass	10	SENT_44	[p2l454t1862r592b1900],
3	A	DT	O	a	det	4	SENT_44	[p2l279t1912r305b1937],
4	total	NN	O	total	dep	2	SENT_44	[p2l322t1912r387b1938],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l406t1912r438b1938],
6	3,496	CD	NUMBER	3,496	num	8	SENT_44	[p2l452t1912r532b1944],
7	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	8	SENT_44	[p2l551t1912r713b1946],
8	samples	NNS	O	sample	prep_of	2	SENT_44	[p2l731t1912r845b1946],
9	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	10	SENT_44	[p2l862t1921r933b1938],
10	used	VBN	O	use	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l951t1912r1018b1938],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l1036t1912r1063b1937],
12	this	DT	O	this	det	13	SENT_44	[p2l1081t1912r1132b1938],
13	study	NN	O	study	prep_in	10	SENT_44	[p2l1151t1912r1235b1946],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l1151t1912r1235b1946],

1	Nasopharyngeal	JJ	MISC	nasopharyngeal	amod	2	SENT_45	[p2l243t1956r485b1990],
2	aspirates	NNS	O	aspirate	nsubj	12	SENT_45	[p2l499t1956r626b1990],
3	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l639t1956r694b1982],
4	nasal	JJ	O	nasal	amod	5	SENT_45	[p2l707t1956r782b1982],
5	swabs	NNS	O	swab	conj_and	2	SENT_45	[p2l795t1956r879b1982],
6	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l892t1956r963b1982],
7	2,256	CD	NUMBER	2,256	num	8	SENT_45	[p2l977t1956r1058b1988],
8	infants	NNS	O	infant	prep_from	5	SENT_45	[p2l1071t1956r1169b1982],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l1183t1956r1238b1982],
10	young	JJ	O	young	amod	11	SENT_45	[p2l242t2008r335b2033],
11	children	NNS	O	child	prep_from	5	SENT_45	[p2l348t1999r470b2025],
12	(	VBP	O	(	ccomp	42	SENT_45	[p2l485t1999r506b2033],
13	1	CD	DURATION	1	dobj	12	SENT_45	[p2l485t1999r506b2033],
14	week	NN	NUMBER	week	tmod	12	SENT_45	[p2l523t1999r599b2025],
15	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l612t2005r640b2025],
16	5	CD	DURATION	5	num	17	SENT_45	[p2l655t2000r670b2025],
17	years	NNS	NUMBER	year	prep_to	12	SENT_45	[p2l685t2008r761b2033],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l776t1999r808b2025],
19	age	NN	O	age	prep_of	17	SENT_45	[p2l817t1999r875b2033],
20	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	19	SENT_45	[p2l817t1999r875b2033],
21	hospitalized	VBN	O	hospitalize	partmod	19	SENT_45	[p2l890t1999r1067b2033],
22	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l1080t1999r1144b2025],
23	acute	JJ	O	acute	amod	24	SENT_45	[p2l1159t2005r1237b2025],
24	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	26	SENT_45	[p2l243t2043r405b2077],
25	lower	JJR	O	lower	amod	26	SENT_45	[p2l428t2043r510b2069],
26	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_with	21	SENT_45	[p2l534t2043r662b2069],
27	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	28	SENT_45	[p2l688t2043r768b2077],
28	ARI	NNP	O	ARI	dep	26	SENT_45	[p2l688t2043r768b2077],
29	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	28	SENT_45	[p2l688t2043r768b2077],
30	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l794t2049r821b2069],
31	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	prep_at	28	SENT_45	[p2l845t2043r999b2077],
32	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l1023t2043r1055b2069],
33	Sao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sao	nn	35	SENT_45	[p2l1075t2043r1129b2069],
34	Paulo	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Paulo	nn	35	SENT_45	[p2l1154t2043r1237b2069],
35	Hospital	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hospital	prep_of	31	SENT_45	[p2l243t2087r376b2121],
36	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l243t2087r376b2121],
37	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	nn	38	SENT_45	[p2l398t2087r452b2113],
38	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	appos	35	SENT_45	[p2l472t2087r564b2119],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l472t2087r564b2119],
40	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	nsubjpass	42	SENT_45	[p2l585t2087r671b2112],
41	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	42	SENT_45	[p2l690t2096r760b2113],
42	used	VBN	O	use	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l780t2087r854b2113],
43	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l780t2087r854b2113],

1	Samples	NNS	O	sample	nsubjpass	3	SENT_46	[p2l877t2087r998b2121],
2	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	3	SENT_46	[p2l1017t2096r1087b2113],
3	collected	VBN	O	collect	dep	9	SENT_46	[p2l1108t2087r1238b2113],
4	over	IN	O	over	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l243t2139r307b2156],
5	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	8	SENT_46	[p2l334t2130r361b2155],
6	consecutive	JJ	O	consecutive	amod	8	SENT_46	[p2l387t2130r557b2156],
7	HRSV	NN	O	hrsv	nn	8	SENT_46	[p2l581t2130r683b2156],
8	seasons	NNS	O	season	prep_over	3	SENT_46	[p2l706t2139r813b2156],
9	(	VBP	O	(	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l836t2130r1027b2164],
10	1995	CD	DATE	1995	num	11	SENT_46	[p2l836t2130r1027b2164],
11	—	CD	DATE	—	dobj	9	SENT_46	[p2l836t2130r1027b2164],
12	2005	CD	DATE	2005	num	13	SENT_46	[p2l836t2130r1027b2164],
13	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	9	SENT_46	[p2l836t2130r1027b2164],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l836t2130r1027b2164],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1052t2130r1083b2155],
2	addition	NN	O	addition	prep_in	12	SENT_47	[p2l1106t2130r1236b2162],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1106t2130r1236b2162],
4	1,240	CD	NUMBER	1,240	num	6	SENT_47	[p2l248t2174r325b2206],
5	respiratory	JJ	O	respiratory	amod	6	SENT_47	[p2l340t2174r501b2208],
6	samples	NNS	O	sample	nsubjpass	12	SENT_47	[p2l516t2174r630b2208],
7	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l645t2174r716b2200],
8	children	NNS	O	child	prep_from	6	SENT_47	[p2l731t2174r852b2200],
9	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l865t2174r930b2200],
10	ARI	NN	PERSON	arus	prep_with	8	SENT_47	[p2l943t2174r1008b2199],
11	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	12	SENT_47	[p2l1022t2183r1092b2200],
12	collected	VBN	O	collect	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1108t2174r1238b2200],
13	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l243t2217r270b2242],
14	2004	CD	DATE	2004	prep_in	12	SENT_47	[p2l282t2217r354b2244],
15	and	CC	DATE	and	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l365t2217r420b2243],
16	2005	CD	DATE	2005	conj_and	14	SENT_47	[p2l431t2217r501b2244],
17	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l513t2217r541b2242],
18	different	JJ	O	different	amod	19	SENT_47	[p2l552t2217r676b2243],
19	cities	NNS	O	city	prep_in	12	SENT_47	[p2l686t2217r758b2243],
20	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l770t2217r797b2242],
21	Sao	NNP	LOCATION	Sao	nn	23	SENT_47	[p2l808t2217r861b2243],
22	Paulo	NNP	LOCATION	Paulo	nn	23	SENT_47	[p2l873t2217r956b2243],
23	State	NNP	LOCATION	State	prep_in	19	SENT_47	[p2l968t2217r1040b2243],
24	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1052t2217r1107b2243],
25	enrolled	VBN	O	enrol	conj_and	12	SENT_47	[p2l1117t2217r1238b2243],
26	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l243t2261r270b2286],
27	the	DT	O	the	det	29	SENT_47	[p2l282t2261r326b2287],
28	present	JJ	DATE	present	amod	29	SENT_47	[p2l338t2267r446b2295],
29	study	NN	O	study	prep_in	25	SENT_47	[p2l457t2261r535b2295],
30	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l546t2270r574b2287],
31	part	NN	O	part	prep_as	29	SENT_47	[p2l585t2267r646b2295],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l657t2261r689b2287],
33	the	DT	O	the	det	36	SENT_47	[p2l695t2261r740b2287],
34	Viral	JJ	ORGANIZATION	viral	amod	36	SENT_47	[p2l751t2261r827b2287],
35	Genetic	JJ	ORGANIZATION	genetic	amod	36	SENT_47	[p2l839t2261r953b2287],
36	Diversity	NN	ORGANIZATION	diversity	prep_of	31	SENT_47	[p2l965t2261r1099b2295],
37	Network	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Network	tmod	25	SENT_47	[p2l1109t2261r1238b2287],
38	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	37	SENT_47	[p2l244t2305r371b2339],
39	VGD1	NN	O	vgd1	nn	41	SENT_47	[p2l244t2305r371b2339],
40	\	NN	O	\	nn	41	SENT_47	[p2l244t2305r371b2339],
41	D	NN	O	d	dobj	12	SENT_47	[p2l244t2305r371b2339],
42	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	43	SENT_47	[p2l384t2305r1143b2339],
43	http://www.lemb.icb.usp.br/LEMB/index.php?p	NN	O	http://www.lemb.icb.usp.br/lemb/index.php?p	dep	41	SENT_47	[p2l384t2305r1143b2339],
44	=	JJ	O	=	amod	47	SENT_47	[p2l1154t2313r1174b2323],
45	1	CD	NUMBER	1	number	46	SENT_47	[p2l1188t2305r1196b2330],
46	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	44	SENT_47	[p2l1207t2305r1235b2339],
47	)	NN	O	)	dep	43	SENT_47	[p2l1207t2305r1235b2339],
48	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1207t2305r1235b2339],

1	Informed	JJ	O	informed	amod	2	SENT_48	[p2l243t2348r383b2374],
2	consent	NN	O	consent	nsubjpass	4	SENT_48	[p2l405t2354r517b2374],
3	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	4	SENT_48	[p2l538t2357r592b2374],
4	obtained	VBN	O	obtain	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l615t2348r745b2374],
5	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l766t2348r837b2374],
6	parents	NNS	O	parent	prep_from	4	SENT_48	[p2l859t2354r968b2382],
7	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l991t2357r1022b2374],
8	guardians	NNS	O	guardian	prep_from	4	SENT_48	[p2l1043t2348r1188b2382],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l1211t2348r1243b2374],
10	children	NNS	O	child	prep_of	6	SENT_48	[p2l243t2392r364b2418],
11	enrolled	VBN	O	enrol	partmod	10	SENT_48	[p2l378t2392r498b2418],
12	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l511t2392r538b2417],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_48	[p2l551t2392r596b2418],
14	study	NN	O	study	prep_in	11	SENT_48	[p2l610t2392r688b2426],
15	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l700t2392r727b2417],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	18	SENT_48	[p2l740t2392r785b2418],
17	different	JJ	O	different	amod	18	SENT_48	[p2l799t2392r924b2418],
18	cities	NNS	O	city	prep_in	14	SENT_48	[p2l936t2392r1008b2418],
19	according	VBG	O	accord	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l1022t2392r1169b2426],
20	to	TO	O	to	prepc_according_to	11	SENT_48	[p2l1181t2398r1208b2418],
21	a	DT	O	a	det	22	SENT_48	[p2l1222t2401r1238b2417],
22	protocol	NN	O	protocol	pobj	11	SENT_48	[p2l242t2436r366b2470],
23	approved	VBN	O	approve	partmod	22	SENT_48	[p2l378t2436r518b2470],
24	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l529t2436r565b2470],
25	their	PRP$	O	they	poss	29	SENT_48	[p2l575t2436r644b2462],
26	respective	JJ	O	respective	amod	29	SENT_48	[p2l655t2436r800b2470],
27	Institutional	JJ	O	institutional	amod	29	SENT_48	[p2l813t2436r992b2462],
28	Review	NN	O	review	nn	29	SENT_48	[p2l1004t2436r1114b2462],
29	Boards	NNS	O	board	agent	23	SENT_48	[p2l1125t2436r1235b2462],
30	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l1125t2436r1235b2462],

1	HRSV	NN	ORGANIZATION	hrsv	nn	3	SENT_49	[p2l245t2527r335b2557],
2	screening	NN	O	screening	nn	3	SENT_49	[p2l351t2527r515b2565],
3	Specimens	NNS	MISC	specimen	nsubjpass	5	SENT_49	[p2l281t2576r438b2610],
4	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	5	SENT_49	[p2l450t2585r521b2602],
5	collected	VBN	O	collect	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l534t2576r664b2602],
6	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l677t2576r704b2601],
7	buffered	VBN	O	buffer	prepc_in	5	SENT_49	[p2l717t2576r841b2602],
8	saline	NN	O	saline	dobj	7	SENT_49	[p2l854t2576r935b2602],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l949t2576r1004b2602],
10	transported	VBN	O	transport	prepc_in	5	SENT_49	[p2l1017t2576r1188b2610],
11	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l1201t2585r1237b2602],
12	ice	NN	O	ice	prep_on	10	SENT_49	[p2l243t2619r282b2645],
13	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l296t2625r323b2645],
14	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_49	[p2l337t2619r382b2645],
15	laboratory	NN	O	laboratory	prep_to	10	SENT_49	[p2l395t2619r551b2653],
16	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l563t2619r604b2645],
17	processing	NN	O	processing	prep_for	15	SENT_49	[p2l616t2619r772b2653],
18	within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l783t2619r877b2645],
19	4	CD	DURATION	4	num	20	SENT_49	[p2l890t2620r907b2644],
20	hours	NNS	NUMBER	hour	prep_within	10	SENT_49	[p2l921t2619r1011b2645],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l921t2619r1011b2645],
