1	Correction	NN	O	correction	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
3	Evidence	NN	O	evidence	dep	1	SENT_1	[p1l529t280r729b317],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l744t279r790b317],
5	Differential	JJ	MISC	differential	amod	7	SENT_1	[p1l805t279r1059b317],
6	HLA	NN	MISC	hlum	nn	7	SENT_1	[p1l1077t282r1167b316],
7	Class	NN	MISC	class	prep_of	3	SENT_1	[p1l1182t280r1294b317],
8	I-Mediated	JJ	MISC	i-mediated	amod	10	SENT_1	[p1l1311t280r1553b317],
9	Viral	JJ	MISC	viral	amod	10	SENT_1	[p1l1568t280r1671b317],
10	Evolution	NN	MISC	evolution	dep	3	SENT_1	[p1l1689t280r1901b317],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1918t280r1956b316],
12	Functional	JJ	O	functional	amod	15	SENT_1	[p1l1975t280r2210b317],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l263t340r347b377],
14	Accessory/Regulatory	JJ	O	accessory/regulatory	amod	15	SENT_1	[p1l367t340r858b387],
15	Genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_in	10	SENT_1	[p1l878t341r1015b377],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1034t339r1081b377],
17	HIV-1	NN	O	hiv-1	prep_of	1	SENT_1	[p1l1100t342r1214b376],
18	Zabrina	NNP	PERSON	Zabrina	nn	20	SENT_1	[p1l263t412r379b439],
19	L.	NNP	PERSON	L.	nn	20	SENT_1	[p1l396t414r418b439],
20	Brumme	NNP	PERSON	Brumme	rcmod	17	SENT_1	[p1l434t414r572b444],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l434t414r572b444],
22	Chanson	NNP	PERSON	Chanson	nn	24	SENT_1	[p1l587t412r720b439],
23	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	24	SENT_1	[p1l735t414r755b439],
24	Brumme	NNP	PERSON	Brumme	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l772t414r909b444],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l772t414r909b444],
26	David	NNP	PERSON	David	nn	27	SENT_1	[p1l926t412r1011b439],
27	Heckerman	NNP	PERSON	Heckerman	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l1028t412r1210b444],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1028t412r1210b444],
29	Bette	NNP	PERSON	Bette	nn	31	SENT_1	[p1l1227t414r1305b439],
30	T.	NNP	PERSON	T.	nn	31	SENT_1	[p1l1319t414r1344b439],
31	Korber	NNP	PERSON	Korber	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l1360t412r1469b444],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1360t412r1469b444],
33	Marcus	NNP	PERSON	Marcus	nn	34	SENT_1	[p1l1485t414r1594b439],
34	Daniels	NNP	PERSON	Daniels	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l1610t412r1728b444],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1610t412r1728b444],
36	Jonathan	NNP	PERSON	Jonathan	nn	37	SENT_1	[p1l1742t412r1884b439],
37	Carlson	NNP	PERSON	Carlson	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l1900t412r2022b444],
38	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1900t412r2022b444],
39	Carl	NNP	PERSON	Carl	nn	40	SENT_1	[p1l2037t412r2093b439],
40	Kadie	NNP	PERSON	Kadie	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l2111t412r2201b444],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l2111t412r2201b444],
42	Tanmoy	NNP	PERSON	Tanmoy	nn	43	SENT_1	[p1l262t460r388b493],
43	Bhattacharya	NNP	PERSON	Bhattacharya	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l404t458r612b493],
44	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l404t458r612b493],
45	Celia	NNP	PERSON	Celia	nn	46	SENT_1	[p1l627t458r699b485],
46	Chui	NNP	PERSON	Chui	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l715t458r792b490],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l715t458r792b490],
48	James	NNP	PERSON	James	nn	49	SENT_1	[p1l805t460r900b485],
49	Szinger	NNP	PERSON	Szinger	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l916t459r1036b493],
50	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l916t459r1036b493],
51	Theresa	NNP	PERSON	Theresa	nn	52	SENT_1	[p1l1050t458r1169b485],
52	Mo	NNP	PERSON	Mo	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l1186t460r1241b490],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1186t460r1241b490],
54	Robert	NNP	PERSON	Robert	nn	56	SENT_1	[p1l1257t458r1359b485],
55	S.	NNP	PERSON	S.	nn	56	SENT_1	[p1l1374t459r1397b485],
56	Hogg	NNP	PERSON	Hogg	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l1413t460r1504b493],
57	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1413t460r1504b493],
58	Julio	NNP	PERSON	Julio	nn	61	SENT_1	[p1l1518t458r1589b485],
59	S.	NNP	PERSON	S.	nn	61	SENT_1	[p1l1604t459r1627b485],
60	G.	NNP	PERSON	G.	nn	61	SENT_1	[p1l1642t459r1672b485],
61	Montaner	NNP	PERSON	Montaner	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l1688t460r1845b490],
62	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1688t460r1845b490],
63	Nicole	NNP	PERSON	Nicole	nn	64	SENT_1	[p1l1861t458r1955b485],
64	Frahm	NNP	PERSON	Frahm	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l1972t458r2075b490],
65	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1972t458r2075b490],
66	Christian	NNP	PERSON	Christian	nn	67	SENT_1	[p1l263t504r397b531],
67	Brander	NNP	PERSON	Brander	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l415t504r541b536],
68	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l415t504r541b536],
69	Bruce	NNP	PERSON	Bruce	nn	71	SENT_1	[p1l557t506r642b531],
70	D.	NNP	PERSON	D.	nn	71	SENT_1	[p1l658t506r687b531],
71	Walker	NNP	PERSON	Walker	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l701t504r813b536],
72	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l701t504r813b536],
73	P.	NNP	PERSON	P.	nn	76	SENT_1	[p1l830t506r853b531],
74	Richard	NNP	PERSON	Richard	nn	76	SENT_1	[p1l870t504r982b531],
75	Harrigan	NNP	PERSON	Harrigan	nn	76	SENT_1	[p1l999t505r1129b539],
76	Correction	NNP	O	Correction	appos	20	SENT_1	[p1l263t575r424b601],
77	for	IN	O	for	dep	20	SENT_1	[p1l439t574r489b601],
78	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l439t574r489b601],

1	Brumme	NNP	O	Brumme	nn	2	SENT_2	[p1l265t647r395b672],
2	ZL	NNP	O	ZL	dep	18	SENT_2	[p1l409t647r453b677],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l409t647r453b677],
4	Brumme	NNP	O	Brumme	nn	5	SENT_2	[p1l469t647r599b672],
5	CJ	NNP	O	CJ	appos	2	SENT_2	[p1l614t646r655b677],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l614t646r655b677],
7	Heckerman	NNP	PERSON	Heckerman	nn	8	SENT_2	[p1l672t645r844b672],
8	D	NNP	O	D	appos	2	SENT_2	[p1l862t647r891b677],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l862t647r891b677],
10	Korber	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Korber	nn	11	SENT_2	[p1l907t645r1009b672],
11	BT	NNP	ORGANIZATION	BT	appos	2	SENT_2	[p1l1025t647r1067b677],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1025t647r1067b677],
13	Daniels	NNP	PERSON	Daniels	nn	14	SENT_2	[p1l1084t645r1194b672],
14	M	NNP	O	M	appos	2	SENT_2	[p1l1210t647r1244b677],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1210t647r1244b677],
16	et	FW	O	et	appos	2	SENT_2	[p1l1259t650r1288b672],
17	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	18	SENT_2	[p1l1303t645r1334b672],
18	(	FW	O	(	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1350t646r1443b677],
19	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	21	SENT_2	[p1l1350t646r1443b677],
20	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	21	SENT_2	[p1l1350t646r1443b677],
21	Evidence	NN	O	evidence	dep	18	SENT_2	[p1l1460t645r1597b672],
22	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1612t645r1644b672],
23	differential	JJ	O	differential	amod	25	SENT_2	[p1l1656t645r1821b672],
24	HLA	NN	O	hlum	nn	25	SENT_2	[p1l1839t647r1900b672],
25	class	NN	O	class	prep_of	21	SENT_2	[p1l1915t645r1985b672],
26	|	CD	NUMBER	|	dep	21	SENT_2	[p1l2001t645r2166b672],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l2001t645r2166b672],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2001t645r2166b672],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2001t645r2166b672],

1	mediated	VBN	O	mediate	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2001t645r2166b672],
2	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	3	SENT_4	[p1l263t690r325b717],
3	evolution	NN	O	evolution	dobj	1	SENT_4	[p1l341t690r486b717],
4	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l503t691r527b717],
5	functional	JJ	O	functional	amod	8	SENT_4	[p1l543t690r697b717],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l714t690r770b717],
7	accessory/regulatory	JJ	O	accessory/regulatory	conj_and	5	SENT_4	[p1l786t690r1108b725],
8	genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_in	1	SENT_4	[p1l1122t698r1213b725],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1228t690r1260b717],
10	HIV-1	NN	O	hiv-1	prep_of	8	SENT_4	[p1l1274t692r1362b717],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1274t692r1362b717],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_5	[p1l1379t691r1451b717],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1467t690r1574b725],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	4	SENT_5	[p1l1591t691r1655b722],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_5	[p1l1591t691r1655b722],
5	7	CD	NUMBER	7	num	6	SENT_5	[p1l1591t691r1655b722],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_5	[p1l1591t691r1655b722],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1591t691r1655b722],
8	e94	NN	O	e94	dep	2	SENT_5	[p1l1670t692r1732b717],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1670t692r1732b717],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1747t690r1939b719],
2	:10.1371	CD	NUMBER	:10.1371	dep	1	SENT_6	[p1l1747t690r1939b719],
3	/	:	O	/	punct	5	SENT_6	[p1l1747t690r1939b719],
4	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	5	SENT_6	[p1l261t736r593b771],
5	|	NN	O	|	dep	2	SENT_6	[p1l261t736r593b771],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l261t736r593b771],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l261t736r593b771],
2	.0030094	CD	NUMBER	.0030094	num	1	SENT_7	[p1l261t736r593b771],
3	Coauthor	NNP	O	Coauthor	nn	5	SENT_7	[p1l263t807r409b834],
4	Tanmoy	NNP	PERSON	Tanmoy	nn	5	SENT_7	[p1l421t809r547b842],
5	Bhattacharya	NNP	PERSON	Bhattacharya	poss	7	SENT_7	[p1l563t807r786b842],
6	’s	POS	O	’s	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l563t807r786b842],
7	affiliations	NNS	O	affiliation	nsubjpass	9	SENT_7	[p1l801t807r958b834],
8	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	9	SENT_7	[p1l973t815r1048b834],
9	listed	VBN	O	list	rcmod	1	SENT_7	[p1l1064t807r1143b834],
10	incorrectly	RB	O	incorrectly	advmod	9	SENT_7	[p1l1160t807r1329b842],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1160t807r1329b842],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_8	[p1l1343t807r1400b834],
2	correct	JJ	O	correct	dep	6	SENT_8	[p1l1415t812r1522b834],
3	affiliations	NNS	O	affiliation	nsubj	6	SENT_8	[p1l1536t807r1694b834],
4	are	VBP	O	be	cop	6	SENT_8	[p1l1709t815r1763b834],
5	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1709t815r1763b834],
6	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	67	SENT_8	[p1l264t880r281b904],
7	Los	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Los	nn	10	SENT_8	[p1l298t879r347b904],
8	Alamos	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Alamos	nn	10	SENT_8	[p1l362t877r475b904],
9	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	nn	10	SENT_8	[p1l492t877r618b904],
10	Laboratory	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Laboratory	nsubjpass	44	SENT_8	[p1l635t877r809b912],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l635t877r809b912],
12	Los	NNP	LOCATION	Los	nn	13	SENT_8	[p1l826t879r874b904],
13	Alamos	NNP	LOCATION	Alamos	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l889t877r1010b909],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l889t877r1010b909],
15	New	NNP	LOCATION	New	nn	16	SENT_8	[p1l1027t879r1094b904],
16	Mexico	NNP	LOCATION	Mexico	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l1110t878r1226b909],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1110t878r1226b909],
18	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	19	SENT_8	[p1l1242t877r1343b904],
19	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l1359t878r1451b904],
20	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1466t877r1497b904],
21	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	19	SENT_8	[p1l1509t878r1643b909],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1509t878r1643b909],
23	6	CD	NUMBER	6	num	26	SENT_8	[p1l263t950r282b975],
24	Santa	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Santa	nn	26	SENT_8	[p1l297t949r380b975],
25	Fe	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Fe	nn	26	SENT_8	[p1l398t950r431b975],
26	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l447t949r580b980],
27	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l447t949r580b980],
28	Santa	NNP	LOCATION	Santa	nn	29	SENT_8	[p1l596t949r679b975],
29	Fe	NNP	LOCATION	Fe	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l696t950r737b980],
30	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l696t950r737b980],
31	New	NNP	LOCATION	New	nn	32	SENT_8	[p1l754t950r821b975],
32	Mexico	NNP	LOCATION	Mexico	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l836t949r952b980],
33	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l836t949r952b980],
34	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	35	SENT_8	[p1l969t948r1069b975],
35	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l1086t949r1177b975],
36	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1192t948r1224b975],
37	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	35	SENT_8	[p1l1236t949r1361b975],
38	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	37	SENT_8	[p1l265t1018r329b1050],
39	The	DT	O	the	det	41	SENT_8	[p1l265t1018r329b1050],
40	second	JJ	ORDINAL	second	amod	41	SENT_8	[p1l345t1018r453b1045],
41	affiliation	NN	O	affiliation	dep	35	SENT_8	[p1l469t1018r611b1045],
42	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	44	SENT_8	[p1l627t1026r685b1045],
43	incorrectly	RB	O	incorrectly	advmod	44	SENT_8	[p1l701t1018r863b1053],
44	listed	VBN	O	list	rcmod	6	SENT_8	[p1l878t1018r957b1045],
45	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l973t1026r1003b1045],
46	7	CD	NUMBER	7	num	47	SENT_8	[p1l1019t1021r1037b1045],
47	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	prep_as	44	SENT_8	[p1l1053t1020r1240b1052],
48	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1254t1018r1286b1045],
49	Computer	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Computer	nn	50	SENT_8	[p1l1298t1019r1456b1052],
50	Science	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Science	prep_of	47	SENT_8	[p1l1470t1019r1585b1045],
51	and	CC	ORGANIZATION	and	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1600t1018r1656b1045],
52	Engineering	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Engineering	prep_of	47	SENT_8	[p1l1674t1019r1866b1053],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1674t1019r1866b1053],
54	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	63	SENT_8	[p1l1883t1019r2035b1053],
55	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2049t1018r2081b1045],
56	Washington	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Washington	nn	60	SENT_8	[p1l263t1064r457b1099],
57	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l263t1064r457b1099],
58	Seattle	NNP	LOCATION	Seattle	appos	60	SENT_8	[p1l473t1064r585b1096],
59	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l473t1064r585b1096],
60	Washington	NNP	LOCATION	Washington	prep_of	54	SENT_8	[p1l599t1064r793b1099],
61	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l599t1064r793b1099],
62	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	63	SENT_8	[p1l810t1064r910b1091],
63	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	67	SENT_8	[p1l927t1065r1018b1091],
64	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1034t1064r1065b1091],
65	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	63	SENT_8	[p1l1077t1065r1220b1096],
66	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1077t1065r1220b1096],
67	)	NN	O	)	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1077t1065r1220b1096],

1	This	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_9	[p1l338t1153r403b1177],
2	correction	NN	O	correction	nn	3	SENT_9	[p1l418t1153r580b1177],
3	note	NN	O	note	nsubjpass	6	SENT_9	[p1l595t1157r662b1177],
4	may	MD	O	may	aux	6	SENT_9	[p1l677t1161r738b1186],
5	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_9	[p1l752t1153r786b1177],
6	found	VBN	O	find	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l801t1152r892b1177],
7	online	NN	O	online	dep	6	SENT_9	[p1l906t1153r1003b1177],
8	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1018t1157r1045b1177],
9	doi	FW	O	doi	nn	10	SENT_9	[p1l1059t1151r1578b1186],
10	:10.1371	FW	O	:10.1371	prep_at	6	SENT_9	[p1l1059t1151r1578b1186],
11	ﬁournal	NN	O	ﬁournal	dep	10	SENT_9	[p1l1059t1151r1578b1186],
12	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1059t1151r1578b1186],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	nn	3	SENT_10	[p1l1059t1151r1578b1186],
2	.003012	CD	NUMBER	.003012	num	3	SENT_10	[p1l1059t1151r1578b1186],
3	l.	NN	O	l.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1059t1151r1578b1186],
4	Received	VBN	O	receive	dep	3	SENT_10	[p1l338t1224r482b1248],
5	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l338t1224r482b1248],
6	July	NNP	DATE	July	nsubj	18	SENT_10	[p1l492t1224r554b1256],
7	6	CD	DATE	6	num	6	SENT_10	[p1l569t1223r591b1252],
8	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l569t1223r591b1252],
9	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	6	SENT_10	[p1l607t1221r685b1252],
10	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l607t1221r685b1252],
11	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	dep	6	SENT_10	[p1l699t1224r850b1257],
12	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l699t1224r850b1257],
13	July	NNP	DATE	July	dep	11	SENT_10	[p1l860t1223r922b1256],
14	6	CD	DATE	6	num	13	SENT_10	[p1l937t1223r960b1252],
15	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l937t1223r960b1252],
16	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	13	SENT_10	[p1l976t1221r1054b1252],
17	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l976t1221r1054b1252],
18	Published	VBN	O	publish	parataxis	4	SENT_10	[p1l1068t1223r1225b1248],
19	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1068t1223r1225b1248],
20	August	NNP	DATE	August	dep	3	SENT_10	[p1l1239t1224r1347b1256],
21	31	CD	DATE	31	num	20	SENT_10	[p1l1362t1223r1403b1252],
22	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1362t1223r1403b1252],
23	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	20	SENT_10	[p1l1418t1221r1488b1249],
24	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	dep	20	SENT_10	[p1l339t1292r472b1316],
25	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l339t1292r472b1316],
26	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	3	SENT_10	[p1l489t1289r580b1322],
27	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	29	SENT_10	[p1l489t1289r580b1322],
28	)	NN	O	)	nn	29	SENT_10	[p1l489t1289r580b1322],
29	Correction	NN	O	correction	dep	26	SENT_10	[p1l596t1292r772b1316],
30	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l596t1292r772b1316],
31	Evidence	NN	O	evidence	dep	3	SENT_10	[p1l788t1292r926b1316],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l941t1291r974b1316],
33	differential	JJ	O	differential	amod	35	SENT_10	[p1l986t1291r1159b1316],
34	HLA	NN	O	hlum	nn	35	SENT_10	[p1l1175t1292r1248b1315],
35	class	NN	O	class	prep_of	31	SENT_10	[p1l1263t1292r1330b1316],
36	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	37	SENT_10	[p1l1345t1292r1513b1316],
37	—	NN	O	—	nsubj	38	SENT_10	[p1l1345t1292r1513b1316],
38	mediated	VBD	O	mediate	rcmod	35	SENT_10	[p1l1345t1292r1513b1316],
39	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	40	SENT_10	[p1l1528t1291r1595b1316],
40	evolution	NN	O	evolution	dobj	38	SENT_10	[p1l1611t1292r1756b1316],
41	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1772t1292r1800b1315],
42	functional	JJ	O	functional	prep_in	38	SENT_10	[p1l1815t1291r1974b1316],
43	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1990t1292r2045b1316],
44	accessory	JJ	O	accessory	prep_in	38	SENT_10	[p1l2061t1292r2213b1325],
45	!	.	O	!	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2061t1292r2213b1325],

1	regulatory	JJ	O	regulatory	amod	2	SENT_11	[p1l339t1328r497b1360],
2	genes	NNS	O	gene	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l511t1336r595b1360],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l610t1327r643b1352],
4	HIV-1	NN	O	hiv-1	prep_of	2	SENT_11	[p1l654t1328r755b1352],
5	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l654t1328r755b1352],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_12	[p1l770t1328r848b1352],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l863t1328r970b1360],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	4	SENT_12	[p1l984t1327r1046b1358],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_12	[p1l984t1327r1046b1358],
5	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	6	SENT_12	[p1l984t1327r1046b1358],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_12	[p1l984t1327r1046b1358],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l984t1327r1046b1358],
8	e121	NN	O	e121	dep	2	SENT_12	[p1l1061t1328r1138b1353],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1061t1328r1138b1353],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	nn	2	SENT_13	[p1l1154t1326r1663b1361],
2	:10.1371	FW	O	:10.1371	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1154t1326r1663b1361],
3	ﬁournal	NN	O	ﬁournal	dep	2	SENT_13	[p1l1154t1326r1663b1361],
4	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1154t1326r1663b1361],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1154t1326r1663b1361],
2	.0030	CD	NUMBER	.0030	num	3	SENT_14	[p1l1154t1326r1663b1361],
3	l21	NN	O	l21	dep	1	SENT_14	[p1l1154t1326r1663b1361],

1	q	VB	O	q	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
2	(	CD	NUMBER	(	number	3	SENT_15	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
3	8	CD	NUMBER	8	dobj	1	SENT_15	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
4	*	CD	NUMBER	*	num	5	SENT_15	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
5	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	6	SENT_15	[p1l288t3093r352b3116],
6	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	rcmod	3	SENT_15	[p1l367t3092r511b3123],
7	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	8	SENT_15	[p1l526t3091r528b3124],
8	www	NN	O	www	dobj	6	SENT_15	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_16	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_16	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
4	1187	CD	DATE	1187	num	7	SENT_16	[p1l1207t3094r1270b3116],
5	August	NNP	DATE	August	nn	7	SENT_16	[p1l1721t3093r1819b3123],
6	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	7	SENT_16	[p1l1832t3094r1897b3116],
7	|	NNP	O	|	dep	3	SENT_16	[p1l1912t3091r1914b3124],
8	Volume	NN	O	volume	nn	11	SENT_16	[p1l1929t3092r2034b3116],
9	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	11	SENT_16	[p1l2047t3094r2061b3116],
10	|	NN	O	|	nn	11	SENT_16	[p1l2077t3091r2079b3124],
11	Issue	NN	O	issue	dep	7	SENT_16	[p1l2095t3093r2161b3116],
12	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	14	SENT_16	[p1l2174t3094r2189b3116],
13	|	NN	O	|	nn	14	SENT_16	[p1l2204t3091r2206b3124],
14	e121	NN	O	e121	dep	3	SENT_16	[p1l2221t3094r2281b3116],

