1	OPEN	NN	MISC	open	nn	3	SENT_1	[p1l187t137r269b160],
2	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	3	SENT_1	[p1l279t118r311b169],
3	ACCESS	NNP	O	ACCESS	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l319t137r431b161],
4	Freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	5	SENT_1	[p1l447t136r536b168],
5	available	JJ	O	available	amod	3	SENT_1	[p1l544t136r677b161],
6	online	NN	O	online	prep	3	SENT_1	[p1l685t136r777b161],
7	p	NN	O	p	dep	6	SENT_1	[p1l1980t118r2096b162],
8	{	CD	NUMBER	{	num	9	SENT_1	[p1l1980t118r2096b162],
9	PATHOGENS	NNS	O	pathogen	dep	3	SENT_1	[p1l2106t138r2286b161],

1	Out	IN	O	out	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l191t218r348b290],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l389t214r477b290],
3	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_of	1	SENT_2	[p1l510t214r773b290],
4	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l510t214r773b290],
5	A	NNP	O	A	dep	1	SENT_2	[p1l814t219r873b289],
6	Molecular	JJ	O	molecular	amod	7	SENT_2	[p1l915t215r1336b290],
7	Perspective	NNP	O	Perspective	dep	5	SENT_2	[p1l1379t218r1867b310],
8	on	IN	O	on	dep	1	SENT_2	[p1l191t361r296b414],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_2	[p1l338t339r477b414],
10	Introduction	NN	MISC	introduction	pobj	8	SENT_2	[p1l523t339r1051b414],
11	of	IN	MISC	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1096t338r1184b414],
12	Yellow	NNP	MISC	Yellow	nn	14	SENT_2	[p1l1216t339r1502b414],
13	Fever	NN	MISC	fever	nn	14	SENT_2	[p1l1547t343r1776b414],
14	Virus	NN	MISC	virus	prep_of	10	SENT_2	[p1l1812t342r2022b414],
15	into	IN	O	into	dep	1	SENT_2	[p1l193t467r356b539],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_2	[p1l397t464r535b539],
17	Americas	NNPS	LOCATION	Americas	pobj	15	SENT_2	[p1l576t467r966b539],

1	Juliet	NNP	PERSON	Juliet	nn	3	SENT_3	[p1l187t611r279b639],
2	E.	NNP	PERSON	E.	nn	3	SENT_3	[p1l295t612r322b638],
3	Bryant1	NN	PERSON	bryant1	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
4	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
5	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	3	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
6	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
7	3	CD	NUMBER	3	dep	5	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
8	’	NN	O	’	nn	10	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
9	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	10	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
10	*	NN	O	*	dep	3	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l338t600r568b646],
12	Edward	NNP	PERSON	Edward	nn	14	SENT_3	[p1l584t611r709b638],
13	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	nn	14	SENT_3	[p1l725t612r755b639],
14	Holmes5	NNP	PERSON	Holmes5	appos	10	SENT_3	[p1l771t600r975b643],
15	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l771t600r975b643],
16	6	CD	NUMBER	6	dep	14	SENT_3	[p1l771t600r975b643],
17	'	''	DATE	'	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l771t600r975b643],
18	7	CD	DATE	7	dep	16	SENT_3	[p1l771t600r975b643],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l771t600r975b643],
20	Alan	NNP	PERSON	Alan	nn	23	SENT_3	[p1l990t611r1065b638],
21	D.	NNP	PERSON	D.	nn	23	SENT_3	[p1l1083t612r1116b638],
22	T.	NNP	PERSON	T.	nn	23	SENT_3	[p1l1130t612r1159b638],
23	Barrett	NNP	PERSON	Barrett	appos	10	SENT_3	[p1l1175t612r1292b639],

1	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l190t677r199b696],
2	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l216t676r362b702],
3	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l374t675r399b696],
4	Pathology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pathology	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l411t675r537b702],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l411t675r537b702],
6	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l552t676r670b702],
7	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l682t675r707b696],
8	Texas	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Texas	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l716t676r783b696],
9	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l796t675r888b696],
10	Branch	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Branch	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l902t675r989b700],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l902t675r989b700],
12	Galveston	NNP	LOCATION	Galveston	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1002t675r1127b700],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1002t675r1127b700],
14	Texas	NNP	LOCATION	Texas	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1139t676r1212b700],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1139t676r1212b700],
16	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1226t675r1304b696],
17	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1318t676r1389b696],
18	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1402t675r1427b696],
19	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1437t676r1541b700],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1437t676r1541b700],
21	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1555t677r1568b696],
22	Center	NNP	O	Center	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1581t676r1661b696],
23	for	IN	O	for	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1672t675r1706b696],
24	Biodefense	NNP	O	Biodefense	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1719t675r1850b696],
25	and	CC	O	and	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1863t675r1906b696],
26	Emerging	VBG	O	emerge	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1921t676r2035b702],
27	Infectious	JJ	O	infectious	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2050t675r2166b696],
28	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2180t676r2286b700],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2180t676r2286b700],
30	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l190t717r308b743],
31	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l316t716r341b737],
32	Texas	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Texas	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l347t717r413b737],
33	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l423t716r514b737],
34	Branch	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Branch	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l525t716r612b741],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l525t716r612b741],
36	Galveston	NNP	LOCATION	Galveston	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l621t716r746b741],
37	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l621t716r746b741],
38	Texas	NNP	LOCATION	Texas	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l755t717r827b741],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l755t717r827b741],
40	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l838t716r915b737],
41	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l926t717r997b737],
42	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1006t716r1031b737],
43	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1037t717r1141b741],
44	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1037t717r1141b741],
45	3	CD	NUMBER	3	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1150t718r1164b737],
46	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1174t717r1272b737],
47	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1280t716r1314b737],
48	Human	JJ	ORGANIZATION	human	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1323t717r1408b737],
49	Infections	NNS	ORGANIZATION	infection	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1419t716r1535b737],
50	and	CC	O	and	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1544t716r1588b737],
51	Immunity	NN	O	immunity	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1599t717r1719b743],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1599t717r1719b743],
53	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1729t717r1848b743],
54	ofTexas	NNP	ORGANIZATION	ofTexas	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1856t716r1953b737],
55	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1963t716r2054b737],
56	Branch	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Branch	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2065t716r2152b741],
57	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2065t716r2152b741],
58	Galveston	NNP	LOCATION	Galveston	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2161t716r2286b741],
59	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2161t716r2286b741],
60	Texas	NNP	LOCATION	Texas	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l187t759r260b783],
61	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l187t759r260b783],
62	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l271t758r349b779],
63	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l360t759r431b779],
64	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l441t758r465b779],
65	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l473t759r576b783],
66	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l473t759r576b783],
67	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l586t760r601b779],
68	Institut	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institut	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l611t759r694b779],
69	Pasteur	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pasteur	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l705t759r798b783],
70	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l705t759r798b783],
71	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l809t758r907b779],
72	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l918t759r998b779],
73	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1006t758r1039b779],
74	Laboratory	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Laboratory	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1049t758r1179b785],
75	and	CC	ORGANIZATION	and	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1188t758r1231b779],
76	Epidemiology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Epidemiology	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1243t758r1414b785],
77	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1243t758r1414b785],
78	Vientiane	NNP	LOCATION	Vientiane	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1423t759r1542b783],
79	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1423t759r1542b783],
80	Lao	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Lao	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1553t759r1593b779],
81	People	NNP	ORGANIZATION	People	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1604t758r1703b785],
82	's	POS	ORGANIZATION	's	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1604t758r1703b785],
83	Democratic	JJ	ORGANIZATION	democratic	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1713t759r1850b779],
84	Republic	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Republic	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1861t758r1970b785],
85	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1861t758r1970b785],
86	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1980t760r1993b779],
87	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2004t759r2150b785],
88	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2159t758r2184b779],
89	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2192t758r2286b785],
90	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2192t758r2286b785],
91	The	DT	O	the	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l187t799r232b820],
92	Pennsylvania	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pennsylvania	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l246t799r400b826],
93	State	NNP	ORGANIZATION	State	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l414t800r474b820],
94	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l488t800r611b826],
95	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l488t800r611b826],
96	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l626t800r744b826],
97	Park	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Park	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l757t799r813b824],
98	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l757t799r813b824],
99	Pennsylvania	NNP	LOCATION	Pennsylvania	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l827t799r988b826],
100	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l827t799r988b826],
101	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1002t799r1080b820],
102	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1094t800r1166b820],
103	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1179t799r1203b820],
104	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1214t800r1317b824],
105	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1214t800r1317b824],
106	6	CD	NUMBER	6	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1331t801r1345b820],
107	Center	NN	ORGANIZATION	center	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1358t800r1438b820],
108	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1449t799r1483b820],
109	Infectious	JJ	ORGANIZATION	infectious	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1496t799r1612b820],
110	Disease	NN	ORGANIZATION	disease	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1626t800r1715b820],
111	Dynamics	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Dynamics	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1729t800r1850b826],
112	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1729t800r1850b826],
113	The	DT	O	the	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1862t799r1906b820],
114	Pennsylvania	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pennsylvania	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1920t799r2075b826],
115	State	NNP	ORGANIZATION	State	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2089t800r2148b820],
116	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2162t800r2286b826],
117	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2162t800r2286b826],
118	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l190t842r308b868],
119	Park	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Park	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l320t841r375b866],
120	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l320t841r375b866],
121	Pennsylvania	NNP	LOCATION	Pennsylvania	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l388t841r550b868],
122	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l388t841r550b868],
123	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l563t841r640b862],
124	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l654t842r725b862],
125	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l737t841r761b862],
126	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l771t842r874b866],
127	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l771t842r874b866],
128	7	CD	NUMBER	7	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l887t843r900b862],
129	Fogarty	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Fogarty	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l913t842r1004b868],
130	International	NNP	ORGANIZATION	International	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1016t841r1168b862],
131	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1181t842r1266b866],
132	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1181t842r1266b866],
133	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1279t841r1377b862],
134	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1391t842r1500b862],
135	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1512t841r1536b862],
136	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1547t841r1630b866],
137	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1547t841r1630b866],
138	Bethesda	NNP	LOCATION	Bethesda	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1643t841r1758b866],
139	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1643t841r1758b866],
140	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1771t841r1887b868],
141	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1771t841r1887b868],
142	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1900t841r1978b862],
143	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l1991t842r2062b862],
144	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	145	SENT_4	[p1l2074t841r2099b862],
145	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2108t842r2205b862],

1	Yellow	JJ	O	yellow	amod	3	SENT_5	[p1l188t942r306b971],
2	fever	NN	O	fever	nn	3	SENT_5	[p1l327t941r417b970],
3	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubj	9	SENT_5	[p1l438t942r523b971],
4	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	6	SENT_5	[p1l547t943r637b975],
5	YFV	NN	O	yfv	nn	6	SENT_5	[p1l547t943r637b975],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	3	SENT_5	[p1l547t943r637b975],
7	remains	VBZ	O	remain	cop	9	SENT_5	[p1l661t942r800b971],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_5	[p1l822t942r878b971],
9	cause	NN	O	cause	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l901t950r998b971],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1021t941r1057b971],
11	severe	JJ	O	severe	amod	12	SENT_5	[p1l1077t950r1191b971],
12	morbidity	NN	O	morbidity	prep_of	9	SENT_5	[p1l1214t942r1386b979],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1408t942r1472b971],
14	mortality	NN	O	mortality	conj_and	12	SENT_5	[p1l1497t942r1657b979],
15	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1680t942r1709b970],
16	South	NNP	LOCATION	South	nn	17	SENT_5	[p1l1733t942r1834b971],
17	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_in	9	SENT_5	[p1l1857t942r1999b971],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l2022t942r2087b971],
19	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_in	9	SENT_5	[p1l2110t941r2221b971],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l2110t941r2221b971],

1	To	TO	O	to	aux	2	SENT_6	[p1l2243t943r2286b971],
2	determine	VB	O	determine	purpcl	13	SENT_6	[p1l189t987r370b1016],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_6	[p1l384t987r440b1016],
4	evolutionary	JJ	O	evolutionary	amod	5	SENT_6	[p1l455t987r678b1024],
5	history	NN	O	history	dobj	2	SENT_6	[p1l694t987r814b1024],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l828t986r864b1016],
7	this	DT	O	this	det	10	SENT_6	[p1l876t987r940b1016],
8	important	JJ	O	important	amod	10	SENT_6	[p1l955t987r1131b1023],
9	reemerging	VBG	O	reemerge	amod	10	SENT_6	[p1l1146t987r1348b1023],
10	pathogen	NN	O	pathogen	prep_of	5	SENT_6	[p1l1365t987r1543b1023],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1365t987r1543b1023],
12	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	13	SENT_6	[p1l1557t995r1606b1015],
13	performed	VBD	O	perform	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1622t986r1806b1023],
14	a	DT	O	a	det	16	SENT_6	[p1l1822t995r1840b1016],
15	phylogenetic	JJ	O	phylogenetic	amod	16	SENT_6	[p1l1856t987r2084b1024],
16	analysis	NN	O	analysis	nsubj	22	SENT_6	[p1l2098t987r2237b1024],
17	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2252t986r2288b1016],
18	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_6	[p1l188t1033r245b1062],
19	largest	JJS	O	largest	amod	21	SENT_6	[p1l258t1033r377b1069],
20	YFV	NN	O	yfv	nn	21	SENT_6	[p1l389t1034r457b1061],
21	data	NNS	O	datum	prep_of	16	SENT_6	[p1l469t1033r546b1062],
22	set	VBP	O	set	ccomp	13	SENT_6	[p1l560t1037r610b1062],
23	compiled	VBN	O	compile	dep	22	SENT_6	[p1l622t1033r782b1069],
24	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l795t1037r831b1062],
25	date	NN	O	date	prep_to	23	SENT_6	[p1l843t1033r930b1066],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l843t1033r930b1066],
27	representing	VBG	O	represent	xcomp	13	SENT_6	[p1l944t1033r1167b1069],
28	the	DT	O	the	det	31	SENT_6	[p1l1180t1033r1236b1062],
29	prM/E	NN	O	prm/e	nn	31	SENT_6	[p1l1247t1034r1351b1069],
30	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	31	SENT_6	[p1l1362t1041r1447b1069],
31	region	NN	O	region	dobj	27	SENT_6	[p1l1461t1033r1571b1069],
32	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1584t1032r1666b1062],
33	133	CD	NUMBER	133	num	35	SENT_6	[p1l1682t1035r1742b1062],
34	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	35	SENT_6	[p1l1755t1033r1831b1062],
35	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	prep_from	27	SENT_6	[p1l1845t1033r1976b1062],
36	sampled	VBN	O	sample	partmod	35	SENT_6	[p1l1989t1033r2136b1069],
37	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2149t1032r2231b1062],
38	22	CD	NUMBER	22	num	39	SENT_6	[p1l2246t1035r2286b1061],
39	countries	NNS	O	country	prep_from	36	SENT_6	[p1l189t1078r351b1107],
40	over	IN	O	over	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l364t1086r442b1107],
41	a	DT	O	a	det	42	SENT_6	[p1l454t1086r472b1107],
42	period	NN	O	period	prep_over	39	SENT_6	[p1l487t1078r599b1114],
43	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l613t1077r649b1107],
44	76	CD	DURATION	76	num	45	SENT_6	[p1l661t1080r702b1107],
45	years	NNS	NUMBER	year	prep_of	42	SENT_6	[p1l714t1086r817b1115],
46	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l714t1086r817b1115],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_7	[p1l830t1079r884b1106],
2	estimate	VBP	O	estimate	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l897t1078r1049b1107],
3	that	IN	O	that	complm	10	SENT_7	[p1l1062t1078r1133b1107],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_7	[p1l1145t1078r1202b1107],
5	currently	RB	DATE	currently	nsubj	10	SENT_7	[p1l1215t1078r1374b1115],
6	circulating	VBG	O	circulate	partmod	5	SENT_7	[p1l1386t1078r1569b1114],
7	strains	NNS	O	strain	dobj	6	SENT_7	[p1l1583t1078r1699b1107],
8	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1713t1077r1748b1107],
9	YFV	NN	O	yfv	prep_of	7	SENT_7	[p1l1760t1079r1828b1106],
10	arose	VBD	O	arise	ccomp	2	SENT_7	[p1l1841t1086r1935b1107],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1949t1078r1978b1106],
12	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_in	10	SENT_7	[p1l1992t1077r2093b1107],
13	within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l2107t1078r2216b1107],
14	the	DT	DURATION	the	det	17	SENT_7	[p1l2230t1078r2286b1107],
15	last	JJ	DURATION	last	amod	17	SENT_7	[p1l190t1124r250b1153],
16	1,500	CD	DURATION	1,500	num	17	SENT_7	[p1l271t1126r364b1157],
17	years	NNS	NUMBER	year	prep_within	10	SENT_7	[p1l382t1132r475b1161],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l495t1124r559b1153],
19	emerged	VBD	O	emerge	conj_and	10	SENT_7	[p1l579t1124r734b1160],
20	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l755t1124r784b1152],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_7	[p1l804t1124r861b1153],
22	Americas	NNPS	LOCATION	Americas	prep_in	19	SENT_7	[p1l880t1124r1040b1153],
23	following	VBG	O	follow	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1058t1123r1222b1160],
24	the	DT	O	the	det	26	SENT_7	[p1l1242t1124r1299b1153],
25	slave	NN	O	slave	nn	26	SENT_7	[p1l1318t1124r1407b1153],
26	trade	NN	O	trade	prep_following	22	SENT_7	[p1l1425t1124r1518b1153],
27	approximately	RB	O	approximately	advmod	29	SENT_7	[p1l1537t1124r1794b1161],
28	300-400	CD	NUMBER	300-400	num	29	SENT_7	[p1l1813t1126r1960b1153],
29	years	NNS	DATE	year	npadvmod	30	SENT_7	[p1l1978t1132r2071b1161],
30	ago	RB	DATE	ago	advmod	26	SENT_7	[p1l2091t1132r2165b1160],
31	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l2091t1132r2165b1160],

1	These	DT	O	these	det	2	SENT_8	[p1l2184t1124r2286b1153],
2	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	10	SENT_8	[p1l188t1170r311b1199],
3	then	RB	O	then	advmod	4	SENT_8	[p1l325t1170r403b1199],
4	spread	VBD	O	spread	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l419t1170r536b1206],
5	westwards	RB	O	westwards	advmod	4	SENT_8	[p1l550t1170r738b1199],
6	across	IN	O	across	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l752t1178r860b1199],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_8	[p1l874t1170r930b1199],
8	continent	NN	O	continent	prep_across	4	SENT_8	[p1l944t1170r1112b1199],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1126t1170r1190b1199],
10	persist	VB	O	persist	conj_and	4	SENT_8	[p1l1206t1170r1322b1206],
11	there	RB	O	there	advmod	10	SENT_8	[p1l1335t1170r1427b1199],
12	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1441t1174r1476b1199],
13	this	DT	DATE	this	det	14	SENT_8	[p1l1490t1170r1553b1199],
14	day	NN	DATE	day	prep_to	10	SENT_8	[p1l1568t1170r1631b1207],
15	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1645t1170r1675b1198],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_8	[p1l1689t1170r1746b1199],
17	jungles	NNS	O	jungle	prep_in	14	SENT_8	[p1l1757t1170r1887b1207],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1901t1169r1937b1199],
19	South	NNP	LOCATION	South	nn	20	SENT_8	[p1l1950t1170r2050b1199],
20	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	17	SENT_8	[p1l2065t1170r2218b1199],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2065t1170r2218b1199],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	21	SENT_9	[p1l2232t1171r2286b1198],
2	therefore	RB	O	therefore	advmod	3	SENT_9	[p1l188t1215r352b1245],
3	illustrate	VBP	O	illustrate	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l367t1216r521b1245],
4	how	WRB	O	how	advmod	10	SENT_9	[p1l537t1216r609b1245],
5	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	7	SENT_9	[p1l623t1224r708b1252],
6	sequence	NN	O	sequence	nn	7	SENT_9	[p1l722t1224r887b1252],
7	data	NNS	O	datum	nsubjpass	10	SENT_9	[p1l901t1216r977b1245],
8	can	MD	O	can	aux	10	SENT_9	[p1l992t1224r1051b1245],
9	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	10	SENT_9	[p1l1067t1216r1108b1245],
10	used	VBN	O	use	ccomp	3	SENT_9	[p1l1123t1216r1203b1245],
11	to	TO	O	to	aux	12	SENT_9	[p1l1217t1220r1253b1245],
12	test	VB	O	test	xcomp	10	SENT_9	[p1l1266t1220r1331b1245],
13	hypotheses	NNS	O	hypothesis	dobj	12	SENT_9	[p1l1346t1216r1546b1253],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1560t1215r1596b1245],
15	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	16	SENT_9	[p1l1607t1216r1683b1245],
16	dispersal	NN	O	dispersal	prep_of	13	SENT_9	[p1l1697t1216r1853b1252],
17	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1868t1216r1933b1245],
18	demographics	NNS	O	demographic	prep_of	13	SENT_9	[p1l1947t1216r2207b1252],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1947t1216r2207b1252],
20	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l2221t1216r2285b1245],
21	document	VBP	O	document	conj_and	3	SENT_9	[p1l189t1261r366b1290],
22	the	DT	O	the	det	23	SENT_9	[p1l380t1261r437b1290],
23	role	NN	O	role	dobj	3	SENT_9	[p1l453t1261r519b1290],
24	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l534t1260r570b1290],
25	human	JJ	O	human	amod	26	SENT_9	[p1l585t1261r704b1290],
26	migration	NN	O	migration	prep_of	23	SENT_9	[p1l722t1261r891b1297],
27	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l909t1261r938b1289],
28	the	DT	O	the	det	29	SENT_9	[p1l954t1261r1011b1290],
29	spread	NN	O	spread	prep_in	3	SENT_9	[p1l1026t1261r1144b1297],
30	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1160t1260r1195b1290],
31	infectious	JJ	O	infectious	amod	32	SENT_9	[p1l1210t1260r1381b1290],
32	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_of	29	SENT_9	[p1l1396t1261r1535b1290],
33	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1396t1261r1535b1290],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l188t1340r288b1360],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l188t1340r288b1360],
3	Bryant	NNP	PERSON	Bryant	nn	4	SENT_10	[p1l300t1340r375b1366],
4	JE	NNP	O	JE	dep	1	SENT_10	[p1l384t1340r414b1364],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l384t1340r414b1364],
6	Holmes	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Holmes	nn	7	SENT_10	[p1l426t1339r515b1360],
7	EC	NNP	ORGANIZATION	EC	appos	4	SENT_10	[p1l526t1340r560b1364],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l526t1340r560b1364],
9	Barrett	NNP	PERSON	Barrett	nn	10	SENT_10	[p1l572t1340r651b1360],
10	ADT	NN	O	adt	appos	4	SENT_10	[p1l661t1340r712b1360],
11	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	10	SENT_10	[p1l722t1340r794b1364],
12	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	13	SENT_10	[p1l722t1340r794b1364],
13	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	10	SENT_10	[p1l722t1340r794b1364],
14	Out	IN	O	out	dep	4	SENT_10	[p1l805t1340r849b1360],
15	of	IN	O	of	dep	4	SENT_10	[p1l859t1339r884b1360],
16	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	pobj	15	SENT_10	[p1l892t1339r965b1360],
17	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l892t1339r965b1360],
18	A	NNP	O	A	nn	20	SENT_10	[p1l975t1340r991b1360],
19	molecular	JJ	O	molecular	amod	20	SENT_10	[p1l1002t1339r1121b1360],
20	perspective	NN	O	perspective	dep	4	SENT_10	[p1l1131t1340r1270b1366],
21	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1280t1346r1309b1360],
22	the	DT	O	the	det	23	SENT_10	[p1l1319t1339r1358b1360],
23	introduction	NN	O	introduction	prep_on	20	SENT_10	[p1l1369t1339r1517b1360],
24	of	IN	O	of	dep	20	SENT_10	[p1l1529t1339r1553b1360],
25	yellow	JJ	O	yellow	amod	27	SENT_10	[p1l1561t1339r1639b1366],
26	fever	NN	O	fever	nn	27	SENT_10	[p1l1648t1339r1708b1360],
27	virus	NN	O	virus	pobj	24	SENT_10	[p1l1717t1340r1773b1360],
28	into	IN	O	into	dep	20	SENT_10	[p1l1784t1340r1830b1360],
29	the	DT	O	the	det	30	SENT_10	[p1l1840t1339r1879b1360],
30	Americas	NNPS	LOCATION	Americas	pobj	28	SENT_10	[p1l1888t1340r2004b1360],
31	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1888t1340r2004b1360],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_11	[p1l2016t1340r2072b1360],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l2083t1339r2167b1366],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	4	SENT_11	[p1l2178t1340r2228b1364],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_11	[p1l2178t1340r2228b1364],
5	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	6	SENT_11	[p1l2178t1340r2228b1364],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_11	[p1l2178t1340r2228b1364],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l2178t1340r2228b1364],
8	e75	NN	O	e75	dep	2	SENT_11	[p1l2238t1341r2286b1360],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l2238t1341r2286b1360],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],
3	l0	NN	O	l0	dep	1	SENT_12	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],
4	.1371	CD	NUMBER	.1371	num	3	SENT_12	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],
5	/	:	O	/	punct	7	SENT_12	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],
6	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	7	SENT_12	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],
7	|	NN	O	|	dep	3	SENT_12	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],
2	.0030075	CD	NUMBER	.0030075	num	1	SENT_13	[p1l188t1372r594b1399],

1	Introduction	NN	O	introduction	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l190t1491r429b1523],

1	Few	JJ	O	few	amod	2	SENT_15	[p1l226t1569r289b1594],
2	diseases	NNS	O	disease	nsubj	4	SENT_15	[p1l307t1568r433b1594],
3	have	VBP	O	have	aux	4	SENT_15	[p1l451t1568r524b1594],
4	attracted	VBN	O	attract	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l542t1568r688b1594],
5	more	RBR	O	more	advmod	4	SENT_15	[p1l706t1577r790b1594],
6	attention	NN	O	attention	dobj	4	SENT_15	[p1l808t1569r958b1594],
7	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l975t1568r1055b1594],
8	medical	JJ	O	medical	amod	9	SENT_15	[p1l1073t1568r1199b1594],
9	historians	NNS	O	historian	prep_from	6	SENT_15	[p1l189t1614r349b1640],
10	than	IN	O	than	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l373t1614r444b1640],
11	yellow	JJ	O	yellow	amod	12	SENT_15	[p1l466t1614r568b1649],
12	fever	NN	O	fever	prep_than	4	SENT_15	[p1l590t1614r671b1640],
13	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	15	SENT_15	[p1l694t1615r766b1646],
14	YF	NN	O	yf	nn	15	SENT_15	[p1l694t1615r766b1646],
15	)	NN	O	)	dep	12	SENT_15	[p1l694t1615r766b1646],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l694t1615r766b1646],

1	It	PRP	O	it	nsubj	3	SENT_16	[p1l789t1615r813b1640],
2	was	VBD	O	be	cop	3	SENT_16	[p1l835t1623r890b1640],
3	one	CD	NUMBER	one	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l913t1623r972b1640],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l995t1614r1030b1640],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_16	[p1l1049t1614r1099b1640],
6	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	7	SENT_16	[p1l1122t1619r1199b1640],
7	feared	VBN	O	fear	prep_of	3	SENT_16	[p1l189t1660r291b1686],
8	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l307t1660r342b1686],
9	epidemic	JJ	O	epidemic	amod	10	SENT_16	[p1l354t1660r502b1695],
10	diseases	NNS	O	disease	prep_of	7	SENT_16	[p1l518t1660r645b1686],
11	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l661t1660r740b1686],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_16	[p1l756t1660r805b1686],
13	15th	JJ	ORDINAL	15th	prep_from	10	SENT_16	[p1l824t1660r892b1686],
14	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l908t1665r938b1686],
15	19th	JJ	ORDINAL	19th	amod	16	SENT_16	[p1l957t1660r1025b1686],
16	centuries	NNS	DURATION	century	prep_to	13	SENT_16	[p1l1041t1661r1198b1691],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1041t1661r1198b1691],
18	when	WRB	O	when	advmod	35	SENT_16	[p1l188t1706r274b1732],
19	large	JJ	O	large	amod	21	SENT_16	[p1l288t1706r367b1741],
20	scale	NN	O	scale	nn	21	SENT_16	[p1l382t1706r458b1732],
21	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	dep	18	SENT_16	[p1l472t1706r632b1732],
22	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l647t1707r677b1731],
23	port	NN	O	port	nn	24	SENT_16	[p1l692t1712r762b1741],
24	cities	NNS	O	city	prep_in	21	SENT_16	[p1l776t1707r858b1732],
25	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l873t1706r908b1732],
26	North	NNP	LOCATION	North	prep_of	24	SENT_16	[p1l918t1706r1016b1732],
27	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1031t1706r1090b1732],
28	South	NNP	LOCATION	South	conj_and	26	SENT_16	[p1l1104t1706r1199b1732],
29	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	nsubj	35	SENT_16	[p1l188t1752r334b1783],
30	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l188t1752r334b1783],
31	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	nsubj	35	SENT_16	[p1l356t1752r465b1783],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l356t1752r465b1783],
33	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l489t1752r548b1778],
34	Europe	NNP	LOCATION	Europe	nsubj	35	SENT_16	[p1l569t1753r688b1787],
35	caused	VBD	O	cause	dep	16	SENT_16	[p1l711t1752r819b1778],
36	devastating	VBG	O	devastate	amod	37	SENT_16	[p1l842t1752r1027b1787],
37	mortality	NN	O	mortality	dobj	35	SENT_16	[p1l1049t1752r1199b1787],
38	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l189t1798r248b1824],
39	helped	VBD	O	help	conj_and	35	SENT_16	[p1l276t1798r386b1833],
40	to	TO	O	to	aux	41	SENT_16	[p1l415t1803r445b1824],
41	shape	VB	O	shape	xcomp	39	SENT_16	[p1l474t1798r566b1833],
42	the	DT	O	the	det	43	SENT_16	[p1l595t1798r644b1824],
43	expansion	NN	O	expansion	dobj	41	SENT_16	[p1l672t1799r839b1833],
44	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l867t1798r902b1824],
45	settlements	NNS	O	settlement	prep_of	43	SENT_16	[p1l926t1798r1111b1824],
46	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1140t1798r1199b1824],
47	colonial	JJ	O	colonial	amod	48	SENT_16	[p1l189t1844r319b1870],
48	powers	NNS	O	power	prep_of	43	SENT_16	[p1l341t1853r463b1879],
49	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l341t1853r463b1879],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_17	[p1l486t1844r548b1870],
2	landmark	NN	O	landmark	nn	3	SENT_17	[p1l570t1844r726b1870],
3	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	9	SENT_17	[p1l748t1844r859b1870],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l881t1844r916b1870],
5	Walter	NNP	PERSON	Walter	nn	6	SENT_17	[p1l934t1844r1044b1870],
6	Reed	NNP	PERSON	Reed	prep_of	3	SENT_17	[p1l1065t1844r1146b1870],
7	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1168t1845r1199b1869],
8	1900-1901	CD	DATE	1900-1901	prep_in	6	SENT_17	[p1l192t1890r358b1915],
9	established	VBD	O	establish	dep	21	SENT_17	[p1l389t1890r568b1916],
10	that	IN	O	that	complm	14	SENT_17	[p1l596t1890r659b1916],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_17	[p1l687t1890r736b1916],
12	disease	NN	O	disease	nsubj	14	SENT_17	[p1l763t1890r876b1916],
13	was	VBD	O	be	cop	14	SENT_17	[p1l902t1899r958b1916],
14	transmissible	JJ	O	transmissible	ccomp	9	SENT_17	[p1l987t1890r1199b1916],
15	among	IN	O	among	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l189t1945r299b1971],
16	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_among	14	SENT_17	[p1l317t1936r443b1962],
17	via	IN	O	via	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l462t1937r508b1962],
18	Aedes	NNP	MISC	Aedes	nn	19	SENT_17	[p1l523t1936r604b1962],
19	aegypti	NNS	O	aegyptus	prep_via	16	SENT_17	[p1l622t1937r722b1971],
20	mosquitoes	NNS	O	mosquito	nsubj	21	SENT_17	[p1l740t1937r924b1971],
21	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l945t1936r990b1968],
22	1	CD	NUMBER	1	number	23	SENT_17	[p1l945t1936r990b1968],
23	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	21	SENT_17	[p1l945t1936r990b1968],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l945t1936r990b1968],

1	Within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1009t1936r1121b1962],
2	one	CD	DURATION	one	num	3	SENT_18	[p1l1140t1945r1199b1962],
3	year	NN	NUMBER	year	prep_within	13	SENT_18	[p1l188t1991r261b2017],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l289t1982r325b2008],
5	Reed	NNP	PERSON	Reed	poss	7	SENT_18	[p1l350t1982r457b2008],
6	’s	POS	O	’s	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l350t1982r457b2008],
7	discovery	NN	O	discovery	prep_of	3	SENT_18	[p1l487t1982r655b2017],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l487t1982r655b2017],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_18	[p1l686t1982r738b2008],
10	disease	NN	O	disease	nsubjpass	13	SENT_18	[p1l767t1982r885b2008],
11	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	13	SENT_18	[p1l914t1991r972b2008],
12	successfully	RB	O	successfully	advmod	13	SENT_18	[p1l1002t1982r1199b2017],
13	controlled	VBN	O	control	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l189t2028r358b2054],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l377t2029r407b2053],
15	Cuba	NNP	LOCATION	Cuba	prep_in	13	SENT_18	[p1l426t2028r510b2054],
16	as	IN	O	as	mark	24	SENT_18	[p1l529t2037r558b2054],
17	a	DT	O	a	det	18	SENT_18	[p1l577t2037r593b2054],
18	result	NN	O	result	nsubj	24	SENT_18	[p1l612t2028r702b2054],
19	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l720t2028r755b2054],
20	vigilant	JJ	O	vigilant	amod	23	SENT_18	[p1l770t2028r891b2063],
21	mosquito	NN	O	mosquito	nn	23	SENT_18	[p1l910t2029r1061b2063],
22	control	NN	O	control	nn	23	SENT_18	[p1l1080t2028r1199b2054],
23	campaigns	NNS	O	campaign	prep_of	18	SENT_18	[p1l189t2075r360b2109],
24	[	VBP	O	[	advcl	13	SENT_18	[p1l385t2074r430b2106],
25	2	CD	NUMBER	2	number	26	SENT_18	[p1l385t2074r430b2106],
26	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	24	SENT_18	[p1l385t2074r430b2106],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l385t2074r430b2106],

1	Twenty-eight	CD	DATE	twenty-eight	num	2	SENT_19	[p1l452t2074r668b2109],
2	years	NNS	DATE	year	npadvmod	3	SENT_19	[p1l688t2083r770b2109],
3	later	RB	DATE	later	advmod	15	SENT_19	[p1l792t2074r874b2105],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l792t2074r874b2105],
5	yellow	JJ	O	yellow	amod	7	SENT_19	[p1l896t2074r998b2109],
6	fever	NN	O	fever	nn	7	SENT_19	[p1l1019t2074r1100b2100],
7	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubj	15	SENT_19	[p1l1121t2075r1198b2100],
8	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	9	SENT_19	[p1l190t2121r280b2152],
9	YFV	NN	O	yfv	dep	7	SENT_19	[p1l190t2121r280b2152],
10	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	7	SENT_19	[p1l190t2121r280b2152],
11	became	VBD	O	become	cop	15	SENT_19	[p1l295t2120r418b2146],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_19	[p1l433t2120r483b2146],
13	first	JJ	ORDINAL	first	amod	15	SENT_19	[p1l497t2120r560b2146],
14	mosquito-borne	JJ	O	mosquito-borne	amod	15	SENT_19	[p1l575t2120r838b2155],
15	virus	NN	O	virus	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l852t2121r930b2146],
16	to	TO	O	to	aux	18	SENT_19	[p1l945t2125r975b2146],
17	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	18	SENT_19	[p1l990t2120r1027b2146],
18	identiﬁed	VBN	O	identiﬁed	xcomp	15	SENT_19	[p1l1043t2120r1199b2146],
19	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	20	SENT_19	[p1l191t2166r237b2198],
20	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	21	SENT_19	[p1l191t2166r237b2198],
21	]	NN	O	]	dobj	18	SENT_19	[p1l191t2166r237b2198],
22	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l191t2166r237b2198],

1	Despite	IN	O	despite	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l266t2167r391b2201],
2	this	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_20	[p1l421t2166r478b2192],
3	legacy	NN	O	legacy	prep_despite	8	SENT_20	[p1l506t2166r615b2201],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l506t2166r615b2201],
5	YF	NN	O	yf	nsubjpass	8	SENT_20	[p1l643t2167r687b2191],
6	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	8	SENT_20	[p1l716t2167r738b2192],
7	currently	RB	DATE	currently	advmod	8	SENT_20	[p1l767t2166r920b2201],
8	classiﬁed	VBN	O	classiﬁed	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l948t2166r1096b2192],
9	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1125t2175r1154b2192],
10	a	DT	O	a	det	12	SENT_20	[p1l1183t2175r1199b2192],
11	reemerging	VBG	O	reemerge	amod	12	SENT_20	[p1l190t2213r382b2247],
12	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_as	8	SENT_20	[p1l409t2212r525b2238],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l554t2212r614b2238],
14	remains	VBZ	O	remain	cop	17	SENT_20	[p1l643t2213r775b2238],
15	a	DT	O	a	det	17	SENT_20	[p1l804t2221r820b2238],
16	signiﬁcant	JJ	O	signiﬁcant	amod	17	SENT_20	[p1l848t2212r1021b2247],
17	cause	NN	O	cause	conj_and	8	SENT_20	[p1l1050t2221r1138b2238],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1167t2212r1202b2238],
19	morbidity	NN	O	morbidity	prep_of	17	SENT_20	[p1l189t2257r351b2292],
20	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l375t2257r434b2283],
21	mortality	NN	O	mortality	prep_of	17	SENT_20	[p1l457t2257r615b2292],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l457t2257r615b2292],
23	with	IN	O	with	conj_and	8	SENT_20	[p1l638t2257r708b2283],
24	an	DT	O	a	det	27	SENT_20	[p1l732t2266r769b2283],
25	estimated	VBN	O	estimate	amod	27	SENT_20	[p1l793t2257r950b2283],
26	200,000	CD	NUMBER	200,000	num	27	SENT_20	[p1l974t2257r1095b2288],
27	cases	NNS	O	case	pobj	23	SENT_20	[p1l1119t2266r1198b2283],
28	each	DT	SET	each	det	29	SENT_20	[p1l189t2303r262b2329],
29	year	NN	SET	year	nsubj	33	SENT_20	[p1l277t2312r347b2338],
30	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l363t2303r422b2329],
31	30,000	CD	NUMBER	30,000	num	32	SENT_20	[p1l439t2303r541b2334],
32	deaths	NNS	O	death	nsubj	33	SENT_20	[p1l558t2303r662b2329],
33	[	VBP	O	[	rcmod	27	SENT_20	[p1l681t2303r754b2335],
34	4,5	CD	NUMBER	4,5	number	35	SENT_20	[p1l681t2303r754b2335],
35	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	33	SENT_20	[p1l681t2303r754b2335],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l681t2303r754b2335],

1	Indeed	RB	O	indeed	advmod	13	SENT_21	[p1l771t2303r891b2334],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l771t2303r891b2334],
3	although	IN	O	although	mark	9	SENT_21	[p1l909t2303r1052b2338],
4	a	DT	O	a	det	7	SENT_21	[p1l1069t2312r1085b2329],
5	highly	RB	O	highly	advmod	6	SENT_21	[p1l1100t2303r1199b2338],
6	effective	JJ	O	effective	amod	7	SENT_21	[p1l189t2350r326b2376],
7	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nsubj	9	SENT_21	[p1l340t2351r460b2376],
8	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	9	SENT_21	[p1l475t2351r497b2376],
9	available	JJ	O	available	advcl	13	SENT_21	[p1l511t2350r660b2381],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l511t2350r660b2381],
11	epidemiological	JJ	O	epidemiological	amod	12	SENT_21	[p1l675t2350r935b2385],
12	data	NNS	O	datum	nsubj	13	SENT_21	[p1l949t2350r1018b2376],
13	suggest	VBP	O	suggest	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1031t2355r1147b2385],
14	an	DT	O	a	det	16	SENT_21	[p1l1161t2359r1199b2376],
15	alarming	JJ	O	alarming	amod	16	SENT_21	[p1l189t2395r334b2430],
16	resurgence	NN	O	resurgence	dobj	13	SENT_21	[p1l349t2404r526b2430],
17	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l542t2395r577b2421],
18	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	19	SENT_21	[p1l588t2396r666b2421],
19	circulation	NN	O	circulation	prep_of	16	SENT_21	[p1l681t2395r859b2421],
20	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l875t2396r905b2420],
21	West	NNP	LOCATION	West	nn	22	SENT_21	[p1l919t2396r999b2421],
22	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_in	19	SENT_21	[p1l1012t2395r1114b2421],
23	over	IN	O	over	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1129t2404r1200b2421],
24	the	DT	DURATION	the	det	27	SENT_21	[p1l190t2441r239b2467],
25	last	JJ	DATE	last	amod	27	SENT_21	[p1l260t2441r314b2467],
26	20	CD	DATE	20	num	27	SENT_21	[p1l334t2441r369b2468],
27	years	NNS	DATE	year	prep_over	13	SENT_21	[p1l390t2450r472b2476],
28	[	CD	DATE	[	number	29	SENT_21	[p1l494t2439r567b2473],
29	6,7	CD	NUMBER	6,7	num	30	SENT_21	[p1l494t2439r567b2473],
30	]	NN	O	]	dep	13	SENT_21	[p1l494t2439r567b2473],
31	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l494t2439r567b2473],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_22	[p1l588t2441r651b2467],
2	failure	NN	O	failure	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l671t2441r777b2467],
3	to	TO	O	to	aux	4	SENT_22	[p1l799t2447r829b2467],
4	implement	VB	O	implement	infmod	2	SENT_22	[p1l850t2441r1027b2476],
5	sustained	JJ	O	sustained	amod	8	SENT_22	[p1l1047t2441r1199b2467],
6	vaccination	NN	O	vaccination	nn	8	SENT_22	[p1l188t2488r377b2513],
7	programs	NNS	O	program	nn	8	SENT_22	[p1l400t2496r555b2522],
8	reﬂects	NNS	O	reﬂects	dobj	4	SENT_22	[p1l579t2487r695b2513],
9	larger	JJR	O	larger	amod	10	SENT_22	[p1l719t2487r815b2522],
10	problems	NNS	O	problem	dep	2	SENT_22	[p1l838t2487r989b2522],
11	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1013t2487r1047b2513],
12	poverty	NN	O	poverty	prep_of	10	SENT_22	[p1l1068t2492r1198b2522],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1068t2492r1198b2522],
14	civil	JJ	O	civil	amod	15	SENT_22	[p1l189t2533r257b2559],
15	war	NN	O	war	prep_of	10	SENT_22	[p1l285t2542r353b2564],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l285t2542r353b2564],
17	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l382t2533r442b2559],
18	the	DT	O	the	det	19	SENT_22	[p1l472t2533r523b2559],
19	inaccessibility	NN	O	inaccessibility	conj_and	12	SENT_22	[p1l552t2533r786b2568],
20	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l815t2533r850b2559],
21	rural	JJ	O	rural	amod	22	SENT_22	[p1l876t2533r957b2559],
22	areas	NNS	O	area	prep_of	19	SENT_22	[p1l986t2542r1070b2559],
23	where	WRB	O	where	advmod	28	SENT_22	[p1l1098t2533r1198b2559],
24	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	nsubj	28	SENT_22	[p1l189t2579r349b2605],
25	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l364t2579r399b2605],
26	the	DT	O	the	det	27	SENT_22	[p1l411t2579r461b2605],
27	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_of	24	SENT_22	[p1l476t2579r589b2605],
28	occur	VBP	O	occur	rcmod	10	SENT_22	[p1l604t2588r696b2605],
29	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	30	SENT_22	[p1l712t2579r757b2611],
30	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	31	SENT_22	[p1l712t2579r757b2611],
31	]	NN	O	]	dobj	28	SENT_22	[p1l712t2579r757b2611],
32	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l712t2579r757b2611],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_23	[p1l226t2625r288b2651],
2	agent	NN	O	agent	nsubj	15	SENT_23	[p1l301t2631r389b2660],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l400t2625r435b2651],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_23	[p1l444t2625r493b2651],
5	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_of	2	SENT_23	[p1l505t2625r626b2656],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l505t2625r626b2656],
7	YFV	NN	O	yfv	appos	5	SENT_23	[p1l637t2626r715b2656],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l637t2626r715b2656],
9	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	15	SENT_23	[p1l728t2626r750b2651],
10	a	DT	O	a	det	15	SENT_23	[p1l762t2634r778b2651],
11	single-stranded	JJ	O	single-stranded	amod	15	SENT_23	[p1l790t2625r1047b2660],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l790t2625r1047b2660],
13	positivesense	JJ	O	positivesense	amod	15	SENT_23	[p1l1060t2626r1198b2660, p1l189t2681r273b2698],
14	RNA	NN	O	rna	nn	15	SENT_23	[p1l287t2672r365b2698],
15	virus	NN	O	virus	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l379t2673r457b2698],
16	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l471t2672r540b2698],
17	a	DT	O	a	det	18	SENT_23	[p1l555t2681r571b2698],
18	genome	NN	O	genome	prep_with	15	SENT_23	[p1l585t2681r713b2707],
19	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l727t2672r762b2698],
20	approximately	RB	O	approximately	quantmod	21	SENT_23	[p1l774t2672r1011b2707],
21	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	22	SENT_23	[p1l1028t2672r1058b2697],
22	kb	NN	O	kb	prep_of	18	SENT_23	[p1l1075t2672r1121b2698],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1075t2672r1121b2698],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_24	[p1l1137t2672r1199b2698],
2	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubj	5	SENT_24	[p1l188t2719r266b2744],
3	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	5	SENT_24	[p1l280t2719r302b2744],
4	a	DT	O	a	det	5	SENT_24	[p1l316t2727r332b2744],
5	member	NN	O	member	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l344t2718r480b2744],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l492t2718r527b2744],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_24	[p1l537t2718r586b2744],
8	genus	NN	O	genus	nn	11	SENT_24	[p1l599t2727r691b2753],
9	Flavivirus	NN	O	flavivirus	nn	11	SENT_24	[p1l702t2718r852b2744],
10	(	NN	O	(	nn	11	SENT_24	[p1l866t2718r977b2753],
11	family	NN	O	family	prep_of	5	SENT_24	[p1l866t2718r977b2753],
12	Flaviviridae	FW	O	flaviviridae	nn	13	SENT_24	[p1l988t2718r1198b2750],
13	)	FW	O	)	tmod	11	SENT_24	[p1l988t2718r1198b2750],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l988t2718r1198b2750],
15	which	WDT	O	which	nsubj	16	SENT_24	[p1l188t2763r284b2789],
16	contains	VBZ	O	contain	rcmod	13	SENT_24	[p1l300t2764r436b2789],
17	a	DT	O	a	det	18	SENT_24	[p1l453t2772r469b2789],
18	number	NN	O	number	dobj	16	SENT_24	[p1l485t2763r614b2789],
19	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l628t2763r663b2789],
20	important	JJ	O	important	amod	36	SENT_24	[p1l676t2764r843b2798],
21	vector-borne	JJ	O	vector-borne	amod	23	SENT_24	[p1l858t2763r1070b2789],
22	human	JJ	O	human	amod	23	SENT_24	[p1l1086t2763r1199b2789],
23	pathogens	NNS	O	pathogen	tmod	20	SENT_24	[p1l189t2809r364b2844],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l189t2809r364b2844],
25	such	JJ	O	such	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l386t2809r458b2835],
26	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l479t2818r508b2835],
27	the	DT	O	the	det	28	SENT_24	[p1l531t2809r581b2835],
28	dengue	NN	O	dengue	prep_such_as	23	SENT_24	[p1l603t2809r728b2844],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l603t2809r728b2844],
30	Japanese	JJ	MISC	japanese	amod	31	SENT_24	[p1l744t2810r892b2844],
31	encephalitis	NN	O	encephalitis	conj_and	28	SENT_24	[p1l914t2809r1117b2844],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l914t2809r1117b2844],
33	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1140t2809r1199b2835],
34	West	NNP	O	West	nn	35	SENT_24	[p1l188t2856r267b2881],
35	Nile	NNP	O	Nile	conj_and	28	SENT_24	[p1l282t2855r349b2881],
36	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_of	18	SENT_24	[p1l364t2856r483b2881],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l364t2856r483b2881],

1	Previous	JJ	O	previous	amod	3	SENT_25	[p1l500t2856r638b2881],
2	evolutionary	JJ	O	evolutionary	amod	3	SENT_25	[p1l655t2855r860b2890],
3	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	4	SENT_25	[p1l876t2855r987b2881],
4	suggest	VBP	O	suggest	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1004t2860r1120b2890],
5	that	IN	O	that	complm	7	SENT_25	[p1l1136t2855r1199b2881],
6	YFV	NN	O	yfv	nsubj	7	SENT_25	[p1l188t2902r259b2927],
7	originated	VBD	O	originate	ccomp	4	SENT_25	[p1l277t2901r446b2936],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l466t2902r496b2926],
9	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_in	7	SENT_25	[p1l514t2901r622b2932],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l514t2901r622b2932],
11	as	IN	O	as	mark	19	SENT_25	[p1l642t2910r671b2927],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_25	[p1l692t2901r741b2927],
13	deepest	JJS	O	deepest	amod	15	SENT_25	[p1l760t2901r883b2936],
14	phylogenetic	JJ	O	phylogenetic	amod	15	SENT_25	[p1l902t2901r1110b2936],
15	split	NN	O	split	nsubj	19	SENT_25	[p1l1130t2901r1199b2936],
16	among	IN	O	among	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l189t2956r299b2982],
17	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	18	SENT_25	[p1l309t2947r381b2973],
18	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	prep_among	15	SENT_25	[p1l393t2953r555b2982],
19	is	VBZ	O	be	advcl	7	SENT_25	[p1l568t2948r590b2973],
20	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l601t2947r736b2973],
21	those	DT	O	those	det	22	SENT_25	[p1l749t2947r833b2973],
22	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	prep_between	19	SENT_25	[p1l845t2947r962b2973],
23	sampled	VBN	O	sample	partmod	22	SENT_25	[p1l974t2947r1108b2982],
24	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1119t2947r1199b2973],
25	East	NNP	O	East	prep_from	23	SENT_25	[p1l188t2994r255b3019],
26	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l267t2993r326b3019],
27	West	NNP	LOCATION	West	nn	28	SENT_25	[p1l337t2994r416b3019],
28	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	conj_and	25	SENT_25	[p1l427t2993r529b3019],
29	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	30	SENT_25	[p1l542t2993r646b3025],
30	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	31	SENT_25	[p1l542t2993r646b3025],
31	—	NN	O	—	dep	28	SENT_25	[p1l542t2993r646b3025],
32	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	33	SENT_25	[p1l542t2993r646b3025],
33	]	NN	O	]	dep	28	SENT_25	[p1l542t2993r646b3025],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l542t2993r646b3025],

1	What	WP	O	what	nsubj	4	SENT_26	[p1l658t2993r745b3019],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	4	SENT_26	[p1l757t2994r779b3019],
3	less	JJR	O	less	advmod	4	SENT_26	[p1l791t2993r845b3019],
4	clear	JJ	O	clear	dep	6	SENT_26	[p1l858t2993r944b3024],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l858t2993r944b3024],
6	however	RB	O	however	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l957t2993r1100b3024],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l957t2993r1100b3024],
8	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	9	SENT_26	[p1l1114t2994r1136b3019],
9	the	DT	O	the	dep	6	SENT_26	[p1l1150t2993r1199b3019],

1	q	NN	O	q	nsubj	4	SENT_27	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
2	{	CD	NUMBER	{	num	3	SENT_27	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
3	PLoS	NN	O	plo	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l288t3093r352b3116],
4	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l367t3092r511b3123],
5	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	6	SENT_27	[p1l526t3091r528b3124],
6	www	NN	O	www	dobj	4	SENT_27	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	4	SENT_28	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	4	SENT_28	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	nn	4	SENT_28	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
4	timing	NN	O	timing	nsubj	25	SENT_28	[p1l1278t1477r1384b1511],
5	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1399t1476r1458b1502],
6	mechanism	NN	O	mechanism	nsubj	25	SENT_28	[p1l1474t1476r1658b1502],
7	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1673t1476r1710b1511],
8	which	WDT	O	which	agent	11	SENT_28	[p1l1725t1476r1820b1502],
9	YFV	NN	O	yfv	nsubjpass	11	SENT_28	[p1l1835t1477r1905b1502],
10	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	11	SENT_28	[p1l1920t1485r1976b1502],
11	introduced	VBN	O	introduce	rcmod	6	SENT_28	[p1l1992t1476r2173b1502],
12	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l2190t1481r2220b1502],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_28	[p1l2237t1476r2286b1502],
14	Americas	NNPS	LOCATION	Americas	prep_to	11	SENT_28	[p1l1275t1523r1432b1548],
15	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1461t1522r1521b1548],
16	whether	IN	O	whether	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1549t1522r1686b1548],
17	the	DT	O	the	det	18	SENT_28	[p1l1714t1522r1764b1548],
18	descendants	NNS	O	descendant	prep_whether	11	SENT_28	[p1l1793t1522r1996b1548],
19	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l2025t1522r2061b1548],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	23	SENT_28	[p1l2087t1522r2137b1548],
21	earliest	JJS	O	earliest	amod	23	SENT_28	[p1l2165t1522r2287b1548],
22	imported	VBN	O	import	amod	23	SENT_28	[p1l1277t1569r1429b1604],
23	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_of	18	SENT_28	[p1l1443t1570r1554b1595],
24	still	RB	O	still	advmod	23	SENT_28	[p1l1569t1569r1626b1595],
25	circulate	VBP	O	circulate	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1641t1569r1782b1595],
26	today	NN	DATE	today	tmod	25	SENT_28	[p1l1799t1569r1894b1604],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1799t1569r1894b1604],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_29	[p1l1314t1615r1376b1641],
2	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	4	SENT_29	[p1l1391t1620r1469b1641],
3	commonly	RB	O	commonly	advmod	4	SENT_29	[p1l1483t1615r1654b1650],
4	cited	VBN	O	cite	amod	5	SENT_29	[p1l1668t1615r1747b1641],
5	hypothesis	NN	O	hypothesis	nsubj	14	SENT_29	[p1l1762t1615r1933b1650],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1948t1615r1983b1641],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_29	[p1l1995t1615r2044b1641],
8	origin	NN	O	origin	prep_of	5	SENT_29	[p1l2059t1616r2157b1650],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2172t1615r2206b1641],
10	YFV	NN	O	yfv	prep_of	8	SENT_29	[p1l2216t1616r2287b1641],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1277t1663r1308b1687],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_29	[p1l1322t1662r1371b1688],
13	Americas	NNPS	LOCATION	Americas	prep_in	5	SENT_29	[p1l1384t1663r1536b1688],
14	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1551t1663r1573b1688],
15	that	IN	O	that	complm	19	SENT_29	[p1l1588t1662r1651b1688],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_29	[p1l1666t1662r1715b1688],
17	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubjpass	19	SENT_29	[p1l1729t1663r1806b1688],
18	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	19	SENT_29	[p1l1820t1671r1876b1688],
19	introduced	VBN	O	introduce	ccomp	14	SENT_29	[p1l1891t1662r2071b1688],
20	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2085t1662r2164b1688],
21	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_from	19	SENT_29	[p1l2177t1662r2286b1693],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2177t1662r2286b1693],
23	along	IN	O	along	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1277t1708r1366b1743],
24	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1377t1708r1447b1734],
25	A.	NN	O	a.	nn	26	SENT_29	[p1l1458t1709r1488b1733],
26	aegypti	NNS	O	aegyptus	prep_along_with	19	SENT_29	[p1l1502t1709r1608b1743],
27	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1502t1709r1608b1743],
28	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1623t1709r1653b1733],
29	the	DT	O	the	det	30	SENT_29	[p1l1668t1708r1717b1734],
30	bilges	NNS	O	bilge	prep_in	19	SENT_29	[p1l1730t1708r1821b1743],
31	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1835t1708r1870b1734],
32	sailing	NN	O	sailing	nn	33	SENT_29	[p1l1880t1708r1984b1743],
33	vessels	NNS	O	vessel	prep_of	30	SENT_29	[p1l1996t1708r2100b1734],
34	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2114t1708r2223b1743],
35	the	DT	O	the	det	37	SENT_29	[p1l2237t1708r2286b1734],
36	slave	NN	O	slave	nn	37	SENT_29	[p1l1277t1754r1354b1780],
37	trade	NN	O	trade	prep_during	19	SENT_29	[p1l1383t1754r1475b1780],
38	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1383t1754r1475b1780],

1	Subsequent	JJ	O	subsequent	nsubj	43	SENT_30	[p1l1505t1754r1696b1789],
2	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1725t1759r1755b1780],
3	devastating	VBG	O	devastate	amod	5	SENT_30	[p1l1784t1754r1971b1789],
4	urban	JJ	O	urban	amod	5	SENT_30	[p1l1998t1754r2096b1780],
5	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	prep_to	1	SENT_30	[p1l2124t1754r2286b1780],
6	within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1276t1801r1379b1827],
7	port	NN	O	port	nn	8	SENT_30	[p1l1396t1806r1465b1836],
8	cities	NNS	O	city	prep_within	5	SENT_30	[p1l1482t1802r1564b1827],
9	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1581t1810r1621b1827],
10	both	CC	O	both	preconj	12	SENT_30	[p1l1637t1801r1712b1827],
11	the	DT	O	the	dep	12	SENT_30	[p1l1729t1801r1778b1827],
12	east	JJ	O	east	prep_on	8	SENT_30	[p1l1794t1806r1856b1827],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1872t1801r1931b1827],
14	west	JJ	O	west	amod	15	SENT_30	[p1l1947t1806r2016b1827],
15	coasts	NNS	O	coast	prep_on	8	SENT_30	[p1l2033t1806r2128b1827],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l2144t1801r2179b1827],
17	South	NNP	LOCATION	South	nn	18	SENT_30	[p1l2192t1801r2286b1827],
18	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	5	SENT_30	[p1l1275t1848r1422b1878],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1275t1848r1422b1878],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_30	[p1l1436t1847r1486b1873],
21	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubj	22	SENT_30	[p1l1498t1848r1576b1873],
22	established	VBD	O	establish	dep	5	SENT_30	[p1l1590t1847r1769b1873],
23	a	DT	O	a	det	26	SENT_30	[p1l1782t1856r1798b1873],
24	sylvatic	JJ	O	sylvatic	amod	26	SENT_30	[p1l1811t1847r1927b1882],
25	enzootic	JJ	O	enzootic	amod	26	SENT_30	[p1l1941t1848r2078b1873],
26	cycle	NN	O	cycle	dobj	22	SENT_30	[p1l2092t1847r2170b1882],
27	within	IN	O	within	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l2183t1847r2286b1873],
28	the	DT	O	the	det	31	SENT_30	[p1l1278t1893r1327b1919],
29	Amazon	NNP	LOCATION	Amazon	nn	31	SENT_30	[p1l1340t1893r1482b1924],
30	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1340t1893r1482b1924],
31	Araguaia	NNP	LOCATION	Araguaia	prep_within	22	SENT_30	[p1l1496t1893r1651b1928],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1496t1893r1651b1928],
33	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1667t1893r1726b1919],
34	Orinoco	NNP	LOCATION	Orinoco	nn	36	SENT_30	[p1l1741t1893r1876b1919],
35	river	NN	O	river	nn	36	SENT_30	[p1l1892t1894r1969b1919],
36	basins	NNS	O	basin	prep_to	1	SENT_30	[p1l1982t1893r2080b1919],
37	vectored	VBN	O	vector	partmod	36	SENT_30	[p1l2095t1893r2236b1919],
38	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l2250t1893r2287b1928],
39	Haemagogus	NNP	PERSON	Haemagogus	nn	42	SENT_30	[p1l1275t1940r1457b1974],
40	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1482t1939r1541b1965],
41	Sabethes	NNP	LOCATION	Sabethes	conj_and	39	SENT_30	[p1l1566t1939r1685b1965],
42	mosquitoes	NNS	O	mosquito	agent	37	SENT_30	[p1l1710t1940r1894b1974],
43	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1921t1939r2033b1971],
44	12,13	CD	NUMBER	12,13	number	45	SENT_30	[p1l1921t1939r2033b1971],
45	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	43	SENT_30	[p1l1921t1939r2033b1971],
46	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1921t1939r2033b1971],

1	Although	IN	O	although	mark	11	SENT_31	[p1l2058t1939r2211b1974],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_31	[p1l2237t1939r2286b1965],
3	hypothesis	NN	O	hypothesis	nsubjpass	11	SENT_31	[p1l1276t1986r1448b2021],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1464t1986r1499b2012],
5	a	DT	O	a	det	8	SENT_31	[p1l1511t1995r1527b2012],
6	slave	NN	O	slave	nn	8	SENT_31	[p1l1542t1986r1618b2012],
7	trade	NN	O	trade	nn	8	SENT_31	[p1l1635t1986r1718b2012],
8	introduction	NN	O	introduction	prep_of	3	SENT_31	[p1l1734t1986r1943b2012],
9	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	11	SENT_31	[p1l1959t1987r1981b2012],
10	often	RB	O	often	advmod	11	SENT_31	[p1l1997t1986r2081b2012],
11	repeated	VBN	O	repeat	advcl	17	SENT_31	[p1l2098t1986r2248b2021],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l2098t1986r2248b2021],
13	it	PRP	O	it	nsubj	17	SENT_31	[p1l2265t1987r2287b2012],
14	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	17	SENT_31	[p1l1276t2032r1327b2058],
15	not	RB	O	not	neg	17	SENT_31	[p1l1351t2037r1405b2058],
16	been	VBN	O	be	cop	17	SENT_31	[p1l1426t2032r1504b2058],
17	subject	JJ	O	subject	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1527t2032r1640b2067],
18	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1664t2037r1694b2058],
19	rigorous	JJ	O	rigorous	amod	20	SENT_31	[p1l1718t2033r1853b2067],
20	examination	NN	O	examination	prep_to	17	SENT_31	[p1l1876t2033r2081b2058],
21	using	VBG	O	use	xcomp	17	SENT_31	[p1l2103t2033r2190b2067],
22	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	24	SENT_31	[p1l2211t2041r2286b2067],
23	sequence	NN	O	sequence	nn	24	SENT_31	[p1l1277t2087r1426b2113],
24	data	NNS	O	datum	dobj	21	SENT_31	[p1l1454t2078r1524b2104],
25	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1551t2078r1610b2104],
26	modern	JJ	O	modern	amod	28	SENT_31	[p1l1638t2078r1767b2104],
27	phylogenetic	JJ	O	phylogenetic	amod	28	SENT_31	[p1l1795t2078r2005b2113],
28	techniques	NNS	O	technique	dobj	21	SENT_31	[p1l2035t2078r2210b2113],
29	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l2238t2078r2287b2104],
30	estimating	VBG	O	estimate	prepc_for	17	SENT_31	[p1l1277t2126r1447b2160],
31	divergence	NN	O	divergence	nn	32	SENT_31	[p1l1470t2125r1647b2160],
32	times	NNS	O	time	nsubj	33	SENT_31	[p1l1672t2126r1757b2151],
33	[	VBP	O	[	ccomp	30	SENT_31	[p1l1783t2125r1847b2157],
34	14	CD	NUMBER	14	num	35	SENT_31	[p1l1783t2125r1847b2157],
35	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	33	SENT_31	[p1l1783t2125r1847b2157],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1783t2125r1847b2157],

1	Determining	VBG	O	determine	csubj	8	SENT_32	[p1l1872t2126r2081b2160],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_32	[p1l2105t2125r2154b2151],
3	age	NN	O	age	dobj	1	SENT_32	[p1l2179t2134r2231b2160],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l2255t2125r2290b2151],
5	American	JJ	MISC	american	amod	7	SENT_32	[p1l1275t2172r1436b2197],
6	sylvan	NN	O	sylvan	nn	7	SENT_32	[p1l1447t2171r1545b2206],
7	YFV	NN	O	yfv	prep_of	3	SENT_32	[p1l1555t2172r1626b2197],
8	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1637t2172r1659b2197],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1671t2171r1705b2197],
10	particular	JJ	O	particular	amod	11	SENT_32	[p1l1714t2171r1876b2206],
11	interest	NN	O	interest	prep_of	8	SENT_32	[p1l1888t2172r2011b2197],
12	given	VBN	O	give	partmod	11	SENT_32	[p1l2022t2172r2107b2206],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_32	[p1l2120t2171r2169b2197],
14	virtual	JJ	O	virtual	amod	15	SENT_32	[p1l2180t2171r2286b2197],
15	disappearance	NN	O	disappearance	iobj	12	SENT_32	[p1l1277t2217r1512b2252],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1528t2217r1563b2243],
17	urban	JJ	O	urban	amod	18	SENT_32	[p1l1574t2217r1671b2243],
18	(	NN	O	(	prep_of	15	SENT_32	[p1l1688t2217r1822b2249],
19	human	JJ	O	human	amod	22	SENT_32	[p1l1688t2217r1822b2249],
20	)	CD	NUMBER	)	tmod	19	SENT_32	[p1l1688t2217r1822b2249],
21	YFV	NN	O	yfv	nn	22	SENT_32	[p1l1837t2218r1908b2243],
22	transmission	NN	O	transmission	dobj	12	SENT_32	[p1l1924t2218r2129b2243],
23	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l2145t2218r2176b2242],
24	South	NNP	LOCATION	South	nn	25	SENT_32	[p1l2192t2217r2286b2243],
25	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_in	22	SENT_32	[p1l1275t2265r1414b2290],
26	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1434t2265r1464b2289],
27	the	DT	DATE	the	det	29	SENT_32	[p1l1485t2264r1534b2290],
28	20th	JJ	DATE	20th	amod	29	SENT_32	[p1l1555t2264r1626b2291],
29	century	NN	DATE	century	prep_in	12	SENT_32	[p1l1646t2269r1777b2299],
30	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1646t2269r1777b2299],

1	Although	IN	O	although	mark	10	SENT_33	[p1l1796t2264r1949b2299],
2	a	DT	O	a	det	4	SENT_33	[p1l1969t2273r1985b2290],
3	small	JJ	O	small	amod	4	SENT_33	[p1l2004t2264r2087b2290],
4	number	NN	O	number	nsubjpass	10	SENT_33	[p1l2108t2264r2236b2290],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l2255t2264r2290b2290],
6	sporadic	JJ	O	sporadic	amod	7	SENT_33	[p1l1277t2310r1415b2345],
7	cases	NNS	O	case	prep_of	4	SENT_33	[p1l1434t2319r1513b2336],
8	have	VBP	O	have	aux	10	SENT_33	[p1l1531t2310r1604b2336],
9	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	10	SENT_33	[p1l1622t2310r1699b2336],
10	reported	VBN	O	report	advcl	60	SENT_33	[p1l1718t2310r1861b2345],
11	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1879t2310r1959b2336],
12	residents	NNS	O	resident	prep_from	10	SENT_33	[p1l1977t2310r2122b2336],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l2141t2310r2175b2336],
14	urban	JJ	O	urban	amod	15	SENT_33	[p1l2190t2310r2286b2336],
15	areas	NNS	O	area	prep_of	12	SENT_33	[p1l1277t2365r1358b2382],
16	(	VBP	O	(	rcmod	15	SENT_33	[p1l1371t2356r1466b2388],
17	three	CD	NUMBER	three	num	18	SENT_33	[p1l1371t2356r1466b2388],
18	cases	NNS	O	case	dobj	16	SENT_33	[p1l1478t2365r1557b2382],
19	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1569t2357r1599b2381],
20	1942	CD	DATE	1942	prep_in	18	SENT_33	[p1l1614t2356r1686b2383],
21	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1698t2357r1729b2381],
22	Sena	NNP	LOCATION	Sena	nn	27	SENT_33	[p1l1740t2356r1817b2382],
23	Madureira	NNP	LOCATION	Madureira	nn	27	SENT_33	[p1l1828t2356r2006b2387],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1828t2356r2006b2387],
25	Acra	NNP	PERSON	Acra	appos	27	SENT_33	[p1l2017t2357r2102b2387],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l2017t2357r2102b2387],
27	Brazil	NNP	LOCATION	Brazil	prep_in	16	SENT_33	[p1l2114t2356r2207b2382],
28	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	27	SENT_33	[p1l2221t2356r2286b2388],
29	15	CD	NUMBER	15	num	30	SENT_33	[p1l2221t2356r2286b2388],
30	]	NN	O	]	dep	27	SENT_33	[p1l2221t2356r2286b2388],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l2221t2356r2286b2388],
32	15	CD	NUMBER	15	num	33	SENT_33	[p1l1279t2403r1313b2428],
33	cases	NNS	O	case	appos	27	SENT_33	[p1l1329t2412r1408b2429],
34	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1426t2404r1456b2428],
35	1954	CD	DATE	1954	prep_in	33	SENT_33	[p1l1475t2403r1548b2428],
36	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1565t2404r1595b2428],
37	Trinidad	NNP	LOCATION	Trinidad	prep_in	33	SENT_33	[p1l1611t2403r1756b2429],
38	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	37	SENT_33	[p1l1774t2403r1839b2435],
39	16	CD	NUMBER	16	num	40	SENT_33	[p1l1774t2403r1839b2435],
40	]	NN	O	]	dep	33	SENT_33	[p1l1774t2403r1839b2435],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1774t2403r1839b2435],
42	six	CD	NUMBER	six	num	43	SENT_33	[p1l1856t2404r1898b2429],
43	cases	NNS	O	case	appos	27	SENT_33	[p1l1915t2412r1994b2429],
44	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l2011t2404r2041b2428],
45	1999	CD	DATE	1999	prep_in	43	SENT_33	[p1l2061t2403r2133b2428],
46	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l2150t2404r2180b2428],
47	Santa	NNP	LOCATION	Santa	nn	51	SENT_33	[p1l2197t2403r2287b2429],
48	Cruz	NNP	LOCATION	Cruz	nn	51	SENT_33	[p1l1277t2449r1353b2475],
49	de	FW	LOCATION	de	nn	51	SENT_33	[p1l1373t2449r1410b2475],
50	la	FW	LOCATION	la	nn	51	SENT_33	[p1l1430t2449r1457b2475],
51	Sierra	NNP	LOCATION	Sierra	prep_in	43	SENT_33	[p1l1478t2449r1582b2480],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1478t2449r1582b2480],
53	Bolivia	NNP	LOCATION	Bolivia	appos	27	SENT_33	[p1l1603t2449r1716b2475],
54	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	53	SENT_33	[p1l1737t2446r1813b2481],
55	17	CD	NUMBER	17	number	56	SENT_33	[p1l1737t2446r1813b2481],
56	]	CD	NUMBER	]	num	57	SENT_33	[p1l1737t2446r1813b2481],
57	)	NN	O	)	dep	53	SENT_33	[p1l1737t2446r1813b2481],
58	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1737t2446r1813b2481],
59	there	EX	O	there	expl	60	SENT_33	[p1l1836t2449r1919b2475],
60	was	VBD	O	be	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1939t2458r1995b2475],
61	no	DT	O	no	det	62	SENT_33	[p1l2016t2458r2055b2475],
62	evidence	NN	O	evidence	nsubj	60	SENT_33	[p1l2077t2449r2219b2475],
63	for	IN	O	for	prep	60	SENT_33	[p1l2239t2449r2288b2475],

1	Editor	NNP	O	Editor	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1277t2566r1361b2587],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1277t2566r1361b2587],
3	Kanta	NNP	PERSON	Kanta	nn	7	SENT_34	[p1l1373t2567r1439b2587],
4	Subbarao	NNP	PERSON	Subbarao	nn	7	SENT_34	[p1l1452t2566r1572b2591],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1452t2566r1572b2591],
6	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	appos	7	SENT_34	[p1l1585t2566r1683b2587],
7	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	dep	1	SENT_34	[p1l1697t2567r1806b2587],
8	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1818t2566r1843b2587],
9	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	nn	12	SENT_34	[p1l1853t2566r1936b2591],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1853t2566r1936b2591],
11	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	appos	12	SENT_34	[p1l1949t2566r2027b2587],
12	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	prep_of	7	SENT_34	[p1l2040t2567r2111b2587],
13	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l2123t2566r2148b2587],
14	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	12	SENT_34	[p1l2157t2567r2254b2587],

1	Received	VBN	O	receive	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1277t2624r1391b2645],
2	January	NNP	DATE	January	nsubj	13	SENT_35	[p1l1402t2625r1496b2651],
3	17	CD	DATE	17	num	2	SENT_35	[p1l1509t2626r1540b2649],
4	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1509t2626r1540b2649],
5	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	2	SENT_35	[p1l1552t2626r1616b2649],
6	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1552t2626r1616b2649],
7	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	amod	2	SENT_35	[p1l1627t2624r1746b2651],
8	April	NNP	DATE	April	tmod	7	SENT_35	[p1l1758t2624r1813b2651],
9	6	CD	DATE	6	num	8	SENT_35	[p1l1825t2626r1844b2649],
10	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1825t2626r1844b2649],
11	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	8	SENT_35	[p1l1856t2626r1919b2649],
12	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1856t2626r1919b2649],
13	Published	VBN	O	publish	dep	1	SENT_35	[p1l1932t2624r2058b2645],
14	May	NNP	DATE	May	tmod	13	SENT_35	[p1l2071t2625r2120b2651],
15	18	CD	DATE	18	num	14	SENT_35	[p1l2133t2626r2164b2649],
16	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l2133t2626r2164b2649],
17	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	14	SENT_35	[p1l2176t2626r2233b2645],

1	Abbreviations	NNS	O	abbreviation	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1276t2840r1465b2861],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1276t2840r1465b2861],
3	dN	NN	O	dn	dep	1	SENT_37	[p1l1482t2840r1516b2866],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1482t2840r1516b2866],
5	nonsynonymous	JJ	O	nonsynonymous	amod	6	SENT_37	[p1l1534t2846r1734b2867],
6	substitution	NN	O	substitution	appos	3	SENT_37	[p1l1752t2840r1902b2865],
7	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1752t2840r1902b2865],
8	ds	JJ	O	ds	amod	10	SENT_37	[p1l1918t2840r1949b2866],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1918t2840r1949b2866],
10	synonymous	JJ	O	synonymous	amod	11	SENT_37	[p1l1967t2846r2119b2867],
11	substitution	NN	O	substitution	dep	3	SENT_37	[p1l2136t2840r2287b2865],
12	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l2136t2840r2287b2865],
13	HPD	NNP	O	HPD	dep	11	SENT_37	[p1l1277t2875r1334b2899],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1277t2875r1334b2899],
15	highest	JJS	O	highest	amod	17	SENT_37	[p1l1344t2874r1432b2901],
16	probability	NN	O	probability	nn	17	SENT_37	[p1l1442t2874r1572b2901],
17	density	NN	O	density	appos	13	SENT_37	[p1l1581t2874r1673b2901],
18	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1581t2874r1673b2901],
19	MAP	NN	O	map	dep	3	SENT_37	[p1l1683t2875r1743b2899],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1683t2875r1743b2899],
21	maximum	NN	O	maximum	appos	19	SENT_37	[p1l1753t2875r1872b2895],
22	a	DT	O	a	det	23	SENT_37	[p1l1882t2880r1893b2895],
23	posteriori	NN	O	posteriorus	dep	21	SENT_37	[p1l1904t2875r2024b2901],
24	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1904t2875r2024b2901],
25	YF	NN	O	yf	dep	3	SENT_37	[p1l2032t2875r2066b2899],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l2032t2875r2066b2899],
27	yellow	JJ	O	yellow	amod	28	SENT_37	[p1l2075t2874r2153b2901],
28	fever	NN	O	fever	appos	25	SENT_37	[p1l2161t2874r2227b2899],
29	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l2161t2874r2227b2899],
30	YFV	NN	O	yfv	dep	3	SENT_37	[p1l2236t2875r2286b2899],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l2236t2875r2286b2899],
32	yellow	JJ	O	yellow	amod	34	SENT_37	[p1l1275t2907r1353b2934],
33	fever	NN	O	fever	nn	34	SENT_37	[p1l1364t2907r1425b2928],
34	virus	NN	O	virus	appos	30	SENT_37	[p1l1435t2908r1491b2928],

1	E	NN	O	e	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1892t2964r1970b2985],
2	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	1	SENT_39	[p1l1892t2964r1970b2985],
3	mai	FW	O	mai	nn	4	SENT_39	[p1l1892t2964r1970b2985],
4	|	FW	O	|	dep	1	SENT_39	[p1l1892t2964r1970b2985],
5	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1892t2964r1970b2985],
6	jebryant@pasteur.fr	NN	O	jebryant@pasteur.fr	nn	9	SENT_39	[p1l1977t2964r2216b2991],
7	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	9	SENT_39	[p1l2226t2965r2287b2989],
8	JEB	NN	O	jeb	nn	9	SENT_39	[p1l2226t2965r2287b2989],
9	)	NN	O	)	dep	1	SENT_39	[p1l2226t2965r2287b2989],
10	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l2226t2965r2287b2989],
11	abarrett@utmb.edu	FW	O	abarrett@utmb.edu	nn	14	SENT_39	[p1l1276t2997r1512b3018],
12	(	FW	O	(	nn	14	SENT_39	[p1l1525t2998r1605b3022],
13	ADTB	NN	O	adtb	nn	14	SENT_39	[p1l1525t2998r1605b3022],
14	)	NN	O	)	dep	9	SENT_39	[p1l1525t2998r1605b3022],

1	inter-human	NN	O	inter-human	nn	2	SENT_40	[p2l189t1232r396b1258],
2	transmission	NN	O	transmission	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l416t1232r623b1258],
3	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l643t1232r752b1267],
4	these	DT	O	these	det	5	SENT_40	[p2l772t1232r854b1258],
5	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	prep_during	2	SENT_40	[p2l874t1232r1042b1258],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l874t1232r1042b1258],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_41	[p2l1063t1232r1125b1258],
2	last	JJ	O	last	amod	3	SENT_41	[p2l1145t1232r1199b1258],
3	documented	JJ	O	documented	nsubj	6	SENT_41	[p2l189t1279r393b1305],
4	Aedes-vectored	JJ	MISC	aedes-vectored	amod	5	SENT_41	[p2l402t1279r639b1305],
5	epidemic	JJ	O	epidemic	amod	3	SENT_41	[p2l651t1279r800b1314],
6	occurred	VBD	O	occur	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l813t1279r959b1305],
7	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l971t1279r1002b1304],
8	1928	CD	DATE	1928	prep_in	6	SENT_41	[p2l1017t1279r1089b1306],
9	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l1102t1279r1132b1304],
10	Rio	NNP	LOCATION	Rio	nn	13	SENT_41	[p2l1144t1279r1198b1305],
11	de	IN	LOCATION	de	amod	13	SENT_41	[p2l189t1325r226b1351],
12	janeiro	NNP	LOCATION	janeiro	nn	13	SENT_41	[p2l237t1325r360b1360],
13	[	NNP	O	[	prep_in	6	SENT_41	[p2l380t1325r444b1357],
14	12	CD	NUMBER	12	number	15	SENT_41	[p2l380t1325r444b1357],
15	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dep	13	SENT_41	[p2l380t1325r444b1357],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l380t1325r444b1357],

1	However	RB	O	however	advmod	22	SENT_42	[p2l462t1326r614b1356],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l462t1326r614b1356],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_42	[p2l633t1325r683b1351],
4	reinfestation	NN	O	reinfestation	nsubj	22	SENT_42	[p2l700t1325r909b1351],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l927t1325r961b1351],
6	many	JJ	O	many	amod	10	SENT_42	[p2l975t1334r1063b1360],
7	densely	RB	O	densely	advmod	8	SENT_42	[p2l1079t1325r1199b1360],
8	populated	JJ	O	populated	amod	10	SENT_42	[p2l189t1372r355b1407],
9	coastal	JJ	O	coastal	amod	10	SENT_42	[p2l370t1372r480b1398],
10	cities	NNS	O	city	prep_of	4	SENT_42	[p2l496t1372r578b1398],
11	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l593t1372r663b1398],
12	A.	NN	O	a.	nn	13	SENT_42	[p2l675t1372r706b1397],
13	aegypti	NNS	O	aegyptus	prep_with	10	SENT_42	[p2l721t1373r822b1407],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l836t1372r895b1398],
15	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_42	[p2l911t1372r960b1398],
16	emergence	NN	O	emergence	conj_and	10	SENT_42	[p2l976t1381r1152b1407],
17	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l1168t1372r1203b1398],
18	dengue	NN	O	dengue	prep_of	16	SENT_42	[p2l189t1418r307b1453],
19	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l335t1418r366b1443],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_42	[p2l395t1418r444b1444],
21	Americas	NNP	LOCATION	Americas	prep_in	18	SENT_42	[p2l471t1418r624b1444],
22	indicates	VBZ	O	indicate	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l652t1418r797b1444],
23	that	IN	O	that	complm	37	SENT_42	[p2l826t1418r890b1444],
24	surveillance	NN	O	surveillance	nsubj	37	SENT_42	[p2l917t1418r1111b1444],
25	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l1140t1418r1199b1444],
26	monitoring	NN	O	monitoring	conj_and	24	SENT_42	[p2l189t1465r376b1500],
27	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l392t1465r427b1491],
28	YF	NN	O	yf	nn	31	SENT_42	[p2l439t1466r483b1490],
29	endemic/epidemic	JJ	O	endemic/epidemic	amod	31	SENT_42	[p2l500t1465r798b1500],
30	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	31	SENT_42	[p2l814t1465r886b1491],
31	activity	NN	O	activity	prep_of	24	SENT_42	[p2l903t1465r1021b1500],
32	remains	VBZ	O	remain	cop	37	SENT_42	[p2l1037t1465r1166b1491],
33	a	DT	O	a	det	37	SENT_42	[p2l1184t1474r1200b1491],
34	critical	JJ	O	critical	amod	37	SENT_42	[p2l189t1512r302b1538],
35	public	JJ	O	public	amod	37	SENT_42	[p2l317t1512r418b1547],
36	health	NN	O	health	nn	37	SENT_42	[p2l433t1512r534b1538],
37	objective	NN	O	objective	ccomp	22	SENT_42	[p2l549t1512r702b1547],
38	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l549t1512r702b1547],

1	To	TO	O	to	aux	2	SENT_43	[p2l226t1560r269b1585],
2	provide	VB	O	provide	ccomp	29	SENT_43	[p2l291t1559r416b1594],
3	an	DT	O	a	det	4	SENT_43	[p2l438t1568r475b1585],
4	insight	NN	O	insight	dobj	2	SENT_43	[p2l497t1559r606b1594],
5	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l627t1568r668b1585],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_43	[p2l690t1559r739b1585],
7	factors	NNS	O	factor	prep_on	2	SENT_43	[p2l760t1559r870b1585],
8	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	9	SENT_43	[p2l893t1559r956b1585],
9	inﬂuence	VBP	O	inﬂuence	rcmod	7	SENT_43	[p2l977t1559r1127b1585],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_43	[p2l1149t1559r1199b1585],
11	emergence	NN	O	emergence	dobj	9	SENT_43	[p2l189t1614r366b1640],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l383t1605r418b1631],
13	YF	NN	O	yf	prep_of	11	SENT_43	[p2l431t1606r475b1630],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l492t1605r523b1630],
15	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_43	[p2l541t1605r590b1631],
16	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	17	SENT_43	[p2l609t1610r665b1631],
17	hemispheres	NNS	O	hemisphere	prep_in	13	SENT_43	[p2l682t1605r887b1640],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l905t1605r964b1631],
19	to	TO	O	to	aux	20	SENT_43	[p2l982t1610r1013b1631],
20	determine	VB	O	determine	conj_and	2	SENT_43	[p2l1031t1605r1199b1631],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_43	[p2l190t1652r240b1678],
22	time-scale	NN	O	time-scale	dobj	20	SENT_43	[p2l270t1652r437b1678],
23	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l466t1652r501b1678],
24	these	DT	O	these	det	25	SENT_43	[p2l527t1652r610b1678],
25	events	NNS	O	event	prep_of	22	SENT_43	[p2l639t1657r751b1683],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l639t1657r751b1683],
27	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	29	SENT_43	[p2l779t1661r822b1678],
28	have	VBP	O	have	aux	29	SENT_43	[p2l849t1652r924b1678],
29	performed	VBN	O	perform	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l953t1652r1132b1687],
30	an	DT	O	a	det	32	SENT_43	[p2l1161t1661r1199b1678],
31	extensive	JJ	O	extensive	amod	32	SENT_43	[p2l189t1698r341b1724],
32	analysis	NN	O	analysis	dobj	29	SENT_43	[p2l369t1698r494b1733],
33	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l522t1698r557b1724],
34	the	DT	O	the	det	36	SENT_43	[p2l583t1698r632b1724],
35	evolutionary	JJ	O	evolutionary	amod	36	SENT_43	[p2l661t1698r869b1733],
36	relationships	NNS	O	relationship	prep_of	32	SENT_43	[p2l897t1698r1111b1733],
37	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l1139t1698r1199b1724],
38	dynamics	NNS	O	dynamics	prep_of	32	SENT_43	[p2l189t1745r340b1780],
39	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l358t1745r393b1771],
40	YFV	NN	O	yfv	prep_of	36	SENT_43	[p2l405t1746r483b1771],
41	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l405t1746r483b1771],

1	To	TO	O	to	aux	2	SENT_44	[p2l501t1746r545b1771],
2	achieve	VB	O	achieve	purpcl	6	SENT_44	[p2l563t1745r682b1771],
3	this	DT	O	this	dobj	2	SENT_44	[p2l701t1745r765b1776],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l701t1745r765b1776],
5	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	6	SENT_44	[p2l782t1754r825b1771],
6	assembled	VBD	O	assemble	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l842t1745r1007b1771],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_44	[p2l1026t1745r1075b1771],
8	largest	JJS	O	largest	amod	10	SENT_44	[p2l1092t1745r1199b1780],
9	data	NNS	O	datum	nn	10	SENT_44	[p2l189t1791r259b1817],
10	set	NN	O	set	dobj	6	SENT_44	[p2l273t1796r316b1817],
11	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l331t1791r366b1817],
12	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	13	SENT_44	[p2l377t1791r449b1817],
13	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	prep_of	10	SENT_44	[p2l464t1791r581b1817],
14	compiled	VBN	O	compile	partmod	13	SENT_44	[p2l597t1791r749b1826],
15	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l765t1796r795b1817],
16	date	NN	O	date	prep_to	14	SENT_44	[p2l811t1791r887b1822],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l811t1791r887b1822],
18	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l903t1791r1058b1826],
19	samples	NNS	O	sample	prep_including	6	SENT_44	[p2l1072t1791r1198b1826],
20	taken	VBN	O	take	partmod	19	SENT_44	[p2l190t1838r278b1864],
21	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l294t1838r374b1864],
22	a	DT	O	a	det	24	SENT_44	[p2l390t1847r406b1864],
23	wide	JJ	O	wide	amod	24	SENT_44	[p2l421t1838r496b1864],
24	range	NN	O	range	prep_from	20	SENT_44	[p2l513t1847r603b1873],
25	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l620t1838r654b1864],
26	geographical	JJ	O	geographical	amod	27	SENT_44	[p2l667t1838r877b1873],
27	localities	NNS	O	locality	prep_of	24	SENT_44	[p2l893t1838r1036b1864],
28	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l1053t1838r1112b1864],
29	over	IN	O	over	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l1129t1847r1200b1864],
30	an	DT	O	a	det	32	SENT_44	[p2l189t1894r227b1911],
31	extensive	JJ	O	extensive	amod	32	SENT_44	[p2l249t1885r398b1911],
32	time-span	NN	O	time-span	prep_over	20	SENT_44	[p2l421t1885r589b1920],
33	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l421t1885r589b1920],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_45	[p2l612t1885r674b1911],
2	fragment	NN	O	fragment	nsubj	3	SENT_45	[p2l696t1885r845b1920],
3	analyzed	VBD	O	analyze	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l867t1885r1006b1920],
4	comprised	VBN	O	comprise	dep	3	SENT_45	[p2l1028t1885r1199b1920],
5	half	NN	O	half	nsubj	11	SENT_45	[p2l188t1931r256b1957],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l282t1931r318b1957],
7	premembrane	NN	O	premembrane	nn	9	SENT_45	[p2l343t1931r584b1966],
8	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	9	SENT_45	[p2l615t1931r701b1966],
9	prM	NN	O	prm	prep_of	5	SENT_45	[p2l615t1931r701b1966],
10	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	11	SENT_45	[p2l615t1931r701b1966],
11	(	NN	O	(	xcomp	4	SENT_45	[p2l732t1931r928b1966],
12	containing	VBG	O	contain	partmod	11	SENT_45	[p2l732t1931r928b1966],
13	an	DT	O	a	det	16	SENT_45	[p2l957t1940r995b1957],
14	important	JJ	O	important	amod	16	SENT_45	[p2l1025t1931r1199b1966],
15	cleavage	NN	O	cleavage	nn	16	SENT_45	[p2l189t1978r324b2013],
16	site	NN	O	site	nn	22	SENT_45	[p2l339t1978r393b2004],
17	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l409t1978r458b2004],
18	pr	NN	O	pr	prep_for	16	SENT_45	[p2l472t1979r596b2013],
19	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	18	SENT_45	[p2l472t1979r596b2013],
20	>	JJR	O	>	dep	21	SENT_45	[p2l472t1979r596b2013],
21	M	NN	O	m	amod	22	SENT_45	[p2l472t1979r596b2013],
22	)	NN	O	)	dobj	12	SENT_45	[p2l472t1979r596b2013],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l472t1979r596b2013],
24	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l613t1978r672b2004],
25	extended	VBN	O	extend	dep	3	SENT_45	[p2l687t1978r837b2004],
26	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l854t1978r983b2013],
27	the	DT	O	the	det	28	SENT_45	[p2l1000t1978r1049b2004],
28	ﬁrst	NN	O	ﬁrst	prep_through	25	SENT_45	[p2l1064t1978r1128b2004],
29	112	CD	NUMBER	112	num	31	SENT_45	[p2l1146t1978r1198b2005],
30	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	31	SENT_45	[p2l189t2024r291b2050],
31	acids	NNS	O	acid	dobj	25	SENT_45	[p2l307t2024r386b2050],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l401t2024r436b2050],
33	envelope	NN	O	envelope	nn	36	SENT_45	[p2l448t2024r593b2059],
34	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	36	SENT_45	[p2l609t2024r655b2056],
35	E	NN	O	e	nn	36	SENT_45	[p2l609t2024r655b2056],
36	)	NN	O	)	prep_of	31	SENT_45	[p2l609t2024r655b2056],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l609t2024r655b2056],

1	This	DT	O	this	det	2	SENT_46	[p2l671t2024r740b2050],
2	region	NN	O	region	nsubjpass	4	SENT_46	[p2l756t2024r861b2059],
3	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	4	SENT_46	[p2l875t2033r931b2050],
4	chosen	VBN	O	choose	dep	16	SENT_46	[p2l946t2024r1058b2050],
5	because	IN	O	because	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l1072t2024r1199b2050],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l189t2071r224b2097],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_46	[p2l234t2071r284b2097],
8	relatively	RB	O	relatively	advmod	9	SENT_46	[p2l297t2071r446b2106],
9	large	JJ	O	large	amod	10	SENT_46	[p2l459t2071r538b2106],
10	data	NNS	O	datum	prep_because_of	4	SENT_46	[p2l551t2071r621b2097],
11	set	VBN	O	set	partmod	10	SENT_46	[p2l633t2076r676b2097],
12	available	JJ	O	available	acomp	11	SENT_46	[p2l689t2071r830b2097],
13	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l843t2071r923b2097],
14	previous	JJ	O	previous	amod	15	SENT_46	[p2l936t2071r1074b2106],
15	studies	NNS	O	study	prep_from	11	SENT_46	[p2l1088t2071r1198b2097],
16	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],
17	9	CD	NUMBER	9	number	18	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],
18	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dobj	16	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],
19	l1	NN	O	l1	dep	18	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],
20	,18	CD	NUMBER	,18	num	19	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],
21	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	23	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],
22	2l	NN	O	2l	nn	23	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],
23	]	NN	O	]	nsubj	16	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l191t2117r400b2149],

1	Further	RB	O	further	advmod	9	SENT_47	[p2l420t2117r553b2148],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l420t2117r553b2148],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_47	[p2l575t2117r624b2143],
4	{	CD	NUMBER	{	num	5	SENT_47	[p2l640t2118r710b2152],
5	NM	NN	O	nm	nsubj	9	SENT_47	[p2l640t2118r710b2152],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l727t2117r786b2143],
7	E	NN	O	e	nn	8	SENT_47	[p2l804t2118r828b2142],
8	genes	NNS	O	gene	conj_and	5	SENT_47	[p2l845t2126r934b2152],
9	are	VBP	O	be	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l955t2126r1004b2143],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1024t2117r1059b2143],
11	interest	NN	O	interest	prep_of	9	SENT_47	[p2l1075t2117r1199b2143],
12	because	IN	O	because	mark	13	SENT_47	[p2l188t2164r315b2190],
13	of	IN	O	of	advcl	9	SENT_47	[p2l329t2164r363b2190],
14	their	PRP$	O	they	poss	16	SENT_47	[p2l374t2164r452b2190],
15	critical	JJ	O	critical	amod	16	SENT_47	[p2l464t2164r577b2190],
16	role	NN	O	role	pobj	13	SENT_47	[p2l590t2164r653b2190],
17	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l666t2164r697b2189],
18	immunity	NN	O	immunity	prep_in	16	SENT_47	[p2l711t2164r869b2199],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l882t2164r941b2190],
20	infectivity	NN	O	infectivity	conj_and	18	SENT_47	[p2l954t2164r1125b2199],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l954t2164r1125b2199],
22	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1140t2164r1199b2190],
23	because	IN	O	because	mark	25	SENT_47	[p2l188t2211r315b2237],
24	they	PRP	O	they	nsubj	25	SENT_47	[p2l343t2211r410b2246],
25	form	VBP	O	form	advcl	9	SENT_47	[p2l436t2211r516b2237],
26	the	DT	O	the	det	28	SENT_47	[p2l543t2211r592b2237],
27	structural	JJ	O	structural	amod	28	SENT_47	[p2l619t2211r778b2237],
28	proteins	NNS	O	protein	dobj	25	SENT_47	[p2l805t2211r940b2246],
29	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l967t2211r1002b2237],
30	the	DT	O	the	det	32	SENT_47	[p2l1026t2211r1075b2237],
31	virion	NN	O	virion	nn	32	SENT_47	[p2l1101t2211r1199b2237],
32	surface	NN	O	surface	prep_of	28	SENT_47	[p2l189t2257r305b2283],
33	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l321t2257r380b2283],
34	are	VBP	O	be	cop	37	SENT_47	[p2l397t2266r446b2283],
35	the	DT	O	the	det	37	SENT_47	[p2l463t2257r513b2283],
36	primary	JJ	O	primary	amod	37	SENT_47	[p2l529t2257r660b2292],
37	antigens	NNS	O	antigen	conj_and	13	SENT_47	[p2l676t2257r811b2292],
38	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	39	SENT_47	[p2l828t2257r891b2283],
39	induce	VBP	O	induce	rcmod	37	SENT_47	[p2l908t2257r1017b2283],
40	protective	JJ	O	protective	amod	41	SENT_47	[p2l1033t2257r1199b2292],
41	immunity	NN	O	immunity	dobj	39	SENT_47	[p2l189t2304r355b2339],
42	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l189t2304r355b2339],

1	From	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l373t2305r461b2330],
2	these	DT	O	these	det	3	SENT_48	[p2l479t2304r561b2330],
3	data	NNS	O	datum	prep_from	6	SENT_48	[p2l579t2304r648b2330],
4	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	6	SENT_48	[p2l664t2313r706b2330],
5	were	VBD	O	be	cop	6	SENT_48	[p2l723t2313r800b2330],
6	able	JJ	O	able	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l818t2304r883b2330],
7	to	TO	O	to	aux	8	SENT_48	[p2l902t2309r932b2330],
8	infer	VB	O	infer	xcomp	6	SENT_48	[p2l950t2304r1029b2330],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_48	[p2l1047t2304r1096b2330],
10	timescale	NN	O	timescale	nn	13	SENT_48	[p2l1115t2304r1198b2330, p2l189t2350r265b2376],
11	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l282t2350r341b2376],
12	evolutionary	JJ	O	evolutionary	conj_and	10	SENT_48	[p2l358t2350r564b2385],
13	history	NN	O	history	dobj	8	SENT_48	[p2l580t2350r693b2385],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l709t2350r743b2376],
15	YFV	NN	O	yfv	prep_of	13	SENT_48	[p2l756t2351r834b2381],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l756t2351r834b2381],
17	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l851t2350r911b2376],
18	provide	VB	O	provide	xcomp	6	SENT_48	[p2l927t2350r1052b2385],
19	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_48	[p2l1070t2350r1119b2376],
20	first	JJ	ORDINAL	first	amod	22	SENT_48	[p2l1136t2350r1199b2376],
21	direct	JJ	O	direct	amod	22	SENT_48	[p2l189t2397r285b2423],
22	evidence	NN	O	evidence	dobj	18	SENT_48	[p2l297t2397r438b2423],
23	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l452t2402r482b2423],
24	our	PRP$	O	we	poss	25	SENT_48	[p2l495t2406r552b2423],
25	knowledge	NN	O	knowledge	prep_to	18	SENT_48	[p2l562t2397r736b2432],
26	that	IN	O	that	complm	29	SENT_48	[p2l749t2397r813b2423],
27	YFV	NN	O	yfv	nsubjpass	29	SENT_48	[p2l823t2398r894b2423],
28	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	29	SENT_48	[p2l905t2406r961b2423],
29	introduced	VBN	O	introduce	ccomp	18	SENT_48	[p2l974t2397r1155b2423],
30	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l1168t2402r1198b2423],
31	the	DT	O	the	det	32	SENT_48	[p2l190t2443r239b2469],
32	Americas	NNPS	LOCATION	Americas	prep_to	29	SENT_48	[p2l253t2443r405b2469],
33	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l421t2443r530b2478],
34	the	DT	O	the	det	36	SENT_48	[p2l545t2443r594b2469],
35	slave	NN	O	slave	nn	36	SENT_48	[p2l609t2443r685b2469],
36	trade	NN	O	trade	prep_during	29	SENT_48	[p2l701t2443r792b2469],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l701t2443r792b2469],

1	Results/Discussion	NN	O	results/discussion	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l190t2543r546b2576],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_50	[p2l226t2622r277b2647],
2	examined	VBD	O	examine	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l289t2621r448b2647],
3	YFV	NN	O	yfv	nn	4	SENT_50	[p2l458t2622r529b2647],
4	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	dobj	2	SENT_50	[p2l540t2621r658b2647],
5	representing	VBG	O	represent	xcomp	2	SENT_50	[p2l670t2621r879b2656],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_50	[p2l890t2621r940b2647],
7	global	JJ	O	global	amod	8	SENT_50	[p2l952t2621r1049b2656],
8	diversity	NN	O	diversity	dobj	5	SENT_50	[p2l1061t2621r1199b2656],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l189t2667r224b2693],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_50	[p2l233t2667r282b2693],
11	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_of	8	SENT_50	[p2l294t2667r407b2693],
12	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l418t2667r498b2693],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_50	[p2l511t2667r560b2693],
14	World	NNP	ORGANIZATION	World	nn	16	SENT_50	[p2l571t2667r673b2693],
15	Reference	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Reference	nn	16	SENT_50	[p2l684t2667r849b2693],
16	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	prep_from	5	SENT_50	[p2l861t2667r973b2693],
17	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l983t2667r1032b2693],
18	Emerging	VBG	ORGANIZATION	emerge	amod	19	SENT_50	[p2l1041t2667r1200b2702],
19	Viruses	NNS	ORGANIZATION	virus	prep_for	5	SENT_50	[p2l188t2714r308b2740],
20	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l326t2714r385b2740],
21	Arboviruses	NNS	O	arbovirus	conj_and	19	SENT_50	[p2l401t2714r596b2740],
22	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l614t2719r643b2740],
23	the	DT	O	the	det	24	SENT_50	[p2l661t2714r711b2740],
24	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	prep_at	19	SENT_50	[p2l728t2714r896b2749],
25	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l913t2714r948b2740],
26	Texas	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Texas	nn	28	SENT_50	[p2l961t2715r1054b2740],
27	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	nn	28	SENT_50	[p2l1072t2714r1199b2740],
28	Branch	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Branch	prep_of	24	SENT_50	[p2l188t2761r314b2792],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l188t2761r314b2792],
30	Galveston	NNP	LOCATION	Galveston	appos	28	SENT_50	[p2l328t2761r495b2792],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l328t2761r495b2792],
32	Texas	NNP	LOCATION	Texas	appos	28	SENT_50	[p2l508t2762r609b2792],
33	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l508t2762r609b2792],
34	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	35	SENT_50	[p2l622t2761r735b2787],
35	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	appos	28	SENT_50	[p2l748t2761r849b2787],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l748t2761r849b2787],

1	Novel	JJ	O	novel	amod	3	SENT_51	[p2l862t2761r956b2787],
2	sequence	NN	O	sequence	nn	3	SENT_51	[p2l969t2770r1117b2796],
3	data	NNS	O	datum	nsubjpass	18	SENT_51	[p2l1130t2761r1200b2787],
4	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l189t2807r269b2833],
5	37	CD	NUMBER	37	num	7	SENT_51	[p2l295t2804r331b2832],
6	human	JJ	O	human	amod	7	SENT_51	[p2l357t2807r470b2833],
7	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	prep_from	3	SENT_51	[p2l497t2807r623b2838],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l497t2807r623b2838],
9	21	CD	NUMBER	21	num	11	SENT_51	[p2l651t2807r683b2834],
10	mosquito	NN	O	mosquito	nn	11	SENT_51	[p2l713t2807r864b2842],
11	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	conj_and	7	SENT_51	[p2l892t2807r1017b2838],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l892t2807r1017b2838],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l1045t2807r1104b2833],
14	four	CD	NUMBER	four	num	16	SENT_51	[p2l1130t2807r1200b2833],
15	vertebrate	JJ	O	vertebrate	amod	16	SENT_51	[p2l188t2854r356b2880],
16	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	conj_and	7	SENT_51	[p2l376t2854r494b2880],
17	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	18	SENT_51	[p2l512t2863r568b2880],
18	obtained	VBN	O	obtain	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l588t2854r732b2880],
19	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l751t2854r800b2880],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	23	SENT_51	[p2l819t2854r868b2880],
21	prM/E	NN	O	prm/e	nn	23	SENT_51	[p2l884t2854r983b2889],
22	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	23	SENT_51	[p2l1000t2863r1075b2889],
23	region	NN	O	region	prep_for	18	SENT_51	[p2l1094t2854r1199b2889],
24	(	CD	NUMBER	(	number	25	SENT_51	[p2l190t2897r256b2933],
25	670	CD	NUMBER	670	num	26	SENT_51	[p2l190t2897r256b2933],
26	nucleotides	NNS	O	nucleotide	dep	23	SENT_51	[p2l271t2900r457b2926],
27	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	29	SENT_51	[p2l475t2901r536b2932],
28	nt	NN	O	nt	nn	29	SENT_51	[p2l475t2901r536b2932],
29	]	NN	O	]	dep	23	SENT_51	[p2l475t2901r536b2932],
30	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l475t2901r536b2932],
31	genomic	JJ	O	genomic	amod	32	SENT_51	[p2l551t2900r689b2935],
32	positions	NNS	O	position	appos	23	SENT_51	[p2l705t2900r852b2935],
33	641-1310	CD	NUMBER	641-1310	num	34	SENT_51	[p2l868t2900r1032b2933],
34	)	NN	O	)	dep	32	SENT_51	[p2l868t2900r1032b2933],
35	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l868t2900r1032b2933],

1	Inclusion	NN	O	inclusion	nsubj	11	SENT_52	[p2l1047t2900r1199b2926],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l189t2947r224b2973],
3	an	DT	O	a	quantmod	6	SENT_52	[p2l236t2956r274b2973],
4	additional	JJ	O	additional	quantmod	6	SENT_52	[p2l290t2947r456b2973],
5	71	CD	NUMBER	71	number	6	SENT_52	[p2l472t2944r504b2972],
6	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	8	SENT_52	[p2l519t2947r618b2982],
7	W114/E	NN	O	w114/e	nn	8	SENT_52	[p2l519t2947r618b2982],
8	sequences	NNS	O	sequence	prep_of	1	SENT_52	[p2l631t2956r793b2982],
9	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l809t2947r889b2973],
10	GenBank	NN	ORGANIZATION	genbank	prep_from	8	SENT_52	[p2l904t2947r1053b2973],
11	resulted	VBD	O	result	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l1069t2947r1199b2973],
12	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l189t2993r220b3018],
13	an	DT	O	a	det	14	SENT_52	[p2l242t3002r280b3019],
14	alignment	NN	O	alignment	prep_in	11	SENT_52	[p2l303t2993r467b3028],
15	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l488t2993r523b3019],
16	133	CD	NUMBER	133	num	18	SENT_52	[p2l544t2993r597b3018],
17	wild-type	JJ	O	wild-type	amod	18	SENT_52	[p2l619t2993r770b3028],
18	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	prep_of	14	SENT_52	[p2l793t2993r910b3019],
19	representing	VBG	O	represent	xcomp	11	SENT_52	[p2l933t2993r1141b3028],
20	22	CD	NUMBER	22	dobj	19	SENT_52	[p2l1163t2993r1198b3020],

1	oAO	NNP	O	oAO	nn	2	SENT_53	[p2l188t3077r261b3136],
2	PLoS	NNP	O	PLoS	nsubj	3	SENT_53	[p2l288t3093r352b3116],
3	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l367t3092r511b3123],
4	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	5	SENT_53	[p2l526t3091r528b3124],
5	www	NN	O	www	dobj	3	SENT_53	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_54	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	dep	1	SENT_54	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],

1	Table	NNP	O	Table	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l1275t247r1366b274],
2	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	1	SENT_55	[p2l1382t250r1408b274],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l1382t250r1408b274],

1	Summary	NN	O	summary	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1422t248r1569b282],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1582t247r1614b274],
3	Yellow	NNP	O	Yellow	nn	8	SENT_56	[p2l1624t247r1727b274],
4	Fever	NN	O	fever	nn	8	SENT_56	[p2l1741t249r1824b274],
5	Virus	NN	O	virus	nn	8	SENT_56	[p2l1836t248r1911b274],
6	prM/E	NN	O	prm/e	nn	8	SENT_56	[p2l1923t248r2016b281],
7	Gene	NN	O	gene	nn	8	SENT_56	[p2l2027t248r2107b274],
8	Sequences	NNS	O	sequence	prep_of	1	SENT_56	[p2l2121t248r2286b281],
9	Used	VBN	O	use	partmod	1	SENT_56	[p2l1278t293r1351b320],
10	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1368t294r1393b320],
11	This	DT	O	this	det	12	SENT_56	[p2l1407t293r1469b320],
12	Study	NN	O	study	prep_in	9	SENT_56	[p2l1484t293r1572b328],

1	Country	NN	O	country	nn	2	SENT_57	[p2l1276t390r1394b420],
2	Years	NNS	DURATION	year	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l1714t390r1795b413],
3	Number	NN	O	number	dep	2	SENT_57	[p2l1989t389r2108b413],
4	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l2120t389r2174b413],
5	Source	NN	O	source	dep	2	SENT_57	[p2l2188t390r2287b413],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l1988t431r2018b455],
7	Isolates	NNPS	O	Isolates	nn	9	SENT_57	[p2l2031t431r2141b455],
8	(	NNP	O	(	nn	9	SENT_57	[p2l2155t432r2279b459],
9	Human	NNP	O	Human	prep_of	3	SENT_57	[p2l2155t432r2279b459],
10	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l2155t432r2279b459],
11	Mosquito	NNP	O	Mosquito	dep	3	SENT_57	[p2l1989t472r2135b503],
12	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l1989t472r2135b503],
13	Monkey	NNP	O	Monkey	dep	11	SENT_57	[p2l2149t472r2275b503],
14	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	13	SENT_57	[p2l2149t472r2275b503],
