1	Correction	NN	O	correction	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
3	A	DT	O	a	det	6	SENT_1	[p1l532t282r563b316],
4	New	JJ	O	new	amod	6	SENT_1	[p1l584t282r681b317],
5	Bacillus	NN	O	bacillus	nn	6	SENT_1	[p1l700t280r868b317],
6	anthracis	NNS	O	anthraci	dep	1	SENT_1	[p1l887t280r1091b317],
7	Found	VBN	O	find	partmod	6	SENT_1	[p1l1112t280r1252b317],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1274t280r1312b316],
9	Wild	NNP	O	Wild	nn	10	SENT_1	[p1l1333t280r1432b317],
10	Chimpanzees	NNPS	O	Chimpanzees	prep_in	7	SENT_1	[p1l1454t280r1755b326],
11	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1775t280r1858b317],
12	a	DT	O	a	det	13	SENT_1	[p1l1878t290r1901b317],
13	Gorilla	NNP	O	Gorilla	conj_and	10	SENT_1	[p1l1923t280r2069b317],
14	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l2090t279r2196b317],
15	West	NNP	O	West	nn	18	SENT_1	[p1l263t342r374b377],
16	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l393t340r477b377],
17	Central	NNP	LOCATION	Central	nn	18	SENT_1	[p1l498t340r658b377],
18	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_from	7	SENT_1	[p1l679t339r809b377],

1	Fabian	NNP	PERSON	Fabian	nn	3	SENT_2	[p1l265t412r364b439],
2	H.	NNP	PERSON	H.	nn	3	SENT_2	[p1l382t414r410b439],
3	Leendertz	NNP	PERSON	Leendertz	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l427t412r586b444],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l427t412r586b444],
5	Saniye	NNP	PERSON	Saniye	nn	6	SENT_2	[p1l602t413r700b447],
6	Yumlu	NNP	PERSON	Yumlu	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l715t412r821b444],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l715t412r821b444],
8	Georg	NNP	PERSON	Georg	nn	9	SENT_2	[p1l836t413r929b447],
9	Pauli	NNP	PERSON	Pauli	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l947t412r1026b444],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l947t412r1026b444],
11	Christophe	NNP	PERSON	Christophe	nn	12	SENT_2	[p1l1041t412r1210b446],
12	Boesch	NNP	PERSON	Boesch	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1227t412r1342b444],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1227t412r1342b444],
14	Emmanuel	NNP	PERSON	Emmanuel	nn	15	SENT_2	[p1l1358t412r1520b439],
15	Couacy	NNP	PERSON	Couacy	appos	3	SENT_2	[p1l1536t413r1800b447],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1536t413r1800b447],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1536t413r1800b447],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1536t413r1800b447],

1	Hymann	NNP	PERSON	Hymann	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1536t413r1800b447],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1536t413r1800b447],
3	Linda	NNP	PERSON	Linda	nn	4	SENT_4	[p1l1817t412r1898b439],
4	Vigilant	NNP	PERSON	Vigilant	appos	1	SENT_4	[p1l1913t412r2037b447],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1913t412r2037b447],
6	Sandra	NNP	PERSON	Sandra	nn	7	SENT_4	[p1l264t458r368b485],
7	Junglen	NNP	PERSON	Junglen	appos	1	SENT_4	[p1l383t458r513b493],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l383t458r513b493],
9	Svenja	NNP	PERSON	Svenja	nn	10	SENT_4	[p1l528t459r627b493],
10	Schenk	NNP	PERSON	Schenk	appos	1	SENT_4	[p1l643t458r760b490],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l643t458r760b490],
12	Heinz	NNP	PERSON	Heinz	nn	13	SENT_4	[p1l777t459r862b485],
13	Ellerbrok	NNP	PERSON	Ellerbrok	appos	1	SENT_4	[p1l878t458r1013b485],

1	DOI	NNP	O	DOI	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l265t530r328b556],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l265t530r328b556],
3	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	dep	1	SENT_5	[p1l346t529r807b564],
4	/	:	O	/	punct	6	SENT_5	[p1l346t529r807b564],
5	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	6	SENT_5	[p1l346t529r807b564],
6	|	NN	O	|	dep	3	SENT_5	[p1l346t529r807b564],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l346t529r807b564],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l346t529r807b564],
2	.0020008	CD	NUMBER	.0020008	num	1	SENT_6	[p1l346t529r807b564],

1	In	IN	O	in	dep	9	SENT_7	[p1l265t601r289b626],
2	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	3	SENT_7	[p1l305t600r376b626],
3	Pathogens	NNS	O	pathogen	pobj	1	SENT_7	[p1l390t599r554b634],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l390t599r554b634],
5	vol	NN	O	vol	appos	3	SENT_7	[p1l569t599r613b626],
6	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	5	SENT_7	[p1l630t601r654b631],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l630t601r654b631],
8	issue	NN	O	issue	appos	5	SENT_7	[p1l670t600r744b626],
9	1	CD	NUMBER	1	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l762t602r783b626],
10	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l762t602r783b626],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_8	[p1l262t670r319b697],
2	data	NNS	O	datum	nsubjpass	14	SENT_8	[p1l334t670r400b697],
3	upon	IN	O	upon	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l417t678r495b704],
4	which	WDT	O	which	dobj	10	SENT_8	[p1l511t670r602b697],
5	Figures	NNS	O	figure	nsubjpass	10	SENT_8	[p1l619t671r729b705],
6	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	5	SENT_8	[p1l747t673r755b697],
7	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l776t670r832b697],
8	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	5	SENT_8	[p1l848t672r864b697],
9	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	10	SENT_8	[p1l879t678r926b697],
10	based	VBN	O	base	prepc_upon	2	SENT_8	[p1l942t670r1030b697],
11	had	VBD	O	have	aux	14	SENT_8	[p1l1048t670r1103b697],
12	not	RB	O	not	neg	14	SENT_8	[p1l1120t675r1170b697],
13	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	14	SENT_8	[p1l1186t670r1260b697],
14	deposited	VBN	O	deposit	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1277t670r1430b704],
15	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1447t671r1472b697],
16	a	DT	O	a	det	19	SENT_8	[p1l1488t678r1503b697],
17	publicly	RB	O	publicly	advmod	18	SENT_8	[p1l1519t670r1640b705],
18	available	JJ	O	available	amod	19	SENT_8	[p1l1654t670r1789b697],
19	repository	NN	O	repository	prep_in	14	SENT_8	[p1l1805t671r1961b705],
20	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1975t675r2003b697],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_8	[p1l2017t670r2067b697],
22	time	NN	O	time	prep_at	19	SENT_8	[p1l2081t671r2150b697],
23	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2165t670r2197b697],
24	publication	NN	O	publication	prep_of	22	SENT_8	[p1l265t715r446b749],
25	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l265t715r446b749],

1	Readers	NNS	O	reader	nsubj	4	SENT_9	[p1l463t715r582b742],
2	can	MD	O	can	aux	4	SENT_9	[p1l597t723r648b742],
3	now	RB	DATE	now	advmod	4	SENT_9	[p1l666t723r731b742],
4	access	VB	O	access	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l746t723r843b742],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_9	[p1l857t715r907b742],
6	data	NNS	O	datum	dobj	4	SENT_9	[p1l922t715r988b742],
7	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1004t720r1032b742],
8	Genbank	NNP	LOCATION	Genbank	prep_at	4	SENT_9	[p1l1047t715r1186b742],
9	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	8	SENT_9	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
10	http://www.ncbi.n	NN	O	http://www.ncbi.n	nn	13	SENT_9	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
11	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	13	SENT_9	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
12	m.	NN	NUMBER	m.	nn	13	SENT_9	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
13	nih	NN	O	nih	dep	8	SENT_9	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],

1	gov/entrez/query	NN	O	gov/entrez/query	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],

1	fcgi	NN	O	fcgus	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
2	?	.	O	?	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],

1	db	NN	O	db	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
2	=	JJ	O	=	amod	4	SENT_12	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
3	Nucleotide	NN	MISC	nucleotide	nn	4	SENT_12	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
4	)	NN	O	)	dep	1	SENT_12	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],
5	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1201t715r2206b750],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_13	[p1l262t761r319b788],
2	accession	NN	O	accession	nn	3	SENT_13	[p1l334t762r479b788],
3	numbers	NNS	O	number	nsubj	5	SENT_13	[p1l497t761r632b788],
4	are	VBP	O	be	cop	5	SENT_13	[p1l647t769r694b788],
5	DQ497165	NN	O	dq497165	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l710t762r1062b792],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l710t762r1062b792],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l710t762r1062b792],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l710t762r1062b792],

1	DQ497182	NN	O	dq497182	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l710t762r1062b792],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l710t762r1062b792],

1	This	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_16	[p1l338t827r391b846],
2	correction	NN	O	correction	nn	3	SENT_16	[p1l404t827r537b846],
3	note	NN	O	note	nsubjpass	6	SENT_16	[p1l549t831r604b846],
4	may	MD	O	may	aux	6	SENT_16	[p1l617t834r667b854],
5	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_16	[p1l679t827r707b846],
6	found	VBN	O	find	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l719t827r794b846],
7	online	NN	O	online	dep	6	SENT_16	[p1l806t827r886b846],
8	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l898t831r920b846],
9	DOI	NNP	O	DOI	prep_at	6	SENT_16	[p1l932t827r991b847],
10	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l932t827r991b847],
11	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	dep	9	SENT_16	[p1l1006t825r1384b854],
12	Qournal	NNP	O	Qournal	dep	11	SENT_16	[p1l1006t825r1384b854],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1006t825r1384b854],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1006t825r1384b854],
2	.0020064	CD	NUMBER	.0020064	dep	1	SENT_17	[p1l1006t825r1384b854],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1006t825r1384b854],

1	Published	VBN	O	publish	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l338t860r462b879],
2	June	NNP	DATE	June	dobj	1	SENT_18	[p1l469t860r529b887],
3	30	CD	DATE	30	num	2	SENT_18	[p1l542t860r576b883],
4	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l542t860r576b883],
5	2006	CD	DATE	2006	num	2	SENT_18	[p1l589t860r647b880],
6	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	dep	2	SENT_18	[p1l338t894r448b914],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l338t894r448b914],
8	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	2	SENT_18	[p1l459t894r534b919],
9	2006	CD	DATE	2006	num	11	SENT_18	[p1l459t894r534b919],
10	)	NN	O	)	nn	11	SENT_18	[p1l459t894r534b919],
11	Correction	NN	O	correction	dep	8	SENT_18	[p1l543t894r688b914],
12	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l543t894r688b914],
13	A	DT	O	a	det	17	SENT_18	[p1l697t894r717b913],
14	New	JJ	O	new	amod	17	SENT_18	[p1l725t894r780b913],
15	Bacillm	NN	O	bacillm	nn	17	SENT_18	[p1l788t894r878b913],
16	zmthmcis	NN	O	zmthmci	nn	17	SENT_18	[p1l886t894r990b913],
17	Found	NN	O	found	dep	2	SENT_18	[p1l998t894r1079b913],
18	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1089t894r1112b913],
19	Wild	NNP	O	Wild	nn	20	SENT_18	[p1l1121t894r1180b914],
20	Chimpanzees	NNPS	O	Chimpanzees	prep_in	17	SENT_18	[p1l1189t894r1357b921],
21	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1367t894r1413b913],
22	21	CD	NUMBER	21	num	23	SENT_18	[p1l1422t901r1434b913],
23	Gorilla	NNP	O	Gorilla	dobj	1	SENT_18	[p1l1443t894r1530b914],
24	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1539t894r1600b913],
25	West	NNP	O	West	nn	28	SENT_18	[p1l1609t894r1670b914],
26	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1680t894r1725b913],
27	Central	NNP	LOCATION	Central	nn	28	SENT_18	[p1l1734t894r1828b914],
28	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_from	23	SENT_18	[p1l1837t894r1921b913],
29	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1837t894r1921b913],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_19	[p1l1931t894r1995b914],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2005t894r2093b921],
3	2	CD	NUMBER	2	number	4	SENT_19	[p1l2102t894r2153b919],
4	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	2	SENT_19	[p1l2102t894r2153b919],
5	6	CD	NUMBER	6	num	6	SENT_19	[p1l2102t894r2153b919],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	4	SENT_19	[p1l2102t894r2153b919],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2102t894r2153b919],
8	e64	NN	O	e64	dep	2	SENT_19	[p1l2163t894r2211b913],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2163t894r2211b913],

1	eR	NN	O	er	nn	2	SENT_20	[p1l189t3077r261b3135],
2	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	3	SENT_20	[p1l288t3093r352b3116],
3	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l367t3092r511b3123],
4	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	5	SENT_20	[p1l526t3091r528b3124],
5	www	NN	O	www	dobj	3	SENT_20	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_21	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_21	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	dep	11	SENT_21	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
4	0632	CD	DATE	0632	num	7	SENT_21	[p1l1205t3094r1270b3116],
5	June	NNP	DATE	June	nn	7	SENT_21	[p1l1771t3093r1836b3116],
6	2006	CD	DATE	2006	num	7	SENT_21	[p1l1849t3094r1914b3116],
7	|	NNP	O	|	dep	3	SENT_21	[p1l1929t3091r1931b3124],
8	Volume	NN	O	volume	dep	11	SENT_21	[p1l1945t3092r2051b3116],
9	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	8	SENT_21	[p1l2064t3094r2078b3116],
10	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	11	SENT_21	[p1l2093t3091r2096b3124],
11	Issue	NN	O	issue	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l2112t3093r2178b3116],
12	6	CD	NUMBER	6	num	14	SENT_21	[p1l2191t3094r2206b3116],
13	|	NN	O	|	nn	14	SENT_21	[p1l2221t3091r2223b3124],
14	e64	NN	O	e64	dep	11	SENT_21	[p1l2238t3094r2287b3116],

