1	OPEN	NN	MISC	open	nn	3	SENT_1	[p1l242t131r323b155],
2	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	3	SENT_1	[p1l333t112r365b162],
3	ACCESS	NNP	O	ACCESS	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l372t131r484b155],
4	Freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	5	SENT_1	[p1l501t130r590b162],
5	available	JJ	O	available	amod	7	SENT_1	[p1l597t130r731b155],
6	online	JJ	O	online	amod	7	SENT_1	[p1l739t130r832b155],
7	PLUS	NNS	O	plus	dep	3	SENT_1	[p1l2004t111r2118b153],
8	PATHOGENS	NNS	O	pathogen	dep	7	SENT_1	[p1l2129t130r2308b154],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_2	[p1l242t240r373b300],
2	Influence	NN	O	influence	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l409t239r737b300],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l771t239r843b300],
4	Host	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Host	prep_of	2	SENT_2	[p1l875t243r1034b300],
5	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1066t240r1197b300],
6	Bacterial	JJ	O	bacterial	amod	7	SENT_2	[p1l1236t240r1540b300],
7	Genotype	NN	O	genotype	conj_and	2	SENT_2	[p1l1575t242r1925b317],
8	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1959t257r2045b300],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_2	[p1l2079t240r2195b300],
10	Development	NN	O	development	prep_on	7	SENT_2	[p1l248t331r733b407],
11	of	IN	O	of	dep	2	SENT_2	[p1l765t330r838b391],
12	Disseminated	NNP	O	Disseminated	nn	13	SENT_2	[p1l870t331r1353b391],
13	Disease	NNP	O	Disease	pobj	11	SENT_2	[p1l1392t331r1659b391],
14	with	IN	O	with	dep	2	SENT_2	[p1l1692t331r1846b391],
15	Mycobacterium	NN	O	mycobacterium	nn	16	SENT_2	[p1l247t422r808b499],
16	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	pobj	14	SENT_2	[p1l842t422r1282b482],

1	Maxine	NNP	PERSON	Maxine	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l244t551r387b582],
2	Caws1	NNP	PERSON	Caws1	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l404t544r578b586],
3	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l404t544r578b586],
4	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l404t544r578b586],
5	*	CD	NUMBER	*	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l404t544r578b586],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l404t544r578b586],
7	Guy	NNP	O	Guy	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l595t553r674b590],
8	Thwaites3	NNP	O	Thwaites3	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l689t544r895b586],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l689t544r895b586],
10	Sarah	NNP	PERSON	Sarah	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l913t551r1023b582],
11	Dunstan	NNP	PERSON	Dunstan	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1042t544r1263b586],
12	”	NNP	O	”	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1042t544r1263b586],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1042t544r1263b586],
14	Thomas	NNP	PERSON	Thomas	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1279t551r1435b582],
15	R.	NNP	PERSON	R.	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1453t553r1487b582],
16	Hawn	NNP	PERSON	Hawn	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1505t544r1644b586],
17	“	NNP	O	“	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1505t544r1644b586],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1505t544r1644b586],
19	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1662t553r1812b590],
20	Thi	NNP	PERSON	Thi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1830t551r1890b581],
21	Ngoc	NNP	PERSON	Ngoc	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1909t553r2009b590],
22	Lans	NNP	PERSON	Lans	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2026t544r2124b586],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2026t544r2124b586],
24	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2142t553r2293b590],
25	Thuy	NNP	PERSON	Thuy	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l242t609r342b648],
26	Thuong	NNP	PERSON	Thuong	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l357t609r509b648],
27	Thuong	NNP	PERSON	Thuong	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l526t603r735b648],
28	“	NNP	O	“	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l526t603r735b648],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l526t603r735b648],
30	Kasia	NNP	PERSON	Kasia	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l754t609r855b640],
31	Stepniewskaz	NNP	PERSON	Stepniewskaz	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l873t603r1152b647],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l873t603r1152b647],
33	Mai	NNP	PERSON	Mai	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1170t609r1239b640],
34	Nguyet	NNP	PERSON	Nguyet	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1258t611r1400b648],
35	Thu	NNP	PERSON	Thu	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1415t609r1489b640],
36	Huyen5	NNP	PERSON	Huyen5	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1508t603r1664b648],
37	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1508t603r1664b648],
38	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1682t611r1833b648],
39	Duc	NNP	PERSON	Duc	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1852t611r1926b640],
40	Bangs	NNP	PERSON	Bangs	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1944t603r2071b648],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1944t603r2071b648],
42	Tran	NNP	PERSON	Tran	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2087t611r2175b640],
43	Huu	NNP	PERSON	Huu	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2195t611r2273b640],
44	Loc7	NNP	O	Loc7	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l245t661r339b702],
45	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l245t661r339b702],
46	Sebastien	NNP	PERSON	Sebastien	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l357t667r547b698],
47	Gagneuxs	NNP	PERSON	Gagneuxs	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l565t661r771b706],
48	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l565t661r771b706],
49	Dick	NNP	PERSON	Dick	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l790t667r876b698],
50	van	NNP	PERSON	van	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l890t676r960b698],
51	Soolingens	NNP	PERSON	Soolingens	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l978t661r1207b706],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l978t661r1207b706],
53	Kristin	NNP	PERSON	Kristin	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1225t667r1350b698],
54	Kremers	NNP	PERSON	Kremers	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1369t661r1541b702],
55	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1369t661r1541b702],
56	Marianne	NNP	PERSON	Marianne	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1559t667r1745b698],
57	van	NNP	PERSON	van	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1760t676r1830b698],
58	der	NNP	PERSON	der	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1848t667r1913b698],
59	Sande	NNP	PERSON	Sande	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1930t661r2080b702],
60	‘	NNP	PERSON	‘	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1930t661r2080b702],
61	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1930t661r2080b702],
62	Peter	NNP	PERSON	Peter	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2098t669r2200b698],
63	Smal	NNP	PERSON	Smal	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l244t719r407b760],
64	|	VBD	O	|	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l244t719r407b760],
65	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l244t719r407b760],
66	'	''	DATE	'	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l244t719r407b760],
67	9	CD	DATE	9	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l244t719r407b760],
68	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l244t719r407b760],
69	Phan	NNP	PERSON	Phan	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l425t725r521b756],
70	Thi	NNP	PERSON	Thi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l538t725r599b755],
71	Hoang	NNP	PERSON	Hoang	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l617t727r745b764],
72	Anh7	NNP	O	Anh7	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l762t719r871b760],
73	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l762t719r871b760],
74	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l889t727r1040b764],
75	Tran	NNP	PERSON	Tran	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1057t727r1145b756],
76	Chinh	NNP	PERSON	Chinh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1163t719r1308b760],
77	°	NNP	O	°	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1163t719r1308b760],
78	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1163t719r1308b760],
79	Hoang	NNP	PERSON	Hoang	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1326t727r1453b764],
80	Thi	NNP	PERSON	Thi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1470t725r1531b755],
81	Quy7	NNP	O	Quy7	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1548t719r1657b764],
82	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1548t719r1657b764],
83	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1675t727r1826b764],
84	Thi	NNP	PERSON	Thi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1843t725r1903b755],
85	Hong	NNP	PERSON	Hong	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1922t727r2026b764],
86	Duyenl	NNP	PERSON	Duyenl	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2045t719r2201b764],
87	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2045t719r2201b764],
88	Dau	NNP	PERSON	Dau	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2219t727r2295b756],
89	Quang	NNP	PERSON	Quang	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l243t784r374b822],
90	Tho	NNP	O	Tho	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l388t777r493b818],
91	‘	NNP	O	‘	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l388t777r493b818],
92	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l388t777r493b818],
93	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l510t785r660b822],
94	T.	NNP	O	T.	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l675t785r710b814],
95	Hieu1	NNP	O	Hieu1	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l726t777r862b818],
96	°	NNP	O	°	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l726t777r862b818],
97	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l726t777r862b818],
98	Estee	NNP	PERSON	Estee	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l879t785r982b814],
99	Torok1	NN	PERSON	torok1	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l995t777r1168b818],
100	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l995t777r1168b818],
101	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l995t777r1168b818],
102	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l995t777r1168b818],
103	Tran	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Tran	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1182t785r1270b814],
104	Tinh	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Tinh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1285t783r1371b813],
105	Hien5	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hien5	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1389t777r1507b818],
106	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1389t777r1507b818],
107	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1523t785r1673b822],
108	Huy	NNP	PERSON	Huy	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1691t785r1768b822],
109	Dung	NNP	PERSON	Dung	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1783t777r1918b822],
110	’	NNP	O	’	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1783t777r1918b822],
111	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1783t777r1918b822],
112	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1934t785r2085b822],
113	Thi	NNP	PERSON	Thi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2100t783r2161b813],
114	Quynh	NNP	PERSON	Quynh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2176t783r2307b822],
115	Nhul	NNP	PERSON	Nhul	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l245t835r353b876],
116	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l245t835r353b876],
117	Phan	NNP	PERSON	Phan	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l371t841r467b872],
118	Minh	NNP	PERSON	Minh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l486t841r583b871],
119	Duyl	NNP	PERSON	Duyl	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l603t835r709b880],
120	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l603t835r709b880],
121	Nguyen	NNP	PERSON	Nguyen	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l727t843r878b880],
122	van	NNP	PERSON	van	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l895t850r965b872],
123	Vinh	NNP	PERSON	Vinh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l982t841r1072b871],
124	Chau	NNP	PERSON	Chau	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1090t835r1220b876],
125	°	NNP	O	°	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1090t835r1220b876],
126	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1090t835r1220b876],
127	Jeremy	NNP	PERSON	Jeremy	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1235t843r1379b880],
128	Farrarm	NNP	PERSON	Farrarm	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1396t835r1558b872],
129	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l245t910r254b929],
130	Oxford	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Oxford	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l265t908r346b929],
131	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l359t909r478b935],
132	Clinical	JJ	ORGANIZATION	clinical	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l489t908r572b929],
133	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l586t908r691b929],
134	Unit	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Unit	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l704t909r758b933],
135	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l704t909r758b933],
136	Hospital	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hospital	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l771t908r867b935],
137	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l879t908r912b929],
138	Tropical	JJ	ORGANIZATION	tropical	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l922t908r1017b935],
139	Diseases	NNS	ORGANIZATION	disease	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1031t909r1137b933],
140	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1031t909r1137b933],
141	District	NNP	O	District	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1150t909r1233b929],
142	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1245t910r1263b933],
143	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1245t910r1263b933],
144	Ho	NNP	LOCATION	Ho	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1276t909r1308b929],
145	Chi	NNP	LOCATION	Chi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1320t908r1357b929],
146	Minh	NNP	LOCATION	Minh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1370t908r1428b929],
147	City	NNP	LOCATION	City	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1440t909r1491b935],
148	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1440t909r1491b935],
149	Vietnam	NNP	LOCATION	Vietnam	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1503t909r1608b933],
150	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1503t909r1608b933],
151	2Centre	NNP	O	2Centre	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1621t909r1722b929],
152	for	IN	O	for	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1733t908r1766b929],
153	Clinical	JJ	O	clinical	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1777t908r1861b929],
154	Vaccinology	NN	O	vaccinology	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1872t908r2020b935],
155	and	CC	O	and	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2030t908r2074b929],
156	Tropical	JJ	ORGANIZATION	tropical	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2085t908r2181b935],
157	Medicine	NN	ORGANIZATION	medicine	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2193t908r2308b933],
158	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2193t908r2308b933],
159	Churchill	NNP	LOCATION	Churchill	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l243t950r348b971],
160	Hospital	NNP	LOCATION	Hospital	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l364t950r467b977],
161	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l364t950r467b977],
162	Old	NNP	LOCATION	Old	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l482t950r522b971],
163	Road	NNP	LOCATION	Road	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l539t950r604b975],
164	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l539t950r604b975],
165	Headington	NNP	LOCATION	Headington	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l620t950r767b977],
166	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l620t950r767b977],
167	Oxford	NNP	LOCATION	Oxford	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l782t950r869b975],
168	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l782t950r869b975],
169	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l885t950r963b971],
170	Kingdom	NNP	LOCATION	Kingdom	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l980t950r1094b977],
171	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l980t950r1094b977],
172	3Centre	NNP	O	3Centre	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1110t951r1211b971],
173	for	IN	O	for	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1225t950r1258b971],
174	Molecular	JJ	O	molecular	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1272t950r1390b971],
175	Microbiology	NNP	O	Microbiology	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1405t950r1563b977],
176	and	CC	O	and	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1577t950r1621b971],
177	Infection	NN	O	infection	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1637t950r1748b975],
178	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1637t950r1748b975],
179	Imperial	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Imperial	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1764t950r1859b977],
180	College	NNP	ORGANIZATION	College	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1874t950r1970b977],
181	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1874t950r1970b977],
182	London	NNP	LOCATION	London	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1986t950r2083b975],
183	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1986t950r2083b975],
184	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2099t950r2177b971],
185	Kingdom	NNP	LOCATION	Kingdom	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2194t950r2308b977],
186	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2194t950r2308b977],
187	4University	NN	O	4university	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l243t993r385b1019],
188	of	IN	O	of	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l397t992r422b1013],
189	Washington	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Washington	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l432t992r577b1019],
190	School	NNP	ORGANIZATION	School	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l591t992r670b1013],
191	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l684t992r709b1013],
192	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l721t992r835b1017],
193	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l721t992r835b1017],
194	Seattle	NNP	LOCATION	Seattle	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l849t992r936b1017],
195	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l849t992r936b1017],
196	Washington	NNP	LOCATION	Washington	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l949t992r1100b1019],
197	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l949t992r1100b1019],
198	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1114t992r1192b1013],
199	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1207t993r1278b1013],
200	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1291t992r1316b1013],
201	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1327t993r1431b1017],
202	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1327t993r1431b1017],
203	Slnstitute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Slnstitute	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1445t993r1565b1013],
204	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1578t992r1611b1013],
205	Systems	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Systems	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1624t993r1721b1019],
206	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1735t992r1829b1019],
207	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1735t992r1829b1019],
208	Seattle	NNP	LOCATION	Seattle	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1843t992r1930b1017],
209	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1843t992r1930b1017],
210	Washington	NNP	LOCATION	Washington	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1943t992r2094b1019],
211	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1943t992r2094b1019],
212	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2109t992r2187b1013],
213	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2201t993r2272b1013],
214	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2285t992r2310b1013],
215	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l243t1034r347b1058],
216	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l243t1034r347b1058],
217	6The	NNP	O	6The	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l358t1033r423b1054],
218	Hospital	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hospital	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l436t1033r532b1060],
219	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l543t1033r577b1054],
220	Tropical	JJ	ORGANIZATION	tropical	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l586t1033r682b1060],
221	Diseases	NNS	ORGANIZATION	disease	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l695t1034r801b1058],
222	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l695t1034r801b1058],
223	District	NNP	O	District	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l814t1034r897b1054],
224	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l908t1035r926b1058],
225	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l908t1035r926b1058],
226	Ho	NNP	LOCATION	Ho	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l939t1034r971b1054],
227	Chi	NNP	LOCATION	Chi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l982t1033r1020b1054],
228	Minh	NNP	LOCATION	Minh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1032t1033r1090b1054],
229	City	NNP	LOCATION	City	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1102t1034r1154b1060],
230	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1102t1034r1154b1060],
231	Vietnam	NNP	LOCATION	Vietnam	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1164t1034r1270b1058],
232	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1164t1034r1270b1058],
233	7	CD	NUMBER	7	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1282t1035r1297b1054],
234	Pham	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pham	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1305t1033r1371b1054],
235	Ngoc	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Ngoc	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1384t1034r1446b1060],
236	Thach	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Thach	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1456t1033r1527b1054],
237	Hospital	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hospital	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1541t1033r1637b1060],
238	for	IN	O	for	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1649t1033r1682b1054],
239	Tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1691t1033r1843b1054],
240	and	CC	O	and	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1854t1033r1898b1054],
241	Lung	NN	O	lung	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1911t1034r1969b1060],
242	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1983t1034r2089b1058],
243	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1983t1034r2089b1058],
244	District	NNP	O	District	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2102t1034r2185b1054],
245	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2196t1035r2215b1058],
246	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2196t1035r2215b1058],
247	Ho	NNP	LOCATION	Ho	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2227t1034r2259b1054],
248	Chi	NNP	LOCATION	Chi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2270t1033r2308b1054],
249	Minh	NNP	LOCATION	Minh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l244t1075r302b1096],
250	City	NNP	LOCATION	City	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l314t1076r365b1102],
251	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l314t1076r365b1102],
252	Vietnam	NNP	LOCATION	Vietnam	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l375t1076r481b1100],
253	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l375t1076r481b1100],
254	8Tubercu	NNP	O	8Tubercu	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l492t1075r665b1096],
255	|	CD	NUMBER	|	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l492t1075r665b1096],
256	osis	NN	O	osis	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l492t1075r665b1096],
257	Reference	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Reference	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l677t1075r795b1096],
258	Laboratory	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Laboratory	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l807t1075r943b1102],
259	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l807t1075r943b1102],
260	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l955t1075r1053b1096],
261	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1066t1076r1164b1096],
262	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1174t1075r1207b1096],
263	Public	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Public	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1219t1075r1290b1096],
264	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1302t1075r1385b1100],
265	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1302t1075r1385b1100],
266	Bilthoeven	NNP	LOCATION	Bilthoeven	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1397t1075r1530b1100],
267	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1397t1075r1530b1100],
268	The	DT	LOCATION	the	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1540t1075r1584b1096],
269	Netherlands	NNP	LOCATION	Netherlands	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1596t1075r1747b1100],
270	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1596t1075r1747b1100],
271	9	CD	NUMBER	9	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1758t1077r1774b1096],
272	Bill	NNP	PERSON	Bill	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1782t1075r1813b1096],
273	and	CC	O	and	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1825t1075r1869b1096],
274	Melinda	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Melinda	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1881t1075r1975b1096],
275	Gates	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Gates	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1987t1076r2053b1096],
276	Foundation	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Foundation	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2066t1075r2209b1100],
277	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2066t1075r2209b1100],
278	Seattle	NNP	LOCATION	Seattle	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l2221t1075r2308b1100],
279	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l2221t1075r2308b1100],
280	Washington	NNP	LOCATION	Washington	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l243t1116r394b1143],
281	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l243t1116r394b1143],
282	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l407t1116r485b1137],
283	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l498t1117r569b1137],
284	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l581t1116r606b1137],
285	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l615t1117r718b1141],
286	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l615t1117r718b1141],
287	10	CD	NUMBER	10	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l733t1118r763b1137],
288	Hung	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hung	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l771t1117r835b1143],
289	Vuong	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Vuong	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l847t1117r925b1143],
290	Obstetric	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Obstetric	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l938t1116r1047b1137],
291	Hospital	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hospital	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1060t1116r1163b1143],
292	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1060t1116r1163b1143],
293	Hung	NNP	LOCATION	Hung	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1176t1117r1239b1143],
294	Vuong	NNP	LOCATION	Vuong	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1252t1117r1330b1143],
295	Street	NNP	LOCATION	Street	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1343t1117r1419b1141],
296	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1343t1117r1419b1141],
297	Ho	NNP	LOCATION	Ho	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1432t1117r1464b1137],
298	Chi	NNP	LOCATION	Chi	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1475t1116r1513b1137],
299	Minh	NNP	LOCATION	Minh	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1526t1116r1584b1137],
300	City	NNP	LOCATION	City	dep	302	SENT_3	[p1l1597t1117r1647b1143],
301	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1597t1117r1647b1143],
302	Vietnam	NNP	LOCATION	Vietnam	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1659t1117r1758b1137],

1	Abstract	JJ	O	abstract	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l308t1233r475b1264],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_5	[p1l307t1298r364b1325],
2	factors	NNS	O	factor	nsubjpass	12	SENT_5	[p1l376t1298r479b1325],
3	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	4	SENT_5	[p1l491t1298r553b1325],
4	govern	VBP	O	govern	rcmod	2	SENT_5	[p1l565t1306r672b1333],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_5	[p1l686t1298r735b1325],
6	development	NN	O	development	dobj	4	SENT_5	[p1l748t1298r955b1332],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l968t1298r999b1325],
8	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	9	SENT_5	[p1l1008t1298r1196b1325],
9	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_of	6	SENT_5	[p1l1209t1298r1320b1325],
10	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	12	SENT_5	[p1l1333t1306r1379b1325],
11	incompletely	RB	O	incompletely	advmod	12	SENT_5	[p1l1392t1298r1594b1333],
12	understood	VBN	O	understand	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1606t1298r1793b1325],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1606t1298r1793b1325],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubjpass	25	SENT_6	[p1l1804t1300r1853b1325],
2	hypothesized	VBD	O	hypothesize	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1867t1298r2072b1333],
3	that	IN	O	that	complm	8	SENT_6	[p1l2086t1298r2147b1325],
4	some	DT	O	some	det	5	SENT_6	[p1l2160t1306r2242b1325],
5	strains	NNS	O	strain	nsubj	8	SENT_6	[p1l309t1341r407b1367],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l423t1340r455b1367],
7	Mycobacterium	NN	O	mycobacterium	prep_of	5	SENT_6	[p1l466t1340r698b1375],
8	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	ccomp	2	SENT_6	[p1l716t1340r892b1367],
9	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	12	SENT_6	[p1l908t1341r951b1372],
10	M.	NN	NUMBER	m.	nn	12	SENT_6	[p1l908t1341r951b1372],
11	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	12	SENT_6	[p1l969t1340r1154b1372],
12	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	15	SENT_6	[p1l969t1340r1154b1372],
13	are	VBP	O	be	cop	15	SENT_6	[p1l1170t1348r1216b1367],
14	more	RBR	O	more	advmod	15	SENT_6	[p1l1233t1348r1312b1367],
15	capable	JJ	O	capable	ccomp	8	SENT_6	[p1l1327t1340r1447b1374],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1463t1340r1494b1367],
17	causing	VBG	O	cause	prepc_of	15	SENT_6	[p1l1507t1341r1623b1375],
18	disseminated	VBN	O	disseminate	dep	17	SENT_6	[p1l1640t1340r1845b1367],
19	disease	NN	O	disease	dobj	18	SENT_6	[p1l1862t1340r1973b1367],
20	than	IN	O	than	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1988t1340r2057b1367],
21	others	NNS	O	other	prep_than	18	SENT_6	[p1l2073t1340r2170b1367],
22	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2185t1340r2241b1367],
23	may	MD	O	may	aux	25	SENT_6	[p1l310t1389r374b1416],
24	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	25	SENT_6	[p1l394t1381r431b1408],
25	associated	VBN	O	associate	conj_and	2	SENT_6	[p1l451t1381r611b1408],
26	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l632t1381r698b1408],
27	polymorphisms	NNS	O	polymorphism	prep_with	25	SENT_6	[p1l721t1381r960b1416],
28	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l982t1382r1006b1408],
29	host	NN	O	host	nn	30	SENT_6	[p1l1029t1381r1094b1408],
30	genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_in	27	SENT_6	[p1l1114t1389r1205b1416],
31	responsible	JJ	O	responsible	amod	30	SENT_6	[p1l1227t1381r1403b1415],
32	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1423t1381r1466b1408],
33	the	DT	O	the	det	36	SENT_6	[p1l1485t1381r1535b1408],
34	innate	JJ	O	innate	amod	36	SENT_6	[p1l1556t1382r1651b1408],
35	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	36	SENT_6	[p1l1673t1382r1800b1408],
36	response	NN	O	response	prep_for	31	SENT_6	[p1l1822t1389r1959b1415],
37	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1979t1386r2010b1408],
38	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_to	25	SENT_6	[p1l2032t1381r2174b1408],
39	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2032t1381r2174b1408],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_7	[p1l2194t1383r2242b1408],
2	compared	VBD	O	compare	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l309t1423r465b1457],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_7	[p1l489t1423r539b1450],
4	host	NN	O	host	nn	7	SENT_7	[p1l564t1423r629b1450],
5	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l652t1423r708b1450],
6	bacterial	JJ	O	bacterial	nn	7	SENT_7	[p1l734t1423r864b1450],
7	genotype	NN	O	genotype	dobj	2	SENT_7	[p1l889t1428r1037b1458],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1062t1424r1086b1450],
9	187	CD	NUMBER	187	num	11	SENT_7	[p1l1114t1425r1166b1450],
10	Vietnamese	JJ	MISC	vietnamese	amod	11	SENT_7	[p1l1189t1424r1370b1450],
11	adults	NNS	O	adult	prep_in	2	SENT_7	[p1l1394t1423r1486b1450],
12	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1510t1423r1576b1450],
13	tuberculous	JJ	O	tuberculous	amod	14	SENT_7	[p1l1600t1423r1785b1450],
14	meningitis	NN	O	meningitis	prep_with	2	SENT_7	[p1l1810t1424r1972b1458],
15	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	17	SENT_7	[p1l1997t1424r2082b1455],
16	TBM	NN	O	tbm	nn	17	SENT_7	[p1l1997t1424r2082b1455],
17	)	NN	O	)	dep	14	SENT_7	[p1l1997t1424r2082b1455],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l2107t1423r2163b1450],
19	237	CD	NUMBER	237	num	21	SENT_7	[p1l2188t1425r2242b1450],
20	Vietnamese	JJ	MISC	vietnamese	amod	21	SENT_7	[p1l308t1465r489b1491],
21	adults	NNS	O	adult	prep_with	2	SENT_7	[p1l500t1464r593b1491],
22	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l603t1464r670b1491],
23	uncomplicated	JJ	O	uncomplicated	amod	25	SENT_7	[p1l683t1464r913b1498],
24	pulmonary	JJ	O	pulmonary	amod	25	SENT_7	[p1l927t1464r1095b1499],
25	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_with	21	SENT_7	[p1l1104t1464r1300b1491],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1104t1464r1300b1491],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_8	[p1l1310t1464r1367b1491],
2	host	NN	O	host	nn	3	SENT_8	[p1l1379t1464r1444b1491],
3	genotype	NN	O	genotype	nsubjpass	9	SENT_8	[p1l1455t1469r1604b1499],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1615t1464r1647b1491],
5	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	6	SENT_8	[p1l1655t1464r1842b1491],
6	cases	NNS	O	case	prep_of	3	SENT_8	[p1l1854t1472r1934b1491],
7	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	9	SENT_8	[p1l1945t1472r2003b1491],
8	also	RB	O	also	advmod	9	SENT_8	[p1l2014t1464r2074b1491],
9	compared	VBN	O	compare	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2085t1464r2241b1498],
10	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l308t1506r374b1533],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_8	[p1l386t1506r436b1533],
12	genotype	NN	O	genotype	prep_with	9	SENT_8	[p1l447t1511r596b1541],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l607t1506r639b1533],
14	392	CD	NUMBER	392	num	17	SENT_8	[p1l648t1508r701b1533],
15	cord	NN	O	cord	nn	17	SENT_8	[p1l713t1506r780b1533],
16	blood	NN	O	blood	nn	17	SENT_8	[p1l793t1506r881b1533],
17	controls	NNS	O	control	prep_of	12	SENT_8	[p1l893t1506r1017b1533],
18	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1028t1506r1099b1533],
19	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_8	[p1l1111t1506r1161b1533],
20	same	JJ	O	same	amod	21	SENT_8	[p1l1173t1514r1252b1533],
21	population	NN	O	population	prep_from	9	SENT_8	[p1l1265t1506r1441b1540],
22	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1265t1506r1441b1540],

1	Isolates	NNS	O	isolate	nsubjpass	6	SENT_9	[p1l1454t1506r1567b1533],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1578t1506r1610b1533],
3	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	4	SENT_9	[p1l1618t1508r1652b1533],
4	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	1	SENT_9	[p1l1665t1506r1842b1533],
5	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_9	[p1l1852t1514r1927b1533],
6	genotyped	VBN	O	genotype	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1938t1506r2107b1541],
7	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l2120t1506r2156b1541],
8	large	JJ	O	large	amod	10	SENT_9	[p1l2168t1506r2242b1541],
9	sequence	NN	O	sequence	nn	10	SENT_9	[p1l309t1555r456b1581],
10	polymorphisms	NNS	O	polymorphism	agent	6	SENT_9	[p1l470t1547r717b1582],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l470t1547r717b1582],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_10	[p1l728t1547r785b1574],
2	hosts	NNS	O	host	nsubjpass	4	SENT_10	[p1l799t1547r878b1574],
3	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	4	SENT_10	[p1l890t1555r965b1574],
4	defined	VBN	O	define	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l977t1547r1093b1574],
5	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1108t1547r1144b1582],
6	polymorphisms	NNS	O	polymorphism	agent	4	SENT_10	[p1l1156t1547r1396b1582],
7	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1409t1548r1434b1574],
8	genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_in	6	SENT_10	[p1l1448t1555r1539b1582],
9	encoding	VBG	O	encode	partmod	8	SENT_10	[p1l1551t1547r1695b1582],
10	To	TO	O	to	aux	11	SENT_10	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],
11	|	VB	O	|	xcomp	9	SENT_10	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],
12	|	NN	O	|	dobj	11	SENT_10	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],

1	inter	NN	O	inter	nn	6	SENT_12	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],
2	|	NN	O	|	nn	6	SENT_12	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],
3	eukin	NN	O	eukin	nn	6	SENT_12	[p1l1708t1547r1940b1574],
4	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	6	SENT_12	[p1l1956t1550r1964b1574],
5	receptor	NN	O	receptor	nn	6	SENT_12	[p1l1983t1552r2113b1581],
6	domain	NN	O	domain	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l2125t1547r2241b1574],
7	containing	VBG	O	contain	partmod	6	SENT_12	[p1l309t1590r473b1624],
8	adaptor	NN	O	adaptor	nn	9	SENT_12	[p1l489t1589r611b1623],
9	protein	NN	O	protein	dobj	7	SENT_12	[p1l626t1590r735b1623],
10	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	12	SENT_12	[p1l752t1590r855b1621],
11	TIRAP	NN	O	tirap	nn	12	SENT_12	[p1l752t1590r855b1621],
12	)	NN	O	)	dep	6	SENT_12	[p1l752t1590r855b1621],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l871t1589r927b1616],
14	To	TO	O	to	aux	15	SENT_12	[p1l942t1589r1061b1616],
15	|	VB	O	|	dep	6	SENT_12	[p1l942t1589r1061b1616],
16	|	NN	O	|	dobj	15	SENT_12	[p1l942t1589r1061b1616],
17	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l942t1589r1061b1616],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l942t1589r1061b1616],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l942t1589r1061b1616],

1	|	NN	O	|	nn	2	SENT_14	[p1l942t1589r1061b1616],
2	ike	NN	O	ike	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l942t1589r1061b1616],
3	receptor	NN	O	receptor	nn	4	SENT_14	[p1l1077t1591r1236b1623],
4	—	NN	O	—	dep	2	SENT_14	[p1l1077t1591r1236b1623],
5	2	CD	NUMBER	2	number	6	SENT_14	[p1l1077t1591r1236b1623],
6	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	10	SENT_14	[p1l1253t1590r1362b1621],
7	TLR	NN	O	tlr	nn	10	SENT_14	[p1l1253t1590r1362b1621],
8	—	NN	O	—	nn	10	SENT_14	[p1l1253t1590r1362b1621],
9	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	10	SENT_14	[p1l1253t1590r1362b1621],
10	)	NN	O	)	dep	4	SENT_14	[p1l1253t1590r1362b1621],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1253t1590r1362b1621],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_15	[p1l1376t1591r1425b1616],
2	found	VBD	O	find	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1439t1589r1530b1616],
3	a	DT	O	a	det	6	SENT_15	[p1l1546t1597r1560b1616],
4	significant	JJ	O	significant	amod	6	SENT_15	[p1l1576t1589r1734b1624],
5	protective	JJ	O	protective	amod	6	SENT_15	[p1l1750t1590r1906b1623],
6	association	NN	O	association	dobj	2	SENT_15	[p1l1921t1590r2090b1616],
7	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l2108t1589r2241b1616],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_15	[p1l308t1630r358b1657],
9	Euro	NNP	O	Euro	prep_between	6	SENT_15	[p1l371t1631r597b1657],
10	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l371t1631r597b1657],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l371t1631r597b1657],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l371t1631r597b1657],

1	American	JJ	MISC	american	amod	2	SENT_17	[p1l371t1631r597b1657],
2	lineage	NN	O	lineage	dep	14	SENT_17	[p1l612t1630r722b1665],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l733t1630r765b1657],
4	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	5	SENT_17	[p1l773t1632r807b1657],
5	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	2	SENT_17	[p1l821t1630r997b1657],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1008t1630r1064b1657],
7	pulmonary	JJ	O	pulmonary	amod	11	SENT_17	[p1l1078t1630r1246b1665],
8	rather	RB	O	rather	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1257t1630r1349b1657],
9	than	IN	O	than	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1358t1630r1427b1657],
10	meningeal	JJ	O	meningeal	amod	11	SENT_17	[p1l1441t1630r1602b1665],
11	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	2	SENT_17	[p1l1614t1630r1801b1657],
12	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	13	SENT_17	[p1l1814t1630r1903b1662],
13	Odds	NNS	O	odds	dep	14	SENT_17	[p1l1814t1630r1903b1662],
14	ratio	NN	O	ratio	dep	18	SENT_17	[p1l1916t1631r1984b1657],
15	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	17	SENT_17	[p1l1997t1631r2060b1662],
16	OR	NN	O	or	nn	17	SENT_17	[p1l1997t1631r2060b1662],
17	)	NN	O	)	dep	14	SENT_17	[p1l1997t1631r2060b1662],
18	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l2071t1630r2114b1657],
19	causing	VBG	O	cause	pcomp	18	SENT_17	[p1l2125t1631r2241b1665],
20	TBM	NN	O	tbm	nsubj	27	SENT_17	[p1l307t1674r374b1699],
21	0.395	CD	NUMBER	0.395	num	20	SENT_17	[p1l396t1674r485b1704],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l396t1674r485b1704],
23	95	CD	PERCENT	95	number	24	SENT_17	[p1l506t1674r572b1700],
24	%	NN	PERCENT	%	amod	26	SENT_17	[p1l506t1674r572b1700],
25	confidence	NN	O	confidence	nn	26	SENT_17	[p1l592t1672r763b1699],
26	intervals	NNS	O	interval	appos	20	SENT_17	[p1l785t1672r913b1699],
27	(	VBP	O	(	ccomp	19	SENT_17	[p1l935t1673r997b1704],
28	C.	NNP	O	C.	nn	29	SENT_17	[p1l935t1673r997b1704],
29	|	NNP	O	|	dobj	27	SENT_17	[p1l935t1673r997b1704],
30	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l935t1673r997b1704],
31	)	NN	O	)	dep	29	SENT_17	[p1l935t1673r997b1704],

1	0	CD	NUMBER	0	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1019t1674r1211b1704],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1019t1674r1211b1704],

1	I93	NN	O	i93	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1019t1674r1211b1704],
2	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	3	SENT_19	[p1l1019t1674r1211b1704],
3	0.806	CD	NUMBER	0.806	dep	1	SENT_19	[p1l1019t1674r1211b1704],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1019t1674r1211b1704],
5	P	NN	O	p	appos	1	SENT_19	[p1l1233t1673r1386b1704],
6	=	JJ	O	=	amod	1	SENT_19	[p1l1233t1673r1386b1704],
7	0.009	CD	NUMBER	0.009	num	8	SENT_19	[p1l1233t1673r1386b1704],
8	)	NN	O	)	dep	6	SENT_19	[p1l1233t1673r1386b1704],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1233t1673r1386b1704],
10	suggesting	VBG	O	suggest	partmod	1	SENT_19	[p1l1408t1673r1577b1707],
11	these	DT	O	these	det	12	SENT_19	[p1l1598t1672r1682b1699],
12	strains	NNS	O	strain	nsubj	15	SENT_19	[p1l1703t1673r1801b1699],
13	are	VBP	O	be	cop	15	SENT_19	[p1l1822t1680r1868b1699],
14	less	RBR	O	less	advmod	15	SENT_19	[p1l1891t1672r1943b1699],
15	capable	JJ	O	capable	ccomp	10	SENT_19	[p1l1964t1672r2084b1706],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2105t1672r2137b1699],
17	extrapulmonary	JJ	O	extrapulmonary	amod	18	SENT_19	[p1l2155t1677r2242b1699, p1l310t1713r478b1748],
18	dissemination	NN	O	dissemination	prep_of	1	SENT_19	[p1l493t1713r708b1740],
19	than	IN	O	than	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l725t1713r793b1740],
20	others	NNS	O	other	prep_than	18	SENT_19	[p1l811t1713r907b1740],
21	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l925t1714r950b1740],
22	the	DT	O	the	det	24	SENT_19	[p1l967t1713r1017b1740],
23	study	NN	O	study	nn	24	SENT_19	[p1l1034t1713r1118b1748],
24	population	NN	O	population	prep_in	20	SENT_19	[p1l1135t1713r1311b1747],
25	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1135t1713r1311b1747],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	3	SENT_20	[p1l1327t1715r1376b1740],
2	also	RB	O	also	advmod	3	SENT_20	[p1l1392t1713r1451b1740],
3	found	VBD	O	find	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1467t1713r1558b1740],
4	that	IN	O	that	complm	18	SENT_20	[p1l1575t1713r1637b1740],
5	individuals	NNS	O	individual	nsubj	18	SENT_20	[p1l1654t1713r1819b1740],
6	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1835t1713r1901b1740],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_20	[p1l1918t1713r1968b1740],
8	C	NN	O	c	nn	9	SENT_20	[p1l1984t1714r2003b1740],
9	allele	NN	O	allele	prep_with	5	SENT_20	[p1l2020t1713r2099b1740],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l2115t1713r2147b1740],
11	TLR	NN	O	tlr	nn	12	SENT_20	[p1l2162t1715r2242b1740],
12	—	NN	O	—	prep_of	9	SENT_20	[p1l2162t1715r2242b1740],
13	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	15	SENT_20	[p1l2162t1715r2242b1740],
14	T597C	NN	O	t597c	nn	15	SENT_20	[p1l307t1756r404b1782],
15	allele	NN	O	allele	dep	12	SENT_20	[p1l415t1755r493b1782],
16	were	VBD	O	be	cop	18	SENT_20	[p1l504t1763r579b1782],
17	more	RBR	O	more	advmod	18	SENT_20	[p1l592t1763r670b1782],
18	likely	JJ	O	likely	ccomp	3	SENT_20	[p1l683t1755r760b1790],
19	to	TO	O	to	aux	20	SENT_20	[p1l769t1760r800b1782],
20	have	VB	O	have	xcomp	18	SENT_20	[p1l813t1755r884b1782],
21	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	dobj	20	SENT_20	[p1l895t1755r1083b1782],
22	caused	VBN	O	cause	partmod	21	SENT_20	[p1l1095t1755r1200b1782],
23	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1214t1755r1250b1790],
24	the	DT	O	the	det	25	SENT_20	[p1l1260t1755r1310b1782],
25	East	NNP	O	East	agent	22	SENT_20	[p1l1322t1756r1596b1790],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1322t1756r1596b1790],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1322t1756r1596b1790],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1322t1756r1596b1790],

1	Asian/Beijing	VBG	O	asian/beijing	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1322t1756r1596b1790],
2	genotype	NN	O	genotype	nn	4	SENT_22	[p1l1609t1760r1757b1790],
3	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	4	SENT_22	[p1l1769t1756r1822b1787],
4	OR	NN	O	or	dobj	1	SENT_22	[p1l1769t1756r1822b1787],
5	=	JJ	O	=	advmod	1	SENT_22	[p1l1831t1767r1850b1777],
6	1.57	CD	PERCENT	1.57	num	7	SENT_22	[p1l1862t1758r1922b1782],
7	[	CD	PERCENT	[	dep	5	SENT_22	[p1l1935t1756r2009b1786],
8	95	CD	PERCENT	95	num	9	SENT_22	[p1l1935t1756r2009b1786],
9	%	NN	PERCENT	%	dep	11	SENT_22	[p1l1935t1756r2009b1786],
10	C.	FW	O	c.	nn	11	SENT_22	[p1l2020t1756r2064b1782],
11	|	FW	O	|	advmod	1	SENT_22	[p1l2020t1756r2064b1782],
12	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l2020t1756r2064b1782],

1	I.	NN	O	i.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l2078t1756r2241b1787],
2	15	CD	NUMBER	15	num	1	SENT_23	[p1l2078t1756r2241b1787],
3	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	4	SENT_23	[p1l2078t1756r2241b1787],
4	2.15	CD	NUMBER	2.15	dep	1	SENT_23	[p1l2078t1756r2241b1787],
5	]	CD	NUMBER	]	num	6	SENT_23	[p1l2078t1756r2241b1787],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	4	SENT_23	[p1l2078t1756r2241b1787],
7	than	IN	O	than	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l308t1796r377b1823],
8	other	JJ	O	other	amod	9	SENT_23	[p1l390t1796r473b1823],
9	individuals	NNS	O	individual	prep_than	1	SENT_23	[p1l485t1796r657b1823],
10	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l485t1796r657b1823],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_24	[p1l668t1796r725b1823],
2	study	NN	O	study	nsubj	3	SENT_24	[p1l737t1796r821b1831],
3	provides	VBZ	O	provide	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l834t1796r965b1830],
4	evidence	NN	O	evidence	dobj	3	SENT_24	[p1l977t1796r1115b1823],
5	that	IN	O	that	complm	9	SENT_24	[p1l1127t1796r1189b1823],
6	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	8	SENT_24	[p1l1199t1798r1234b1823],
7	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	8	SENT_24	[p1l1248t1796r1424b1823],
8	genotype	NN	O	genotype	nsubj	14	SENT_24	[p1l1436t1801r1584b1831],
9	influences	VBZ	O	influence	ccomp	3	SENT_24	[p1l1597t1796r1752b1823],
10	clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	12	SENT_24	[p1l1764t1796r1867b1823],
11	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	12	SENT_24	[p1l1880t1796r1992b1823],
12	phenotype	NN	O	phenotype	dobj	9	SENT_24	[p1l2005t1796r2173b1831],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l2185t1796r2241b1823],
14	demonstrates	VBZ	O	demonstrate	conj_and	9	SENT_24	[p1l309t1838r529b1870],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l309t1838r529b1870],
16	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l544t1838r587b1865],
17	the	DT	O	the	det	19	SENT_24	[p1l602t1838r651b1865],
18	first	JJ	ORDINAL	first	amod	19	SENT_24	[p1l666t1838r724b1865],
19	time	NN	O	time	prep_for	3	SENT_24	[p1l739t1839r815b1870],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l739t1839r815b1870],
21	a	DT	O	a	det	23	SENT_24	[p1l831t1846r846b1865],
22	significant	JJ	O	significant	amod	23	SENT_24	[p1l863t1838r1021b1873],
23	interaction	NN	O	interaction	prep_for	3	SENT_24	[p1l1037t1839r1202b1865],
24	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1220t1838r1353b1865],
25	host	NN	O	host	nn	28	SENT_24	[p1l1372t1838r1437b1865],
26	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1452t1838r1508b1865],
27	bacterial	JJ	O	bacterial	nn	28	SENT_24	[p1l1527t1838r1656b1865],
28	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	prep_between	23	SENT_24	[p1l1673t1843r1836b1873],
29	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1852t1838r1908b1865],
30	the	DT	O	the	det	31	SENT_24	[p1l1924t1838r1974b1865],
31	development	NN	O	development	conj_and	19	SENT_24	[p1l1990t1838r2198b1872],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l2213t1838r2245b1865],
33	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	31	SENT_24	[p1l308t1879r504b1906],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l308t1879r504b1906],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l278t1984r396b2005],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l278t1984r396b2005],
3	Caws	NNS	O	caw	nn	4	SENT_25	[p1l406t1985r468b2005],
4	M	NN	O	m	dep	1	SENT_25	[p1l480t1985r507b2009],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l480t1985r507b2009],
6	Thwaites	NNP	LOCATION	Thwaites	nn	7	SENT_25	[p1l517t1984r624b2005],
7	G	NNP	LOCATION	G	appos	4	SENT_25	[p1l635t1985r658b2009],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l635t1985r658b2009],
9	Dunstan	NNP	PERSON	Dunstan	nn	10	SENT_25	[p1l671t1985r769b2005],
10	S	NNP	PERSON	S	appos	4	SENT_25	[p1l782t1985r799b2009],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l782t1985r799b2009],
12	Hawn	NNP	O	Hawn	nn	13	SENT_25	[p1l812t1985r878b2005],
13	TR	NN	O	tr	appos	4	SENT_25	[p1l889t1985r924b2009],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l889t1985r924b2009],
15	Lan	NN	O	lan	nn	16	SENT_25	[p1l937t1985r976b2005],
16	NTN	NNP	ORGANIZATION	NTN	appos	4	SENT_25	[p1l989t1985r1045b2009],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l989t1985r1045b2009],
18	et	FW	O	et	dep	4	SENT_25	[p1l1056t1988r1078b2005],
19	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	20	SENT_25	[p1l1089t1984r1114b2005],
20	(	FW	O	(	dep	4	SENT_25	[p1l1125t1985r1198b2009],
21	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	22	SENT_25	[p1l1125t1985r1198b2009],
22	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	20	SENT_25	[p1l1125t1985r1198b2009],
23	The	DT	O	the	det	24	SENT_25	[p1l1208t1984r1253b2005],
24	Influence	NN	O	influence	dep	20	SENT_25	[p1l1265t1984r1374b2005],
25	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1385t1984r1410b2005],
26	Host	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Host	prep_of	24	SENT_25	[p1l1420t1985r1473b2005],
27	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1484t1984r1527b2005],
28	Bacterial	JJ	O	bacterial	amod	29	SENT_25	[p1l1540t1984r1640b2005],
29	Genotype	NN	O	genotype	dep	1	SENT_25	[p1l1652t1985r1770b2011],
30	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1781t1991r1810b2005],
31	the	DT	O	the	det	32	SENT_25	[p1l1822t1984r1861b2005],
32	Development	NN	MISC	development	prep_on	29	SENT_25	[p1l1873t1984r2036b2011],
33	of	IN	MISC	of	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l2047t1984r2072b2005],
34	Disseminated	NNP	MISC	Disseminated	nn	35	SENT_25	[p1l2082t1984r2242b2005],
35	Disease	NNP	MISC	Disease	prep_of	32	SENT_25	[p1l279t2018r368b2038],
36	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l380t2017r431b2038],
37	Mycobacterium	NN	O	mycobacterium	nn	38	SENT_25	[p1l443t2017r624b2044],
38	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_with	35	SENT_25	[p1l637t2017r780b2038],
39	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l637t2017r780b2038],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_26	[p1l793t2018r849b2038],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l862t2017r945b2044],
3	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	4	SENT_26	[p1l958t2018r1008b2042],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_26	[p1l958t2018r1008b2042],
5	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	6	SENT_26	[p1l958t2018r1008b2042],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_26	[p1l958t2018r1008b2042],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l958t2018r1008b2042],
8	eI000034	NN	O	ei000034	dep	2	SENT_26	[p1l1020t2019r1142b2038],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1020t2019r1142b2038],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],
2	:10.1371	CD	NUMBER	:10.1371	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],
3	/	:	O	/	punct	5	SENT_27	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],
4	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	5	SENT_27	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],
5	|	NN	O	|	dep	2	SENT_27	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],

1	I0O0034	NN	O	i0o0034	nn	2	SENT_29	[p1l1154t2017r1561b2044],
2	Editor	NNP	O	Editor	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l279t2069r370b2090],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l279t2069r370b2090],
4	William	NNP	PERSON	William	nn	5	SENT_29	[p1l381t2069r468b2090],
5	Bishai	NNP	PERSON	Bishai	dep	2	SENT_29	[p1l482t2069r555b2094],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l482t2069r555b2094],
7	Johns	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Johns	nn	9	SENT_29	[p1l566t2069r635b2090],
8	Hopkins	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hopkins	nn	9	SENT_29	[p1l648t2069r745b2096],
9	School	NNP	ORGANIZATION	School	appos	2	SENT_29	[p1l757t2069r836b2090],
10	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l848t2069r873b2090],
11	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	prep_of	9	SENT_29	[p1l883t2069r998b2094],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l883t2069r998b2094],
13	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	14	SENT_29	[p1l1011t2069r1089b2090],
14	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	nsubj	17	SENT_29	[p1l1102t2070r1173b2090],
15	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1184t2069r1209b2090],
16	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	14	SENT_29	[p1l1219t2070r1316b2090],
17	Received	VBD	O	receive	dep	2	SENT_29	[p1l279t2121r401b2142],
18	October	NNP	DATE	October	nsubj	29	SENT_29	[p1l414t2121r512b2142],
19	22	CD	DATE	22	num	18	SENT_29	[p1l523t2123r556b2146],
20	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l523t2123r556b2146],
21	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	18	SENT_29	[p1l569t2123r632b2146],
22	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l569t2123r632b2146],
23	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	amod	18	SENT_29	[p1l643t2121r772b2148],
24	February	NNP	DATE	February	tmod	23	SENT_29	[p1l785t2121r891b2148],
25	26	CD	DATE	26	num	24	SENT_29	[p1l902t2123r935b2146],
26	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l902t2123r935b2146],
27	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	24	SENT_29	[p1l947t2123r1011b2146],
28	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l947t2123r1011b2146],
29	Published	VBN	O	publish	ccomp	17	SENT_29	[p1l1023t2121r1159b2142],
30	March	NNP	DATE	March	tmod	29	SENT_29	[p1l1172t2121r1244b2142],
31	28	CD	DATE	28	num	30	SENT_29	[p1l1257t2123r1290b2146],
32	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1257t2123r1290b2146],
33	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	34	SENT_29	[p1l1302t2123r1359b2142],
34	Copyright	NN	O	copyright	appos	2	SENT_29	[p1l278t2173r425b2200],
35	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l278t2173r425b2200],
36	©	CD	NUMBER	©	num	37	SENT_29	[p1l441t2174r461b2194],
37	2008	CD	DATE	2008	dep	2	SENT_29	[p1l478t2175r535b2194],
38	Caws	NNP	O	Caws	dep	37	SENT_29	[p1l550t2174r612b2194],
39	et	FW	O	et	nn	40	SENT_29	[p1l628t2177r650b2194],
40	al.	FW	O	al.	dep	37	SENT_29	[p1l666t2173r690b2194],
41	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l666t2173r690b2194],

1	Funding	NNP	O	Funding	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l279t2258r401b2285],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l279t2258r401b2285],
3	This	DT	O	this	det	4	SENT_31	[p1l409t2258r457b2279],
4	work	NN	O	work	nsubjpass	6	SENT_31	[p1l466t2258r526b2279],
5	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_31	[p1l534t2265r579b2279],
6	supported	VBN	O	support	dep	1	SENT_31	[p1l589t2258r712b2285],
7	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l723t2258r752b2285],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_31	[p1l760t2258r799b2279],
9	Wellcome	NNP	O	Wellcome	nn	10	SENT_31	[p1l808t2258r926b2279],
10	Trust	NNP	O	Trust	agent	6	SENT_31	[p1l934t2259r995b2279],
11	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1004t2258r1029b2279],
12	Great	NNP	LOCATION	Great	nn	13	SENT_31	[p1l1036t2259r1100b2279],
13	Britain	NNP	LOCATION	Britain	prep_of	10	SENT_31	[p1l1110t2259r1192b2279],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1110t2259r1192b2279],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_32	[p1l1200t2258r1244b2279],
2	funders	NNS	O	funder	nsubj	3	SENT_32	[p1l1253t2258r1343b2279],
3	had	VBD	O	have	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1354t2258r1396b2279],
4	no	DT	O	no	det	5	SENT_32	[p1l1407t2264r1437b2279],
5	role	NN	O	role	dobj	3	SENT_32	[p1l1447t2258r1491b2279],
6	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1501t2259r1520b2279],
7	data	NN	O	datum	nn	8	SENT_32	[p1l1530t2258r1581b2279],
8	analysis	NN	O	analysis	prep_in	5	SENT_32	[p1l1591t2258r1689b2285],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1591t2258r1689b2285],
10	preparation	NN	O	preparation	dobj	3	SENT_32	[p1l1699t2259r1839b2285],
11	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1849t2258r1874b2279],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_32	[p1l1880t2258r1919b2279],
13	manuscript	NN	O	manuscript	prep_of	10	SENT_32	[p1l1929t2259r2070b2285],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1929t2259r2070b2285],
15	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l2079t2265r2103b2279],
16	decision	NN	O	decision	conj_or	5	SENT_32	[p1l2111t2258r2210b2279],
17	to	TO	O	to	aux	18	SENT_32	[p1l2219t2262r2243b2279],
18	publish	VB	O	publish	infmod	16	SENT_32	[p1l279t2291r373b2318],
19	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l279t2291r373b2318],

1	Competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	2	SENT_33	[p1l278t2343r431b2370],
2	Interests	NNS	O	interest	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l444t2344r571b2364],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l444t2344r571b2364],
4	The	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_33	[p1l581t2343r626b2364],
5	authors	NNS	O	author	nsubj	7	SENT_33	[p1l637t2343r728b2364],
6	have	VBP	O	have	aux	7	SENT_33	[p1l741t2343r796b2364],
7	declared	VBN	O	declare	dep	2	SENT_33	[p1l808t2343r910b2364],
8	that	IN	O	that	complm	12	SENT_33	[p1l922t2343r970b2364],
9	no	DT	O	no	det	11	SENT_33	[p1l982t2349r1011b2364],
10	competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	11	SENT_33	[p1l1023t2344r1153b2370],
11	interests	NNS	O	interest	nsubj	12	SENT_33	[p1l1167t2344r1268b2364],
12	exist	VBP	O	exist	ccomp	7	SENT_33	[p1l1279t2344r1339b2364],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1279t2344r1339b2364],

1	*	NN	O	*	nn	2	SENT_34	[p1l278t2396r289b2406],
2	E	NN	O	e	nsubj	8	SENT_34	[p1l301t2395r379b2416],
3	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	2	SENT_34	[p1l301t2395r379b2416],
4	mai	FW	O	mai	nn	5	SENT_34	[p1l301t2395r379b2416],
5	|	FW	O	|	dep	2	SENT_34	[p1l301t2395r379b2416],
6	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l301t2395r379b2416],
7	mcaws@hotmai	NNS	O	mcaws@hotmai	dep	5	SENT_34	[p1l391t2395r646b2416],
8	|	VBP	O	|	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l391t2395r646b2416],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l391t2395r646b2416],

1	com	NN	O	com	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l391t2395r646b2416],

1	Introduction	NN	O	introduction	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l245t2536r490b2567],

1	It	PRP	O	it	nsubjpass	3	SENT_37	[p1l280t2622r303b2648],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	3	SENT_37	[p1l313t2622r333b2648],
3	estimated	VBN	O	estimate	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l344t2622r485b2648],
4	that	IN	O	that	complm	13	SENT_37	[p1l496t2622r554b2648],
5	one	CD	NUMBER	one	num	6	SENT_37	[p1l564t2631r616b2648],
6	third	NN	ORDINAL	third	nsubjpass	13	SENT_37	[p1l627t2622r699b2648],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l710t2622r742b2648],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_37	[p1l747t2622r792b2648],
9	world	NN	O	world	poss	11	SENT_37	[p1l802t2622r908b2648],
10	’s	POS	O	’s	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l802t2622r908b2648],
11	population	NN	O	population	prep_of	6	SENT_37	[p1l919t2622r1079b2656],
12	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	13	SENT_37	[p1l1090t2622r1110b2648],
13	infected	VBN	O	infect	ccomp	3	SENT_37	[p1l1121t2622r1238b2648],
14	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l242t2666r306b2692],
15	/	:	O	/	punct	17	SENT_37	[p1l317t2666r512b2700],
16	I/Iycobucterium	NN	O	i/iycobucterium	nn	17	SENT_37	[p1l317t2666r512b2700],
17	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	dep	21	SENT_37	[p1l524t2666r669b2692],
18	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	20	SENT_37	[p1l679t2666r726b2700],
19	M.	NN	NUMBER	m.	nn	20	SENT_37	[p1l679t2666r726b2700],
20	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	dep	17	SENT_37	[p1l740t2666r900b2700],
21	)	NN	O	)	prep_with	13	SENT_37	[p1l740t2666r900b2700],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l740t2666r900b2700],
23	although	IN	O	although	mark	28	SENT_37	[p1l913t2666r1044b2700],
24	the	DT	O	the	det	25	SENT_37	[p1l1056t2666r1100b2692],
25	majority	NN	O	majority	nsubj	28	SENT_37	[p1l1113t2666r1239b2700],
26	will	MD	O	will	aux	28	SENT_37	[p1l242t2711r294b2737],
27	never	RB	O	never	neg	28	SENT_37	[p1l315t2720r397b2737],
28	develop	VB	O	develop	advcl	13	SENT_37	[p1l417t2711r531b2745],
29	active	JJ	O	active	amod	30	SENT_37	[p1l553t2711r637b2737],
30	disease	NN	O	disease	dobj	28	SENT_37	[p1l659t2711r768b2737],
31	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l659t2711r768b2737],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_38	[p1l791t2711r851b2737],
2	factors	NNS	O	factor	nsubjpass	11	SENT_38	[p1l872t2711r970b2737],
3	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	4	SENT_38	[p1l991t2711r1049b2737],
4	govern	VBP	O	govern	rcmod	2	SENT_38	[p1l1070t2720r1171b2745],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_38	[p1l1192t2711r1237b2737],
6	development	NN	O	development	dobj	4	SENT_38	[p1l243t2755r435b2789],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l447t2755r479b2781],
8	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	9	SENT_38	[p1l485t2755r660b2781],
9	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_of	6	SENT_38	[p1l672t2755r773b2781],
10	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	11	SENT_38	[p1l786t2764r831b2781],
11	complex	JJ	O	complex	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l843t2755r969b2789],
12	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l981t2755r1036b2781],
13	incompletely	RB	O	incompletely	advmod	14	SENT_38	[p1l1047t2755r1238b2789],
14	understood	VBN	O	understand	conj_and	11	SENT_38	[p1l243t2799r417b2825],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l243t2799r417b2825],

1	Various	JJ	O	various	amod	2	SENT_39	[p1l441t2799r558b2825],
2	factors	NNS	O	factor	nsubjpass	6	SENT_39	[p1l580t2799r677b2825],
3	have	VBP	O	have	aux	6	SENT_39	[p1l700t2799r768b2825],
4	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_39	[p1l791t2799r861b2825],
5	clearly	RB	O	clearly	advmod	6	SENT_39	[p1l884t2799r982b2833],
6	associated	VBN	O	associate	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1003t2799r1152b2825],
7	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1173t2799r1237b2825],
8	increased	VBN	O	increase	amod	9	SENT_39	[p1l243t2844r382b2870],
9	susceptibility	NN	O	susceptibility	prep_with	6	SENT_39	[p1l403t2844r593b2878],
10	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l612t2850r639b2870],
11	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_to	9	SENT_39	[p1l660t2844r843b2870],
12	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l660t2844r843b2870],

1	HIV	NN	O	hiv	nn	2	SENT_40	[p1l865t2844r934b2870],
2	infection	NN	O	infection	nsubj	3	SENT_40	[p1l954t2844r1082b2870],
3	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1103t2844r1122b2870],
4	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1143t2844r1179b2878],
5	far	RB	O	far	advmod	6	SENT_40	[p1l1197t2844r1238b2869],
6	the	DT	O	the	prep_by	3	SENT_40	[p1l243t2888r287b2914],
7	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	8	SENT_40	[p1l307t2894r378b2914],
8	important	JJ	O	important	amod	6	SENT_40	[p1l397t2888r553b2922],
9	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l397t2888r553b2922],
10	it	PRP	O	it	nsubj	11	SENT_40	[p1l573t2888r592b2914],
11	increases	VBZ	O	increase	parataxis	3	SENT_40	[p1l611t2888r742b2914],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_40	[p1l762t2888r806b2914],
13	lifetime	NN	O	lifetime	nn	14	SENT_40	[p1l826t2888r935b2914],
14	risk	NN	O	risk	dobj	11	SENT_40	[p1l955t2888r1006b2914],
15	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1025t2888r1057b2914],
16	sub-clinical	JJ	O	sub-clinical	amod	17	SENT_40	[p1l1071t2888r1237b2914],
17	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_of	14	SENT_40	[p1l243t2933r371b2959],
18	converting	VBG	O	convert	xcomp	11	SENT_40	[p1l388t2933r546b2967],
19	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l561t2939r589b2959],
20	active	JJ	O	active	amod	21	SENT_40	[p1l606t2933r690b2959],
21	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_to	18	SENT_40	[p1l707t2933r808b2959],
22	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l825t2933r896b2959],
23	1	CD	NUMBER	1	prep_from	18	SENT_40	[p1l917t2933r925b2958],
24	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l945t2933r973b2958],
25	10	CD	NUMBER	10	prep_in	18	SENT_40	[p1l994t2933r1024b2959],
26	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1041t2939r1068b2959],
27	l	NN	O	l	prep_to	18	SENT_40	[p1l1090t2934r1098b2958],
28	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1118t2933r1145b2958],
29	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	30	SENT_40	[p1l1163t2933r1177b2959],
30	[	NN	O	[	prep_in	27	SENT_40	[p1l1199t2933r1233b2967],
31	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	32	SENT_40	[p1l1199t2933r1233b2967],
32	]	NN	O	]	dep	30	SENT_40	[p1l1199t2933r1233b2967],
33	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l243t2977r298b3003],
34	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	36	SENT_40	[p1l321t2977r340b3003],
35	strongly	RB	O	strongly	advmod	36	SENT_40	[p1l363t2977r481b3011],
36	associated	VBN	O	associate	conj_and	11	SENT_40	[p1l503t2977r652b3003],
37	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l673t2977r738b3003],
38	disseminated	VBN	O	disseminate	amod	39	SENT_40	[p1l761t2977r952b3003],
39	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_with	36	SENT_40	[p1l974t2977r1084b3003],
40	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l974t2977r1084b3003],

1	Deﬁning	VBG	O	deﬁning	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1108t2977r1238b3011],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_41	[p1l243t3022r287b3048],
3	contribution	NN	O	contribution	dobj	1	SENT_41	[p1l319t3022r503b3048],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l534t3022r566b3048],
5	host	NN	O	host	nn	7	SENT_41	[p1l592t3022r652b3048],
6	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	7	SENT_41	[p1l683t3022r787b3056],
7	polymorphisms	NNS	O	polymorphism	prep_of	3	SENT_41	[p1l817t3022r1046b3056],
8	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l1077t3028r1104b3048],
9	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_to	1	SENT_41	[p1l1135t3022r1237b3048],

1	01	CD	NUMBER	01	num	2	SENT_42	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
2	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	3	SENT_42	[p1l344t3144r408b3167],
3	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l423t3143r567b3174],
4	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	5	SENT_42	[p1l587t3142r590b3175],
5	www	NN	O	www	dobj	3	SENT_42	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],

1	p	NN	O	p	nsubj	8	SENT_43	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	4	SENT_43	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	nn	4	SENT_43	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
4	susceptibility	NN	O	susceptibility	dep	1	SENT_43	[p1l1314t2535r1504b2569],
5	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	8	SENT_43	[p1l1528t2535r1576b2561],
6	been	VBN	O	be	cop	8	SENT_43	[p1l1601t2535r1671b2561],
7	more	RBR	O	more	advmod	8	SENT_43	[p1l1696t2544r1772b2561],
8	difficult	JJ	O	difficult	_	0	SENT_43	[p1l1797t2535r1916b2561],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_43	[p1l1797t2535r1916b2561],

1	Studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	3	SENT_44	[p1l1944t2535r2049b2561],
2	have	VBP	O	have	aux	3	SENT_44	[p1l2074t2535r2142b2561],
3	suggested	VBN	O	suggest	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l2168t2535r2309b2569],
4	polymorphisms	NNS	O	polymorphism	nsubjpass	9	SENT_44	[p1l1313t2579r1542b2613],
5	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1558t2579r1585b2604],
6	several	JJ	O	several	amod	7	SENT_44	[p1l1602t2579r1702b2605],
7	genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_in	4	SENT_44	[p1l1718t2588r1798b2613],
8	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	9	SENT_44	[p1l1815t2588r1860b2605],
9	associated	VBN	O	associate	ccomp	3	SENT_44	[p1l1877t2579r2026b2605],
10	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l2040t2579r2105b2605],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_44	[p1l2121t2579r2165b2605],
12	development	NN	O	development	prep_with	9	SENT_44	[p1l2182t2579r2308b2613, p1l1314t2629r1390b2649],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1420t2623r1452b2649],
14	pulmonary	JJ	O	pulmonary	amod	15	SENT_44	[p1l1477t2623r1641b2657],
15	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	12	SENT_44	[p1l1671t2623r1853b2649],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1671t2623r1853b2649],

1	Some	DT	O	some	nsubj	22	SENT_45	[p1l1887t2623r1969b2649],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2000t2623r2032b2649],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_45	[p1l2057t2623r2102b2649],
4	genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_of	1	SENT_45	[p1l2133t2632r2214b2657],
5	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2244t2623r2308b2649],
6	polymorphisms	NNS	O	polymorphism	prep_with	4	SENT_45	[p1l1313t2668r1542b2702],
7	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	16	SENT_45	[p1l1558t2668r1616b2694],
8	have	VBP	O	have	aux	10	SENT_45	[p1l1632t2668r1701b2694],
9	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	10	SENT_45	[p1l1718t2668r1788b2694],
10	validated	VBN	O	validate	rcmod	6	SENT_45	[p1l1804t2668r1940b2694],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1956t2668r1983b2693],
12	multiple	JJ	O	multiple	amod	13	SENT_45	[p1l2000t2668r2121b2702],
13	studies	NNS	O	study	prep_in	10	SENT_45	[p1l2139t2668r2236b2694],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2254t2668r2309b2694],
15	may	MD	O	may	aux	16	SENT_45	[p1l1314t2721r1378b2746],
16	have	VB	O	have	conj_and	10	SENT_45	[p1l1391t2712r1459b2738],
17	an	DT	O	a	det	18	SENT_45	[p1l1474t2721r1509b2737],
18	effect	NN	O	effect	dobj	16	SENT_45	[p1l1524t2712r1602b2738],
19	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1616t2721r1652b2738],
20	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	21	SENT_45	[p1l1666t2721r1733b2746],
21	function	NN	O	function	prep_on	18	SENT_45	[p1l1748t2712r1870b2738],
22	include	VBP	O	include	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1885t2712r1991b2738],
23	solute	JJ	O	solute	amod	25	SENT_45	[p1l2006t2712r2090b2738],
24	carrier	NN	O	carrier	nn	25	SENT_45	[p1l2105t2712r2204b2738],
25	family	NN	O	family	dobj	22	SENT_45	[p1l2216t2712r2309b2746],
26	11	CD	NUMBER	11	dep	25	SENT_45	[p1l1319t2756r1358b2788],
27	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1319t2756r1358b2788],
28	member	NN	O	member	conj_and	25	SENT_45	[p1l1375t2756r1500b2782],
29	1	CD	NUMBER	1	number	30	SENT_45	[p1l1521t2757r1529b2781],
30	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	31	SENT_45	[p1l1550t2756r1716b2790],
31	SLCl1A1	NN	O	slcl1a1	dep	28	SENT_45	[p1l1550t2756r1716b2790],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1550t2756r1716b2790],
33	formerly	RB	O	formerly	advmod	36	SENT_45	[p1l1733t2756r1861b2790],
34	NRAMPI	NNP	O	NRAMPI	nn	36	SENT_45	[p1l1877t2756r2038b2790],
35	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	36	SENT_45	[p1l1877t2756r2038b2790],
36	[	NN	O	[	rcmod	28	SENT_45	[p1l2059t2756r2144b2790],
37	2	CD	NUMBER	2	number	38	SENT_45	[p1l2059t2756r2144b2790],
38	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	36	SENT_45	[p1l2059t2756r2144b2790],
39	6	CD	NUMBER	6	num	40	SENT_45	[p1l2059t2756r2144b2790],
40	]	NN	O	]	dep	38	SENT_45	[p1l2059t2756r2144b2790],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2059t2756r2144b2790],
42	interferon	NN	O	interferon	nn	44	SENT_45	[p1l2162t2756r2308b2782],
43	gamma	NN	O	gamma	nn	44	SENT_45	[p1l1314t2809r1425b2834],
44	[	NN	O	[	dobj	22	SENT_45	[p1l1445t2800r1520b2834],
45	7,8	CD	NUMBER	7,8	num	46	SENT_45	[p1l1445t2800r1520b2834],
46	]	NN	O	]	dep	44	SENT_45	[p1l1445t2800r1520b2834],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1445t2800r1520b2834],
48	TIRAP/MAL	NN	O	tirap/mal	dobj	22	SENT_45	[p1l1542t2799r1741b2826],
49	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	50	SENT_45	[p1l1761t2800r1808b2834],
50	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	51	SENT_45	[p1l1761t2800r1808b2834],
51	]	NN	O	]	dep	48	SENT_45	[p1l1761t2800r1808b2834],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1761t2800r1808b2834],
53	PQXA7	NN	O	pqxa7	nn	55	SENT_45	[p1l1826t2800r1935b2827],
54	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	55	SENT_45	[p1l1957t2800r2069b2834],
55	lO	NN	O	lo	dobj	22	SENT_45	[p1l1957t2800r2069b2834],
56	,11	CD	NUMBER	,11	num	57	SENT_45	[p1l1957t2800r2069b2834],
57	]	NN	O	]	dep	55	SENT_45	[p1l1957t2800r2069b2834],
58	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1957t2800r2069b2834],
59	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2088t2800r2143b2826],
60	CCL2	NN	O	ccl2	dobj	22	SENT_45	[p1l2160t2800r2251b2826],
61	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	60	SENT_45	[p1l2270t2800r2309b2834],
62	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2270t2800r2309b2834],
63	MCP-1	NN	O	mcp-1	conj_or	25	SENT_45	[p1l1314t2845r1442b2879],
64	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	63	SENT_45	[p1l1314t2845r1442b2879],
65	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1314t2845r1442b2879],
66	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	67	SENT_45	[p1l1467t2845r1588b2879],
67	12	CD	NUMBER	12	num	68	SENT_45	[p1l1467t2845r1588b2879],
68	—	NN	O	—	appos	63	SENT_45	[p1l1467t2845r1588b2879],
69	14	CD	NUMBER	14	num	70	SENT_45	[p1l1467t2845r1588b2879],
70	]	NN	O	]	dep	68	SENT_45	[p1l1467t2845r1588b2879],
71	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1467t2845r1588b2879],

1	Others	NNS	O	other	nsubj	3	SENT_46	[p1l1611t2845r1712b2871],
2	have	VBP	O	have	aux	3	SENT_46	[p1l1733t2845r1801b2871],
3	shown	VBN	O	show	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l1822t2845r1916b2871],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	41	SENT_46	[p1l1936t2845r1981b2871],
5	less	JJR	O	less	amod	41	SENT_46	[p1l2002t2845r2050b2871],
6	common	JJ	O	common	amod	8	SENT_46	[p1l2071t2854r2202b2871],
7	extrapulmonary	JJ	O	extrapulmonary	amod	8	SENT_46	[p1l2222t2851r2308b2871, p1l1313t2889r1478b2923],
8	manifestations	NNS	O	manifestation	nsubj	12	SENT_46	[p1l1487t2889r1700b2915],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l1712t2889r1743b2915],
10	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	8	SENT_46	[p1l1749t2889r1924b2915],
11	may	MD	O	may	aux	12	SENT_46	[p1l1934t2898r1998b2923],
12	have	VB	O	have	ccomp	5	SENT_46	[p1l2007t2889r2076b2915],
13	a	DT	O	a	det	18	SENT_46	[p1l2088t2898r2103b2914],
14	different	JJ	O	different	amod	18	SENT_46	[p1l2114t2889r2238b2915],
15	host	NN	O	host	nn	18	SENT_46	[p1l2248t2889r2309b2915],
16	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	18	SENT_46	[p1l1314t2933r1418b2967],
17	susceptibility	NN	O	susceptibility	nn	18	SENT_46	[p1l1439t2933r1630b2967],
18	proﬁle	NN	O	proﬁle	dobj	12	SENT_46	[p1l1649t2933r1743b2967],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l1765t2933r1820b2959],
20	have	VBP	O	have	aux	21	SENT_46	[p1l1841t2933r1909b2959],
21	implicated	VBN	O	implicate	conj_and	12	SENT_46	[p1l1931t2933r2087b2967],
22	various	JJ	O	various	amod	23	SENT_46	[p1l2106t2933r2213b2959],
23	polymorphism	NN	O	polymorphism	dobj	21	SENT_46	[p1l2233t2933r2308b2967, p1l1314t2977r1465b3011],
24	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l1480t2977r1507b3002],
25	components	NNS	O	component	prep_in	21	SENT_46	[p1l1521t2983r1701b3011],
26	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l1716t2977r1748b3003],
27	the	DT	O	the	det	30	SENT_46	[p1l1756t2977r1801b3003],
28	innate	JJ	O	innate	amod	30	SENT_46	[p1l1816t2977r1907b3003],
29	host	NN	O	host	nn	30	SENT_46	[p1l1922t2977r1983b3003],
30	response	NN	O	response	prep_of	25	SENT_46	[p1l1996t2986r2123b3011],
31	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l2138t2983r2165b3003],
32	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_to	5	SENT_46	[p1l2180t2977r2308b3003],
33	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	32	SENT_46	[p1l1318t3022r1371b3056],
34	15	CD	NUMBER	15	num	35	SENT_46	[p1l1318t3022r1371b3056],
35	]	NN	O	]	dep	32	SENT_46	[p1l1318t3022r1371b3056],
36	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	37	SENT_46	[p1l1404t3022r1504b3056],
37	16,17	CD	NUMBER	16,17	num	38	SENT_46	[p1l1404t3022r1504b3056],
38	]	NN	O	]	dep	35	SENT_46	[p1l1404t3022r1504b3056],
39	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	40	SENT_46	[p1l1536t3022r1647b3056],
40	18,19	CD	NUMBER	18,19	num	41	SENT_46	[p1l1536t3022r1647b3056],
41	]	NN	O	]	dobj	3	SENT_46	[p1l1536t3022r1647b3056],
42	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l1536t3022r1647b3056],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	4	SENT_47	[p1l1673t3022r1723b3048],
2	have	VBP	O	have	aux	4	SENT_47	[p1l1748t3022r1817b3048],
3	recently	RB	DATE	recently	advmod	4	SENT_47	[p1l1842t3022r1960b3056],
4	reported	VBN	O	report	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l1984t3022r2111b3056],
5	associations	NNS	O	association	dobj	4	SENT_47	[p1l2135t3022r2308b3048],

1	Author	NN	O	author	nn	2	SENT_48	[p2l279t269r418b300],
2	Summary	NN	O	summary	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l435t270r623b308],

1	It	PRP	O	it	nsubjpass	3	SENT_50	[p2l1138t388r1156b413],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	3	SENT_50	[p2l1178t387r1198b413],
3	estimated	VBN	O	estimate	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l279t428r431b455],
4	that	IN	O	that	complm	14	SENT_50	[p2l461t428r523b455],
5	approximately	RB	O	approximately	quantmod	6	SENT_50	[p2l551t428r775b463],
6	one	CD	NUMBER	one	num	8	SENT_50	[p2l803t428r945b455],
7	—	NN	O	—	nn	8	SENT_50	[p2l803t428r945b455],
8	third	NN	ORDINAL	third	nsubjpass	14	SENT_50	[p2l803t428r945b455],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l975t428r1007b455],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_50	[p2l1032t428r1082b455],
11	world	NN	O	world	nn	12	SENT_50	[p2l1110t428r1197b455],
12	population	NN	O	population	prep_of	8	SENT_50	[p2l280t469r448b503],
13	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	14	SENT_50	[p2l472t470r492b496],
14	infected	VBN	O	infect	ccomp	3	SENT_50	[p2l515t469r638b496],
15	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l661t469r727b496],
16	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	17	SENT_50	[p2l750t471r784b496],
17	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_with	14	SENT_50	[p2l808t469r992b501],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l808t469r992b501],
19	though	IN	O	though	mark	24	SENT_50	[p2l1013t469r1126b504],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_50	[p2l1148t469r1198b496],
21	majority	NN	O	majority	nsubj	24	SENT_50	[p2l280t512r407b546],
22	will	MD	O	will	aux	24	SENT_50	[p2l417t511r467b538],
23	never	RB	O	never	neg	24	SENT_50	[p2l481t519r566b538],
24	develop	VB	O	develop	advcl	14	SENT_50	[p2l577t511r701b545],
25	active	JJ	O	active	amod	26	SENT_50	[p2l713t512r802b538],
26	disease	NN	O	disease	dobj	24	SENT_50	[p2l814t511r933b538],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l814t511r933b538],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_51	[p2l944t511r1001b538],
2	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	3	SENT_51	[p2l1013t515r1089b538],
3	severe	JJ	O	severe	amod	4	SENT_51	[p2l1100t519r1198b538],
4	form	NN	O	form	nsubj	7	SENT_51	[p2l278t552r350b579],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l363t552r395b579],
6	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	4	SENT_51	[p2l403t552r591b579],
7	occurs	VBZ	O	occur	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l602t560r701b579],
8	when	WRB	O	when	advmod	11	SENT_51	[p2l712t552r796b579],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_51	[p2l808t552r858b579],
10	bacterium	NN	O	bacterium	nsubj	11	SENT_51	[p2l871t552r1025b579],
11	spreads	VBZ	O	spread	advcl	7	SENT_51	[p2l1038t552r1156b586],
12	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l1167t557r1198b579],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_51	[p2l279t594r328b621],
14	brain	NN	O	brain	prep_to	11	SENT_51	[p2l346t594r421b621],
15	to	TO	O	to	aux	16	SENT_51	[p2l438t599r469b621],
16	cause	VB	O	cause	infmod	14	SENT_51	[p2l485t602r571b621],
17	meningitis	NN	O	meningitis	dobj	16	SENT_51	[p2l589t595r758b629],
18	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l589t595r758b629],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_52	[p2l773t596r821b621],
2	examined	VBD	O	examine	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l838t594r988b621],
3	whether	IN	O	whether	complm	13	SENT_52	[p2l1004t594r1134b621],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_52	[p2l1149t594r1198b621],
5	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	6	SENT_52	[p2l279t636r394b670],
6	variation	NN	O	variation	nsubj	13	SENT_52	[p2l405t636r538b662],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l552t635r583b662],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_52	[p2l592t635r641b662],
9	person	NN	O	person	prep_of	6	SENT_52	[p2l655t643r758b669],
10	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l771t635r827b662],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_52	[p2l839t635r889b662],
12	bacteria	NNS	O	bacterium	prep_of	6	SENT_52	[p2l902t635r1023b662],
13	influenced	VBD	O	influence	ccomp	2	SENT_52	[p2l1037t635r1197b662],
14	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_52	[p2l279t677r328b704],
15	type	NN	O	type	nsubj	20	SENT_52	[p2l341t681r409b712],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l422t677r453b704],
17	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_of	15	SENT_52	[p2l464t677r575b704],
18	a	DT	O	a	det	19	SENT_52	[p2l588t685r603b704],
19	person	NN	O	person	dep	17	SENT_52	[p2l617t685r721b711],
20	develops	VBZ	O	develop	ccomp	13	SENT_52	[p2l735t677r882b711],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l735t677r882b711],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	4	SENT_53	[p2l894t679r942b704],
2	have	VBP	O	have	aux	4	SENT_53	[p2l956t677r1027b704],
3	previously	RB	DATE	previously	advmod	4	SENT_53	[p2l1041t677r1199b712],
4	shown	VBN	O	show	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l279t718r380b745],
5	that	IN	O	that	complm	16	SENT_53	[p2l404t718r466b745],
6	certain	JJ	O	certain	amod	7	SENT_53	[p2l490t719r593b745],
7	mutations	NNS	O	mutation	nsubj	16	SENT_53	[p2l619t719r774b745],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l799t719r824b745],
9	genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_in	7	SENT_53	[p2l849t726r940b753],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l964t718r996b745],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_53	[p2l1016t718r1066b745],
12	human	JJ	O	human	amod	14	SENT_53	[p2l1091t718r1197b745],
13	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	14	SENT_53	[p2l280t761r407b787],
14	system	NN	O	system	prep_of	9	SENT_53	[p2l434t765r539b795],
15	can	MD	O	can	aux	16	SENT_53	[p2l567t768r618b787],
16	predispose	VB	O	predispose	ccomp	4	SENT_53	[p2l647t760r815b794],
17	adults	NNS	O	adult	dobj	16	SENT_53	[p2l842t760r934b787],
18	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l962t761r986b787],
19	Vietnam	NNP	LOCATION	Vietnam	prep_in	17	SENT_53	[p2l1012t761r1140b787],
20	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l1167t765r1198b787],
21	developing	VBG	O	develop	amod	23	SENT_53	[p2l279t801r452b836],
22	tuberculous	JJ	O	tuberculous	amod	23	SENT_53	[p2l468t801r653b828],
23	meningitis	NN	O	meningitis	prep_to	16	SENT_53	[p2l668t802r837b836],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l668t802r837b836],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l853t803r877b828],
2	this	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_54	[p2l892t801r947b828],
3	study	NN	O	study	prep_in	5	SENT_54	[p2l961t801r1046b836],
4	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	5	SENT_54	[p2l1059t809r1103b828],
5	show	VBP	O	show	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l1117t801r1199b828],
6	that	IN	O	that	complm	20	SENT_54	[p2l279t843r341b870],
7	some	DT	O	some	det	8	SENT_54	[p2l360t851r442b870],
8	strains	NNS	O	strain	nsubj	20	SENT_54	[p2l462t844r560b870],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l580t843r611b870],
10	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	11	SENT_54	[p2l627t845r661b870],
11	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	8	SENT_54	[p2l682t843r858b870],
12	commonly	RB	O	commonly	advmod	13	SENT_54	[p2l878t843r1043b878],
13	found	VBN	O	find	partmod	11	SENT_54	[p2l1060t843r1151b870],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l1173t844r1197b870],
15	Europe	NNP	LOCATION	Europe	prep_in	13	SENT_54	[p2l281t886r388b918],
16	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l407t884r463b911],
17	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_in	13	SENT_54	[p2l482t885r607b911],
18	are	VBP	O	be	cop	20	SENT_54	[p2l627t892r673b911],
19	less	RBR	O	less	advmod	20	SENT_54	[p2l693t884r746b911],
20	likely	JJ	O	likely	ccomp	5	SENT_54	[p2l766t884r842b919],
21	to	TO	O	to	aux	22	SENT_54	[p2l859t889r890b911],
22	cause	VB	O	cause	xcomp	20	SENT_54	[p2l909t892r995b911],
23	tuberculous	JJ	O	tuberculous	amod	24	SENT_54	[p2l1013t884r1198b911],
24	meningitis	NN	O	meningitis	dobj	22	SENT_54	[p2l280t927r442b961],
25	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l455t927r480b953],
26	Vietnamese	JJ	MISC	vietnamese	amod	27	SENT_54	[p2l493t927r674b953],
27	adults	NNS	O	adult	prep_in	24	SENT_54	[p2l686t926r779b953],
28	than	IN	O	than	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l791t926r859b953],
29	strains	NNS	O	strain	prep_than	22	SENT_54	[p2l873t927r972b953],
30	predominantly	RB	O	predominantly	advmod	31	SENT_54	[p2l986t926r1199b960, p2l281t967r304b1002],
31	found	VBN	O	find	partmod	29	SENT_54	[p2l329t967r420b994],
32	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l449t968r473b994],
33	Asia	NNP	LOCATION	Asia	prep_in	31	SENT_54	[p2l501t968r571b994],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l501t968r571b994],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	18	SENT_55	[p2l597t969r646b994],
2	then	RB	O	then	advmod	3	SENT_55	[p2l672t967r741b994],
3	looked	VBD	O	look	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l771t967r873b994],
4	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l901t971r929b994],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_55	[p2l955t967r1005b994],
6	interaction	NN	O	interaction	prep_at	3	SENT_55	[p2l1032t968r1197b994],
7	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l280t1009r414b1036],
8	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	10	SENT_55	[p2l432t1011r466b1036],
9	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	10	SENT_55	[p2l486t1009r662b1036],
10	strains	NNS	O	strain	prep_between	6	SENT_55	[p2l680t1010r778b1036],
11	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l796t1009r852b1036],
12	mutations	NNS	O	mutation	conj_and	10	SENT_55	[p2l872t1010r1027b1036],
13	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l1046t1010r1071b1036],
14	human	JJ	O	human	amod	16	SENT_55	[p2l1091t1009r1197b1036],
15	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	16	SENT_55	[p2l280t1051r407b1077],
16	genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_in	3	SENT_55	[p2l422t1058r513b1085],
17	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l528t1050r584b1077],
18	show	VBP	O	show	conj_and	3	SENT_55	[p2l600t1050r681b1077],
19	that	IN	O	that	complm	30	SENT_55	[p2l695t1050r757b1077],
20	a	DT	O	a	det	22	SENT_55	[p2l771t1058r785b1077],
21	particular	JJ	O	particular	amod	22	SENT_55	[p2l802t1050r947b1084],
22	mutation	NN	O	mutation	nsubjpass	30	SENT_55	[p2l962t1051r1111b1082],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l962t1051r1111b1082],
24	TLR2	NN	O	tlr2	nn	25	SENT_55	[p2l1124t1052r1198b1077],
25	T597C	NN	O	t597c	appos	22	SENT_55	[p2l278t1093r382b1124],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l278t1093r382b1124],
27	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	30	SENT_55	[p2l398t1093r418b1119],
28	more	RBR	O	more	advmod	29	SENT_55	[p2l433t1100r512b1119],
29	commonly	RB	O	commonly	advmod	30	SENT_55	[p2l527t1092r692b1127],
30	found	VBN	O	find	ccomp	18	SENT_55	[p2l705t1092r796b1119],
31	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l813t1093r837b1119],
32	patients	NNS	O	patient	prep_in	30	SENT_55	[p2l854t1093r977b1126],
33	infected	VBN	O	infect	partmod	32	SENT_55	[p2l993t1092r1116b1119],
34	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l1131t1092r1197b1119],
35	the	DT	O	the	det	36	SENT_55	[p2l279t1133r328b1160],
36	East	NNP	O	East	prep_with	33	SENT_55	[p2l344t1134r618b1168],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l344t1134r618b1168],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l344t1134r618b1168],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l344t1134r618b1168],

1	Asian/Beijing	VBG	O	asian/beijing	amod	2	SENT_57	[p2l344t1134r618b1168],
2	strains	NNS	O	strain	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l634t1134r732b1160],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l748t1133r779b1160],
4	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	5	SENT_57	[p2l790t1135r824b1160],
5	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	2	SENT_57	[p2l841t1133r1025b1160],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l841t1133r1025b1160],

1	This	DT	O	this	nsubj	5	SENT_58	[p2l1038t1133r1099b1160],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	5	SENT_58	[p2l1115t1134r1135b1160],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_58	[p2l1149t1133r1198b1160],
4	first	JJ	ORDINAL	first	amod	5	SENT_58	[p2l278t1175r336b1202],
5	study	NN	O	study	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l365t1175r449b1210],
6	to	TO	O	to	aux	7	SENT_58	[p2l477t1180r508b1202],
7	look	VB	O	look	infmod	5	SENT_58	[p2l538t1175r603b1202],
8	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l630t1179r659b1202],
9	both	CC	O	both	preconj	11	SENT_58	[p2l688t1175r758b1202],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_58	[p2l788t1175r838b1202],
11	host	NN	O	host	prep_at	7	SENT_58	[p2l868t1175r933b1202],
12	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l962t1175r1018b1202],
13	pathogen	NN	O	pathogen	nn	14	SENT_58	[p2l1049t1175r1197b1210],
14	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	prep_at	7	SENT_58	[p2l279t1221r442b1251],
15	together	RB	O	together	advmod	7	SENT_58	[p2l468t1216r604b1251],
16	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l630t1217r655b1243],
17	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	18	SENT_58	[p2l682t1216r870b1243],
18	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_in	7	SENT_58	[p2l897t1216r1039b1248],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l897t1216r1039b1248],
20	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l1065t1216r1121b1243],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_58	[p2l1149t1216r1198b1243],
22	findings	NNS	O	finding	nsubj	23	SENT_58	[p2l278t1258r403b1293],
23	suggest	VBP	O	suggest	conj_and	5	SENT_58	[p2l427t1262r548b1293],
24	that	IN	O	that	complm	33	SENT_58	[p2l571t1258r633b1285],
25	the	DT	O	the	det	26	SENT_58	[p2l656t1258r705b1285],
26	outcome	NN	O	outcome	nsubj	33	SENT_58	[p2l729t1262r867b1285],
27	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l891t1258r923b1285],
28	exposure	NN	O	exposure	prep_of	26	SENT_58	[p2l944t1266r1085b1292],
29	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l1109t1262r1140b1285],
30	M.	FW	O	m.	nn	31	SENT_58	[p2l1163t1260r1197b1285],
31	tuberculosis	FW	O	tuberculosis	prep_to	28	SENT_58	[p2l280t1299r456b1326],
32	can	MD	O	can	aux	33	SENT_58	[p2l468t1307r520b1326],
33	depend	VB	O	depend	ccomp	23	SENT_58	[p2l533t1299r651b1333],
34	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l664t1307r701b1326],
35	both	CC	O	both	preconj	38	SENT_58	[p2l716t1299r786b1326],
36	the	DT	O	the	det	38	SENT_58	[p2l799t1299r848b1326],
37	human	JJ	O	human	amod	38	SENT_58	[p2l862t1299r968b1326],
38	genotype	NN	O	genotype	prep_on	33	SENT_58	[p2l981t1304r1129b1334],
39	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l1141t1299r1197b1326],
40	the	DT	O	the	det	42	SENT_58	[p2l279t1341r328b1368],
41	bacterial	JJ	O	bacterial	amod	42	SENT_58	[p2l345t1341r474b1368],
42	genotype	NN	O	genotype	prep_on	33	SENT_58	[p2l490t1346r646b1376],
43	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l490t1346r646b1376],

1	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1314t255r1436b281],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_59	[p2l1470t255r1515b281],
3	development	NN	O	development	prep_between	10	SENT_59	[p2l1549t255r1741b289],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1775t255r1807b281],
5	TBM	NN	O	tbm	nn	9	SENT_59	[p2l1835t255r1917b280],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1950t255r2005b281],
7	single	JJ	O	single	conj_and	5	SENT_59	[p2l2039t255r2120b289],
8	nucleotide	NN	O	nucleotide	nn	9	SENT_59	[p2l2155t255r2307b281],
9	polymorphisms	NNS	O	polymorphism	prep_of	3	SENT_59	[p2l1313t299r1542b333],
10	(	VBP	O	(	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1561t299r1645b333],
11	SNP	NN	O	snp	nn	12	SENT_59	[p2l1561t299r1645b333],
12	)	NN	O	)	dobj	10	SENT_59	[p2l1561t299r1645b333],
13	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1664t299r1691b324],
14	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_59	[p2l1709t299r1753b325],
15	Toll-interleukin-l	NN	O	toll-interleukin-l	nn	17	SENT_59	[p2l1772t299r2032b325],
16	receptor	NN	O	receptor	nn	17	SENT_59	[p2l2054t305r2178b333],
17	domain	NN	O	domain	prep_in	10	SENT_59	[p2l2196t299r2308b325],
18	containing	VBG	O	contain	partmod	17	SENT_59	[p2l1314t342r1472b376],
19	adaptor	NN	O	adaptor	nn	20	SENT_59	[p2l1499t342r1614b376],
20	protein	NN	O	protein	dobj	18	SENT_59	[p2l1640t342r1747b376],
21	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	22	SENT_59	[p2l1776t341r1893b376],
22	TIRAH	NN	O	tirah	nsubj	10	SENT_59	[p2l1776t341r1893b376],
23	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1921t342r1976b368],
24	Toll-like	JJ	MISC	toll-like	amod	25	SENT_59	[p2l2003t342r2127b368],
25	receptor-2	NN	O	receptor-2	nsubj	10	SENT_59	[p2l2155t342r2307b376],
26	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	29	SENT_59	[p2l1315t385r1428b420],
27	TLR-2	NN	O	tlr-2	nn	29	SENT_59	[p2l1315t385r1428b420],
28	)	NN	O	)	nn	29	SENT_59	[p2l1315t385r1428b420],
29	genes	NNS	O	gene	nsubj	30	SENT_59	[p2l1456t395r1537b420],
30	[	VBP	O	[	rcmod	25	SENT_59	[p2l1569t386r1680b420],
31	19,20	CD	NUMBER	19,20	number	32	SENT_59	[p2l1569t386r1680b420],
32	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	30	SENT_59	[p2l1569t386r1680b420],
33	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1569t386r1680b420],

1	However	RB	O	however	advmod	5	SENT_60	[p2l1710t386r1854b418],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1710t386r1854b418],
3	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	4	SENT_60	[p2l1883t386r2058b412],
4	disease	NN	O	disease	nsubj	5	SENT_60	[p2l2086t386r2187b412],
5	results	VBZ	O	result	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l2216t386r2308b412],
6	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1313t429r1384b455],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_60	[p2l1412t429r1457b455],
8	interactions	NNS	O	interaction	prep_from	5	SENT_60	[p2l1485t429r1657b455],
9	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1685t429r1807b455],
10	host	NN	O	host	prep_between	8	SENT_60	[p2l1835t429r1895b455],
11	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1922t429r1978b455],
12	bacteria	NNS	O	bacterium	conj_and	10	SENT_60	[p2l2004t429r2124b455],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l2151t429r2206b455],
14	there	EX	O	there	expl	18	SENT_60	[p2l2233t429r2307b455],
15	have	VBP	O	have	aux	18	SENT_60	[p2l1314t473r1382b499],
16	been	VBN	O	be	cop	18	SENT_60	[p2l1402t473r1472b499],
17	no	DT	O	no	det	18	SENT_60	[p2l1492t482r1528b499],
18	studies	NNS	O	study	conj_and	5	SENT_60	[p2l1548t473r1646b499],
19	examining	VBG	O	examine	partmod	18	SENT_60	[p2l1666t473r1823b507],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_60	[p2l1841t473r1886b499],
21	inﬂuence	NN	O	inﬂuence	dobj	19	SENT_60	[p2l1906t473r2039b499],
22	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l2060t473r2115b499],
23	relationship	NN	O	relationship	conj_and	21	SENT_60	[p2l2134t473r2308b507],
24	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1314t516r1346b542],
25	both	CC	O	both	preconj	26	SENT_60	[p2l1357t516r1424b542],
26	host	NN	O	host	prep_of	21	SENT_60	[p2l1441t516r1502b542],
27	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1518t516r1573b542],
28	bacterial	JJ	O	bacterial	amod	30	SENT_60	[p2l1589t516r1717b542],
29	genotype	NN	O	genotype	nn	30	SENT_60	[p2l1733t522r1867b550],
30	variation	NN	O	variation	prep_of	21	SENT_60	[p2l1883t516r2016b542],
31	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l2033t525r2069b542],
32	clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	34	SENT_60	[p2l2086t516r2190b542],
33	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	34	SENT_60	[p2l2206t516r2308b542],
34	phenotype	NN	O	phenotype	prep_on	19	SENT_60	[p2l1313t560r1477b594],
35	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1313t560r1477b594],

1	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	3	SENT_61	[p2l1350t604r1390b630],
2	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	3	SENT_61	[p2l1405t604r1549b630],
3	‘	NN	O	‘	nsubj	4	SENT_61	[p2l1405t604r1549b630],
4	exhibits	VBZ	O	exhibit	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l1561t604r1674b630],
5	a	DT	O	a	det	8	SENT_61	[p2l1687t613r1703b629],
6	clonal	JJ	O	clonal	amod	8	SENT_61	[p2l1715t604r1803b630],
7	population	NN	O	population	nn	8	SENT_61	[p2l1815t604r1976b638],
8	structure	NN	O	structure	nsubj	11	SENT_61	[p2l1990t610r2119b630],
9	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	10	SENT_61	[p2l2136t604r2237b638],
10	21,22	CD	NUMBER	21,22	num	11	SENT_61	[p2l2136t604r2237b638],
11	]	NN	O	]	xcomp	4	SENT_61	[p2l2136t604r2237b638],
12	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l2254t604r2309b630],
13	therefore	RB	O	therefore	advmod	15	SENT_61	[p2l1314t647r1447b673],
14	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	15	SENT_61	[p2l1465t656r1519b673],
15	regarded	VBN	O	regard	conj_and	4	SENT_61	[p2l1538t647r1670b681],
16	until	IN	O	until	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l1687t647r1755b673],
17	recently	RB	DATE	recently	advmod	18	SENT_61	[p2l1773t647r1891b681],
18	as	IN	O	as	amod	28	SENT_61	[p2l1908t656r1936b673],
19	an	DT	O	a	det	20	SENT_61	[p2l1955t656r1990b672],
20	organism	NN	O	organism	dep	18	SENT_61	[p2l2008t647r2145b681],
21	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l2162t647r2226b673],
22	little	JJ	O	little	amod	25	SENT_61	[p2l2244t647r2308b673],
23	relevant	JJ	O	relevant	amod	25	SENT_61	[p2l1314t691r1433b717],
24	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	25	SENT_61	[p2l1451t691r1555b725],
25	variation	NN	O	variation	prep_with	20	SENT_61	[p2l1573t691r1706b717],
26	[	NN	O	[	nn	28	SENT_61	[p2l1729t691r1793b725],
27	23	CD	NUMBER	23	num	28	SENT_61	[p2l1729t691r1793b725],
28	]	NN	O	]	prep_until	15	SENT_61	[p2l1729t691r1793b725],
29	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l1729t691r1793b725],

1	However	RB	O	however	advmod	19	SENT_62	[p2l1814t691r1957b723],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1814t691r1957b723],
3	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	19	SENT_62	[p2l1978t691r2075b717],
4	examining	VBG	O	examine	partmod	3	SENT_62	[p2l2095t691r2251b725],
5	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	8	SENT_62	[p2l2267t691r2307b717],
6	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	8	SENT_62	[p2l1315t734r1459b760],
7	‘	NN	O	‘	nn	8	SENT_62	[p2l1315t734r1459b760],
8	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	dobj	4	SENT_62	[p2l1469t734r1574b760],
9	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1585t734r1656b760],
10	wider	JJR	O	wider	amod	12	SENT_62	[p2l1667t734r1751b760],
11	geographic	JJ	O	geographic	amod	12	SENT_62	[p2l1762t734r1926b768],
12	distributions	NNS	O	distribution	prep_from	4	SENT_62	[p2l1938t734r2120b760],
13	using	VBG	O	use	partmod	12	SENT_62	[p2l2132t734r2210b768],
14	whole	JJ	O	whole	amod	17	SENT_62	[p2l2220t734r2308b760],
15	genome	NN	O	genome	nn	17	SENT_62	[p2l1314t787r1430b812],
16	scanning	NN	O	scanning	nn	17	SENT_62	[p2l1451t778r1582b812],
17	approaches	NNS	O	approach	dobj	13	SENT_62	[p2l1601t778r1769b812],
18	have	VBP	O	have	aux	19	SENT_62	[p2l1789t778r1857b804],
19	revealed	VBN	O	reveal	dep	40	SENT_62	[p2l1877t778r2001b804],
20	a	DT	O	a	det	23	SENT_62	[p2l2021t787r2037b803],
21	cladal	JJ	O	cladal	amod	23	SENT_62	[p2l2056t778r2142b804],
22	phylogeographic	JJ	O	phylogeographic	amod	23	SENT_62	[p2l2161t778r2308b812, p2l1314t822r1425b856],
23	distribution	NN	O	distribution	dobj	19	SENT_62	[p2l1452t822r1622b848],
24	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1647t822r1712b848],
25	signiﬁcant	JJ	O	signiﬁcant	amod	26	SENT_62	[p2l1738t822r1889b856],
26	variation	NN	O	variation	prep_with	19	SENT_62	[p2l1913t822r2046b848],
27	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l2072t822r2195b848],
28	major	JJ	O	major	amod	29	SENT_62	[p2l2221t822r2309b856],
29	lineages	NNS	O	lineage	prep_between	26	SENT_62	[p2l1314t865r1438b899],
30	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1314t865r1438b899],
31	each	DT	O	each	nsubjpass	35	SENT_62	[p2l1463t865r1530b891],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1554t865r1585b891],
33	which	WDT	O	which	prep_of	31	SENT_62	[p2l1602t865r1691b891],
34	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	35	SENT_62	[p2l1714t865r1734b891],
35	associated	VBN	O	associate	rcmod	29	SENT_62	[p2l1757t865r1906b891],
36	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1927t865r1992b891],
37	speciﬁc	NN	O	speciﬁc	nn	39	SENT_62	[p2l2015t865r2121b899],
38	geographic	JJ	O	geographic	amod	39	SENT_62	[p2l2144t865r2308b899],
39	regions	NNS	O	region	prep_with	35	SENT_62	[p2l1314t909r1420b943],
40	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1447t909r1547b943],
41	24,25	CD	NUMBER	24,25	num	42	SENT_62	[p2l1447t909r1547b943],
42	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	40	SENT_62	[p2l1447t909r1547b943],
43	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	46	SENT_62	[p2l1576t909r1678b943],
44	Figure	NNP	O	Figure	nn	46	SENT_62	[p2l1576t909r1678b943],
45	l	NN	O	l	nn	46	SENT_62	[p2l1707t909r1736b943],
46	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	40	SENT_62	[p2l1707t909r1736b943],
47	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1707t909r1736b943],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_63	[p2l1761t909r1821b935],
2	degree	NN	O	degree	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l1845t909r1942b943],
3	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l1966t915r1994b935],
4	which	WDT	O	which	rel	13	SENT_63	[p2l2017t909r2106b935],
5	this	DT	O	this	det	8	SENT_63	[p2l2130t909r2180b935],
6	genetic	JJ	O	genetic	amod	8	SENT_63	[p2l2204t909r2308b943],
7	variation	NN	O	variation	nn	8	SENT_63	[p2l1313t952r1446b978],
8	inﬂuences	NNS	O	inﬂuences	nsubj	13	SENT_63	[p2l1460t952r1607b978],
9	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	10	SENT_63	[p2l1621t952r1722b978],
10	phenotype	NN	O	phenotype	dep	8	SENT_63	[p2l1737t952r1893b986],
11	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	13	SENT_63	[p2l1907t952r1955b978],
12	been	VBN	O	be	cop	13	SENT_63	[p2l1969t952r2039b978],
13	difficult	JJ	O	difficult	ccomp	2	SENT_63	[p2l2054t952r2166b978],
14	to	TO	O	to	aux	15	SENT_63	[p2l2179t958r2207b978],
15	study	VB	O	study	xcomp	13	SENT_63	[p2l2222t952r2306b986],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l2222t952r2306b986],

1	In	FW	O	in	nn	2	SENT_64	[p2l1314t996r1341b1022],
2	vitro	FW	O	vitro	dep	6	SENT_64	[p2l1366t996r1419b1022],
3	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1444t996r1499b1022],
4	in	FW	O	in	conj_and	2	SENT_64	[p2l1523t996r1546b1022],
5	vivo	FW	O	vivo	pobj	4	SENT_64	[p2l1570t996r1617b1022],
6	models	NNS	O	model	nsubj	10	SENT_64	[p2l1640t996r1744b1022],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1769t996r1801b1022],
8	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_of	6	SENT_64	[p2l1820t996r1948b1022],
9	have	VBP	O	have	aux	10	SENT_64	[p2l1972t996r2041b1022],
10	shown	VBN	O	show	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l2066t996r2160b1022],
11	different	JJ	O	different	amod	12	SENT_64	[p2l2184t996r2309b1022],
12	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	nsubj	16	SENT_64	[p2l1314t1045r1460b1073],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1487t1039r1519b1065],
14	M.	NN	O	m.	nn	15	SENT_64	[p2l1538t1039r1578b1065],
15	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	prep_of	12	SENT_64	[p2l1607t1039r1751b1065],
16	induce	VBP	O	induce	ccomp	10	SENT_64	[p2l1775t1039r1873b1065],
17	different	JJ	O	different	amod	18	SENT_64	[p2l1900t1039r2025b1065],
18	patterns	NNS	O	pattern	dobj	16	SENT_64	[p2l2050t1045r2169b1073],
19	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l2196t1039r2228b1065],
20	host	NN	O	host	nn	23	SENT_64	[p2l2248t1039r2309b1065],
21	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	23	SENT_64	[p2l1314t1083r1436b1109],
22	response	NN	O	response	nn	23	SENT_64	[p2l1453t1092r1579b1117],
23	[	NN	O	[	prep_of	18	SENT_64	[p2l1599t1083r1721b1117],
24	26	CD	NUMBER	26	num	25	SENT_64	[p2l1599t1083r1721b1117],
25	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	16	SENT_64	[p2l1599t1083r1721b1117],
26	30	CD	NUMBER	30	num	27	SENT_64	[p2l1599t1083r1721b1117],
27	]	NN	O	]	dep	25	SENT_64	[p2l1599t1083r1721b1117],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1599t1083r1721b1117],
29	but	CC	O	but	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1737t1083r1786b1109],
30	the	DT	O	the	det	31	SENT_64	[p2l1801t1083r1845b1109],
31	relevance	NN	O	relevance	nsubj	39	SENT_64	[p2l1862t1083r2001b1109],
32	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l2017t1083r2049b1109],
33	these	DT	O	these	det	34	SENT_64	[p2l2059t1083r2133b1109],
34	ﬁndings	NNS	O	ﬁndings	prep_of	31	SENT_64	[p2l2148t1083r2265b1117],
35	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l2280t1089r2308b1109],
36	human	JJ	O	human	amod	37	SENT_64	[p2l1314t1127r1418b1153],
37	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_to	34	SENT_64	[p2l1437t1127r1539b1153],
38	remains	VBZ	O	remain	cop	39	SENT_64	[p2l1558t1127r1675b1153],
39	uncertain	JJ	O	uncertain	conj_but	10	SENT_64	[p2l1693t1127r1842b1153],
40	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1693t1127r1842b1153],

1	Epidemiological	JJ	O	epidemiological	amod	2	SENT_65	[p2l1863t1127r2104b1161],
2	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	4	SENT_65	[p2l2123t1127r2220b1153],
3	have	VBP	O	have	aux	4	SENT_65	[p2l2239t1127r2308b1153],
4	found	VBN	O	find	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l1313t1170r1400b1196],
5	some	DT	O	some	det	6	SENT_65	[p2l1419t1179r1494b1196],
6	genotypes	NNS	O	genotype	nsubjpass	9	SENT_65	[p2l1513t1176r1659b1204],
7	may	MD	O	may	aux	9	SENT_65	[p2l1678t1179r1742b1204],
8	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	9	SENT_65	[p2l1760t1170r1794b1196],
9	associated	VBN	O	associate	ccomp	4	SENT_65	[p2l1814t1170r1962b1196],
10	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l1980t1170r2044b1196],
11	different	JJ	O	different	amod	13	SENT_65	[p2l2063t1170r2188b1196],
12	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	13	SENT_65	[p2l2206t1170r2308b1196],
13	phenotypes	NNS	O	phenotype	prep_with	9	SENT_65	[p2l1313t1214r1490b1248],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l1313t1214r1490b1248],

1	For	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1519t1214r1570b1240],
2	example	NN	O	example	prep_for	7	SENT_66	[p2l1597t1214r1729b1248],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1597t1214r1729b1248],
4	several	JJ	O	several	amod	5	SENT_66	[p2l1758t1214r1858b1240],
5	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	16	SENT_66	[p2l1885t1214r1983b1240],
6	have	VBP	O	have	aux	7	SENT_66	[p2l2010t1214r2078b1240],
7	suggested	VBN	O	suggest	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l2106t1214r2246b1248],
8	an	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_66	[p2l2273t1223r2308b1239],
9	association	NN	O	association	dobj	7	SENT_66	[p2l1314t1257r1474b1283],
10	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1496t1257r1618b1283],
11	mycobacterial	JJ	O	mycobacterial	amod	14	SENT_66	[p2l1640t1257r1850b1291],
12	plc	NN	O	plc	nn	14	SENT_66	[p2l1867t1257r1907b1291],
13	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	14	SENT_66	[p2l1927t1266r1994b1291],
14	polymorphism	NN	O	polymorphism	prep_between	9	SENT_66	[p2l2016t1257r2232b1291],
15	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l2254t1257r2309b1283],
16	disseminated	VBN	O	disseminate	conj_and	7	SENT_66	[p2l1314t1301r1506b1327],
17	extra-pulmonary	JJ	O	extra-pulmonary	amod	20	SENT_66	[p2l1523t1301r1774b1335],
18	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	20	SENT_66	[p2l1791t1301r1892b1327],
19	[	NN	O	[	nn	20	SENT_66	[p2l1913t1301r2035b1335],
20	3l	NN	O	3l	dobj	16	SENT_66	[p2l1913t1301r2035b1335],
21	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	23	SENT_66	[p2l1913t1301r2035b1335],
22	33	CD	NUMBER	33	num	23	SENT_66	[p2l1913t1301r2035b1335],
23	]	NN	O	]	dobj	7	SENT_66	[p2l1913t1301r2035b1335],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1913t1301r2035b1335],
25	but	CC	O	but	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l2053t1301r2102b1327],
26	these	DT	O	these	det	27	SENT_66	[p2l2118t1301r2192b1327],
27	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	35	SENT_66	[p2l2210t1301r2308b1327],
28	have	VBP	O	have	aux	30	SENT_66	[p2l1314t1345r1382b1371],
29	been	VBN	O	be	cop	30	SENT_66	[p2l1413t1345r1484b1371],
30	small	JJ	O	small	conj_but	7	SENT_66	[p2l1515t1345r1599b1377],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1515t1345r1599b1377],
32	retrospective	JJ	O	retrospective	conj_or	30	SENT_66	[p2l1631t1345r1828b1379],
33	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1631t1345r1828b1379],
34	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1860t1354r1891b1371],
35	unable	JJ	O	unable	conj_or	30	SENT_66	[p2l1921t1345r2020b1371],
36	to	TO	O	to	aux	37	SENT_66	[p2l2051t1351r2079b1371],
37	determine	VB	O	determine	xcomp	30	SENT_66	[p2l2110t1345r2259b1371],
38	if	IN	O	if	advmod	37	SENT_66	[p2l2291t1345r2314b1370],

1	East	JJ	MISC	east	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l1226t1523r1304b1549],
2	Asian	JJ	MISC	asian	dep	1	SENT_67	[p2l1314t1521r1414b1549],

1	East	JJ	MISC	east	dep	2	SENT_68	[p2l1042t2448r1120b2473],
2	African	JJ	MISC	african	_	0	SENT_68	[p2l1130t2448r1258b2473],
3	I	PRP	O	I	nsubj	4	SENT_68	[p2l1088t2491r1092b2517],
4	ineage	VBP	O	ineage	ccomp	2	SENT_68	[p2l1098t2491r1214b2525],

1	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	2	SENT_69	[p2l242t2687r280b2713],
2	Bovis	NNP	PERSON	Bovis	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l296t2687r396b2713],
3	lineage	NN	O	lineage	dep	2	SENT_69	[p2l410t2687r538b2721],

1	@	IN	O	@	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l448t2787r556b2891],
2	West	NNP	O	West	nn	3	SENT_70	[p2l600t2841r688b2869],
3	African-2	NN	O	african-2	pobj	1	SENT_70	[p2l698t2841r864b2869],

1	Euro-American	JJ	MISC	euro-american	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l2046t1758r2313b1786],

1	Figure	NNP	O	Figure	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l244t2948r343b2979],
2	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	1	SENT_72	[p2l358t2950r382b2972],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l358t2950r382b2972],

1	Mycobacterium	NN	O	mycobacterium	nn	3	SENT_73	[p2l395t2948r620b2979],
2	tuberculosis	NN	O	tuberculosis	nn	3	SENT_73	[p2l632t2948r808b2972],
3	lineages	NNS	O	lineage	nsubj	4	SENT_73	[p2l817t2948r947b2979],
4	defined	VBN	O	define	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l959t2948r1078b2972],
5	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l1092t2948r1130b2979],
6	large	JJ	O	large	amod	8	SENT_73	[p2l1143t2948r1221b2979],
7	sequence	NN	O	sequence	nn	8	SENT_73	[p2l1234t2955r1382b2979],
8	polymorphism	NN	O	polymorphism	prep_by	4	SENT_73	[p2l1395t2948r1624b2979],
9	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	12	SENT_73	[p2l1638t2949r1715b2976],
10	LSP	NN	O	lsp	nn	12	SENT_73	[p2l1638t2949r1715b2976],
11	)	NN	O	)	nn	12	SENT_73	[p2l1638t2949r1715b2976],
12	analysis	NN	O	analysis	dep	8	SENT_73	[p2l1728t2948r1862b2979],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l1728t2948r1862b2979],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_74	[p2l1873t2948r1924b2972],
2	circles	NNS	O	circle	nsubj	3	SENT_74	[p2l1936t2948r2019b2972],
3	represent	VBP	O	represent	_	0	SENT_74	[p2l2033t2952r2163b2979],
4	Region	NN	O	region	nsubj	10	SENT_74	[p2l2176t2949r2269b2979],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_74	[p2l2282t2948r2310b2972],
6	difference	NN	O	difference	nn	9	SENT_74	[p2l243t2985r380b3009],
7	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	9	SENT_74	[p2l394t2986r441b3013],
8	RD	NN	O	rd	nn	9	SENT_74	[p2l394t2986r441b3013],
9	region	NN	O	region	prep_of	4	SENT_74	[p2l454t2986r550b3016],
10	)	CD	NUMBER	)	xcomp	3	SENT_74	[p2l454t2986r550b3016],
11	deleted	VBN	O	delete	partmod	10	SENT_74	[p2l564t2985r667b3009],
12	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_74	[p2l681t2986r703b3009],
13	each	DT	O	each	det	14	SENT_74	[p2l717t2985r780b3009],
14	lineage	NN	O	lineage	prep_in	11	SENT_74	[p2l795t2985r900b3016],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_74	[p2l795t2985r900b3016],

1	Only	RB	O	only	advmod	2	SENT_75	[p2l913t2985r976b3016],
2	East	JJ	MISC	east	_	0	SENT_75	[p2l989t2986r1043b3009],
3	Asian	JJ	MISC	asian	amod	6	SENT_75	[p2l1055t2986r1135b3013],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_75	[p2l1055t2986r1135b3013],
5	|	JJ	O	|	amod	6	SENT_75	[p2l1150t2985r1330b3009],
6	ndo	NN	O	ndo	dep	2	SENT_75	[p2l1150t2985r1330b3009],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_75	[p2l1150t2985r1330b3009],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_76	[p2l1150t2985r1330b3009],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_76	[p2l1150t2985r1330b3009],

1	Oceanic	NNP	O	Oceanic	_	0	SENT_77	[p2l1150t2985r1330b3009],
2	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_77	[p2l1344t2985r1393b3009],
3	Euro	NNP	O	Euro	conj_and	1	SENT_77	[p2l1409t2986r1609b3009],
4	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_77	[p2l1409t2986r1609b3009],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_78	[p2l1409t2986r1609b3009],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_78	[p2l1409t2986r1609b3009],

1	American	JJ	MISC	american	amod	2	SENT_79	[p2l1409t2986r1609b3009],
2	lineages	NNS	O	lineage	nsubjpass	4	SENT_79	[p2l1625t2985r1736b3016],
3	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	4	SENT_79	[p2l1748t2992r1815b3009],
4	identiﬁed	VBN	O	identiﬁed	_	0	SENT_79	[p2l1829t2985r1957b3009],
5	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_79	[p2l1972t2986r1994b3009],
6	Vietnam	NNP	LOCATION	Vietnam	prep_in	4	SENT_79	[p2l2007t2986r2129b3009],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_79	[p2l2007t2986r2129b3009],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_80	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],
2	:10.1371	CD	NUMBER	:10.1371	dep	1	SENT_80	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],
3	/	:	O	/	punct	5	SENT_80	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],
4	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	5	SENT_80	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],
5	|	NN	O	|	dep	2	SENT_80	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_80	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_81	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],
2	.1000034	CD	NUMBER	.1000034	dep	1	SENT_81	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_81	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],

1	g001	NN	O	g001	_	0	SENT_82	[p2l243t3023r777b3054],

1	T	NN	PERCENT	t	nn	3	SENT_83	[p2l242t3124r316b3183],
2	%	NN	PERCENT	%	nn	3	SENT_83	[p2l242t3124r316b3183],
3	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	4	SENT_83	[p2l344t3144r408b3167],
4	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_83	[p2l423t3143r567b3174],
5	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	6	SENT_83	[p2l587t3142r590b3175],
6	www	NN	O	www	dobj	4	SENT_83	[p2l610t3143r949b3174],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_83	[p2l610t3143r949b3174],
