1	OPEN	NN	MISC	open	nn	3	SENT_1	[p1l242t131r323b155],
2	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	3	SENT_1	[p1l333t112r365b162],
3	ACCESS	NNP	O	ACCESS	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l372t131r484b155],
4	Freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	5	SENT_1	[p1l501t130r590b162],
5	available	JJ	O	available	amod	7	SENT_1	[p1l597t130r731b155],
6	online	JJ	O	online	amod	7	SENT_1	[p1l739t130r832b155],
7	PLUS	NNS	O	plus	dep	3	SENT_1	[p1l2004t111r2118b153],
8	PATHOGENS	NNS	O	pathogen	dep	7	SENT_1	[p1l2129t130r2308b154],

1	Vesicular	JJ	O	vesicular	amod	5	SENT_2	[p1l243t240r569b300],
2	Stomatitis	NNP	O	Stomatitis	nn	5	SENT_2	[p1l601t240r963b300],
3	Virus-Based	NNP	O	Virus-Based	nn	5	SENT_2	[p1l994t240r1414b300],
4	Ebola	NNP	O	Ebola	nn	5	SENT_2	[p1l1453t240r1644b300],
5	Vaccine	NNP	O	Vaccine	nsubj	7	SENT_2	[p1l1677t240r1953b300],
6	Is	VBZ	O	be	cop	7	SENT_2	[p1l1989t243r2037b300],
7	WellTolerated	NNP	O	WellTolerated	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l2069t240r2249b300, p1l242t331r585b391],

1	and	CC	O	and	dep	2	SENT_3	[p1l611t331r742b391],
2	Protects	VBZ	O	protect	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l773t333r1061b391],
3	lmmunocompromised	JJ	O	lmmunocompromised	amod	5	SENT_3	[p1l1089t331r1878b407],
4	Nonhuman	JJ	MISC	nonhuman	amod	5	SENT_3	[p1l1909t331r2303b391],
5	Primates	NNS	MISC	primate	dobj	2	SENT_3	[p1l248t422r556b482],

1	Thomas	NNP	PERSON	Thomas	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l242t551r399b582],
2	W.	NNP	PERSON	W.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l414t553r464b582],
3	Geisbert	NNP	PERSON	Geisbert	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
4	"	``	O	"	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
5	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
6	'	''	DATE	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
7	3	CD	DATE	3	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
8	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
9	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
10	’	CD	NUMBER	’	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
11	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
12	’	NN	O	’	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
13	°	CD	NUMBER	°	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
14	*	NN	O	*	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l480t544r828b586],
16	Kathleen	NNP	PERSON	Kathleen	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l847t551r1019b582],
17	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1038t553r1084b582],
18	Daddario-DiCaprio	NNP	PERSON	Daddario-DiCaprio	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1102t544r1559b589],
19	"	``	O	"	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1102t544r1559b589],
20	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1102t544r1559b589],
21	’	CD	NUMBER	’	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1102t544r1559b589],
22	°	NN	O	°	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1102t544r1559b589],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1102t544r1559b589],
24	Mark	NNP	PERSON	Mark	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1577t551r1678b582],
25	G.	NNP	PERSON	G.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1693t553r1733b582],
26	Lewis	NNP	PERSON	Lewis	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1750t544r1887b586],
27	’	NNP	O	’	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1750t544r1887b586],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1750t544r1887b586],
29	Joan	NNP	PERSON	Joan	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1903t553r1994b582],
30	B.	NNP	PERSON	B.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2013t553r2047b582],
31	Geisbert	NNP	PERSON	Geisbert	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2064t544r2287b586],
32	“	NNP	O	“	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2064t544r2287b586],
33	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2064t544r2287b586],
34	Allen	NNP	PERSON	Allen	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l243t609r343b640],
35	Grolla7	NNP	O	Grolla7	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l357t603r505b644],
36	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l357t603r505b644],
37	Anders	NNP	PERSON	Anders	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l518t609r659b640],
38	Leungs	NNP	PERSON	Leungs	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l673t603r822b648],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l673t603r822b648],
40	Jason	NNP	PERSON	Jason	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l834t611r945b640],
41	Paragasg	NNP	PERSON	Paragasg	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l960t603r1144b648],
42	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l960t603r1144b648],
43	Lennox	NNP	PERSON	Lennox	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1159t611r1304b640],
44	Matthias	NNP	PERSON	Matthias	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1317t603r1517b644],
45	’	NN	O	’	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1317t603r1517b644],
46	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1317t603r1517b644],
47	Mark	NNP	PERSON	Mark	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1531t609r1632b640],
48	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1642t611r1681b640],
49	Smith	NNP	PERSON	Smith	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1695t603r1856b644],
50	‘	VBD	O	‘	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1695t603r1856b644],
51	°	CD	NUMBER	°	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1695t603r1856b644],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1695t603r1856b644],
53	Steven	NNP	PERSON	Steven	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1870t610r2003b640],
54	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2018t611r2064b640],
55	Jones8	NNP	PERSON	Jones8	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2075t603r2307b644],
56	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2075t603r2307b644],
57	"	``	O	"	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2075t603r2307b644],
58	"	``	O	"	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2075t603r2307b644],
59	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2075t603r2307b644],
60	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2075t603r2307b644],
61	Lisa	NNP	PERSON	Lisa	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l245t667r317b698],
62	E.	NNP	PERSON	E.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l336t669r368b698],
63	Hensleys	NNPS	PERSON	Hensleys	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l386t661r570b706],
64	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l386t661r570b706],
65	Heinz	NNP	PERSON	Heinz	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l588t667r699b698],
66	Feldmann8	NNP	O	Feldmann8	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l716t661r1007b702],
67	"	``	O	"	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l716t661r1007b702],
68	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l716t661r1007b702],
69	“	CD	NUMBER	“	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l716t661r1007b702],
70	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l716t661r1007b702],
71	Peter	NNP	PERSON	Peter	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1025t669r1127b698],
72	B.	NNP	PERSON	B.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1145t669r1179b698],
73	Jahrling5	NNP	PERSON	Jahrling5	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1194t661r1400b706],
74	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1194t661r1400b706],
75	9	CD	NUMBER	9	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1194t661r1400b706],
76	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l245t736r254b755],
77	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l266t734r364b755],
78	Emerging	VBG	ORGANIZATION	emerge	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l376t735r490b761],
79	Infectious	JJ	ORGANIZATION	infectious	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l502t734r618b755],
80	Diseases	NNS	ORGANIZATION	disease	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l629t735r729b755],
81	Laboratories	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Laboratories	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l740t734r889b755],
82	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l900t735r1004b759],
83	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l900t735r1004b759],
84	Boston	NNP	LOCATION	Boston	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1015t735r1103b759],
85	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1015t735r1103b759],
86	Massachusetts	NNP	LOCATION	Massachusetts	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1113t734r1293b759],
87	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1113t734r1293b759],
88	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1304t734r1382b755],
89	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1393t735r1464b755],
90	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1474t734r1499b755],
91	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1507t735r1611b759],
92	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1507t735r1611b759],
93	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1621t736r1636b755],
94	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1644t735r1789b761],
95	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1799t734r1824b755],
96	Microbiology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Microbiology	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1832t734r1996b761],
97	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1832t734r1996b761],
98	Boston	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Boston	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2007t735r2088b755],
99	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2100t735r2219b761],
100	School	NNP	ORGANIZATION	School	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2228t734r2307b755],
101	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l243t776r268b797],
102	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l277t776r391b801],
103	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l277t776r391b801],
104	Boston	NNP	LOCATION	Boston	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l403t777r490b801],
105	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l403t777r490b801],
106	Massachusetts	NNP	LOCATION	Massachusetts	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l502t776r681b801],
107	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l502t776r681b801],
108	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l693t776r771b797],
109	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l783t777r854b797],
110	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l865t776r890b797],
111	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l898t777r1001b801],
112	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l898t777r1001b801],
113	3	CD	NUMBER	3	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1013t778r1027b797],
114	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1036t777r1181b803],
115	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1191t776r1216b797],
116	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1225t776r1339b801],
117	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1225t776r1339b801],
118	Boston	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Boston	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1351t777r1432b797],
119	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1445t777r1563b803],
120	School	NNP	ORGANIZATION	School	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1573t776r1652b797],
121	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1663t776r1688b797],
122	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1697t776r1811b801],
123	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1697t776r1811b801],
124	Boston	NNP	LOCATION	Boston	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1823t777r1911b801],
125	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1823t777r1911b801],
126	Massachusetts	NNP	LOCATION	Massachusetts	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1922t776r2102b801],
127	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1922t776r2102b801],
128	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2114t776r2192b797],
129	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2204t777r2275b797],
130	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2285t776r2310b797],
131	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l243t818r347b842],
132	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l243t818r347b842],
133	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l355t819r371b838],
134	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l379t818r524b844],
135	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l533t817r558b838],
136	Pathology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Pathology	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l566t817r692b844],
137	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l566t817r692b844],
138	Uniformed	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Uniformed	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l703t817r829b838],
139	Services	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Services	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l840t818r935b838],
140	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l946t818r1064b844],
141	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1072t817r1097b838],
142	the	DT	ORGANIZATION	the	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1104t817r1143b838],
143	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1153t817r1229b838],
144	Sciences	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Sciences	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1239t818r1346b842],
145	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1239t818r1346b842],
146	Bethesda	NNP	LOCATION	Bethesda	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1357t817r1472b842],
147	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1357t817r1472b842],
148	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1482t817r1598b844],
149	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1482t817r1598b844],
150	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1609t817r1687b838],
151	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1697t818r1768b838],
152	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1777t817r1802b838],
153	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1809t818r1913b842],
154	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1809t818r1913b842],
155	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1923t819r1937b838],
156	Integrated	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Integrated	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1946t817r2069b844],
157	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2080t817r2185b838],
158	Facility	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Facility	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2196t817r2278b844],
159	at	IN	O	at	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2286t821r2308b838],
160	Fort	NNP	LOCATION	Fort	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l244t860r290b880],
161	Detrick	NNP	LOCATION	Detrick	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l307t859r396b884],
162	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l307t859r396b884],
163	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l412t859r510b880],
164	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l527t860r625b880],
165	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l640t859r665b880],
166	Allergy	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Allergy	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l678t859r762b886],
167	and	CC	O	and	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l776t859r819b880],
168	Infectious	JJ	O	infectious	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l837t859r953b880],
169	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l969t860r1075b884],
170	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l969t860r1075b884],
171	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1092t859r1190b880],
172	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1207t860r1316b880],
173	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1331t859r1356b880],
174	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1370t859r1453b884],
175	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1370t859r1453b884],
176	Bethesda	NNP	LOCATION	Bethesda	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1469t859r1584b884],
177	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1469t859r1584b884],
178	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1600t859r1717b886],
179	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1600t859r1717b886],
180	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1733t859r1811b880],
181	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1828t860r1899b880],
182	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1914t859r1939b880],
183	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1951t860r2055b884],
184	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1951t860r2055b884],
185	6Viro	NNP	O	6Viro	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2071t859r2193b886],
186	|	CD	NUMBER	|	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2071t859r2193b886],
187	ogy	NN	O	ogy	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2071t859r2193b886],
188	Division	NN	O	division	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2208t860r2308b884],
189	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2208t860r2308b884],
190	BIOQUAL	NN	LOCATION	bioqual	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l244t901r360b925],
191	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t901r360b925],
192	Rockville	NNP	LOCATION	Rockville	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l372t900r482b925],
193	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l372t900r482b925],
194	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l493t900r610b927],
195	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l493t900r610b927],
196	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l622t900r700b921],
197	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l712t901r783b921],
198	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l794t900r819b921],
199	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l828t901r931b925],
200	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l828t901r931b925],
201	7	CD	NUMBER	7	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l943t902r957b921],
202	BIOQUAL	NN	ORGANIZATION	bioqual	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l965t901r1081b925],
203	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l965t901r1081b925],
204	Rockville	NNP	LOCATION	Rockville	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1093t900r1203b925],
205	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1093t900r1203b925],
206	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1215t900r1331b927],
207	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1215t900r1331b927],
208	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1343t900r1421b921],
209	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1433t901r1505b921],
210	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1515t900r1540b921],
211	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1549t901r1652b925],
212	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1549t901r1652b925],
213	8Specia	NNP	O	8Specia	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1664t900r1769b927],
214	|	CD	NUMBER	|	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1664t900r1769b927],
215	Pathogens	NNP	O	Pathogens	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1782t900r1908b927],
216	Program	NNP	O	Program	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1920t901r2027b927],
217	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1920t901r2027b927],
218	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2040t900r2138b921],
219	Microbiology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Microbiology	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2150t900r2309b927],
220	Laboratory	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Laboratory	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l244t942r379b969],
221	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t942r379b969],
222	Public	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Public	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l394t942r465b963],
223	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l479t942r555b963],
224	Agency	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Agency	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l569t943r659b969],
225	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l672t942r696b963],
226	Canada	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Canada	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l707t942r802b967],
227	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l707t942r802b967],
228	Winnipeg	NNP	LOCATION	Winnipeg	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l815t943r937b969],
229	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l815t943r937b969],
230	Manitoba	NNP	LOCATION	Manitoba	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l951t942r1071b967],
231	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l951t942r1071b967],
232	Canada	NNP	LOCATION	Canada	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1084t942r1179b967],
233	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1084t942r1179b967],
234	9Emerging	VBG	O	9emerge	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1192t943r1329b969],
235	Viral	JJ	O	viral	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1343t942r1394b963],
236	Pathogens	NNS	O	pathogen	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1409t942r1535b969],
237	Section	NN	O	section	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1549t943r1642b967],
238	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1549t943r1642b967],
239	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1657t942r1755b963],
240	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1770t943r1868b963],
241	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1881t942r1906b963],
242	Allergy	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Allergy	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1916t942r2000b969],
243	and	CC	O	and	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2013t942r2056b963],
244	Infectious	JJ	O	infectious	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2071t942r2187b963],
245	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2201t943r2308b967],
246	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2201t943r2308b967],
247	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l244t983r342b1004],
248	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l358t984r467b1004],
249	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l481t983r506b1004],
250	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l518t983r601b1008],
251	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l518t983r601b1008],
252	Bethesda	NNP	LOCATION	Bethesda	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l616t983r731b1008],
253	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l616t983r731b1008],
254	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l746t983r862b1010],
255	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l746t983r862b1010],
256	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l877t983r955b1004],
257	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l970t984r1041b1004],
258	of	IN	LOCATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1055t983r1080b1004],
259	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1092t984r1195b1008],
260	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1092t984r1195b1008],
261	10	CD	NUMBER	10	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1211t985r1242b1004],
262	Pathology	NN	O	pathology	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1250t983r1371b1010],
263	Division	NN	O	division	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1385t984r1485b1008],
264	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1385t984r1485b1008],
265	U.S.	NNP	ORGANIZATION	U.S.	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1500t984r1542b1004],
266	Army	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Army	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1556t984r1620b1010],
267	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1633t983r1724b1004],
268	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1740t983r1845b1004],
269	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1861t984r1958b1004],
270	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1972t983r1997b1004],
271	Infectious	JJ	ORGANIZATION	infectious	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2010t983r2125b1004],
272	Diseases	NNS	ORGANIZATION	disease	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2140t984r2246b1008],
273	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2140t984r2246b1008],
274	Fort	NNP	LOCATION	Fort	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2262t984r2308b1004],
275	Detrick	NNP	LOCATION	Detrick	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l244t1025r333b1050],
276	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t1025r333b1050],
277	Maryland	NNP	LOCATION	Maryland	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l344t1025r460b1052],
278	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l344t1025r460b1052],
279	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l471t1025r549b1046],
280	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l560t1026r631b1046],
281	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l641t1025r666b1046],
282	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l673t1026r777b1050],
283	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l673t1026r777b1050],
284	11	CD	NUMBER	11	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l789t1027r815b1046],
285	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l827t1026r972b1052],
286	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l982t1025r1006b1046],
287	Immunology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Immunology	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1015t1025r1174b1052],
288	,	,	ORGANIZATION	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1015t1025r1174b1052],
289	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1185t1026r1304b1052],
290	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1313t1025r1337b1046],
291	Manitoba	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Manitoba	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1345t1025r1465b1050],
292	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1345t1025r1465b1050],
293	Winnipeg	NNP	LOCATION	Winnipeg	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1475t1026r1596b1052],
294	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1475t1026r1596b1052],
295	Manitoba	NNP	LOCATION	Manitoba	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1607t1025r1726b1050],
296	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1607t1025r1726b1050],
297	Canada	NNP	LOCATION	Canada	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1736t1025r1831b1050],
298	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1736t1025r1831b1050],
299	12	CD	NUMBER	12	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1843t1027r1873b1046],
300	Medical	JJ	O	medical	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1881t1025r1972b1046],
301	Microbiology	NNP	O	Microbiology	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l1983t1025r2147b1052],
302	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1983t1025r2147b1052],
303	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2158t1026r2277b1052],
304	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l2286t1025r2310b1046],
305	Manitoba	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Manitoba	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l244t1066r363b1091],
306	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l244t1066r363b1091],
307	Winnipeg	NNP	LOCATION	Winnipeg	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l375t1067r496b1093],
308	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l375t1067r496b1093],
309	Manitoba	NNP	LOCATION	Manitoba	dep	311	SENT_4	[p1l509t1066r629b1091],
310	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l509t1066r629b1091],
311	Canada	NNP	LOCATION	Canada	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l640t1066r729b1087],

1	Abstract	JJ	O	abstract	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l308t1183r475b1214],

1	Ebola	NN	MISC	ebolum	nn	2	SENT_6	[p1l310t1248r392b1275],
2	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubj	10	SENT_6	[p1l405t1249r476b1275],
3	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	5	SENT_6	[p1l490t1249r591b1280],
4	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	nn	5	SENT_6	[p1l490t1249r591b1280],
5	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_6	[p1l490t1249r591b1280],
6	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	10	SENT_6	[p1l605t1249r625b1275],
7	a	DT	O	a	det	10	SENT_6	[p1l637t1256r652b1275],
8	significant	JJ	O	significant	amod	10	SENT_6	[p1l665t1248r823b1283],
9	human	JJ	O	human	amod	10	SENT_6	[p1l836t1248r942b1275],
10	pathogen	NN	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l957t1248r1105b1283],
11	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	12	SENT_6	[p1l1118t1248r1180b1275],
12	presents	VBZ	O	present	rcmod	10	SENT_6	[p1l1192t1253r1322b1282],
13	a	DT	O	a	det	16	SENT_6	[p1l1334t1256r1349b1275],
14	public	JJ	O	public	amod	16	SENT_6	[p1l1363t1248r1457b1282],
15	health	NN	O	health	nn	16	SENT_6	[p1l1470t1248r1564b1275],
16	concern	NN	O	concern	dobj	12	SENT_6	[p1l1577t1256r1699b1275],
17	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1712t1256r1743b1275],
18	an	DT	O	a	det	22	SENT_6	[p1l1755t1256r1790b1275],
19	emerging/re	JJ	O	emerging/re	amod	22	SENT_6	[p1l1803t1249r2157b1283],
20	—	NN	O	—	nn	22	SENT_6	[p1l1803t1249r2157b1283],
21	emerging	VBG	O	emerge	amod	22	SENT_6	[p1l1803t1249r2157b1283],
22	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_as	12	SENT_6	[p1l2170t1249r2242b1275],
23	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l309t1290r365b1317],
24	as	IN	O	as	amod	28	SENT_6	[p1l381t1298r411b1317],
25	a	DT	O	a	det	28	SENT_6	[p1l427t1298r441b1317],
26	potential	JJ	O	potential	amod	28	SENT_6	[p1l459t1290r595b1324],
27	biological	JJ	O	biological	amod	28	SENT_6	[p1l613t1290r760b1325],
28	weapon	NN	O	weapon	prep_as	12	SENT_6	[p1l776t1298r908b1324],
29	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l776t1298r908b1324],

1	Substantial	JJ	O	substantial	amod	2	SENT_7	[p1l924t1290r1094b1317],
2	progress	NN	O	progress	nsubjpass	5	SENT_7	[p1l1111t1298r1243b1325],
3	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	5	SENT_7	[p1l1260t1290r1309b1317],
4	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	5	SENT_7	[p1l1326t1290r1400b1317],
5	made	VBN	O	make	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1418t1290r1503b1317],
6	over	IN	O	over	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1518t1298r1586b1317],
7	the	DT	DATE	the	det	9	SENT_7	[p1l1600t1290r1649b1317],
8	last	JJ	DATE	last	amod	9	SENT_7	[p1l1666t1290r1716b1317],
9	decade	NN	DATE	decade	prep_over	5	SENT_7	[p1l1731t1290r1843b1317],
10	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1859t1291r1883b1317],
11	developing	VBG	O	develop	prepc_in	5	SENT_7	[p1l1900t1290r2073b1325],
12	candidate	NN	O	candidate	nn	14	SENT_7	[p1l2090t1290r2242b1317],
13	preventive	JJ	O	preventive	amod	14	SENT_7	[p1l310t1332r473b1365],
14	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	dobj	11	SENT_7	[p1l492t1332r622b1358],
15	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	17	SENT_7	[p1l641t1331r703b1358],
16	can	MD	O	can	aux	17	SENT_7	[p1l722t1339r774b1358],
17	protect	VB	O	protect	rcmod	14	SENT_7	[p1l796t1336r907b1365],
18	nonhuman	JJ	O	nonhuman	amod	19	SENT_7	[p1l927t1331r1095b1358],
19	primates	NNS	O	primate	dobj	17	SENT_7	[p1l1117t1332r1250b1365],
20	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1270t1332r1381b1366],
21	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	prep_against	17	SENT_7	[p1l1401t1332r1490b1358],
22	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1401t1332r1490b1358],

1	Among	IN	O	among	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1510t1333r1623b1366],
2	these	DT	O	these	det	3	SENT_8	[p1l1643t1331r1726b1358],
3	prospects	NNS	O	prospects	prep_among	7	SENT_8	[p1l1747t1336r1904b1365],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1747t1336r1904b1365],
5	a	DT	O	a	det	6	SENT_8	[p1l1923t1339r1938b1358],
6	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nsubj	7	SENT_8	[p1l1958t1332r2073b1358],
7	based	VBN	O	base	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2094t1331r2183b1358],
8	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2203t1339r2241b1358],
9	recombinant	JJ	O	recombinant	amod	12	SENT_8	[p1l310t1373r507b1400],
10	vesicular	JJ	O	vesicular	amod	12	SENT_8	[p1l521t1373r656b1400],
11	stomatitis	NN	O	stomatitis	nn	12	SENT_8	[p1l670t1374r820b1400],
12	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_on	7	SENT_8	[p1l835t1374r906b1400],
13	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	15	SENT_8	[p1l922t1374r999b1405],
14	VSV	NN	ORGANIZATION	vsv	nn	15	SENT_8	[p1l922t1374r999b1405],
15	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	18	SENT_8	[p1l922t1374r999b1405],
16	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	18	SENT_8	[p1l1015t1374r1035b1400],
17	particularly	RB	O	particularly	advmod	18	SENT_8	[p1l1051t1373r1223b1408],
18	robust	JJ	O	robust	rcmod	12	SENT_8	[p1l1237t1373r1343b1405],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1237t1373r1343b1405],
20	as	IN	O	as	mark	24	SENT_8	[p1l1358t1381r1388b1400],
21	it	PRP	O	it	nsubj	24	SENT_8	[p1l1404t1374r1422b1400],
22	can	MD	O	can	aux	24	SENT_8	[p1l1436t1381r1487b1400],
23	also	RB	O	also	advmod	24	SENT_8	[p1l1503t1373r1562b1400],
24	confer	VB	O	confer	advcl	18	SENT_8	[p1l1577t1373r1675b1400],
25	protection	NN	O	protection	dobj	24	SENT_8	[p1l1690t1374r1849b1407],
26	when	WRB	O	when	advmod	27	SENT_8	[p1l1864t1373r1949b1400],
27	administered	VBN	O	administer	advcl	24	SENT_8	[p1l1964t1373r2166b1400],
28	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2182t1381r2212b1400],
29	a	DT	O	a	det	31	SENT_8	[p1l2227t1381r2241b1400],
30	postexposure	NN	O	postexposure	nn	31	SENT_8	[p1l310t1419r519b1448],
31	treatment	NN	O	treatment	prep_as	27	SENT_8	[p1l530t1419r692b1441],
32	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l530t1419r692b1441],

1	A	DT	O	a	det	2	SENT_9	[p1l703t1416r724b1441],
2	concern	NN	O	concern	nsubj	16	SENT_9	[p1l735t1422r857b1441],
3	that	WDT	O	that	nsubjpass	6	SENT_9	[p1l868t1414r930b1441],
4	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	6	SENT_9	[p1l942t1414r991b1441],
5	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_9	[p1l1003t1414r1078b1441],
6	raised	VBN	O	raise	rcmod	2	SENT_9	[p1l1091t1414r1179b1441],
7	regarding	VBG	O	regard	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1193t1414r1340b1449],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_9	[p1l1352t1414r1402b1441],
9	replication-competent	JJ	O	replication-competent	amod	11	SENT_9	[p1l1414t1414r1761b1448],
10	VSV	NN	ORGANIZATION	vsv	nn	11	SENT_9	[p1l1770t1415r1830b1441],
11	vectors	NNS	O	vector	prep_regarding	6	SENT_9	[p1l1839t1419r1951b1441],
12	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	13	SENT_9	[p1l1961t1414r2023b1441],
13	express	VBP	O	express	rcmod	11	SENT_9	[p1l2034t1422r2148b1448],
14	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	nn	15	SENT_9	[p1l2161t1415r2243b1441],
15	glycoproteins	NNS	O	glycoprotein	dobj	13	SENT_9	[p1l309t1456r520b1491],
16	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l532t1457r552b1483],
17	how	WRB	O	how	advmod	22	SENT_9	[p1l566t1456r631b1483],
18	these	DT	O	these	det	19	SENT_9	[p1l641t1456r725b1483],
19	vectors	NNS	O	vector	nsubjpass	22	SENT_9	[p1l736t1461r847b1483],
20	would	MD	O	would	aux	22	SENT_9	[p1l858t1456r953b1483],
21	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	22	SENT_9	[p1l967t1456r1004b1483],
22	tolerated	VBN	O	tolerate	ccomp	16	SENT_9	[p1l1015t1456r1154b1483],
23	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1168t1456r1205b1491],
24	individuals	NNS	O	individual	agent	22	SENT_9	[p1l1216t1456r1380b1483],
25	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1392t1456r1458b1483],
26	altered	JJ	O	altered	prep_with	24	SENT_9	[p1l1471t1456r1577b1483],
27	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1589t1464r1620b1483],
28	compromised	VBN	O	compromise	ccomp	16	SENT_9	[p1l1631t1456r1844b1490],
29	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	30	SENT_9	[p1l1858t1457r1985b1483],
30	systems	NNS	O	system	dobj	28	SENT_9	[p1l1997t1461r2118b1491],
31	such	JJ	O	such	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l2130t1456r2199b1483],
32	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l2212t1464r2242b1483],
33	patients	NNS	O	patient	prep_such_as	30	SENT_9	[p1l310t1499r433b1532],
34	infected	VBN	O	infect	partmod	33	SENT_9	[p1l447t1498r570b1525],
35	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l584t1498r650b1525],
36	HIV	NN	MISC	hiv	prep_with	34	SENT_9	[p1l666t1500r725b1525],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l666t1500r725b1525],

1	This	DT	O	this	nsubj	4	SENT_10	[p1l737t1498r798b1525],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	4	SENT_10	[p1l812t1499r832b1525],
3	especially	RB	O	especially	advmod	4	SENT_10	[p1l846t1498r996b1533],
4	important	JJ	O	important	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1009t1499r1163b1532],
5	as	IN	O	as	mark	12	SENT_10	[p1l1176t1506r1206b1525],
6	all	DT	O	all	det	8	SENT_10	[p1l1219t1498r1251b1525],
7	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	nn	8	SENT_10	[p1l1267t1499r1349b1525],
8	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	nsubj	12	SENT_10	[p1l1361t1498r1514b1525],
9	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1527t1503r1558b1525],
10	date	NN	O	date	prep_to	8	SENT_10	[p1l1572t1498r1639b1525],
11	have	VBP	O	have	aux	12	SENT_10	[p1l1654t1498r1725b1525],
12	occurred	VBN	O	occur	advcl	4	SENT_10	[p1l1739t1498r1873b1525],
13	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1889t1499r1913b1525],
14	areas	NNS	O	area	prep_in	12	SENT_10	[p1l1928t1506r2007b1525],
15	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2020t1498r2052b1525],
16	Central	NNP	LOCATION	Central	nn	19	SENT_10	[p1l2062t1498r2171b1525],
17	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2185t1498r2241b1525],
18	Western	NNP	LOCATION	Western	nn	19	SENT_10	[p1l308t1541r434b1566],
19	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_of	14	SENT_10	[p1l447t1539r533b1566],
20	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l546t1539r612b1566],
21	high	JJ	O	high	amod	24	SENT_10	[p1l628t1539r694b1574],
22	HIV	NN	MISC	hiv	nn	24	SENT_10	[p1l709t1541r760b1566],
23	incidence	NN	O	incidence	nn	24	SENT_10	[p1l773t1539r920b1566],
24	rates	NNS	O	rate	prep_with	12	SENT_10	[p1l933t1544r1006b1566],
25	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1019t1540r1044b1566],
26	the	DT	O	the	det	27	SENT_10	[p1l1057t1539r1107b1566],
27	population	NN	O	population	prep_in	24	SENT_10	[p1l1121t1539r1297b1573],
28	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1121t1539r1297b1573],

1	In	IN	O	in	mark	4	SENT_11	[p1l1312t1541r1336b1566],
2	order	NN	O	order	dep	4	SENT_11	[p1l1350t1539r1433b1566],
3	to	TO	O	to	aux	4	SENT_11	[p1l1444t1544r1475b1566],
4	address	VB	O	address	dep	9	SENT_11	[p1l1488t1539r1605b1566],
5	this	DT	O	this	det	6	SENT_11	[p1l1617t1539r1672b1566],
6	concern	NN	O	concern	dobj	4	SENT_11	[p1l1685t1547r1816b1571],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1685t1547r1816b1571],
8	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	9	SENT_11	[p1l1828t1547r1872b1566],
9	evaluated	VBD	O	evaluate	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1885t1539r2035b1566],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_11	[p1l2048t1539r2098b1566],
11	safety	NN	O	safety	dobj	9	SENT_11	[p1l2111t1539r2201b1574],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l2213t1539r2245b1566],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_11	[p1l308t1580r358b1607],
14	recombinant	JJ	O	recombinant	amod	16	SENT_11	[p1l371t1580r568b1607],
15	VSV	NN	ORGANIZATION	vsv	nn	16	SENT_11	[p1l578t1581r638b1607],
16	vector	NN	O	vector	prep_of	11	SENT_11	[p1l648t1585r745b1607],
17	expressing	VBG	O	express	partmod	16	SENT_11	[p1l756t1581r919b1615],
18	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_11	[p1l932t1580r982b1607],
19	Zaire	NNP	LOCATION	Zaire	nn	21	SENT_11	[p1l991t1581r1068b1607],
20	ebolavirus	NN	O	ebolavirus	nn	21	SENT_11	[p1l1078t1580r1231b1607],
21	glycoprotein	NN	O	glycoprotein	dobj	17	SENT_11	[p1l1242t1580r1437b1615],
22	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	24	SENT_11	[p1l1451t1580r1739b1612],
23	VSVAG/ZEBOVGP	NN	O	vsvag/zebovgp	nn	24	SENT_11	[p1l1451t1580r1739b1612],
24	)	NN	O	)	tmod	17	SENT_11	[p1l1451t1580r1739b1612],
25	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1752t1581r1777b1607],
26	six	CD	NUMBER	six	num	28	SENT_11	[p1l1790t1581r1828b1607],
27	rhesus	NN	O	rhesus	nn	28	SENT_11	[p1l1840t1580r1938b1607],
28	macaques	NNS	O	macaque	prep_in	24	SENT_11	[p1l1951t1588r2106b1614],
29	infected	VBN	O	infect	partmod	28	SENT_11	[p1l2118t1580r2241b1607],
30	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l308t1622r374b1649],
31	simian	JJ	O	simian	amod	35	SENT_11	[p1l387t1622r607b1649],
32	—	NN	O	—	nn	35	SENT_11	[p1l387t1622r607b1649],
33	human	JJ	O	human	amod	35	SENT_11	[p1l387t1622r607b1649],
34	immunodeﬁciency	NN	O	immunodeﬁciency	nn	35	SENT_11	[p1l620t1622r908b1657],
35	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_with	29	SENT_11	[p1l918t1623r990b1649],
36	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	37	SENT_11	[p1l1002t1623r1100b1654],
37	SHIV	NNP	O	SHIV	dep	24	SENT_11	[p1l1002t1623r1100b1654],
38	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	37	SENT_11	[p1l1002t1623r1100b1654],
39	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1002t1623r1100b1654],

1	All	DT	O	all	det	3	SENT_12	[p1l1111t1622r1148b1649],
2	six	CD	NUMBER	six	num	3	SENT_12	[p1l1160t1623r1199b1649],
3	animals	NNS	O	animal	nsubj	4	SENT_12	[p1l1209t1622r1326b1649],
4	showed	VBD	O	show	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1338t1622r1457b1649],
5	no	DT	O	no	det	6	SENT_12	[p1l1470t1630r1508b1649],
6	evidence	NN	O	evidence	dobj	4	SENT_12	[p1l1519t1622r1657b1649],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1669t1622r1700b1649],
8	illness	NN	O	illness	prep_of	6	SENT_12	[p1l1710t1622r1801b1649],
9	associated	VBN	O	associate	partmod	8	SENT_12	[p1l1812t1622r1972b1649],
10	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1983t1622r2050b1649],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_12	[p1l2061t1622r2111b1649],
12	VSVAG	NNP	O	VSVAG	prep_with	9	SENT_12	[p1l2121t1622r2243b1651],
13	/	:	O	/	punct	15	SENT_12	[p1l2121t1622r2243b1651],
14	ZEBOVGP	NN	O	zebovgp	nn	15	SENT_12	[p1l308t1664r456b1690],
15	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	dep	12	SENT_12	[p1l471t1664r594b1695],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l471t1664r594b1695],
17	suggesting	VBG	O	suggest	partmod	4	SENT_12	[p1l610t1664r779b1698],
18	that	IN	O	that	complm	23	SENT_12	[p1l795t1663r857b1690],
19	this	DT	O	this	det	20	SENT_12	[p1l872t1663r926b1690],
20	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nsubj	23	SENT_12	[p1l941t1664r1057b1690],
21	may	MD	O	may	aux	23	SENT_12	[p1l1073t1671r1137b1698],
22	be	VB	O	be	cop	23	SENT_12	[p1l1153t1663r1189b1690],
23	safe	JJ	O	safe	ccomp	17	SENT_12	[p1l1205t1663r1265b1690],
24	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1281t1664r1306b1690],
25	immunocompromised	JJ	O	immunocompromised	amod	26	SENT_12	[p1l1323t1663r1668b1697],
26	populations	NNS	O	population	prep_in	23	SENT_12	[p1l1686t1663r1877b1697],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1686t1663r1877b1697],

1	While	IN	O	while	mark	7	SENT_13	[p1l1893t1663r1979b1690],
2	one	CD	NUMBER	one	num	3	SENT_13	[p1l1994t1671r2052b1690],
3	goal	NN	O	goal	nsubj	7	SENT_13	[p1l2067t1663r2132b1698],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l2148t1663r2180b1690],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_13	[p1l2192t1663r2242b1690],
6	study	NN	O	study	prep_of	3	SENT_13	[p1l309t1705r394b1740],
7	was	VBD	O	be	advcl	19	SENT_13	[p1l406t1713r464b1732],
8	to	TO	O	to	aux	9	SENT_13	[p1l478t1710r509b1732],
9	evaluate	VB	O	evaluate	xcomp	7	SENT_13	[p1l524t1705r654b1732],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_13	[p1l667t1705r717b1732],
11	safety	NN	O	safety	dobj	9	SENT_13	[p1l732t1705r822b1740],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l836t1705r867b1732],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_13	[p1l878t1705r928b1732],
14	candidate	NN	O	candidate	nn	16	SENT_13	[p1l942t1705r1094b1732],
15	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nn	16	SENT_13	[p1l1108t1706r1223b1732],
16	platform	NN	O	platform	prep_of	11	SENT_13	[p1l1239t1705r1378b1739],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1239t1705r1378b1739],
18	it	PRP	O	it	nsubj	19	SENT_13	[p1l1393t1706r1411b1732],
19	was	VBD	O	be	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1424t1713r1482b1732],
20	also	RB	O	also	advmod	19	SENT_13	[p1l1497t1705r1556b1732],
21	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1570t1705r1602b1732],
22	interest	NN	O	interest	prep_of	19	SENT_13	[p1l1614t1706r1730b1732],
23	to	TO	O	to	aux	24	SENT_13	[p1l1743t1710r1774b1732],
24	determine	VB	O	determine	xcomp	19	SENT_13	[p1l1788t1705r1947b1732],
25	if	IN	O	if	mark	30	SENT_13	[p1l1963t1705r1981b1732],
26	altered	JJ	O	altered	amod	28	SENT_13	[p1l1993t1705r2099b1732],
27	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	28	SENT_13	[p1l2115t1706r2242b1732],
28	status	NN	O	status	nsubj	30	SENT_13	[p1l309t1751r399b1773],
29	would	MD	O	would	aux	30	SENT_13	[p1l415t1746r511b1773],
30	affect	VB	O	affect	advcl	24	SENT_13	[p1l528t1746r614b1773],
31	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nn	32	SENT_13	[p1l630t1747r745b1773],
32	efficacy	NN	O	efficacy	dobj	30	SENT_13	[p1l762t1746r884b1781],
33	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l762t1746r884b1781],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_14	[p1l900t1746r957b1773],
2	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nsubj	3	SENT_14	[p1l973t1747r1088b1773],
3	protected	VBD	O	protect	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1106t1746r1255b1780],
4	4	CD	TIME	4	dobj	3	SENT_14	[p1l1272t1749r1290b1773],
5	of	IN	TIME	of	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1306t1746r1338b1773],
6	6	CD	TIME	6	num	7	SENT_14	[p1l1352t1748r1369b1773],
7	SHIV	NN	O	shiv	prep_of	4	SENT_14	[p1l1386t1746r1593b1773],
8	—	RB	O	—	advmod	4	SENT_14	[p1l1386t1746r1593b1773],
9	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	10	SENT_14	[p1l1386t1746r1593b1773],
10	macaques	NNS	O	macaque	dep	4	SENT_14	[p1l1612t1754r1767b1780],
11	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1783t1746r1855b1773],
12	death	NN	O	death	prep_from	3	SENT_14	[p1l1873t1746r1960b1773],
13	following	VBG	O	follow	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1977t1746r2121b1781],
14	ZEBOV	NN	O	zebov	nn	15	SENT_14	[p1l2138t1747r2243b1773],
15	challenge	NN	O	challenge	prep_following	12	SENT_14	[p1l309t1788r465b1823],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l309t1788r465b1823],

1	Evaluation	NN	O	evaluation	nsubj	10	SENT_15	[p1l479t1788r637b1815],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l651t1788r683b1815],
3	CD4	NN	O	cd4	nn	6	SENT_15	[p1l692t1789r777b1815],
4	+	CC	O	+	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l692t1789r777b1815],
5	T	NN	O	t	conj_+	3	SENT_15	[p1l787t1790r806b1815],
6	cells	NNS	O	cell	prep_of	1	SENT_15	[p1l817t1788r882b1815],
7	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l895t1789r920b1815],
8	all	DT	O	all	det	9	SENT_15	[p1l933t1788r964b1815],
9	animals	NNS	O	animal	prep_in	6	SENT_15	[p1l978t1788r1095b1815],
10	showed	VBD	O	show	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1108t1788r1227b1815],
11	that	IN	O	that	complm	20	SENT_15	[p1l1240t1788r1302b1815],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_15	[p1l1313t1788r1363b1815],
13	animals	NNS	O	animal	nsubj	20	SENT_15	[p1l1375t1788r1492b1815],
14	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	15	SENT_15	[p1l1504t1788r1566b1815],
15	succumbed	VBD	O	succumb	rcmod	13	SENT_15	[p1l1578t1788r1755b1815],
16	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1768t1793r1799b1815],
17	lethal	JJ	O	lethal	amod	19	SENT_15	[p1l1813t1788r1895b1815],
18	ZEBOV	NN	O	zebov	nn	19	SENT_15	[p1l1908t1789r2013b1815],
19	challenge	NN	O	challenge	prep_to	15	SENT_15	[p1l2024t1788r2173b1823],
20	had	VBD	O	have	ccomp	10	SENT_15	[p1l2187t1788r2241b1815],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	23	SENT_15	[p1l308t1829r358b1856],
22	lowest	JJS	O	lowest	amod	23	SENT_15	[p1l373t1829r472b1856],
23	CD4	NN	O	cd4	dobj	20	SENT_15	[p1l486t1830r571b1856],
24	+	CC	O	+	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l486t1830r571b1856],
25	counts	NNS	O	count	conj_+	23	SENT_15	[p1l583t1834r694b1861],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l583t1834r694b1861],
27	suggesting	VBG	O	suggest	partmod	20	SENT_15	[p1l708t1830r878b1864],
28	that	IN	O	that	complm	34	SENT_15	[p1l892t1829r954b1856],
29	CD4	NN	O	cd4	nsubj	34	SENT_15	[p1l967t1830r1052b1856],
30	+	CC	O	+	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l967t1830r1052b1856],
31	T	NN	O	t	nn	32	SENT_15	[p1l1064t1831r1082b1856],
32	cells	NNS	O	cell	nsubj	34	SENT_15	[p1l1095t1829r1160b1856],
33	may	MD	O	may	aux	34	SENT_15	[p1l1174t1837r1239b1864],
34	play	VB	O	play	ccomp	27	SENT_15	[p1l1252t1829r1315b1864],
35	a	DT	O	a	det	36	SENT_15	[p1l1328t1837r1342b1856],
36	role	NN	O	role	dobj	34	SENT_15	[p1l1358t1829r1414b1856],
37	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1429t1830r1453b1856],
38	mediating	VBG	O	mediate	prepc_in	34	SENT_15	[p1l1470t1829r1624b1864],
39	protection	NN	O	protection	dobj	38	SENT_15	[p1l1641t1830r1800b1863],
40	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1815t1830r1926b1864],
41	ZEBOV	NNP	O	ZEBOV	prep_against	38	SENT_15	[p1l1939t1830r2050b1856],
42	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1939t1830r2050b1856],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l278t1934r396b1955],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l278t1934r396b1955],
3	Geisbert	NNP	PERSON	Geisbert	nn	4	SENT_16	[p1l406t1934r506b1955],
4	TW	NNP	O	TW	dep	1	SENT_16	[p1l516t1935r560b1959],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l516t1935r560b1959],
6	Daddario	NNP	PERSON	Daddario	appos	4	SENT_16	[p1l572t1934r795b1961],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l572t1934r795b1961],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l572t1934r795b1961],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l572t1934r795b1961],

1	DiCaprio	NNP	PERSON	DiCaprio	nn	2	SENT_18	[p1l572t1934r795b1961],
2	KM	NNP	O	KM	nsubj	23	SENT_18	[p1l807t1935r849b1959],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l807t1935r849b1959],
4	Lewis	NNP	PERSON	Lewis	nn	5	SENT_18	[p1l861t1935r925b1955],
5	MG	NN	O	mg	appos	2	SENT_18	[p1l937t1935r982b1959],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l937t1935r982b1959],
7	Geisbert	NNP	PERSON	Geisbert	nn	8	SENT_18	[p1l993t1934r1093b1955],
8	JB	NNP	O	JB	appos	2	SENT_18	[p1l1103t1935r1134b1959],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1103t1935r1134b1959],
10	Grolla	NNP	O	Grolla	nn	11	SENT_18	[p1l1145t1934r1214b1955],
11	A	NNP	O	A	appos	2	SENT_18	[p1l1225t1935r1247b1959],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1225t1935r1247b1959],
13	et	FW	O	et	appos	2	SENT_18	[p1l1258t1938r1280b1955],
14	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	15	SENT_18	[p1l1290t1934r1315b1955],
15	(	FW	O	(	dep	13	SENT_18	[p1l1327t1935r1399b1959],
16	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	17	SENT_18	[p1l1327t1935r1399b1959],
17	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	13	SENT_18	[p1l1327t1935r1399b1959],
18	Vesicular	NNP	O	Vesicular	nn	22	SENT_18	[p1l1410t1934r1517b1955],
19	Stomatitis	NNP	O	Stomatitis	nn	22	SENT_18	[p1l1528t1935r1647b1955],
20	Virus-Based	NNP	O	Virus-Based	nn	22	SENT_18	[p1l1658t1934r1796b1955],
21	Ebola	NNP	O	Ebola	nn	22	SENT_18	[p1l1809t1934r1873b1955],
22	Vaccine	NNP	O	Vaccine	dep	17	SENT_18	[p1l1883t1935r1976b1955],
23	Is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1988t1935r2003b1955],
24	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	25	SENT_18	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],
25	|	VBP	O	|	ccomp	23	SENT_18	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],
26	|	NN	O	|	dobj	25	SENT_18	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],

1	To	TO	O	to	aux	2	SENT_20	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],
2	|	VB	O	|	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],
3	erated	JJ	O	erated	acomp	2	SENT_20	[p1l2013t1934r2188b1955],
4	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l2199t1934r2243b1955],
5	Protects	VBZ	O	protect	conj_and	2	SENT_20	[p1l279t1968r375b1988],
6	lmmunocompromised	JJ	O	lmmunocompromised	amod	8	SENT_20	[p1l389t1967r657b1994],
7	Nonhuman	JJ	O	nonhuman	amod	8	SENT_20	[p1l671t1967r804b1988],
8	Primates	NNS	O	primate	dobj	5	SENT_20	[p1l818t1968r927b1988],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l818t1968r927b1988],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_21	[p1l939t1968r995b1988],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1008t1967r1092b1994],
3	4	CD	NUMBER	4	number	4	SENT_21	[p1l1104t1968r1169b1992],
4	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	2	SENT_21	[p1l1104t1968r1169b1992],
5	I1	NN	O	i1	dep	4	SENT_21	[p1l1104t1968r1169b1992],
6	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	5	SENT_21	[p1l1104t1968r1169b1992],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1104t1968r1169b1992],
8	eI000225	NN	O	ei000225	dep	2	SENT_21	[p1l1181t1969r1303b1988],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1181t1969r1303b1988],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
3	I0	NN	O	i0	dep	1	SENT_22	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
4	.1371	CD	NUMBER	.1371	num	3	SENT_22	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
5	/	:	O	/	punct	7	SENT_22	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
6	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	7	SENT_22	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
7	|	NN	O	|	dep	3	SENT_22	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],

1	IO00225	CD	NUMBER	io00225	dep	17	SENT_24	[p1l1315t1967r1721b1994],
2	Editor	NNP	O	Editor	dep	1	SENT_24	[p1l279t2019r370b2040],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l279t2019r370b2040],
4	Yoshihiro	NNP	PERSON	Yoshihiro	nn	7	SENT_24	[p1l381t2019r493b2040],
5	Kawaoka	NNP	PERSON	Kawaoka	nn	7	SENT_24	[p1l506t2019r618b2044],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l506t2019r618b2044],
7	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	dep	1	SENT_24	[p1l631t2020r749b2046],
8	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l760t2019r785b2040],
9	Wisconsin	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Wisconsin	nn	11	SENT_24	[p1l794t2019r1033b2044],
10	»	NNP	O	»	nn	11	SENT_24	[p1l794t2019r1033b2044],
11	Madison	NNP	O	Madison	prep_of	7	SENT_24	[p1l794t2019r1033b2044],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l794t2019r1033b2044],
13	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	14	SENT_24	[p1l1046t2019r1124b2040],
14	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	nsubj	17	SENT_24	[p1l1137t2020r1208b2040],
15	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1220t2019r1245b2040],
16	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	14	SENT_24	[p1l1255t2020r1352b2040],
17	Received	VBD	O	receive	ccomp	68	SENT_24	[p1l279t2071r401b2092],
18	August	NNP	DATE	August	nsubj	29	SENT_24	[p1l414t2072r499b2098],
19	18	CD	DATE	18	num	18	SENT_24	[p1l513t2073r544b2096],
20	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l513t2073r544b2096],
21	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	18	SENT_24	[p1l557t2073r620b2096],
22	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l557t2073r620b2096],
23	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	amod	18	SENT_24	[p1l631t2071r760b2098],
24	October	NNP	DATE	October	tmod	23	SENT_24	[p1l772t2071r870b2092],
25	31	CD	DATE	31	num	24	SENT_24	[p1l882t2073r915b2096],
26	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l882t2073r915b2096],
27	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	24	SENT_24	[p1l927t2073r991b2096],
28	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l927t2073r991b2096],
29	Published	VBN	O	publish	dep	17	SENT_24	[p1l1003t2071r1138b2092],
30	November	NNP	DATE	November	tmod	29	SENT_24	[p1l1152t2071r1278b2092],
31	28	CD	DATE	28	num	30	SENT_24	[p1l1289t2073r1323b2096],
32	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1289t2073r1323b2096],
33	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	30	SENT_24	[p1l1335t2073r1392b2092],
34	This	DT	O	this	nsubj	40	SENT_24	[p1l277t2123r325b2144],
35	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	40	SENT_24	[p1l337t2124r352b2144],
36	an	DT	O	a	det	40	SENT_24	[p1l363t2129r390b2144],
37	open	JJ	O	open	amod	40	SENT_24	[p1l402t2129r550b2150],
38	—	NN	O	—	nn	40	SENT_24	[p1l402t2129r550b2150],
39	access	NN	O	access	nn	40	SENT_24	[p1l402t2129r550b2150],
40	article	NN	O	article	ccomp	17	SENT_24	[p1l561t2123r633b2144],
41	distributed	VBN	O	distribute	partmod	40	SENT_24	[p1l644t2123r775b2144],
42	under	IN	O	under	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l788t2123r858b2144],
43	the	DT	O	the	det	44	SENT_24	[p1l868t2123r907b2144],
44	terms	NNS	O	term	prep_under	41	SENT_24	[p1l917t2127r985b2144],
45	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l996t2123r1021b2144],
46	the	DT	O	the	det	51	SENT_24	[p1l1029t2123r1068b2144],
47	Creative	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Creative	nn	51	SENT_24	[p1l1079t2124r1177b2144],
48	Commons	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Commons	nn	51	SENT_24	[p1l1188t2124r1311b2144],
49	Public	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Public	nn	51	SENT_24	[p1l1323t2123r1395b2144],
50	Domain	NN	ORGANIZATION	domain	nn	51	SENT_24	[p1l1407t2124r1499b2144],
51	declaration	NN	O	declaration	prep_of	44	SENT_24	[p1l1511t2123r1645b2144],
52	which	WDT	O	which	nsubj	53	SENT_24	[p1l1656t2123r1727b2144],
53	stipulates	VBZ	O	stipulate	rcmod	51	SENT_24	[p1l1740t2123r1854b2150],
54	that	IN	O	that	nsubj	57	SENT_24	[p1l1864t2123r1918b2148],
55	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1864t2123r1918b2148],
56	once	RB	DATE	once	advmod	57	SENT_24	[p1l1930t2129r1987b2144],
57	placed	VBN	O	place	ccomp	53	SENT_24	[p1l1999t2123r2077b2150],
58	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l2089t2124r2108b2144],
59	the	DT	O	the	det	61	SENT_24	[p1l2120t2123r2159b2144],
60	public	JJ	O	public	amod	61	SENT_24	[p1l2171t2123r2244b2150],
61	domain	NN	O	domain	prep_in	57	SENT_24	[p1l278t2156r375b2181],
62	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l278t2156r375b2181],
63	this	DT	O	this	det	64	SENT_24	[p1l387t2156r429b2177],
64	work	NN	O	work	nsubjpass	70	SENT_24	[p1l441t2156r501b2177],
65	may	MD	O	may	aux	68	SENT_24	[p1l512t2163r562b2183],
66	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	68	SENT_24	[p1l574t2156r602b2177],
67	freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	68	SENT_24	[p1l613t2156r680b2183],
68	reproduced	VBN	O	reproduce	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l692t2156r837b2183],
69	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l692t2156r837b2183],
70	distributed	VBN	O	distribute	conj_or	68	SENT_24	[p1l849t2156r986b2181],
71	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l849t2156r986b2181],
72	transmitted	VBN	O	transmit	conj_or	68	SENT_24	[p1l998t2156r1144b2181],
73	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l998t2156r1144b2181],
74	modiﬁed	VBN	O	modiﬁed	conj_or	68	SENT_24	[p1l1157t2156r1269b2181],
75	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1157t2156r1269b2181],
76	built	VBN	O	build	conj_or	68	SENT_24	[p1l1282t2156r1335b2177],
77	upon	IN	O	upon	prep	76	SENT_24	[p1l1347t2162r1415b2183],
78	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1347t2162r1415b2183],
79	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1427t2163r1451b2177],
80	otherwise	RB	O	otherwise	advmod	81	SENT_24	[p1l1462t2156r1580b2177],
81	used	VBN	O	use	conj_or	68	SENT_24	[p1l1593t2156r1647b2177],
82	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1661t2156r1689b2183],
83	anyone	NN	O	anyone	prep_by	81	SENT_24	[p1l1700t2162r1788b2183],
84	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1799t2156r1833b2177],
85	any	DT	O	any	det	87	SENT_24	[p1l1844t2162r1886b2183],
86	lawful	JJ	O	lawful	amod	87	SENT_24	[p1l1898t2156r1968b2177],
87	purpose	NN	O	purpose	prep_for	83	SENT_24	[p1l1981t2162r2085b2183],
88	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1981t2162r2085b2183],

1	Funding	NNP	O	Funding	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l279t2208r401b2235],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l279t2208r401b2235],
3	Work	NN	O	work	nsubjpass	9	SENT_25	[p1l414t2208r476b2229],
4	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l489t2215r518b2229],
5	ﬁloviruses	NNS	O	ﬁloviruses	prep_on	3	SENT_25	[p1l531t2208r651b2229],
6	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l665t2212r687b2229],
7	USAMRIID	NNP	ORGANIZATION	USAMRIID	prep_at	5	SENT_25	[p1l701t2209r821b2229],
8	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	9	SENT_25	[p1l834t2215r879b2229],
9	funded	VBN	O	fund	dep	1	SENT_25	[p1l892t2208r977b2229],
10	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l992t2208r1020b2235],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	18	SENT_25	[p1l1032t2208r1071b2229],
12	Defense	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Defense	nn	18	SENT_25	[p1l1085t2208r1181b2229],
13	Threat	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Threat	nn	18	SENT_25	[p1l1193t2208r1271b2229],
14	Reduction	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Reduction	nn	18	SENT_25	[p1l1285t2208r1405b2229],
15	Agency	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Agency	nn	18	SENT_25	[p1l1419t2209r1509b2235],
16	(	NN	O	(	nn	18	SENT_25	[p1l1522t2209r1615b2235],
17	project	NN	O	project	nn	18	SENT_25	[p1l1522t2209r1615b2235],
18	O4	NN	O	o4	agent	9	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],
19	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	20	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],
20	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	22	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],
21	—	NN	O	—	nn	22	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],
22	7J	NN	O	7j	dep	18	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],
23	»	NN	O	»	nn	25	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],
24	012	CD	NUMBER	012	num	25	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],
25	)	NN	O	)	dep	22	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1628t2209r1781b2233],

1	Work	NN	O	work	nsubjpass	8	SENT_26	[p1l1794t2208r1857b2229],
2	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1869t2215r1898b2229],
3	filoviruses	NNS	O	filovirus	prep_on	1	SENT_26	[p1l1912t2208r2032b2229],
4	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l2045t2212r2067b2229],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_26	[p1l2079t2208r2118b2229],
6	NML	NNP	ORGANIZATION	NML	prep_at	3	SENT_26	[p1l2133t2209r2186b2229],
7	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	8	SENT_26	[p1l2198t2214r2243b2229],
8	supported	VBN	O	support	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l279t2241r402b2268],
9	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l414t2241r442b2268],
10	PHAC	NN	O	phac	agent	8	SENT_26	[p1l452t2242r524b2266],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l452t2242r524b2266],
12	a	DT	O	a	det	13	SENT_26	[p1l534t2247r545b2262],
13	grant	NN	O	grant	appos	10	SENT_26	[p1l555t2245r619b2268],
14	awarded	VBN	O	award	partmod	13	SENT_26	[p1l628t2241r731b2262],
15	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l741t2245r765b2262],
16	HF	NN	O	hf	prep_to	14	SENT_26	[p1l776t2242r806b2262],
17	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l815t2241r871b2262],
18	the	DT	O	the	det	20	SENT_26	[p1l881t2241r920b2262],
19	Canadian	JJ	O	canadian	amod	20	SENT_26	[p1l929t2241r1041b2262],
20	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	prep_from	16	SENT_26	[p1l1052t2242r1161b2262],
21	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1171t2241r1196b2262],
22	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	nn	23	SENT_26	[p1l1204t2241r1280b2262],
23	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	prep_of	16	SENT_26	[p1l1292t2241r1397b2262],
24	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	25	SENT_26	[p1l1408t2242r1569b2266],
25	MOP	NN	O	mop	tmod	14	SENT_26	[p1l1408t2242r1569b2266],
26	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	27	SENT_26	[p1l1408t2242r1569b2266],
27	39321	CD	NUMBER	39321	num	28	SENT_26	[p1l1408t2242r1569b2266],
28	)	NN	O	)	dep	25	SENT_26	[p1l1408t2242r1569b2266],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1408t2242r1569b2266],
30	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1579t2241r1622b2262],
31	a	DT	O	a	det	32	SENT_26	[p1l1632t2248r1644b2262],
32	grant	NN	O	grant	conj_and	25	SENT_26	[p1l1654t2245r1718b2268],
33	awarded	VBN	O	award	partmod	32	SENT_26	[p1l1727t2241r1830b2262],
34	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1840t2245r1864b2262],
35	SMJ	JJ	O	smj	amod	48	SENT_26	[p1l1875t2242r1920b2262],
36	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1930t2241r1985b2262],
37	Chemical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Chemical	nn	41	SENT_26	[p1l1996t2241r2112b2266],
38	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1996t2241r2112b2266],
39	Biological	NNP	O	Biological	appos	41	SENT_26	[p1l2123t2241r2244b2268],
40	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l2123t2241r2244b2268],
41	Radiological	NNP	O	Radiological	prep_from	35	SENT_26	[p1l279t2275r430b2302],
42	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l279t2275r430b2302],
43	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l440t2275r483b2296],
44	Nuclear	JJ	O	nuclear	amod	46	SENT_26	[p1l494t2275r584b2296],
45	(	NN	O	(	nn	46	SENT_26	[p1l593t2276r674b2300],
46	CBRN	NN	O	cbrn	prep_from	35	SENT_26	[p1l593t2276r674b2300],
47	)	CD	NUMBER	)	tmod	35	SENT_26	[p1l593t2276r674b2300],
48	Research	NNP	O	Research	prep_to	33	SENT_26	[p1l685t2275r789b2296],
49	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l799t2275r843b2296],
50	Technology	NNP	O	Technology	nn	51	SENT_26	[p1l852t2275r995b2302],
51	Initiative	NNP	O	Initiative	conj_and	48	SENT_26	[p1l1004t2276r1106b2296],
52	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	53	SENT_26	[p1l1116t2276r1190b2300],
53	CRTI	NNP	O	CRTI	dep	25	SENT_26	[p1l1116t2276r1190b2300],
54	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	53	SENT_26	[p1l1116t2276r1190b2300],
55	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1116t2276r1190b2300],

1	Opinions	NNS	MISC	opinion	nsubj	10	SENT_27	[p1l1199t2276r1312b2302],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1199t2276r1312b2302],
3	interpretations	NNS	O	interpretation	nsubj	10	SENT_27	[p1l1322t2276r1506b2302],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1322t2276r1506b2302],
5	conclusions	NNS	O	conclusion	nsubj	10	SENT_27	[p1l1515t2275r1662b2300],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1515t2275r1662b2300],
7	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1671t2275r1714b2296],
8	recommendations	NNS	O	recommendation	nsubj	10	SENT_27	[p1l1725t2275r1945b2296],
9	are	VBP	O	be	cop	10	SENT_27	[p1l1954t2281r1990b2296],
10	those	DT	O	those	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1998t2275r2065b2296],
11	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l2074t2275r2099b2296],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_27	[p1l2105t2275r2144b2296],
13	authors	NNS	O	author	prep_of	10	SENT_27	[p1l2153t2275r2244b2296],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l278t2308r322b2329],
15	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	18	SENT_27	[p1l334t2315r370b2329],
16	not	RB	O	not	neg	18	SENT_27	[p1l383t2312r422b2329],
17	necessarily	RB	O	necessarily	advmod	18	SENT_27	[p1l434t2308r563b2335],
18	endorsed	VBN	O	endorse	conj_and	10	SENT_27	[p1l575t2308r686b2329],
19	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l700t2308r728b2335],
20	Boston	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Boston	nn	21	SENT_27	[p1l740t2309r821b2329],
21	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	agent	18	SENT_27	[p1l835t2309r959b2335],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l835t2309r959b2335],
23	the	DT	O	the	det	25	SENT_27	[p1l970t2308r1009b2329],
24	U.S.	NNP	ORGANIZATION	U.S.	nn	25	SENT_27	[p1l1022t2309r1064b2329],
25	Army	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Army	appos	21	SENT_27	[p1l1075t2309r1145b2335],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1075t2309r1145b2335],
27	the	DT	O	the	det	29	SENT_27	[p1l1156t2308r1195b2329],
28	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	nn	29	SENT_27	[p1l1208t2308r1306b2329],
29	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	conj_or	21	SENT_27	[p1l1319t2309r1428b2329],
30	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1440t2308r1465b2329],
31	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	prep_of	29	SENT_27	[p1l1476t2308r1558b2333],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1476t2308r1558b2333],
33	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1570t2314r1595b2329],
34	the	DT	O	the	det	37	SENT_27	[p1l1605t2308r1644b2329],
35	Public	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Public	nn	37	SENT_27	[p1l1657t2308r1728b2329],
36	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	nn	37	SENT_27	[p1l1741t2308r1817b2329],
37	Agency	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Agency	conj_or	21	SENT_27	[p1l1829t2309r1920b2335],
38	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1931t2308r1955b2329],
39	Canada	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Canada	prep_of	37	SENT_27	[p1l1965t2308r2060b2329],
40	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1965t2308r2060b2329],

1	Competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	2	SENT_28	[p1l278t2360r431b2387],
2	Interests	NNS	O	interest	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l444t2361r571b2381],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l444t2361r571b2381],
4	The	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_28	[p1l581t2360r626b2381],
5	authors	NNS	O	author	nsubj	7	SENT_28	[p1l637t2360r728b2381],
6	have	VBP	O	have	aux	7	SENT_28	[p1l741t2360r796b2381],
7	declared	VBN	O	declare	dep	2	SENT_28	[p1l808t2360r910b2381],
8	that	IN	O	that	complm	12	SENT_28	[p1l922t2360r970b2381],
9	no	DT	O	no	det	11	SENT_28	[p1l982t2366r1011b2381],
10	competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	11	SENT_28	[p1l1023t2361r1153b2387],
11	interests	NNS	O	interest	nsubj	12	SENT_28	[p1l1167t2361r1268b2381],
12	exist	VBP	O	exist	ccomp	7	SENT_28	[p1l1279t2361r1339b2381],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1279t2361r1339b2381],

1	*	NN	O	*	nn	2	SENT_29	[p1l278t2413r289b2423],
2	E	NN	O	e	nsubjpass	43	SENT_29	[p1l301t2412r379b2433],
3	—	CD	NUMBER	—	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l301t2412r379b2433],
4	mai	FW	O	mai	nn	5	SENT_29	[p1l301t2412r379b2433],
5	|	FW	O	|	dep	3	SENT_29	[p1l301t2412r379b2433],
6	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l301t2412r379b2433],
7	geisbert@bu.edu	NN	O	geisbert@bu.edu	dep	3	SENT_29	[p1l390t2412r594b2439],
8	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l278t2469r291b2482],
9	Current	JJ	DATE	current	amod	10	SENT_29	[p1l303t2465r394b2485],
10	address	NN	O	address	prep_in	7	SENT_29	[p1l405t2464r503b2485],
11	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l405t2464r503b2485],
12	Laboratow	NN	O	laboratow	dep	3	SENT_29	[p1l517t2464r646b2491],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l658t2464r683b2485],
14	Virology	NNP	O	Virology	prep_of	12	SENT_29	[p1l692t2464r798b2491],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l692t2464r798b2491],
16	Division	NNP	O	Division	appos	3	SENT_29	[p1l811t2465r904b2485],
17	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l917t2464r942b2485],
18	Intramural	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Intramural	nn	19	SENT_29	[p1l953t2464r1075b2485],
19	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	prep_of	16	SENT_29	[p1l1090t2464r1201b2489],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1090t2464r1201b2489],
21	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	dep	34	SENT_29	[p1l1214t2464r1313b2485],
22	Institutes	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Institutes	dep	21	SENT_29	[p1l1327t2465r1436b2485],
23	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1448t2464r1473b2485],
24	Allergy	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Allergy	nn	27	SENT_29	[p1l1483t2464r1567b2491],
25	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1578t2464r1621b2485],
26	Infectious	JJ	ORGANIZATION	infectious	nn	27	SENT_29	[p1l1636t2464r1751b2485],
27	Diseases	NNS	ORGANIZATION	disease	prep_of	21	SENT_29	[p1l1765t2465r1865b2485],
28	Rocky	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Rocky	nn	34	SENT_29	[p1l1879t2464r1948b2491],
29	Mountain	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Mountain	nn	34	SENT_29	[p1l1961t2465r2075b2485],
30	Laboratories	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Laboratories	nn	34	SENT_29	[p1l2089t2464r2244b2489],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2089t2464r2244b2489],
32	Hamilton	NNP	PERSON	Hamilton	dep	34	SENT_29	[p1l279t2497r394b2522],
33	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l279t2497r394b2522],
34	Montana	NNP	LOCATION	Montana	appos	3	SENT_29	[p1l407t2498r519b2522],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l407t2498r519b2522],
36	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	37	SENT_29	[p1l532t2497r610b2518],
37	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	appos	34	SENT_29	[p1l624t2498r695b2518],
38	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l706t2497r731b2518],
39	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	nn	40	SENT_29	[p1l741t2498r838b2518],
40	weapon	NN	O	weapon	prep_of	3	SENT_29	[p1l1313t2637r1429b2662],
41	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1443t2628r1498b2654],
42	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	43	SENT_29	[p1l1511t2628r1530b2654],
43	categorized	VBN	O	categorize	conj_and	3	SENT_29	[p1l1544t2628r1714b2662],
44	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1727t2637r1754b2654],
45	a	DT	O	a	det	49	SENT_29	[p1l1768t2637r1784b2653],
46	Category	NN	O	category	nn	49	SENT_29	[p1l1797t2628r1934b2662],
47	A	NN	O	a	nn	49	SENT_29	[p1l1945t2628r1971b2653],
48	bioterrorism	NN	O	bioterrorism	nn	49	SENT_29	[p1l1983t2628r2167b2654],
49	agent	NN	O	agent	prep_as	43	SENT_29	[p1l2180t2634r2261b2662],
50	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2273t2628r2309b2662],
51	the	DT	O	the	det	52	SENT_29	[p1l1314t2672r1359b2698],
52	Centers	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Centers	agent	43	SENT_29	[p1l1374t2672r1488b2698],
53	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1502t2672r1543b2698],
54	Disease	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Disease	nn	55	SENT_29	[p1l1557t2672r1667b2698],
55	Control	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Control	prep_for	52	SENT_29	[p1l1683t2672r1798b2698],
56	and	CC	ORGANIZATION	and	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1813t2672r1868b2698],
57	Prevention	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Prevention	conj_and	52	SENT_29	[p1l1882t2672r2042b2698],
58	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	59	SENT_29	[p1l2061t2672r2144b2706],
59	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	60	SENT_29	[p1l2061t2672r2144b2706],
60	—	NN	O	—	dep	57	SENT_29	[p1l2061t2672r2144b2706],
61	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	62	SENT_29	[p1l2061t2672r2144b2706],
62	]	NN	O	]	dep	57	SENT_29	[p1l2061t2672r2144b2706],
63	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l2061t2672r2144b2706],

1	While	IN	O	while	mark	3	SENT_30	[p1l1350t2717r1439b2743],
2	there	EX	O	there	expl	3	SENT_30	[p1l1471t2717r1545b2743],
3	are	VBP	O	be	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1578t2726r1622b2743],
4	no	DT	O	no	det	5	SENT_30	[p1l1655t2726r1691b2743],
5	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	nsubj	3	SENT_30	[p1l1721t2717r1845b2743],
6	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1877t2726r1908b2743],
7	postexposure	JJ	O	postexposure	amod	8	SENT_30	[p1l1938t2723r2132b2751],
8	treatment	NN	O	treatment	nsubj	3	SENT_30	[p1l2164t2723r2309b2743],

1	Introduction	NN	O	introduction	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l245t2630r490b2661],

1	Ebola	NN	MISC	ebolum	nn	2	SENT_32	[p1l281t2713r367b2739],
2	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubjpass	8	SENT_32	[p1l378t2713r449b2739],
3	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	5	SENT_32	[p1l463t2713r582b2747],
4	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	nn	5	SENT_32	[p1l463t2713r582b2747],
5	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_32	[p1l463t2713r582b2747],
6	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	8	SENT_32	[p1l595t2713r643b2739],
7	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	8	SENT_32	[p1l656t2713r726b2739],
8	associated	VBN	O	associate	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l740t2713r888b2739],
9	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l900t2713r964b2739],
10	sporadic	JJ	O	sporadic	amod	11	SENT_32	[p1l978t2713r1101b2747],
11	episodes	NNS	O	episode	prep_with	8	SENT_32	[p1l1115t2713r1237b2747],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l243t2757r275b2783],
13	hemorrhagic	JJ	O	hemorrhagic	amod	14	SENT_32	[p1l284t2757r474b2791],
14	fever	NN	O	fever	prep_of	11	SENT_32	[p1l487t2757r560b2783],
15	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	14	SENT_32	[p1l574t2757r639b2791],
16	HE	PRP	O	he	dep	14	SENT_32	[p1l574t2757r639b2791],
17	that	IN	O	that	nsubj	18	SENT_32	[p1l654t2757r712b2783],
18	produce	VBP	O	produce	rcmod	11	SENT_32	[p1l724t2757r845b2791],
19	severe	JJ	O	severe	amod	20	SENT_32	[p1l860t2766r949b2783],
20	disease	NN	O	disease	dobj	18	SENT_32	[p1l964t2757r1065b2783],
21	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1080t2757r1107b2782],
22	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	23	SENT_32	[p1l1121t2757r1238b2783],
23	patients	NNS	O	patient	prep_in	20	SENT_32	[p1l242t2801r365b2835],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l242t2801r365b2835],

1	Mortality	NN	O	mortality	nn	2	SENT_33	[p1l383t2801r523b2835],
2	rates	NNS	O	rate	nsubj	6	SENT_33	[p1l538t2807r607b2827],
3	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l623t2801r650b2826],
4	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	prep_in	2	SENT_33	[p1l666t2801r809b2827],
5	have	VBP	O	have	aux	6	SENT_33	[p1l825t2801r893b2827],
6	ranged	VBN	O	range	dep	23	SENT_33	[p1l909t2801r1012b2835],
7	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1026t2801r1098b2827],
8	50	CD	PERCENT	50	num	9	SENT_33	[p1l1114t2801r1179b2827],
9	%	NN	PERCENT	%	prep_from	6	SENT_33	[p1l1114t2801r1179b2827],
10	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1196t2801r1238b2827],
11	Sudan	NNP	LOCATION	Sudan	prep_for	9	SENT_33	[p1l244t2845r322b2871],
12	ebolavirus	NN	O	ebolavirus	nn	15	SENT_33	[p1l333t2845r459b2871],
13	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	15	SENT_33	[p1l469t2845r608b2879],
14	SEBOV	NN	O	sebov	nn	15	SENT_33	[p1l469t2845r608b2879],
15	)	NN	O	)	dobj	6	SENT_33	[p1l469t2845r608b2879],
16	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l620t2851r648b2871],
17	up	RB	O	up	quantmod	19	SENT_33	[p1l659t2854r696b2879],
18	to	TO	O	to	dep	19	SENT_33	[p1l708t2851r736b2871],
19	90	CD	PERCENT	90	num	20	SENT_33	[p1l748t2845r813b2871],
20	%	NN	PERCENT	%	prep_to	15	SENT_33	[p1l748t2845r813b2871],
21	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l827t2845r868b2871],
22	Zaire	NNP	LOCATION	Zaire	prep_for	20	SENT_33	[p1l880t2845r948b2879],
23	ebolavirus	VBZ	O	ebolavirus	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l958t2845r1083b2871],
24	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	27	SENT_33	[p1l1094t2845r1237b2879],
25	ZEBOV	NN	O	zebov	nn	27	SENT_33	[p1l1094t2845r1237b2879],
26	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	27	SENT_33	[p1l1094t2845r1237b2879],
27	(	NN	O	(	nsubj	23	SENT_33	[p1l244t2889r384b2923],
28	reviewed	VBN	O	review	dep	23	SENT_33	[p1l244t2889r384b2923],
29	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l397t2889r424b2914],
30	[	NN	O	[	prep_in	28	SENT_33	[p1l441t2889r496b2923],
31	1	CD	NUMBER	1	number	32	SENT_33	[p1l441t2889r496b2923],
32	]	CD	NUMBER	]	num	33	SENT_33	[p1l441t2889r496b2923],
33	)	NN	O	)	dobj	28	SENT_33	[p1l441t2889r496b2923],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l441t2889r496b2923],

1	A	DT	O	a	det	3	SENT_34	[p1l510t2889r536b2914],
2	recent	JJ	O	recent	amod	3	SENT_34	[p1l548t2895r640b2915],
3	outbreak	NN	O	outbreak	nsubj	14	SENT_34	[p1l653t2889r785b2915],
4	caused	VBN	O	cause	partmod	3	SENT_34	[p1l797t2889r897b2915],
5	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l909t2889r945b2923],
6	an	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_34	[p1l958t2898r992b2914],
7	apparently	RB	O	apparently	advmod	8	SENT_34	[p1l1006t2889r1166b2923],
8	new	JJ	O	new	amod	9	SENT_34	[p1l1178t2898r1238b2915],
9	species	NNS	O	species	agent	4	SENT_34	[p1l243t2934r343b2968],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l360t2934r392b2960],
11	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	prep_of	9	SENT_34	[p1l404t2934r506b2960],
12	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l522t2934r549b2959],
13	Uganda	NNP	LOCATION	Uganda	prep_in	4	SENT_34	[p1l566t2934r685b2968],
14	appears	VBZ	O	appear	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l701t2943r815b2968],
15	to	TO	O	to	aux	18	SENT_34	[p1l832t2940r859b2960],
16	be	VB	O	be	cop	18	SENT_34	[p1l876t2934r909b2960],
17	less	RBR	O	less	advmod	18	SENT_34	[p1l926t2934r974b2960],
18	pathogenic	JJ	O	pathogenic	xcomp	14	SENT_34	[p1l991t2934r1154b2968],
19	than	IN	O	than	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1171t2934r1237b2960],
20	SEBOV	NN	O	sebov	prep_than	18	SENT_34	[p1l244t2978r366b3004],
21	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l379t2987r410b3004],
22	ZEBOV	NN	O	zebov	xcomp	14	SENT_34	[p1l423t2978r549b3004],
23	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l561t2978r626b3004],
24	a	DT	O	a	det	28	SENT_34	[p1l640t2987r656b3003],
25	preliminary	JJ	O	preliminary	amod	28	SENT_34	[p1l668t2978r843b3012],
26	case	NN	O	case	nn	28	SENT_34	[p1l855t2987r915b3004],
27	fatality	NN	O	fatality	nn	28	SENT_34	[p1l928t2978r1030b3012],
28	rate	NN	O	rate	prep_with	22	SENT_34	[p1l1043t2984r1099b3004],
29	of	IN	O	of	prep	28	SENT_34	[p1l1113t2978r1145b3004],
30	about	IN	O	about	pcomp	29	SENT_34	[p1l1154t2978r1238b3004],
31	25	CD	PERCENT	25	num	32	SENT_34	[p1l244t3022r277b3049],
32	%	NN	PERCENT	%	pobj	30	SENT_34	[p1l283t3022r308b3048],
33	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	34	SENT_34	[p1l326t3022r372b3056],
34	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	35	SENT_34	[p1l326t3022r372b3056],
35	]	NN	O	]	dep	18	SENT_34	[p1l326t3022r372b3056],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l326t3022r372b3056],

1	EBOV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ebov	nsubjpass	4	SENT_35	[p1l386t3022r488b3048],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	4	SENT_35	[p1l499t3022r519b3048],
3	also	RB	O	also	advmod	4	SENT_35	[p1l531t3022r586b3048],
4	considered	VBN	O	consider	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l597t3022r757b3048],
5	to	TO	O	to	aux	6	SENT_35	[p1l768t3028r795b3048],
6	have	VB	O	have	xcomp	4	SENT_35	[p1l807t3022r875b3048],
7	potential	JJ	O	potential	dobj	6	SENT_35	[p1l887t3022r1017b3056],
8	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1029t3031r1056b3048],
9	a	DT	O	a	det	10	SENT_35	[p1l1068t3031r1084b3047],
10	biological	JJ	O	biological	prep_as	7	SENT_35	[p1l1095t3022r1238b3056],

1	o	NN	O	o	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
2	-	:	O	-	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
3	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	4	SENT_36	[p1l344t3144r408b3167],
4	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	dep	1	SENT_36	[p1l423t3143r567b3174],
5	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	6	SENT_36	[p1l587t3142r590b3175],
6	www	NN	O	www	dobj	4	SENT_36	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],

1	p	NN	O	p	nsubj	13	SENT_37	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	1	SENT_37	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	nn	4	SENT_37	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
4	modalities	NNS	O	modality	dep	5	SENT_37	[p1l1314t2760r1465b2786],
5	available	JJ	O	available	parataxis	13	SENT_37	[p1l1479t2760r1608b2786],
6	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1622t2760r1663b2786],
7	preventing	VBG	O	prevent	prepc_for	5	SENT_37	[p1l1675t2760r1836b2794],
8	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1848t2769r1879b2786],
9	managing	VBG	O	manage	conj_or	7	SENT_37	[p1l1891t2760r2040b2794],
10	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	nn	11	SENT_37	[p1l2052t2760r2155b2786],
11	infections	NNS	O	infection	dobj	7	SENT_37	[p1l2167t2760r2308b2786],
12	there	EX	O	there	expl	13	SENT_37	[p1l1314t2804r1388b2830],
13	are	VBP	O	be	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1405t2813r1450b2830],
14	at	IN	O	at	quantmod	16	SENT_37	[p1l1467t2810r1493b2830],
15	least	JJS	O	least	mwe	14	SENT_37	[p1l1508t2804r1574b2830],
16	four	CD	NUMBER	four	num	19	SENT_37	[p1l1588t2804r1649b2830],
17	different	JJ	O	different	amod	19	SENT_37	[p1l1665t2804r1789b2830],
18	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nn	19	SENT_37	[p1l1803t2804r1914b2830],
19	systems	NNS	O	system	nsubj	13	SENT_37	[p1l1931t2810r2040b2838],
20	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	22	SENT_37	[p1l2056t2804r2114b2830],
21	have	VBP	O	have	aux	22	SENT_37	[p1l2129t2804r2198b2830],
22	shown	VBN	O	show	rcmod	19	SENT_37	[p1l2214t2804r2308b2830],
23	promise	NN	O	promise	dobj	22	SENT_37	[p1l1313t2847r1431b2881],
24	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1450t2847r1477b2872],
25	completely	RB	O	completely	advmod	26	SENT_37	[p1l1496t2847r1658b2881],
26	protecting	VBG	O	protect	prepc_in	22	SENT_37	[p1l1674t2847r1827b2881],
27	nonhuman	JJ	O	nonhuman	amod	28	SENT_37	[p1l1844t2847r2007b2873],
28	primates	NNS	O	primate	dobj	26	SENT_37	[p1l2024t2847r2152b2881],
29	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l2171t2847r2275b2881],
30	a	DT	O	a	det	33	SENT_37	[p1l2293t2856r2309b2872],
31	lethal	JJ	O	lethal	amod	33	SENT_37	[p1l1314t2891r1395b2917],
32	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	nn	33	SENT_37	[p1l1421t2891r1523b2917],
33	challenge	NN	O	challenge	prep_against	26	SENT_37	[p1l1549t2891r1687b2925],
34	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	35	SENT_37	[p1l1718t2891r1820b2925],
35	6	CD	NUMBER	6	dep	33	SENT_37	[p1l1718t2891r1820b2925],
36	—	NN	O	—	nn	38	SENT_37	[p1l1718t2891r1820b2925],
37	l2	NN	O	l2	nn	38	SENT_37	[p1l1718t2891r1820b2925],
38	]	NN	O	]	dep	35	SENT_37	[p1l1718t2891r1820b2925],
39	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1718t2891r1820b2925],

1	Of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1848t2891r1892b2917],
2	these	DT	O	these	det	5	SENT_38	[p1l1912t2891r1986b2917],
3	prospective	JJ	O	prospective	amod	5	SENT_38	[p1l2012t2891r2179b2925],
4	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	nn	5	SENT_38	[p1l2206t2891r2309b2917],
5	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	pobj	1	SENT_38	[p1l1313t2935r1436b2961],
6	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	7	SENT_38	[p1l1466t2941r1519b2961],
7	systems	NNS	O	system	nsubjpass	31	SENT_38	[p1l1550t2941r1667b2969],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1550t2941r1667b2969],
9	one	CD	NUMBER	one	appos	7	SENT_38	[p1l1699t2944r1751b2961],
10	based	VBN	O	base	partmod	9	SENT_38	[p1l1781t2935r1865b2961],
11	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1895t2944r1931b2961],
12	a	DT	O	a	det	14	SENT_38	[p1l1961t2944r1977b2960],
13	replication-defective	JJ	O	replication-defective	amod	14	SENT_38	[p1l2007t2935r2307b2969],
14	adenovirus	NN	O	adenovirus	prep_on	10	SENT_38	[p1l1314t2978r1476b3004],
15	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1503t2978r1559b3004],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_38	[p1l1585t2978r1630b3004],
17	other	JJ	O	other	prep_on	10	SENT_38	[p1l1658t2978r1736b3004],
18	based	VBN	O	base	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1763t2978r1846b3004],
19	on	IN	O	on	prepc_based_on	10	SENT_38	[p1l1874t2987r1910b3004],
20	a	DT	O	a	det	24	SENT_38	[p1l1938t2987r1953b3003],
21	replication-competent	JJ	O	replication-competent	amod	24	SENT_38	[p1l1980t2978r2309b3012],
22	vesicular	JJ	O	vesicular	amod	24	SENT_38	[p1l1313t3022r1443b3048],
23	stomatitis	NN	O	stomatitis	nn	24	SENT_38	[p1l1458t3022r1598b3048],
24	virus	NN	O	virus	pobj	10	SENT_38	[p1l1611t3022r1682b3048],
25	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	28	SENT_38	[p1l1698t3022r1732b3056],
26	V	NN	O	v	nn	28	SENT_38	[p1l1698t3022r1732b3056],
27	SV	NN	O	sv	nn	28	SENT_38	[p1l1734t3022r1796b3056],
28	)	NN	O	)	dep	24	SENT_38	[p1l1734t3022r1796b3056],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1734t3022r1796b3056],
30	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	31	SENT_38	[p1l1810t3031r1881b3048],
31	shown	VBN	O	show	rcmod	5	SENT_38	[p1l1896t3022r1990b3048],
32	to	TO	O	to	aux	33	SENT_38	[p1l2004t3028r2032b3048],
33	provide	VB	O	provide	xcomp	31	SENT_38	[p1l2046t3022r2158b3056],
34	complete	JJ	O	complete	acomp	33	SENT_38	[p1l2174t3022r2308b3056],

1	Author	NN	O	author	nn	2	SENT_39	[p2l280t269r419b300],
2	Summary	NN	O	summary	_	0	SENT_39	[p2l436t270r625b308],

1	Ebola	NN	MISC	ebolum	nn	2	SENT_40	[p2l282t342r364b369],
2	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubj	3	SENT_40	[p2l380t343r452b369],
3	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l470t343r490b369],
4	among	IN	O	among	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l506t350r614b377],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_40	[p2l631t342r680b369],
6	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	8	SENT_40	[p2l698t347r774b369],
7	lethal	JJ	O	lethal	amod	8	SENT_40	[p2l791t342r873b369],
8	microbes	NNS	O	microbe	prep_among	3	SENT_40	[p2l891t342r1032b369],
9	known	VBN	O	know	partmod	8	SENT_40	[p2l1049t342r1151b369],
10	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l1168t347r1199b369],
11	man	NN	O	man	prep_to	9	SENT_40	[p2l282t392r355b416],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l282t392r355b416],
13	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l367t384r433b411],
14	case	NN	O	case	nn	16	SENT_40	[p2l447t392r512b411],
15	fatality	NN	O	fatality	nn	16	SENT_40	[p2l523t384r629b419],
16	rates	NNS	O	rate	nsubj	18	SENT_40	[p2l641t389r713b411],
17	often	RB	O	often	advmod	18	SENT_40	[p2l725t384r805b411],
18	exceeding	VBG	O	exceed	prepc_with	9	SENT_40	[p2l818t384r975b419],
19	80	CD	PERCENT	80	num	20	SENT_40	[p2l989t386r1062b412],
20	%	NN	PERCENT	%	dobj	18	SENT_40	[p2l989t386r1062b412],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_40	[p2l989t386r1062b412],

1	Since	IN	O	since	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l1074t385r1154b411],
2	its	PRP$	O	its	poss	3	SENT_41	[p2l1167t385r1199b411],
3	discovery	NN	O	discovery	prep_since	10	SENT_41	[p2l281t425r427b460],
4	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l452t426r476b452],
5	1976	CD	DATE	1976	prep_in	3	SENT_41	[p2l505t427r584b457],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l505t427r584b457],
7	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	nsubj	13	SENT_41	[p2l609t425r762b452],
8	have	VBP	O	have	aux	10	SENT_41	[p2l789t425r860b452],
9	been	VBN	O	be	cop	10	SENT_41	[p2l886t425r961b452],
10	sporadic	JJ	O	sporadic	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l987t425r1118b459],
11	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l1142t425r1198b452],
12	geographically	RB	O	geographically	advmod	13	SENT_41	[p2l281t467r510b502],
13	restricted	JJ	O	restricted	conj_and	10	SENT_41	[p2l536t467r688b499],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l536t467r688b499],
15	primarily	RB	O	primarily	advmod	10	SENT_41	[p2l715t467r850b502],
16	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l874t472r905b494],
17	areas	NNS	O	area	prep_to	10	SENT_41	[p2l931t475r1009b494],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l1035t467r1067b494],
19	Central	NNP	LOCATION	Central	nn	20	SENT_41	[p2l1090t467r1198b494],
20	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_of	17	SENT_41	[p2l280t508r375b535],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_41	[p2l280t508r375b535],

1	However	RB	O	however	advmod	19	SENT_42	[p2l395t510r539b540],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l395t510r539b540],
3	concern	NN	O	concern	nsubj	19	SENT_42	[p2l557t516r680b535],
4	about	IN	O	about	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l699t508r790b535],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_42	[p2l808t508r857b535],
6	natural	JJ	O	natural	amod	9	SENT_42	[p2l877t508r982b535],
7	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l1002t516r1033b535],
8	unnatural	JJ	O	unnatural	amod	9	SENT_42	[p2l1052t508r1198b535],
9	introduction	NN	O	introduction	prep_about	3	SENT_42	[p2l281t550r472b577],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l493t550r525b577],
11	Ebola	NNP	MISC	Ebola	prep_of	9	SENT_42	[p2l543t550r625b577],
12	outside	IN	O	outside	advmod	11	SENT_42	[p2l646t550r760b577],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l780t550r811b577],
14	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_42	[p2l828t550r878b577],
15	endemic	JJ	O	endemic	amod	16	SENT_42	[p2l898t550r1030b577],
16	areas	NNS	O	area	prep_of	9	SENT_42	[p2l1050t558r1129b577],
17	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	19	SENT_42	[p2l1150t550r1199b577],
18	dramatically	RB	O	dramatically	advmod	19	SENT_42	[p2l281t591r469b626],
19	increased	VBN	O	increase	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l488t591r633b618],
20	both	CC	O	both	preconj	22	SENT_42	[p2l655t591r725b618],
21	research	NN	O	research	nn	22	SENT_42	[p2l746t591r873b618],
22	interest	NN	O	interest	xcomp	19	SENT_42	[p2l894t592r1010b618],
23	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l1028t591r1084b618],
24	public	JJ	O	public	amod	25	SENT_42	[p2l1106t591r1200b625],
25	awareness	NN	O	awareness	xcomp	19	SENT_42	[p2l280t641r449b660],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_42	[p2l280t641r449b660],

1	A	DT	O	a	det	2	SENT_43	[p2l470t635r491b660],
2	number	NN	O	number	nsubjpass	8	SENT_43	[p2l513t633r635b660],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l655t633r687b660],
4	candidate	NN	O	candidate	nn	5	SENT_43	[p2l705t633r857b660],
5	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	prep_of	2	SENT_43	[p2l878t634r1008b660],
6	have	VBP	O	have	aux	8	SENT_43	[p2l1030t633r1102b660],
7	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	8	SENT_43	[p2l1124t633r1198b660],
8	developed	VBN	O	develop	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l281t674r443b708],
9	to	TO	O	to	aux	10	SENT_43	[p2l457t679r488b701],
10	combat	VB	O	combat	xcomp	8	SENT_43	[p2l501t674r619b701],
11	Ebola	NNP	MISC	Ebola	nn	12	SENT_43	[p2l632t674r714b701],
12	virus	NN	O	virus	dobj	10	SENT_43	[p2l727t675r807b706],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l727t675r807b706],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l820t674r876b701],
15	these	DT	O	these	det	16	SENT_43	[p2l889t674r972b701],
16	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	nsubj	18	SENT_43	[p2l984t675r1114b701],
17	have	VBP	O	have	aux	18	SENT_43	[p2l1128t674r1200b701],
18	shown	VBN	O	show	conj_and	8	SENT_43	[p2l281t716r381b743],
19	varying	VBG	O	vary	amod	20	SENT_43	[p2l399t717r511b751],
20	degrees	NNS	O	degree	dobj	18	SENT_43	[p2l530t716r652b751],
21	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l670t716r702b743],
22	success	NN	O	success	prep_of	20	SENT_43	[p2l716t724r831b743],
23	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l849t717r874b743],
24	nonhuman	JJ	O	nonhuman	amod	26	SENT_43	[p2l893t716r1061b743],
25	primate	JJ	O	primate	amod	26	SENT_43	[p2l1081t717r1199b750],
26	models	NNS	O	model	prep_in	22	SENT_43	[p2l282t757r401b784],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_43	[p2l282t757r401b784],

1	Safety	NN	O	safety	nsubj	5	SENT_44	[p2l414t757r508b792],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	5	SENT_44	[p2l522t758r542b784],
3	a	DT	O	a	det	5	SENT_44	[p2l555t765r570b784],
4	signiﬁcant	JJ	O	signiﬁcant	amod	5	SENT_44	[p2l584t757r742b792],
5	concern	NN	O	concern	conj_and	5	SENT_44	[p2l756t765r878b784],
6	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l892t757r935b784],
7	any	DT	O	any	det	8	SENT_44	[p2l947t765r1002b792],
8	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	prep_for	5	SENT_44	[p2l1013t758r1129b784],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l1142t757r1198b784],
10	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l281t800r306b826],
11	particular	JJ	O	particular	prep_in	5	SENT_44	[p2l326t799r471b833],
12	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l486t799r529b826],
13	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	prep_for	11	SENT_44	[p2l544t800r674b826],
14	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	15	SENT_44	[p2l691t799r753b826],
15	replicate	VBP	O	replicate	rcmod	13	SENT_44	[p2l771t799r902b833],
16	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l920t800r945b826],
17	the	DT	O	the	det	18	SENT_44	[p2l962t799r1012b826],
18	host	NN	O	host	prep_in	15	SENT_44	[p2l1031t799r1103b826],
19	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_44	[p2l1031t799r1103b826],

1	Here	RB	O	here	advmod	4	SENT_45	[p2l1122t801r1200b831],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l1122t801r1200b831],
3	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	4	SENT_45	[p2l280t848r324b867],
4	evaluated	VBD	O	evaluate	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l351t840r501b867],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_45	[p2l527t840r577b867],
6	safety	NN	O	safety	dobj	4	SENT_45	[p2l604t840r694b875],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l720t840r751b867],
8	our	PRP$	O	we	poss	12	SENT_45	[p2l775t848r827b867],
9	replication-competent	JJ	O	replication-competent	amod	12	SENT_45	[p2l853t840r1200b874],
10	vesicular	JJ	O	vesicular	amod	12	SENT_45	[p2l280t882r415b909],
11	stomatitus	NN	O	stomatitus	nn	12	SENT_45	[p2l438t883r601b909],
12	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	6	SENT_45	[p2l623t883r696b909],
13	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	15	SENT_45	[p2l720t882r902b914],
14	VSV	NN	ORGANIZATION	vsv	nn	15	SENT_45	[p2l720t882r902b914],
15	)	NN	O	)	dep	12	SENT_45	[p2l720t882r902b914],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_45	[p2l720t882r902b914],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l720t882r902b914],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_46	[p2l720t882r902b914],

1	based	VBN	O	base	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l720t882r902b914],
2	Ebola	NNP	MISC	Ebola	nn	3	SENT_47	[p2l928t882r1010b909],
3	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	dobj	1	SENT_47	[p2l1034t883r1149b909],
4	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l1174t883r1198b909],
5	SH	NNP	O	SH	nn	7	SENT_47	[p2l281t923r488b950],
6	|	NNP	O	|	nn	7	SENT_47	[p2l281t923r488b950],
7	V	NNP	O	V	prep_in	3	SENT_47	[p2l281t923r488b950],
8	—	RB	O	—	advmod	3	SENT_47	[p2l281t923r488b950],
9	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	11	SENT_47	[p2l281t923r488b950],
10	rhesus	NN	O	rhesus	nn	11	SENT_47	[p2l505t923r603b950],
11	monkeys	NNS	O	monkey	dep	3	SENT_47	[p2l619t923r764b958],
12	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_47	[p2l619t923r764b958],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	2	SENT_48	[p2l777t925r826b950],
2	found	VBD	O	find	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l839t923r930b950],
3	that	IN	O	that	complm	6	SENT_48	[p2l945t923r1007b950],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_48	[p2l1021t923r1070b950],
5	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nsubj	6	SENT_48	[p2l1084t924r1199b950],
6	caused	VBD	O	cause	ccomp	2	SENT_48	[p2l281t965r386b992],
7	no	DT	O	no	det	8	SENT_48	[p2l416t973r453b992],
8	evidence	NN	O	evidence	dobj	6	SENT_48	[p2l481t965r619b992],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l646t965r677b992],
10	overt	JJ	O	overt	amod	11	SENT_48	[p2l702t970r781b992],
11	illness	NN	O	illness	prep_of	8	SENT_48	[p2l809t965r900b992],
12	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l928t966r952b992],
13	any	DT	O	any	prep_in	6	SENT_48	[p2l980t973r1035b1000],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l1061t965r1093b992],
15	these	DT	O	these	det	17	SENT_48	[p2l1116t965r1199b992],
16	immunocompromised	JJ	O	immunocompromised	amod	17	SENT_48	[p2l281t1006r626b1040],
17	animals	NNS	O	animal	prep_of	13	SENT_48	[p2l639t1006r764b1033],
18	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_48	[p2l639t1006r764b1033],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	3	SENT_49	[p2l776t1008r824b1033],
2	also	RB	O	also	advmod	3	SENT_49	[p2l836t1006r895b1033],
3	demonstrated	VBD	O	demonstrate	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l908t1006r1125b1033],
4	that	IN	O	that	complm	8	SENT_49	[p2l1138t1006r1200b1033],
5	this	DT	O	this	det	6	SENT_49	[p2l280t1048r334b1075],
6	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nsubj	24	SENT_49	[p2l347t1049r462b1075],
7	partially	RB	O	partially	advmod	8	SENT_49	[p2l477t1048r599b1083],
8	protected	VBD	O	protect	ccomp	3	SENT_49	[p2l612t1048r762b1082],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_49	[p2l776t1048r825b1075],
10	SH	NNP	O	SH	nn	12	SENT_49	[p2l839t1048r1047b1075],
11	|	NNP	O	|	nn	12	SENT_49	[p2l839t1048r1047b1075],
12	V	NNP	O	V	nsubj	15	SENT_49	[p2l839t1048r1047b1075],
13	—	RB	O	—	advmod	14	SENT_49	[p2l839t1048r1047b1075],
14	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	15	SENT_49	[p2l839t1048r1047b1075],
15	monkeys	NNS	O	monkey	xcomp	8	SENT_49	[p2l1062t1048r1199b1083],
16	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l280t1090r392b1124],
17	a	DT	O	a	det	20	SENT_49	[p2l405t1097r420b1116],
18	lethal	JJ	O	lethal	amod	20	SENT_49	[p2l436t1089r518b1116],
19	Ebola	NN	MISC	ebolum	nn	20	SENT_49	[p2l534t1089r616b1116],
20	challenge	NN	O	challenge	prep_against	15	SENT_49	[p2l631t1089r780b1124],
21	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l794t1089r850b1116],
22	that	IN	O	that	complm	24	SENT_49	[p2l864t1089r926b1116],
23	there	EX	O	there	expl	24	SENT_49	[p2l939t1089r1019b1116],
24	appears	VBZ	O	appear	ccomp	3	SENT_49	[p2l1033t1097r1155b1123],
25	to	TO	O	to	aux	28	SENT_49	[p2l1168t1094r1199b1116],
26	be	VB	O	be	cop	28	SENT_49	[p2l282t1131r318b1158],
27	an	DT	O	a	det	28	SENT_49	[p2l338t1139r372b1158],
28	association	NN	O	association	xcomp	24	SENT_49	[p2l393t1132r563b1158],
29	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l583t1131r649b1158],
30	levels	NNS	O	level	prep_with	28	SENT_49	[p2l671t1131r754b1158],
31	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l774t1131r806b1158],
32	CD4	NN	O	cd4	prep_of	30	SENT_49	[p2l822t1132r907b1158],
33	+	CC	O	+	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l822t1132r907b1158],
34	lymphocytes	NNS	O	lymphocyte	prep_of	30	SENT_49	[p2l927t1131r1123b1166],
35	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l1143t1131r1199b1158],
36	survival	NN	O	survival	conj_and	32	SENT_49	[p2l281t1172r404b1199],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_49	[p2l281t1172r404b1199],

1	Our	PRP$	O	we	poss	2	SENT_50	[p2l427t1173r484b1199],
2	study	NN	O	study	nsubj	18	SENT_50	[p2l507t1172r591b1207],
3	suggests	VBZ	O	suggest	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l614t1176r749b1207],
4	that	IN	O	that	complm	13	SENT_50	[p2l772t1172r834b1199],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_50	[p2l856t1172r906b1199],
6	VSV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	VSV	nn	7	SENT_50	[p2l928t1172r1091b1199],
7	—	NN	O	—	nsubj	13	SENT_50	[p2l928t1172r1091b1199],
8	based	VBN	O	base	partmod	7	SENT_50	[p2l928t1172r1091b1199],
9	Ebola	NNP	MISC	Ebola	nn	10	SENT_50	[p2l1117t1172r1199b1199],
10	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	dobj	8	SENT_50	[p2l280t1215r395b1241],
11	will	MD	O	will	aux	13	SENT_50	[p2l411t1214r461b1241],
12	be	VB	O	be	cop	13	SENT_50	[p2l480t1214r516b1241],
13	safe	JJ	O	safe	ccomp	3	SENT_50	[p2l533t1214r592b1241],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l609t1215r634b1241],
15	immunocompromised	JJ	O	immunocompromised	amod	16	SENT_50	[p2l652t1214r997b1248],
16	populations	NNS	O	population	prep_in	13	SENT_50	[p2l1016t1214r1199b1248],
17	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l280t1255r336b1282],
18	supports	VBZ	O	support	conj_and	3	SENT_50	[p2l365t1259r500b1289],
19	further	JJ	O	further	amod	20	SENT_50	[p2l527t1255r633b1282],
20	study	NN	O	study	dobj	18	SENT_50	[p2l660t1255r745b1290],
21	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l771t1255r827b1282],
22	development	NN	O	development	dobj	18	SENT_50	[p2l855t1255r1062b1289],
23	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l1090t1255r1121b1282],
24	this	DT	O	this	det	27	SENT_50	[p2l1145t1255r1199b1282],
25	promising	JJ	O	promising	amod	27	SENT_50	[p2l282t1298r435b1332],
26	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nn	27	SENT_50	[p2l451t1298r566b1324],
27	platform	NN	O	platform	prep_of	20	SENT_50	[p2l582t1297r713b1331],
28	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l728t1297r771b1324],
29	its	PRP$	O	its	poss	30	SENT_50	[p2l786t1298r818b1324],
30	use	NN	O	use	prep_for	27	SENT_50	[p2l834t1305r884b1324],
31	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l900t1298r925b1324],
32	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_in	18	SENT_50	[p2l942t1297r1072b1324],
33	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_50	[p2l942t1297r1072b1324],

1	protection	NN	O	protection	dep	3	SENT_51	[p2l242t1431r395b1465],
2	when	WRB	O	when	advmod	3	SENT_51	[p2l408t1431r489b1457],
3	administered	VBN	O	administer	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l504t1431r696b1457],
4	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l711t1440r739b1457],
5	a	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_51	[p2l754t1440r770b1456],
6	single	JJ	O	single	amod	9	SENT_51	[p2l784t1431r866b1465],
7	injection	NN	O	injection	nn	9	SENT_51	[p2l881t1431r1008b1465],
8	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nn	9	SENT_51	[p2l1022t1431r1133b1457],
9	[	NN	O	[	prep_as	3	SENT_51	[p2l1152t1431r1235b1465],
10	7	CD	NUMBER	7	number	11	SENT_51	[p2l1152t1431r1235b1465],
11	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	9	SENT_51	[p2l1152t1431r1235b1465],
12	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	13	SENT_51	[p2l1152t1431r1235b1465],
13	]	NN	O	]	dep	11	SENT_51	[p2l1152t1431r1235b1465],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_51	[p2l1152t1431r1235b1465],

1	Most	JJS	O	most	nsubj	12	SENT_52	[p2l243t1475r318b1501],
2	intriguingly	RB	O	intriguingly	advmod	12	SENT_52	[p2l340t1475r519b1509],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l340t1475r519b1509],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_52	[p2l542t1475r586b1501],
5	VSV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	VSV	nn	6	SENT_52	[p2l608t1475r779b1501],
6	—	NN	O	—	nsubj	7	SENT_52	[p2l608t1475r779b1501],
7	based	VBN	O	base	parataxis	12	SENT_52	[p2l608t1475r779b1501],
8	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nsubj	12	SENT_52	[p2l800t1475r911b1501],
9	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	12	SENT_52	[p2l933t1475r953b1501],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_52	[p2l975t1475r1020b1501],
11	only	JJ	O	only	amod	12	SENT_52	[p2l1043t1475r1106b1509],
12	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l1126t1475r1237b1501],
13	which	WDT	O	which	nsubj	15	SENT_52	[p2l242t1519r331b1545],
14	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	15	SENT_52	[p2l344t1519r392b1545],
15	shown	VBN	O	show	rcmod	12	SENT_52	[p2l406t1519r500b1545],
16	any	DT	O	any	det	17	SENT_52	[p2l513t1528r566b1553],
17	utility	NN	O	utility	dobj	15	SENT_52	[p2l578t1519r663b1553],
18	when	WRB	O	when	advmod	19	SENT_52	[p2l674t1519r755b1545],
19	administered	VBN	O	administer	advcl	15	SENT_52	[p2l768t1519r961b1545],
20	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l974t1528r1002b1545],
21	a	DT	O	a	det	23	SENT_52	[p2l1015t1528r1031b1544],
22	postexposure	NN	O	postexposure	nn	23	SENT_52	[p2l1043t1525r1236b1553],
23	treatment	NN	O	treatment	prep_as	19	SENT_52	[p2l243t1570r388b1590],
24	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	25	SENT_52	[p2l405t1564r517b1598],
25	13,14	CD	NUMBER	13,14	num	26	SENT_52	[p2l405t1564r517b1598],
26	]	NN	O	]	dobj	19	SENT_52	[p2l405t1564r517b1598],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_52	[p2l405t1564r517b1598],

1	Of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l281t1609r325b1635],
2	these	DT	O	these	det	3	SENT_53	[p2l332t1609r405b1635],
3	two	CD	NUMBER	two	prep_of	17	SENT_53	[p2l418t1615r471b1635],
4	leading	VBG	O	lead	amod	7	SENT_53	[p2l484t1609r592b1643],
5	EBOV	NN	O	ebov	nn	7	SENT_53	[p2l604t1609r706b1635],
6	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nn	7	SENT_53	[p2l717t1609r828b1635],
7	candidates	NNS	O	candidate	nsubj	17	SENT_53	[p2l842t1609r998b1635],
8	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	10	SENT_53	[p2l1011t1609r1069b1635],
9	can	MD	O	can	aux	10	SENT_53	[p2l1081t1618r1132b1635],
10	confer	VB	O	confer	rcmod	7	SENT_53	[p2l1145t1609r1238b1635],
11	protection	NN	O	protection	dobj	10	SENT_53	[p2l242t1654r395b1688],
12	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l414t1663r441b1680],
13	single	JJ	O	single	amod	15	SENT_53	[p2l460t1654r541b1688],
14	injection	NN	O	injection	nn	15	SENT_53	[p2l560t1654r688b1688],
15	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	prep_as	10	SENT_53	[p2l705t1654r829b1680],
16	each	DT	O	each	dep	15	SENT_53	[p2l848t1654r915b1680],
17	has	VBZ	O	have	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l933t1654r981b1680],
18	advantages	NNS	O	advantage	dobj	17	SENT_53	[p2l1000t1654r1164b1688],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l1183t1654r1238b1680],
20	disadvantages	NNS	O	disadvantage	dobj	17	SENT_53	[p2l243t1698r456b1732],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_53	[p2l243t1698r456b1732],

1	Adenovirus	NN	O	adenovirus	nn	2	SENT_54	[p2l480t1698r650b1724],
2	vectors	NNS	O	vector	nsubj	5	SENT_54	[p2l672t1704r776b1724],
3	are	VBP	O	be	cop	5	SENT_54	[p2l800t1707r845b1724],
4	highly	RB	O	highly	advmod	5	SENT_54	[p2l868t1698r960b1732],
5	immunogenic	JJ	O	immunogenic	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l982t1698r1186b1732],
6	as	IN	O	as	mark	7	SENT_54	[p2l1210t1707r1237b1724],
7	documented	VBN	O	document	ccomp	5	SENT_54	[p2l243t1742r428b1768],
8	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l440t1742r476b1776],
9	clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	10	SENT_54	[p2l488t1742r592b1768],
10	trials	NNS	O	trial	prep_by	7	SENT_54	[p2l604t1742r675b1768],
11	evaluating	VBG	O	evaluate	partmod	10	SENT_54	[p2l688t1742r841b1776],
12	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	14	SENT_54	[p2l853t1751r920b1776],
13	transfer	NN	O	transfer	nn	14	SENT_54	[p2l934t1742r1047b1768],
14	efficacy	NN	O	efficacy	dobj	11	SENT_54	[p2l1060t1742r1171b1776],
15	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l1183t1742r1238b1768],
16	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	17	SENT_54	[p2l243t1787r365b1813],
17	responses	NNS	O	response	dobj	11	SENT_54	[p2l381t1796r528b1821],
18	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_54	[p2l381t1796r528b1821],

1	Because	IN	O	because	mark	4	SENT_55	[p2l546t1787r664b1813],
2	they	PRP	O	they	nsubj	4	SENT_55	[p2l680t1787r743b1821],
3	are	VBP	O	be	cop	4	SENT_55	[p2l758t1796r803b1813],
4	replication-defective	JJ	O	replication-defective	advcl	9	SENT_55	[p2l819t1787r1119b1821],
5	adenovirus	NN	O	adenovirus	nn	6	SENT_55	[p2l1136t1787r1237b1813, p2l242t1831r313b1857],
6	vectors	NNS	O	vector	nsubjpass	9	SENT_55	[p2l327t1837r431b1857],
7	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	9	SENT_55	[p2l446t1840r490b1857],
8	also	RB	O	also	advmod	9	SENT_55	[p2l506t1831r561b1857],
9	perceived	VBN	O	perceive	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l575t1831r718b1865],
10	to	TO	O	to	aux	12	SENT_55	[p2l732t1837r760b1857],
11	be	VB	O	be	cop	12	SENT_55	[p2l774t1831r808b1857],
12	safer	JJR	O	safer	xcomp	9	SENT_55	[p2l823t1831r892b1857],
13	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l905t1831r947b1857],
14	human	JJ	O	human	amod	15	SENT_55	[p2l961t1831r1065b1857],
15	use	NN	O	use	prep_for	12	SENT_55	[p2l1080t1840r1126b1857],
16	than	IN	O	than	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l1141t1831r1207b1857],
17	a	DT	O	a	det	19	SENT_55	[p2l1222t1840r1238b1856],
18	replication-competent	JJ	O	replication-competent	amod	19	SENT_55	[p2l243t1876r571b1910],
19	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	prep_than	12	SENT_55	[p2l584t1876r703b1902],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l584t1876r703b1902],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_56	[p2l719t1876r779b1902],
2	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	3	SENT_56	[p2l794t1882r865b1902],
3	signiﬁcant	JJ	O	signiﬁcant	amod	4	SENT_56	[p2l879t1876r1029b1910],
4	challenge	NN	O	challenge	nsubj	11	SENT_56	[p2l1043t1876r1182b1910],
5	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1196t1876r1238b1902],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_56	[p2l243t1920r287b1946],
7	adenovirus-based	JJ	O	adenovirus-based	amod	8	SENT_56	[p2l309t1920r567b1946],
8	vaccines	NNS	O	vaccine	prep_for	4	SENT_56	[p2l586t1920r710b1946],
9	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	11	SENT_56	[p2l730t1920r750b1946],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_56	[p2l770t1920r815b1946],
11	concern	NN	O	concern	dep	48	SENT_56	[p2l835t1929r953b1946],
12	that	IN	O	that	complm	20	SENT_56	[p2l974t1920r1032b1946],
13	a	DT	O	a	det	15	SENT_56	[p2l1052t1929r1067b1945],
14	signiﬁcant	JJ	O	signiﬁcant	amod	15	SENT_56	[p2l1087t1920r1238b1954],
15	portion	NN	O	portion	nsubj	38	SENT_56	[p2l242t1964r351b1998],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l363t1964r395b1990],
17	the	DT	O	the	det	19	SENT_56	[p2l401t1964r445b1990],
18	global	JJ	O	global	amod	19	SENT_56	[p2l457t1964r546b1998],
19	population	NN	O	population	prep_of	15	SENT_56	[p2l557t1964r717b1998],
20	has	VBZ	O	have	ccomp	11	SENT_56	[p2l729t1964r776b1990],
21	pre-existing	JJ	O	pre-existing	amod	22	SENT_56	[p2l787t1964r962b1998],
22	antibodies	NNS	O	antibody	dobj	20	SENT_56	[p2l972t1964r1123b1990],
23	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1134t1964r1238b1998],
24	the	DT	O	the	det	26	SENT_56	[p2l243t2009r287b2035],
25	adenovirus	NN	O	adenovirus	nn	26	SENT_56	[p2l304t2009r465b2035],
26	vector	NN	O	vector	prep_against	22	SENT_56	[p2l479t2015r572b2035],
27	which	WDT	O	which	nsubj	29	SENT_56	[p2l585t2009r674b2035],
28	may	MD	O	may	aux	29	SENT_56	[p2l689t2018r753b2043],
29	affect	VB	O	affect	rcmod	22	SENT_56	[p2l768t2009r847b2035],
30	efﬁcacy	NN	O	efﬁcacy	nn	32	SENT_56	[p2l862t2009r973b2043],
31	[	NN	O	[	nn	32	SENT_56	[p2l991t2009r1100b2043],
32	l5	NN	O	l5	dobj	29	SENT_56	[p2l991t2009r1100b2043],
33	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	35	SENT_56	[p2l991t2009r1100b2043],
34	l7	NN	O	l7	nn	35	SENT_56	[p2l991t2009r1100b2043],
35	]	NN	O	]	dep	32	SENT_56	[p2l991t2009r1100b2043],
36	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1120t2009r1175b2035],
37	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	38	SENT_56	[p2l1189t2009r1237b2035],
38	performed	VBN	O	perform	conj_and	20	SENT_56	[p2l242t2053r399b2087],
39	poorly	RB	O	poorly	advmod	38	SENT_56	[p2l412t2053r508b2087],
40	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l522t2062r549b2079],
41	a	DT	O	a	det	43	SENT_56	[p2l564t2062r579b2078],
42	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nn	43	SENT_56	[p2l592t2053r702b2079],
43	vector	NN	O	vector	prep_as	38	SENT_56	[p2l716t2059r808b2079],
44	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l821t2053r849b2078],
45	recent	JJ	O	recent	amod	47	SENT_56	[p2l863t2059r954b2079],
46	clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	47	SENT_56	[p2l968t2053r1072b2079],
47	trials	NNS	O	trial	prep_in	43	SENT_56	[p2l1085t2053r1156b2079],
48	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1174t2053r1238b2087],
49	l8	NN	O	l8	dobj	48	SENT_56	[p2l1174t2053r1238b2087],
50	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	49	SENT_56	[p2l1174t2053r1238b2087],
51	19	CD	NUMBER	19	num	52	SENT_56	[p2l248t2098r299b2132],
52	]	NN	O	]	nsubj	48	SENT_56	[p2l248t2098r299b2132],
53	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l248t2098r299b2132],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l320t2098r351b2123],
2	contrast	NN	O	contrast	prep_in	12	SENT_57	[p2l370t2104r496b2130],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l370t2104r496b2130],
4	pre-existing	JJ	O	pre-existing	amod	5	SENT_57	[p2l516t2098r691b2132],
5	immunity	NN	O	immunity	nsubj	12	SENT_57	[p2l709t2098r854b2132],
6	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l872t2098r975b2132],
7	VSV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	VSV	prep_against	5	SENT_57	[p2l993t2098r1067b2124],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l1086t2098r1113b2123],
9	human	JJ	O	human	amod	10	SENT_57	[p2l1133t2098r1237b2124],
10	populations	NNS	O	population	prep_in	7	SENT_57	[p2l242t2142r415b2176],
11	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	12	SENT_57	[p2l435t2142r454b2168],
12	negligible	JJ	O	negligible	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l474t2142r614b2176],
13	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	14	SENT_57	[p2l638t2142r691b2176],
14	20	CD	NUMBER	20	num	15	SENT_57	[p2l638t2142r691b2176],
15	]	NN	O	]	dep	12	SENT_57	[p2l638t2142r691b2176],
16	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l714t2142r770b2168],
17	efﬁcacy	NN	O	efﬁcacy	nsubj	19	SENT_57	[p2l788t2142r899b2176],
18	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	19	SENT_57	[p2l917t2142r937b2168],
19	likely	JJ	O	likely	conj_and	12	SENT_57	[p2l956t2142r1033b2176],
20	greater	JJR	O	greater	dep	19	SENT_57	[p2l1051t2148r1155b2176],
21	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l1173t2142r1237b2168],
22	replication-competent	JJ	O	replication-competent	amod	23	SENT_57	[p2l243t2186r571b2220],
23	vectors	NNS	O	vector	prep_with	19	SENT_57	[p2l587t2192r699b2212],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l587t2192r699b2212],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_58	[p2l717t2186r777b2212],
2	main	JJ	O	main	amod	3	SENT_58	[p2l795t2186r870b2211],
3	concern	NN	O	concern	nsubj	9	SENT_58	[p2l887t2195r1005b2212],
4	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l1021t2186r1085b2212],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_58	[p2l1102t2186r1147b2212],
6	VSV	NN	ORGANIZATION	vsv	nn	8	SENT_58	[p2l1164t2186r1238b2212],
7	vaccine	NN	O	vaccine	nn	8	SENT_58	[p2l242t2231r352b2257],
8	vector	NN	O	vector	prep_with	3	SENT_58	[p2l368t2237r461b2257],
9	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l477t2231r496b2257],
10	that	IN	O	that	complm	14	SENT_58	[p2l513t2231r571b2257],
11	replication-competent	JJ	O	replication-competent	amod	12	SENT_58	[p2l587t2231r915b2265],
12	vectors	NNS	O	vector	nsubj	14	SENT_58	[p2l930t2237r1034b2257],
13	may	MD	O	may	aux	14	SENT_58	[p2l1051t2240r1115b2265],
14	present	VB	DATE	present	ccomp	9	SENT_58	[p2l1130t2237r1238b2265],
15	more	RBR	O	more	advmod	16	SENT_58	[p2l1314t265r1390b282],
16	signiﬁcant	JJ	O	signiﬁcant	amod	18	SENT_58	[p2l1411t256r1562b290],
17	safety	NN	O	safety	nn	18	SENT_58	[p2l1582t256r1665b290],
18	challenges	NNS	O	challenge	dobj	14	SENT_58	[p2l1684t256r1836b290],
19	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l1856t256r1883b281],
20	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_in	14	SENT_58	[p2l1904t256r2021b282],
21	particularly	RB	O	particularly	prep	14	SENT_58	[p2l2041t256r2213b290],
22	those	DT	O	those	pobj	21	SENT_58	[p2l2232t256r2308b282],
23	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l1313t300r1377b326],
24	altered	JJ	O	altered	amod	26	SENT_58	[p2l1392t300r1494b326],
25	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	26	SENT_58	[p2l1507t300r1630b326],
26	status	NN	O	status	prep_with	22	SENT_58	[p2l1645t306r1734b326],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l1645t306r1734b326],
