1	OPEN	NN	MISC	open	nn	3	SENT_1	[p1l187t137r269b160],
2	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	3	SENT_1	[p1l279t118r311b169],
3	ACCESS	NNP	O	ACCESS	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l319t137r431b161],
4	Freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	5	SENT_1	[p1l447t136r536b168],
5	available	JJ	O	available	amod	6	SENT_1	[p1l544t136r677b161],
6	online	NN	O	online	dep	3	SENT_1	[p1l685t136r777b161],
7	`	``	O	`	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1981t118r2095b161],
8	PATHOGENS	NNS	O	pathogen	dep	6	SENT_1	[p1l2106t138r2286b161],

1	Characterization	NN	O	characterization	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l191t215r889b290],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l934t214r1022b290],
3	Reemerging	VBG	O	reemerge	prepc_of	1	SENT_2	[p1l1060t218r1575b311],
4	Chikungunya	NNP	LOCATION	Chikungunya	dobj	3	SENT_2	[p1l1620t215r2187b312],

1	Virus	NN	O	virus	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l188t342r398b414],

1	Marion	NNP	PERSON	Marion	nn	2	SENT_4	[p1l189t486r307b514],
2	Sourisseau1	NNP	O	Sourisseau1	nsubj	8	SENT_4	[p1l323t475r559b518],
3	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l323t475r559b518],
4	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	2	SENT_4	[p1l323t475r559b518],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l323t475r559b518],
6	Clémentine	NNP	O	Clémentine	nn	7	SENT_4	[p1l574t484r768b514],
7	Schi	NNP	O	Schi	appos	4	SENT_4	[p1l783t475r948b518],
8	|	VBD	O	|	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l783t475r948b518],
9	te3	NN	O	te3	dobj	8	SENT_4	[p1l783t475r948b518],
10	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l783t475r948b518],
11	4	CD	NUMBER	4	nsubj	15	SENT_4	[p1l783t475r948b518],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l783t475r948b518],
13	Nicoletta	NNP	PERSON	Nicoletta	nn	14	SENT_4	[p1l965t486r1114b514],
14	Casarte	NNP	PERSON	Casarte	nsubj	15	SENT_4	[p1l1130t475r1341b518],
15	|	VBD	O	|	dep	9	SENT_4	[p1l1130t475r1341b518],
16	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	17	SENT_4	[p1l1130t475r1341b518],
17	i1	NN	O	i1	dobj	15	SENT_4	[p1l1130t475r1341b518],
18	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1130t475r1341b518],
19	2	CD	NUMBER	2	nsubj	23	SENT_4	[p1l1130t475r1341b518],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1130t475r1341b518],
21	Céline	NNP	O	Céline	nn	22	SENT_4	[p1l1356t484r1460b514],
22	Troui	NNP	O	Troui	appos	19	SENT_4	[p1l1474t475r1670b518],
23	|	VBD	O	|	rcmod	17	SENT_4	[p1l1474t475r1670b518],
24	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	25	SENT_4	[p1l1474t475r1670b518],
25	et1	NN	O	et1	dobj	23	SENT_4	[p1l1474t475r1670b518],
26	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1474t475r1670b518],
27	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	8	SENT_4	[p1l1474t475r1670b518],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1474t475r1670b518],
29	Florence	NNP	PERSON	Florence	nn	30	SENT_4	[p1l1687t486r1830b513],
30	Guivel-Benhassinel	NNP	PERSON	Guivel-Benhassinel	appos	27	SENT_4	[p1l1845t476r2172b514],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l2204t506r2212b518],
32	Dominika	NNP	PERSON	Dominika	nn	33	SENT_4	[p1l190t544r351b572],
33	Rudnickal	NNP	PERSON	Rudnickal	appos	27	SENT_4	[p1l368t533r576b576],
34	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l368t533r576b576],
35	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	33	SENT_4	[p1l368t533r576b576],
36	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l368t533r576b576],
37	Nathalie	NNP	PERSON	Nathalie	nn	40	SENT_4	[p1l592t544r733b572],
38	Sol-Fou	NNP	PERSON	Sol-Fou	nn	40	SENT_4	[p1l748t533r983b576],
39	|	NNP	O	|	nn	40	SENT_4	[p1l748t533r983b576],
40	onl	NN	O	onl	appos	27	SENT_4	[p1l748t533r983b576],
41	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l748t533r983b576],
42	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	40	SENT_4	[p1l748t533r983b576],
43	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l748t533r983b576],
44	Karin	NNP	PERSON	Karin	nn	46	SENT_4	[p1l999t544r1085b571],
45	Le	NNP	PERSON	Le	nn	46	SENT_4	[p1l1102t545r1139b571],
46	Rouxs	NNP	PERSON	Rouxs	appos	27	SENT_4	[p1l1155t534r1265b576],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1155t534r1265b576],
48	Marie-Christine	NNP	PERSON	Marie-Christine	nn	49	SENT_4	[p1l1281t544r1541b572],
49	Prevosté	NNP	PERSON	Prevosté	appos	27	SENT_4	[p1l1557t533r1711b576],
50	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1557t533r1711b576],
51	Hafida	NNP	O	Hafida	nn	52	SENT_4	[p1l1727t543r1835b572],
52	Fsihi7	NNP	O	Fsihi7	appos	27	SENT_4	[p1l1853t534r1956b576],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1853t534r1956b576],

1	,9	CD	NUMBER	,9	num	3	SENT_5	[p1l2133t591r2157b613],
2	Marie-Pascale	NNP	O	Marie-Pascale	nn	3	SENT_5	[p1l189t602r423b630],
3	Frenkiels	NNP	O	Frenkiels	nsubj	7	SENT_5	[p1l439t591r602b634],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l439t591r602b634],
5	Fabien	NNP	PERSON	Fabien	nn	6	SENT_5	[p1l618t602r730b630],
6	B	NNP	PERSON	B	appos	3	SENT_5	[p1l747t591r946b634],
7	|	VBD	O	|	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l747t591r946b634],
8	anchet1	NN	O	anchet1	dobj	7	SENT_5	[p1l747t591r946b634],
9	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l747t591r946b634],
10	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	8	SENT_5	[p1l747t591r946b634],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l747t591r946b634],
12	Philippe	NNP	PERSON	Philippe	nn	14	SENT_5	[p1l963t602r1100b637],
13	V.	NNP	PERSON	V.	nn	14	SENT_5	[p1l1115t603r1147b629],
14	Afonso2	NNP	PERSON	Afonso2	appos	8	SENT_5	[p1l1162t591r1334b634],
15	’	CD	NUMBER	’	number	16	SENT_5	[p1l1162t591r1334b634],
16	9	CD	NUMBER	9	dep	14	SENT_5	[p1l1162t591r1334b634],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1162t591r1334b634],
18	Pierre-Emmanuel	NNP	PERSON	Pierre-Emmanuel	nn	21	SENT_5	[p1l1350t602r1642b630],
19	Cecca	NNP	PERSON	Cecca	nn	21	SENT_5	[p1l1658t591r1849b634],
20	|	NN	O	|	nn	21	SENT_5	[p1l1658t591r1849b634],
21	di2	NN	O	di2	appos	8	SENT_5	[p1l1658t591r1849b634],
22	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1658t591r1849b634],
23	9	CD	NUMBER	9	dep	21	SENT_5	[p1l1658t591r1849b634],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1658t591r1849b634],
25	Simona	NNP	PERSON	Simona	nn	26	SENT_5	[p1l1865t602r1989b630],
26	Ozdenz	NNP	PERSON	Ozdenz	appos	8	SENT_5	[p1l2006t591r2131b629],
27	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l2159t622r2167b634],
28	Antoine	NNP	PERSON	Antoine	nn	29	SENT_5	[p1l188t660r322b688],
29	Gessain2	NNP	PERSON	Gessain2	appos	26	SENT_5	[p1l337t650r521b692],
30	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l337t650r521b692],
31	9	CD	NUMBER	9	dep	29	SENT_5	[p1l337t650r521b692],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l337t650r521b692],
33	Isabelle	NNP	PERSON	Isabelle	nn	34	SENT_5	[p1l537t660r665b688],
34	Schuffeneckerm	NNP	PERSON	Schuffeneckerm	appos	31	SENT_5	[p1l680t650r966b692],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l680t650r966b692],
36	Bruno	NNP	PERSON	Bruno	nn	37	SENT_5	[p1l983t661r1083b688],
37	Verhasseltll	NNP	PERSON	Verhasseltll	appos	31	SENT_5	[p1l1097t651r1320b692],
38	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1097t651r1320b692],
39	Alessia	NNP	PERSON	Alessia	nn	40	SENT_5	[p1l1335t660r1451b688],
40	Zamborlinilz	NNP	PERSON	Zamborlinilz	appos	31	SENT_5	[p1l1467t650r1697b692],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1467t650r1697b692],
42	Ali	NNP	PERSON	Ali	nn	43	SENT_5	[p1l1712t660r1755b687],
43	Saibn	NNP	PERSON	Saibn	appos	31	SENT_5	[p1l1771t650r1888b692],
44	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1771t650r1888b692],
45	Felix	NNP	PERSON	Felix	nn	47	SENT_5	[p1l1904t660r1982b687],
46	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	47	SENT_5	[p1l1996t661r2029b687],
47	Rey2	NNP	PERSON	Rey2	appos	31	SENT_5	[p1l2045t650r2175b695],
48	’	CD	NUMBER	’	number	49	SENT_5	[p1l2045t650r2175b695],
49	13	CD	NUMBER	13	dep	47	SENT_5	[p1l2045t650r2175b695],
50	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l2045t650r2175b695],
51	Fernando	NNP	PERSON	Fernando	nn	52	SENT_5	[p1l190t719r351b746],
52	Arenzana-Seisdedos2	NN	O	arenzana-seisdedos2	poss	54	SENT_5	[p1l365t708r781b751],
53	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l365t708r781b751],
54	”	NN	O	”	appos	31	SENT_5	[p1l365t708r781b751],
55	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l365t708r781b751],
56	Philippe	NNP	PERSON	Philippe	nn	57	SENT_5	[p1l797t719r935b754],
57	Despress	NNP	PERSON	Despress	appos	8	SENT_5	[p1l951t708r1113b754],
58	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l951t708r1113b754],
59	Alain	NNP	PERSON	Alain	nn	60	SENT_5	[p1l1127t719r1213b746],
60	Michaults	NNP	PERSON	Michaults	appos	57	SENT_5	[p1l1229t709r1403b751],
61	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1229t709r1403b751],
62	Matthew	NNP	PERSON	Matthew	nn	64	SENT_5	[p1l1418t719r1568b746],
63	L.	NNP	PERSON	L.	nn	64	SENT_5	[p1l1583t720r1609b746],
64	AIbert3	NNP	PERSON	AIbert3	appos	57	SENT_5	[p1l1624t708r1782b751],
65	’	CD	NUMBER	’	number	66	SENT_5	[p1l1624t708r1782b751],
66	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	64	SENT_5	[p1l1624t708r1782b751],
67	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1624t708r1782b751],
68	Olivier	NNP	PERSON	Olivier	nn	69	SENT_5	[p1l1797t719r1909b747],
69	Schwartz1	NNP	O	Schwartz1	appos	57	SENT_5	[p1l1923t708r2134b747],
70	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1923t708r2134b747],
71	2	CD	NUMBER	2	number	72	SENT_5	[p1l1923t708r2134b747],
72	*	CD	NUMBER	*	num	69	SENT_5	[p1l1923t708r2134b747],

1	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l190t785r199b804],
2	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l214t784r360b810],
3	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l370t783r395b804],
4	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l403t783r508b810],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l403t783r508b810],
6	Unité	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Unité	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l520t783r583b804],
7	Virus	NN	ORGANIZATION	virus	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l593t784r651b804],
8	et	FW	ORGANIZATION	et	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l662t787r685b804],
9	Immunité	FW	ORGANIZATION	immunité	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l696t783r818b808],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l696t783r818b808],
11	Institut	NNP	LOCATION	Institut	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l830t784r913b804],
12	Pasteur	NNP	LOCATION	Pasteur	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l925t784r1018b808],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l925t784r1018b808],
14	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1030t784r1090b808],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1030t784r1090b808],
16	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1102t784r1186b808],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1102t784r1186b808],
18	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1197t785r1210b804],
19	CNRS	NNS	ORGANIZATION	cnr	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1221t784r1285b804],
20	URA	VBP	O	ura	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1297t784r1347b804],
21	3015	CD	NUMBER	3015	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1357t785r1420b808],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1357t785r1420b808],
23	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1432t784r1492b808],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1432t784r1492b808],
25	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1504t784r1588b808],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1504t784r1588b808],
27	3	CD	NUMBER	3	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1599t785r1613b804],
28	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1625t784r1770b810],
29	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1781t783r1805b804],
30	Immunology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Immunology	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1815t783r1974b810],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1815t783r1974b810],
32	Groupe	NNP	PERSON	Groupe	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1985t784r2074b810],
33	Immunobiologie	NNP	PERSON	Immunobiologie	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l2086t783r2286b810],
34	des	NNP	PERSON	des	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l188t824r229b845],
35	Cellules	NNP	PERSON	Cellules	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l240t824r332b845],
36	Dendritiques	NNP	PERSON	Dendritiques	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l344t824r504b851],
37	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l344t824r504b851],
38	Institut	NNP	LOCATION	Institut	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l517t825r600b845],
39	Pasteur	NNP	LOCATION	Pasteur	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l612t825r706b849],
40	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l612t825r706b849],
41	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l718t825r778b849],
42	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l718t825r778b849],
43	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l791t825r875b849],
44	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l791t825r875b849],
45	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l886t826r901b845],
46	INSERM	NN	ORGANIZATION	inserm	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l913t825r1002b845],
47	U818	NN	O	u818	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1015t825r1081b849],
48	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1015t825r1081b849],
49	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1094t825r1154b849],
50	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1094t825r1154b849],
51	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1166t825r1250b849],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1166t825r1250b849],
53	5	CD	NUMBER	5	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1262t826r1276b845],
54	Laboratoire	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Laboratoire	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1288t824r1425b845],
55	de	IN	ORGANIZATION	de	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1436t824r1465b845],
56	Microbiologie	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Microbiologie	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1477t824r1649b851],
57	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1477t824r1649b851],
58	Groupe	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Groupe	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1660t825r1750b851],
59	Hospitalier	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hospitalier	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1762t824r1890b851],
60	Sud	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Sud	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1901t824r1945b845],
61	Reunion	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Reunion	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1958t824r2062b849],
62	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1958t824r2062b849],
63	Ile	NN	LOCATION	ile	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l2075t824r2100b845],
64	de	FW	LOCATION	de	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l2111t824r2140b845],
65	la	FW	LOCATION	la	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l2152t824r2169b845],
66	Réunion	NNP	LOCATION	Réunion	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l2182t824r2286b849],
67	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2182t824r2286b849],
68	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l190t867r273b891],
69	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l190t867r273b891],
70	6	CD	NUMBER	6	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l284t868r298b887],
71	Département	NNP	O	Département	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l309t866r468b893],
72	de	IN	O	de	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l478t866r507b887],
73	Biologie	NNP	O	Biologie	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l518t866r614b893],
74	Cellulaire	NNP	O	Cellulaire	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l624t866r734b887],
75	et	FW	O	et	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l744t870r766b887],
76	Infection	NN	O	infection	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l777t866r887b891],
77	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l777t866r887b891],
78	Plateforme	NNP	O	Plateforme	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l898t866r1029b887],
79	de	IN	O	de	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1038t866r1067b887],
80	Microscopie	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Microscopie	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1078t867r1222b893],
81	Electronique	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Electronique	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1233t860r1389b893],
82	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1233t860r1389b893],
83	Institut	NNP	LOCATION	Institut	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1401t867r1484b887],
84	Pasteur	NNP	LOCATION	Pasteur	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1495t867r1588b891],
85	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1495t867r1588b891],
86	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1599t867r1659b891],
87	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1599t867r1659b891],
88	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1670t867r1754b891],
89	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1670t867r1754b891],
90	7	CD	NUMBER	7	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1765t868r1778b887],
91	Département	NN	ORGANIZATION	département	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1789t866r1949b893],
92	Infection	NN	ORGANIZATION	infection	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1960t866r2064b887],
93	et	FW	ORGANIZATION	et	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l2074t870r2097b887],
94	Epidemiologie	FW	ORGANIZATION	epidemiologie	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l2108t866r2286b893],
95	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2108t866r2286b893],
96	Institut	NNP	LOCATION	Institut	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l190t908r273b928],
97	Pasteur	NNP	LOCATION	Pasteur	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l287t908r380b932],
98	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l287t908r380b932],
99	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l394t908r454b932],
100	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l394t908r454b932],
101	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l468t908r552b932],
102	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l468t908r552b932],
103	8	CD	NUMBER	8	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l565t909r579b928],
104	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l593t908r738b934],
105	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l750t907r775b928],
106	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l785t907r891b934],
107	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l785t907r891b934],
108	Unité	NNP	O	Unité	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l905t907r967b928],
109	Interactions	NNS	O	interaction	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l981t908r1122b928],
110	Moleculaires	NNS	O	moleculaire	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1135t907r1285b928],
111	F	NN	O	f	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1299t907r1494b932],
112	|	NN	O	|	dep	113	SENT_6	[p1l1299t907r1494b932],
113	avivirus	NN	O	avivirus	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1299t907r1494b932],
114	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1299t907r1494b932],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1299t907r1494b932],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1299t907r1494b932],

1	H6tes	NNS	O	h6te	dep	19	SENT_8	[p1l1299t907r1494b932],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1299t907r1494b932],
3	Institut	NNP	PERSON	Institut	nn	4	SENT_8	[p1l1508t908r1592b928],
4	Pasteur	NNP	PERSON	Pasteur	appos	1	SENT_8	[p1l1606t908r1699b932],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1606t908r1699b932],
6	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	appos	1	SENT_8	[p1l1713t908r1773b932],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1713t908r1773b932],
8	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	appos	1	SENT_8	[p1l1787t908r1871b932],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1787t908r1871b932],
10	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	11	SENT_8	[p1l1884t909r1898b928],
11	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	appos	1	SENT_8	[p1l1911t908r2057b934],
12	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2069t907r2094b928],
13	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	prep_of	11	SENT_8	[p1l2104t907r2210b934],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2104t907r2210b934],
15	Unité	NNP	O	Unité	nn	16	SENT_8	[p1l2224t907r2286b928],
16	d’	NN	O	d’	appos	1	SENT_8	[p1l188t944r385b976],
17	F_pidémio	NN	O	f_pidémio	dep	19	SENT_8	[p1l188t944r385b976],
18	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	17	SENT_8	[p1l188t944r385b976],
19	ogie	NN	O	ogie	dep	39	SENT_8	[p1l188t944r385b976],
20	et	FW	O	et	nn	19	SENT_8	[p1l394t953r417b970],
21	Physiopathologie	FW	MISC	physiopathologie	nn	19	SENT_8	[p1l428t949r637b976],
22	des	FW	MISC	des	dep	19	SENT_8	[p1l646t949r687b970],
23	Virus	NN	MISC	virus	nn	24	SENT_8	[p1l696t950r755b970],
24	Oncogénes	NNS	MISC	oncogénes	dep	19	SENT_8	[p1l765t949r907b976],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l765t949r907b976],
26	Institut	NNP	LOCATION	Institut	nn	27	SENT_8	[p1l918t950r1001b970],
27	Pasteur	NNP	LOCATION	Pasteur	appos	24	SENT_8	[p1l1012t950r1106b974],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1012t950r1106b974],
29	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	appos	24	SENT_8	[p1l1117t950r1176b974],
30	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1117t950r1176b974],
31	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	appos	24	SENT_8	[p1l1188t950r1271b974],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1188t950r1271b974],
33	10	CD	NUMBER	10	appos	24	SENT_8	[p1l1283t951r1312b970],
34	Centre	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Centre	nn	39	SENT_8	[p1l1322t950r1401b970],
35	National	NNP	ORGANIZATION	National	nn	39	SENT_8	[p1l1412t949r1510b970],
36	de	NNP	ORGANIZATION	de	nn	39	SENT_8	[p1l1521t949r1550b970],
37	Référence	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Référence	nn	39	SENT_8	[p1l1561t949r1679b970],
38	des	NNP	ORGANIZATION	des	nn	39	SENT_8	[p1l1688t949r1729b970],
39	Arbovirus	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Arbovirus	dep	54	SENT_8	[p1l1738t949r1860b974],
40	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1738t949r1860b974],
41	Lyon	NNP	LOCATION	Lyon	appos	39	SENT_8	[p1l1871t950r1933b976],
42	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1871t950r1933b976],
43	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	appos	39	SENT_8	[p1l1945t950r2028b974],
44	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1945t950r2028b974],
45	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	47	SENT_8	[p1l2040t951r2065b970],
46	Ghent	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Ghent	nn	47	SENT_8	[p1l2078t949r2152b970],
47	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	appos	39	SENT_8	[p1l2163t950r2286b976],
48	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l2163t950r2286b976],
49	Ghent	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Ghent	appos	39	SENT_8	[p1l188t990r267b1015],
50	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l188t990r267b1015],
51	Belgium	NNP	LOCATION	Belgium	appos	39	SENT_8	[p1l282t990r384b1017],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l282t990r384b1017],
53	12	CD	NUMBER	12	appos	39	SENT_8	[p1l399t992r427b1011],
54	Hépital	JJ	O	hépital	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l441t990r526b1017],
55	St	NNP	O	St	dep	54	SENT_8	[p1l540t991r640b1015],
56	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l540t991r640b1015],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l540t991r640b1015],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l540t991r640b1015],

1	Louis	NNP	PERSON	Louis	dep	33	SENT_10	[p1l540t991r640b1015],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l540t991r640b1015],
3	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l655t991r714b1015],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l655t991r714b1015],
5	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l728t991r812b1015],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l728t991r812b1015],
7	13	CD	NUMBER	13	num	10	SENT_10	[p1l827t992r855b1011],
8	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	nn	10	SENT_10	[p1l869t991r1014b1017],
9	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	amod	10	SENT_10	[p1l1027t990r1052b1011],
10	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l1062t990r1167b1017],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1062t990r1167b1017],
12	Unité	NNP	PERSON	Unité	nn	15	SENT_10	[p1l1182t990r1244b1011],
13	de	IN	PERSON	de	amod	15	SENT_10	[p1l1257t990r1286b1011],
14	Virologie	NNP	PERSON	Virologie	nn	15	SENT_10	[p1l1298t990r1405b1017],
15	Structurale	NNP	PERSON	Structurale	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l1418t990r1555b1015],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1418t990r1555b1015],
17	Institut	NNP	LOCATION	Institut	nn	18	SENT_10	[p1l1569t991r1652b1011],
18	Pasteur	NNP	LOCATION	Pasteur	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l1666t991r1759b1015],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1666t991r1759b1015],
20	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l1773t991r1833b1015],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1773t991r1833b1015],
22	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l1847t991r1931b1015],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1847t991r1931b1015],
24	14	CD	NUMBER	14	num	25	SENT_10	[p1l1946t992r1975b1011],
25	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l1988t991r2133b1017],
26	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2146t990r2171b1011],
27	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	prep_of	25	SENT_10	[p1l2180t990r2286b1017],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2180t990r2286b1017],
29	Laboratoire	NNP	PERSON	Laboratoire	nn	31	SENT_10	[p1l190t1032r326b1053],
30	de	IN	PERSON	de	amod	31	SENT_10	[p1l338t1032r367b1053],
31	Pathogénie	NNP	PERSON	Pathogénie	appos	1	SENT_10	[p1l380t1032r516b1059],
32	Virale	NNP	PERSON	Virale	dep	33	SENT_10	[p1l527t1032r594b1053],
33	Moléculaire	NNP	PERSON	Moléculaire	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l606t1032r750b1057],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l606t1032r750b1057],
35	Institut	NNP	LOCATION	Institut	nn	36	SENT_10	[p1l763t1033r846b1053],
36	Pasteur	NNP	LOCATION	Pasteur	appos	33	SENT_10	[p1l859t1033r953b1057],
37	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l859t1033r953b1057],
38	Paris	NNP	LOCATION	Paris	appos	33	SENT_10	[p1l966t1033r1025b1057],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l966t1033r1025b1057],
40	France	NNP	LOCATION	France	appos	33	SENT_10	[p1l1038t1033r1116b1053],

1	An	DT	O	a	det	3	SENT_11	[p1l188t1134r234b1161],
2	unprecedented	JJ	O	unprecedented	amod	3	SENT_11	[p1l247t1133r507b1169],
3	epidemic	JJ	O	epidemic	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l519t1133r676b1169],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l687t1132r722b1162],
5	chikungunya	NN	O	chikungunya	nn	6	SENT_11	[p1l731t1133r953b1170],
6	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	3	SENT_11	[p1l965t1133r1048b1162],
7	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	10	SENT_11	[p1l1060t1134r1188b1166],
8	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nn	10	SENT_11	[p1l1060t1134r1188b1166],
9	)	NN	O	)	nn	10	SENT_11	[p1l1060t1134r1188b1166],
10	infection	NN	O	infection	nsubj	12	SENT_11	[p1l1201t1132r1350b1162],
11	recently	RB	DATE	recently	advmod	12	SENT_11	[p1l1363t1133r1501b1170],
12	started	VBD	O	start	dep	3	SENT_11	[p1l1511t1133r1631b1162],
13	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1644t1133r1674b1161],
14	countries	NNS	O	country	prep_in	12	SENT_11	[p1l1685t1133r1844b1162],
15	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1855t1132r1890b1162],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	19	SENT_11	[p1l1899t1133r1954b1162],
17	Indian	NNP	LOCATION	Indian	nn	19	SENT_11	[p1l1967t1133r2073b1162],
18	Ocean	NNP	LOCATION	Ocean	nn	19	SENT_11	[p1l2085t1134r2190b1162],
19	area	NN	O	area	prep_of	14	SENT_11	[p1l2202t1141r2286b1166],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l2202t1141r2286b1166],
21	causing	VBG	O	cause	partmod	3	SENT_11	[p1l189t1178r318b1214],
22	an	DT	O	a	det	26	SENT_11	[p1l343t1186r383b1207],
23	acute	JJ	O	acute	amod	26	SENT_11	[p1l409t1182r502b1207],
24	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l525t1178r589b1207],
25	painful	JJ	O	painful	conj_and	23	SENT_11	[p1l615t1177r733b1214],
26	syndrome	NN	O	syndrome	dobj	21	SENT_11	[p1l758t1178r929b1215],
27	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l953t1178r1027b1207],
28	strong	JJ	O	strong	amod	29	SENT_11	[p1l1052t1182r1161b1214],
29	fever	NN	O	fever	prep_with	26	SENT_11	[p1l1185t1177r1283b1211],
30	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1185t1177r1283b1211],
31	asthenia	NN	O	asthenia	prep_with	26	SENT_11	[p1l1307t1178r1463b1211],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1307t1178r1463b1211],
33	skin	NN	O	skin	nn	34	SENT_11	[p1l1487t1178r1555b1207],
34	rash	NN	O	rash	prep_with	26	SENT_11	[p1l1581t1178r1662b1211],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1581t1178r1662b1211],
36	polyarthritis	NN	O	polyarthritis	conj_and	29	SENT_11	[p1l1687t1178r1906b1215],
37	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1687t1178r1906b1215],
38	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l1930t1178r1994b1207],
39	lethal	JJ	O	lethal	amod	40	SENT_11	[p1l2020t1178r2114b1207],
40	cases	NNS	O	case	conj_and	29	SENT_11	[p1l2139t1186r2229b1207],
41	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l2253t1177r2288b1207],
42	encephalitis	NN	O	encephalitis	prep_of	3	SENT_11	[p1l189t1224r405b1260],
43	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l189t1224r405b1260],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_12	[p1l424t1224r488b1252],
2	basis	NN	O	basis	nsubj	12	SENT_12	[p1l508t1224r593b1253],
3	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l612t1223r661b1253],
4	chikungunya	NN	O	chikungunya	nn	5	SENT_12	[p1l680t1224r902b1261],
5	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_for	2	SENT_12	[p1l922t1224r1049b1253],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1068t1224r1132b1253],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_12	[p1l1152t1224r1208b1253],
8	tropism	NN	O	tropism	conj_and	2	SENT_12	[p1l1227t1224r1358b1260],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1380t1223r1415b1253],
10	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	prep_of	8	SENT_12	[p1l1433t1225r1541b1253],
11	remain	VBP	O	remain	cop	12	SENT_12	[p1l1560t1224r1678b1253],
12	unknown	JJ	O	unknown	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1700t1224r1870b1253],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1700t1224r1870b1253],

1	Here	RB	O	here	advmod	4	SENT_13	[p1l1891t1225r1980b1257],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1891t1225r1980b1257],
3	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	4	SENT_13	[p1l1999t1232r2048b1252],
4	describe	VBP	O	describe	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l2067t1224r2211b1253],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_13	[p1l2230t1224r2286b1253],
6	replication	NN	O	replication	nn	7	SENT_13	[p1l190t1270r371b1306],
7	characteristics	NNS	O	characteristic	dobj	4	SENT_13	[p1l384t1270r629b1299],
8	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l640t1269r676b1299],
9	recent	JJ	O	recent	amod	12	SENT_13	[p1l686t1274r793b1299],
10	clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	12	SENT_13	[p1l804t1270r920b1299],
11	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nn	12	SENT_13	[p1l933t1271r1041b1299],
12	strains	NNS	O	strain	prep_of	7	SENT_13	[p1l1052t1270r1175b1299],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1052t1270r1175b1299],

1	Human	JJ	O	human	amod	5	SENT_14	[p1l1188t1271r1310b1299],
2	epithelial	JJ	O	epithelial	amod	5	SENT_14	[p1l1322t1270r1482b1306],
3	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1494t1270r1558b1299],
4	endothelial	JJ	O	endothelial	conj_and	2	SENT_14	[p1l1570t1270r1765b1299],
5	cells	NNS	O	cell	nsubj	24	SENT_14	[p1l1777t1270r1860b1303],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1777t1270r1860b1303],
7	primary	JJ	O	primary	amod	8	SENT_14	[p1l1873t1270r2008b1307],
8	fibroblasts	NNS	O	fibroblast	appos	5	SENT_14	[p1l2017t1269r2201b1299],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l2212t1270r2286b1303],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l2212t1270r2286b1303],
11	to	TO	O	to	dep	8	SENT_14	[p1l188t1319r224b1344],
12	a	DT	O	a	det	14	SENT_14	[p1l233t1323r251b1344],
13	lesser	JJR	O	lesser	amod	14	SENT_14	[p1l264t1315r361b1344],
14	extent	NN	O	extent	pobj	11	SENT_14	[p1l370t1319r490b1348],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l370t1319r490b1348],
16	monocyte-derived	JJ	O	monocyte-derived	amod	17	SENT_14	[p1l501t1315r815b1352],
17	macrophages	NNS	O	macrophage	appos	5	SENT_14	[p1l827t1315r1068b1351],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l827t1315r1068b1351],
19	were	VBD	O	be	cop	20	SENT_14	[p1l1078t1323r1162b1343],
20	susceptible	JJ	O	susceptible	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1172t1315r1365b1351],
21	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1375t1319r1410b1344],
22	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_to	20	SENT_14	[p1l1420t1314r1570b1344],
23	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1581t1315r1644b1344],
24	allowed	VBD	O	allow	conj_and	20	SENT_14	[p1l1656t1315r1790b1344],
25	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	26	SENT_14	[p1l1800t1315r1874b1344],
26	production	NN	O	production	dobj	24	SENT_14	[p1l1886t1315r2084b1351],
27	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1886t1315r2084b1351],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l2096t1316r2126b1343],
2	contrast	NN	O	contrast	prep_in	7	SENT_15	[p1l2137t1319r2286b1348],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l2137t1319r2286b1348],
4	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nsubj	7	SENT_15	[p1l189t1362r297b1390],
5	did	VBD	O	do	aux	7	SENT_15	[p1l306t1361r360b1390],
6	not	RB	O	not	neg	7	SENT_15	[p1l372t1365r429b1390],
7	replicate	VB	O	replicate	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l439t1361r587b1397],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l598t1361r628b1389],
9	lymphoid	JJ	O	lymphoid	amod	13	SENT_15	[p1l640t1361r801b1398],
10	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l813t1361r876b1390],
11	monocytoid	JJ	O	monocytoid	amod	13	SENT_15	[p1l889t1361r1092b1398],
12	cell	NN	O	cell	nn	13	SENT_15	[p1l1103t1361r1159b1390],
13	lines	NNS	O	line	prep_in	7	SENT_15	[p1l1172t1361r1259b1394],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1172t1361r1259b1394],
15	primary	JJ	O	primary	amod	16	SENT_15	[p1l1270t1361r1405b1398],
16	lymphocytes	NNS	O	lymphocyte	prep_in	7	SENT_15	[p1l1416t1361r1633b1398],
17	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1643t1361r1707b1390],
18	monocytes	NNS	O	monocyte	conj_or	13	SENT_15	[p1l1719t1365r1915b1398],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1719t1365r1915b1398],
20	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1926t1369r1962b1390],
21	monocyte-derived	JJ	O	monocyte-derived	amod	23	SENT_15	[p1l1972t1361r2286b1398],
22	dendritic	JJ	O	dendritic	amod	23	SENT_15	[p1l189t1407r342b1436],
23	cells	NNS	O	cell	prep_in	7	SENT_15	[p1l365t1407r449b1436],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l365t1407r449b1436],

1	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nn	2	SENT_16	[p1l472t1408r579b1436],
2	replication	NN	O	replication	nsubjpass	4	SENT_16	[p1l603t1407r785b1443],
3	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	4	SENT_16	[p1l808t1415r874b1436],
4	cytopathic	JJ	O	cytopathic	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l897t1407r1076b1444],
5	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1099t1407r1163b1436],
6	associated	VBN	O	associate	conj_and	4	SENT_16	[p1l1187t1407r1367b1436],
7	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1390t1407r1464b1436],
8	an	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_16	[p1l1488t1415r1529b1436],
9	induction	NN	O	induction	prep_with	6	SENT_16	[p1l1554t1407r1715b1436],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1739t1406r1775b1436],
11	apoptosis	NN	O	apoptosis	prep_of	9	SENT_16	[p1l1796t1407r1963b1443],
12	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1987t1407r2016b1435],
13	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	14	SENT_16	[p1l2041t1406r2179b1436],
14	cells	NNS	O	cell	prep_in	6	SENT_16	[p1l2203t1407r2286b1436],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l2203t1407r2286b1436],

1	Chloroquine	NN	MISC	chloroquine	nsubj	11	SENT_17	[p1l189t1452r410b1488],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l189t1452r410b1488],
3	bafilomycin-A1	NN	O	bafilomycin-a1	conj_and	1	SENT_17	[p1l426t1451r695b1489],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l426t1451r695b1489],
5	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l709t1452r773b1481],
6	short	JJ	O	short	amod	8	SENT_17	[p1l789t1452r877b1481],
7	hairpin	NN	O	hairpin	nn	8	SENT_17	[p1l892t1452r1011b1488],
8	RNAs	NNS	MISC	rna	conj_and	1	SENT_17	[p1l1028t1453r1117b1481],
9	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1132t1452r1258b1488],
10	dynamin-2	NN	O	dynamin-2	prep_against	8	SENT_17	[p1l1272t1452r1455b1489],
11	inhibited	VBD	O	inhibit	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1471t1452r1624b1481],
12	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	13	SENT_17	[p1l1639t1452r1713b1481],
13	production	NN	O	production	dobj	11	SENT_17	[p1l1730t1452r1927b1488],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1730t1452r1927b1488],
15	indicating	VBG	O	indicate	partmod	11	SENT_17	[p1l1943t1452r2113b1488],
16	that	IN	O	that	complm	19	SENT_17	[p1l2128t1452r2198b1481],
17	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	18	SENT_17	[p1l2212t1452r2286b1481],
18	entry	NN	O	entry	nsubj	19	SENT_17	[p1l189t1502r279b1535],
19	occurs	VBZ	O	occur	ccomp	15	SENT_17	[p1l297t1506r406b1527],
20	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l423t1498r561b1534],
21	pH-dependent	JJ	O	ph-dependent	amod	22	SENT_17	[p1l582t1498r831b1534],
22	endocytosis	NN	O	endocytosis	prep_through	19	SENT_17	[p1l849t1498r1063b1535],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l849t1498r1063b1535],

1	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nsubj	4	SENT_18	[p1l1081t1499r1188b1527],
2	was	VBD	O	be	cop	4	SENT_18	[p1l1205t1506r1271b1527],
3	highly	RB	O	highly	advmod	4	SENT_18	[p1l1290t1498r1396b1535],
4	sensitive	JJ	O	sensitive	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1414t1498r1565b1527],
5	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1582t1502r1617b1527],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_18	[p1l1634t1498r1690b1527],
7	antiviral	JJ	O	antiviral	amod	8	SENT_18	[p1l1708t1498r1849b1527],
8	activity	NN	O	activity	prep_to	4	SENT_18	[p1l1868t1498r1994b1535],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l2011t1497r2047b1527],
10	type	NN	O	type	prep_of	8	SENT_18	[p1l2063t1502r2139b1535],
11	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	10	SENT_18	[p1l2158t1499r2165b1526],
12	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l2184t1498r2247b1527],
13	II	CD	NUMBER	ii	num	14	SENT_18	[p1l2268t1499r2286b1526],
14	interferons	NNS	O	interferon	prep_of	8	SENT_18	[p1l189t1543r388b1573],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l189t1543r388b1573],

1	These	DT	O	these	det	2	SENT_19	[p1l401t1544r502b1573],
2	results	NNS	O	result	nsubj	3	SENT_19	[p1l517t1544r630b1573],
3	provide	VBP	O	provide	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l645t1544r775b1580],
4	a	DT	O	a	det	6	SENT_19	[p1l790t1552r807b1573],
5	general	JJ	O	general	amod	6	SENT_19	[p1l822t1544r951b1580],
6	insight	NN	O	insight	dobj	3	SENT_19	[p1l966t1544r1083b1580],
7	into	IN	O	into	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1098t1544r1164b1573],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_19	[p1l1178t1544r1233b1573],
9	interaction	NN	O	interaction	prep_into	3	SENT_19	[p1l1248t1544r1433b1573],
10	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1449t1544r1596b1573],
11	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	prep_between	9	SENT_19	[p1l1611t1545r1719b1573],
12	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1732t1544r1795b1573],
13	its	PRP$	O	its	poss	15	SENT_19	[p1l1811t1544r1850b1573],
14	mammalian	JJ	O	mammalian	amod	15	SENT_19	[p1l1864t1544r2067b1573],
15	host	NN	O	host	conj_and	11	SENT_19	[p1l2082t1544r2165b1573],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l2082t1544r2165b1573],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l188t1622r288b1642],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l188t1622r288b1642],
3	Sourisseau	NNP	O	Sourisseau	nn	4	SENT_20	[p1l299t1622r425b1642],
4	M	NNP	O	M	dep	1	SENT_20	[p1l437t1622r464b1646],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l437t1622r464b1646],
6	Schilte	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Schilte	nn	7	SENT_20	[p1l475t1621r553b1642],
7	C	NNP	ORGANIZATION	C	appos	4	SENT_20	[p1l563t1622r584b1646],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l563t1622r584b1646],
9	Casartelli	NNP	PERSON	Casartelli	nn	10	SENT_20	[p1l595t1621r702b1642],
10	N	NNP	O	N	appos	4	SENT_20	[p1l714t1622r736b1646],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l714t1622r736b1646],
12	Trouillet	NNP	O	Trouillet	nn	13	SENT_20	[p1l746t1621r845b1642],
13	C	NNP	O	C	appos	4	SENT_20	[p1l855t1622r876b1646],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l855t1622r876b1646],
15	Guive	NNP	O	Guive	nn	16	SENT_20	[p1l886t1621r1107b1642],
16	|	NNP	O	|	appos	4	SENT_20	[p1l886t1621r1107b1642],
17	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l886t1621r1107b1642],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l886t1621r1107b1642],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l886t1621r1107b1642],

1	Benhassine	NNP	O	Benhassine	nn	2	SENT_22	[p1l886t1621r1107b1642],
2	F	NN	O	f	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1118t1622r1135b1646],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1118t1622r1135b1646],
4	et	FW	O	et	nn	6	SENT_22	[p1l1145t1625r1168b1642],
5	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	6	SENT_22	[p1l1178t1621r1203b1642],
6	(	FW	O	(	dep	2	SENT_22	[p1l1213t1622r1286b1646],
7	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	9	SENT_22	[p1l1213t1622r1286b1646],
8	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	9	SENT_22	[p1l1213t1622r1286b1646],
9	Characterization	NN	O	characterization	dep	6	SENT_22	[p1l1297t1621r1492b1642],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1504t1621r1529b1642],
11	reemerging	VBG	O	reemerge	amod	13	SENT_22	[p1l1538t1622r1676b1648],
12	chikungunya	NN	O	chikungunya	nn	13	SENT_22	[p1l1687t1621r1842b1648],
13	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	9	SENT_22	[p1l1853t1622r1915b1642],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1853t1622r1915b1642],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_23	[p1l1926t1622r1982b1642],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l1994t1621r2077b1648],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	4	SENT_23	[p1l2089t1622r2139b1646],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_23	[p1l2089t1622r2139b1646],
5	6	CD	NUMBER	6	num	6	SENT_23	[p1l2089t1622r2139b1646],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_23	[p1l2089t1622r2139b1646],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l2089t1622r2139b1646],
8	e89	NN	O	e89	dep	2	SENT_23	[p1l2149t1623r2197b1642],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l2149t1623r2197b1642],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	nn	2	SENT_24	[p1l2207t1621r2286b1642],
2	:10	FW	O	:10	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l2207t1621r2286b1642],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l2207t1621r2286b1642],

1	1371	CD	DATE	1371	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l191t1656r241b1675],
2	/	:	O	/	punct	1	SENT_25	[p1l247t1654r514b1681],
3	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	4	SENT_25	[p1l247t1654r514b1681],
4	|	NN	O	|	dep	1	SENT_25	[p1l247t1654r514b1681],
5	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l247t1654r514b1681],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l247t1654r514b1681],
2	.0030089	CD	NUMBER	.0030089	num	1	SENT_26	[p1l247t1654r514b1681],

1	Introduction	NN	O	introduction	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l190t1773r429b1805],
2	lethal	JJ	O	lethal	amod	3	SENT_27	[p1l1277t1758r1366b1784],
3	hepatitis	NN	O	hepatitis	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l1393t1758r1534b1793],
4	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1562t1758r1621b1784],
5	encephalitis	NN	O	encephalitis	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l1648t1758r1843b1793],
6	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1872t1759r1902b1783],
7	adults	NNS	O	adult	prep_in	3	SENT_27	[p1l1930t1758r2025b1784],
8	(	RB	O	(	advmod	12	SENT_27	[p1l2054t1758r2149b1790],
9	often	RB	O	often	advmod	12	SENT_27	[p1l2054t1758r2149b1790],
10	elderly	JJ	O	elderly	amod	12	SENT_27	[p1l2177t1758r2287b1793],
11	persons	NNS	O	person	nn	12	SENT_27	[p1l1277t1807r1418b1841],
12	)	NN	O	)	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l1277t1807r1418b1841],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1447t1806r1508b1832],
14	newborns	NNS	O	newborn	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l1537t1806r1709b1837],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1537t1806r1709b1837],
16	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1739t1806r1799b1832],
17	fetal	JJ	O	fetal	amod	18	SENT_27	[p1l1828t1806r1901b1832],
18	transmission	NN	O	transmission	conj_and	12	SENT_27	[p1l1932t1807r2146b1832],
19	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l2175t1806r2287b1841],
20	Chi1	NN	O	chi1	prep_during	18	SENT_27	[p1l227t1850r743b1885],
21	<	JJR	O	<	amod	22	SENT_27	[p1l227t1850r743b1885],
22	ungunyaVirus	NN	O	ungunyavirus	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l227t1850r743b1885],
23	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	25	SENT_27	[p1l227t1850r743b1885],
24	CH1KV	NN	O	ch1kv	nn	25	SENT_27	[p1l227t1850r743b1885],
25	)	NN	O	)	dep	22	SENT_27	[p1l227t1850r743b1885],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l227t1850r743b1885],

1	an	DT	O	a	det	2	SENT_28	[p1l227t1850r743b1885],
2	211phaVir11S	NN	O	211phavir11	nsubj	3	SENT_28	[p1l754t1850r922b1885],
3	belonging	VBG	O	belong	dep	17	SENT_28	[p1l933t1850r1095b1885],
4	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1107t1856r1137b1876],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_28	[p1l1150t1850r1199b1876],
6	pregnancy	NN	O	pregnancy	prep_to	3	SENT_28	[p1l1277t1863r1447b1889],
7	leading	VBG	O	lead	partmod	6	SENT_28	[p1l1465t1854r1585b1889],
8	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1603t1859r1633b1880],
9	neonatal	JJ	O	neonatal	amod	10	SENT_28	[p1l1653t1854r1794b1880],
10	encephalopathy	NN	O	encephalopathy	prep_to	7	SENT_28	[p1l1813t1854r2073b1889],
11	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l2092t1863r2127b1880],
12	abortion	NN	O	abortion	nn	14	SENT_28	[p1l2145t1854r2286b1880],
13	Togaviridae	NN	O	togavirida	nn	14	SENT_28	[p1l189t1896r383b1931],
14	family	NN	O	family	prep_to	7	SENT_28	[p1l396t1896r503b1931],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l396t1896r503b1931],
16	was	VBD	O	be	cop	17	SENT_28	[p1l516t1905r571b1922],
17	ﬁrst	JJ	O	ﬁrst	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l584t1896r647b1922],
18	isolated	VBN	O	isolate	ccomp	17	SENT_28	[p1l660t1896r785b1922],
19	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l797t1896r877b1922],
20	a	DT	O	a	det	22	SENT_28	[p1l889t1905r905b1922],
21	febrile	JJ	O	febrile	amod	22	SENT_28	[p1l917t1896r1022b1922],
22	individual	NN	O	individual	prep_from	18	SENT_28	[p1l1035t1896r1199b1922],
23	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l190t1942r220b1966],
24	Tanzania	NNP	LOCATION	Tanzania	prep_in	22	SENT_28	[p1l232t1942r381b1967],
25	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l393t1942r424b1966],
26	1952	CD	DATE	1952	num	27	SENT_28	[p1l439t1941r510b1968],
27	[	CD	NUMBER	[	prep_in	17	SENT_28	[p1l525t1941r598b1973],
28	1,2	CD	NUMBER	1,2	num	29	SENT_28	[p1l525t1941r598b1973],
29	]	NN	O	]	nsubj	17	SENT_28	[p1l525t1941r598b1973],
30	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l525t1941r598b1973],

1	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nsubjpass	3	SENT_29	[p1l612t1941r731b1967],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	3	SENT_29	[p1l744t1942r765b1967],
3	transmitted	VBN	O	transmit	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l779t1941r968b1967],
4	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l981t1946r1011b1967],
5	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_to	3	SENT_29	[p1l1024t1941r1150b1967],
6	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1163t1941r1199b1976],
7	several	JJ	O	several	amod	8	SENT_29	[p1l189t1987r300b2013],
8	species	NNS	O	species	agent	3	SENT_29	[p1l328t1988r442b2022],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l470t1987r505b2013],
10	mosquitoes	NNS	O	mosquito	prep_of	8	SENT_29	[p1l529t1988r724b2022],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l529t1988r724b2022],
12	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l751t1987r821b2013],
13	Aedes	NNS	MISC	aede	nn	14	SENT_29	[p1l846t1987r928b2013],
14	aegypti	NNS	O	aegyptus	nsubj	22	SENT_29	[p1l954t1988r1056b2022],
15	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1083t1987r1142b2013],
16	A.	NN	O	a.	nn	17	SENT_29	[p1l1167t1988r1198b2012],
17	albopictus	NN	O	albopictus	nsubj	22	SENT_29	[p1l188t2033r331b2068],
18	being	VBG	O	be	cop	22	SENT_29	[p1l342t2033r433b2068],
19	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_29	[p1l445t2033r494b2059],
20	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	22	SENT_29	[p1l507t2038r562b2059],
21	main	JJ	O	main	amod	22	SENT_29	[p1l575t2034r656b2059],
22	vectors	NNS	O	vector	prepc_with	3	SENT_29	[p1l667t2038r790b2059],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l667t2038r790b2059],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_30	[p1l802t2033r865b2059],
2	symptoms	NNS	O	symptom	nsubj	4	SENT_30	[p1l877t2038r1039b2068],
3	generally	RB	O	generally	advmod	4	SENT_30	[p1l1051t2033r1199b2068],
4	start	VBP	O	start	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l189t2083r262b2104],
5	4-7	CD	NUMBER	4-7	num	6	SENT_30	[p1l276t2075r332b2103],
6	d	NN	O	d	dobj	4	SENT_30	[p1l347t2078r366b2104],
7	after	IN	O	after	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l382t2078r459b2104],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_30	[p1l474t2078r523b2104],
9	bite	NN	O	bite	prep_after	4	SENT_30	[p1l538t2078r607b2104],
10	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l538t2078r607b2104],

1	Acute	JJ	O	acute	amod	2	SENT_31	[p1l622t2078r717b2104],
2	infection	NN	O	infection	nsubjpass	8	SENT_31	[p1l733t2078r879b2104],
3	lasts	VBZ	O	last	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l894t2078r962b2104],
4	1-10	CD	NUMBER	1-10	num	5	SENT_31	[p1l980t2078r1052b2103],
5	d	NN	O	d	dobj	3	SENT_31	[p1l1068t2078r1087b2104],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1102t2078r1161b2104],
7	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	8	SENT_31	[p1l1177t2079r1198b2104],
8	characterized	VBN	O	characterize	conj_and	3	SENT_31	[p1l189t2124r409b2150],
9	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l421t2124r457b2159],
10	a	DT	O	a	det	12	SENT_31	[p1l469t2133r485b2150],
11	painful	JJ	O	painful	amod	12	SENT_31	[p1l496t2124r612b2159],
12	polyarthralgia	NN	O	polyarthralgium	agent	8	SENT_31	[p1l624t2124r861b2159],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l624t2124r861b2159],
14	high	JJ	O	high	amod	15	SENT_31	[p1l873t2124r944b2159],
15	fever	NN	O	fever	conj_and	12	SENT_31	[p1l955t2124r1044b2155],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l955t2124r1044b2155],
17	asthenia	NN	O	asthenia	conj_and	12	SENT_31	[p1l1056t2124r1198b2155],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1056t2124r1198b2155],
19	headache	NN	O	headache	conj_and	12	SENT_31	[p1l189t2170r349b2201],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l189t2170r349b2201],
21	vomiting	VBG	O	vomit	conj_and	12	SENT_31	[p1l367t2171r520b2205],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l367t2171r520b2205],
23	rash	NN	O	rash	appos	21	SENT_31	[p1l539t2170r613b2201],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l539t2170r613b2201],
25	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l632t2170r691b2196],
26	myalgia	NN	O	myalgium	nn	27	SENT_31	[p1l709t2170r833b2205],
27	[	NN	O	[	conj_and	12	SENT_31	[p1l853t2170r937b2202],
28	2	CD	NUMBER	2	number	29	SENT_31	[p1l853t2170r937b2202],
29	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	27	SENT_31	[p1l853t2170r937b2202],
30	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	31	SENT_31	[p1l853t2170r937b2202],
31	]	NN	O	]	dep	29	SENT_31	[p1l853t2170r937b2202],
32	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l853t2170r937b2202],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l955t2171r988b2195],
2	Swahili	NNS	O	swahilus	prep_in	9	SENT_32	[p1l1006t2170r1130b2201],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l1006t2170r1130b2201],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_32	[p1l1150t2170r1199b2196],
5	term	NN	O	term	nn	8	SENT_32	[p1l190t2221r266b2242],
6	“	NN	O	“	nn	8	SENT_32	[p1l289t2215r533b2251],
7	chikungunya	NN	O	chikungunya	nn	8	SENT_32	[p1l289t2215r533b2251],
8	”	NN	O	”	nsubj	9	SENT_32	[p1l289t2215r533b2251],
9	means	VBZ	O	mean	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l558t2225r659b2242],
10	“	IN	O	“	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l683t2215r751b2242],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_32	[p1l683t2215r751b2242],
12	bent	JJ	O	bent	amod	14	SENT_32	[p1l774t2216r846b2242],
13	walker	NN	O	walker	nn	14	SENT_32	[p1l868t2215r1001b2242],
14	”	NN	O	”	prep_“	9	SENT_32	[p1l868t2215r1001b2242],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l868t2215r1001b2242],

1	Indeed	RB	O	indeed	advmod	12	SENT_33	[p1l1024t2216r1145b2247],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1024t2216r1145b2247],
3	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l1169t2217r1199b2241],
4	numerous	JJ	O	numerous	amod	5	SENT_33	[p1l190t2270r352b2287],
5	patients	NNS	O	patient	prep_in	12	SENT_33	[p1l372t2262r510b2296],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l372t2262r510b2296],
7	a	DT	O	a	det	11	SENT_33	[p1l530t2270r546b2287],
8	chronic	JJ	O	chronic	amod	11	SENT_33	[p1l565t2261r688b2287],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l709t2261r768b2287],
10	incapacitating	JJ	O	incapacitating	amod	11	SENT_33	[p1l788t2262r1021b2296],
11	arthralgia	NN	O	arthralgium	nsubj	12	SENT_33	[p1l1040t2261r1199b2296],
12	persists	VBZ	O	persist	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l189t2308r309b2342],
13	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l331t2307r380b2333],
14	months	NNS	DURATION	month	prep_for	12	SENT_33	[p1l401t2307r529b2333],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l401t2307r529b2333],

1	During	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l552t2308r668b2342],
2	the	DT	DURATION	the	det	5	SENT_34	[p1l689t2307r739b2333],
3	last	JJ	DATE	last	amod	5	SENT_34	[p1l761t2307r815b2333],
4	50	CD	DATE	50	num	5	SENT_34	[p1l837t2307r872b2332],
5	years	NNS	DATE	year	prep_during	9	SENT_34	[p1l893t2316r984b2342],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l893t2316r984b2342],
7	CHIKV	NNP	O	CHIKV	nsubj	9	SENT_34	[p1l1007t2307r1127b2333],
8	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	9	SENT_34	[p1l1147t2307r1199b2333],
9	caused	VBN	O	cause	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l189t2353r297b2379],
10	a	DT	O	a	det	11	SENT_34	[p1l309t2362r325b2379],
11	number	NN	O	number	dobj	9	SENT_34	[p1l337t2353r465b2379],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l476t2353r510b2379],
13	outbreaks	NNS	O	outbreak	prep_of	11	SENT_34	[p1l518t2353r678b2379],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l691t2354r721b2378],
15	East	NNP	O	East	nn	18	SENT_34	[p1l732t2354r798b2379],
16	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l809t2353r868b2379],
17	South	NNP	LOCATION	South	nn	18	SENT_34	[p1l880t2353r974b2379],
18	Africa	NNP	LOCATION	Africa	prep_in	13	SENT_34	[p1l985t2353r1086b2379],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1098t2353r1156b2379],
20	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1168t2354r1199b2378],
21	Southeast	NNP	LOCATION	Southeast	nn	22	SENT_34	[p1l189t2399r348b2425],
22	Asia	NNP	LOCATION	Asia	prep_in	13	SENT_34	[p1l363t2400r433b2425],
23	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	24	SENT_34	[p1l451t2399r496b2431],
24	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	25	SENT_34	[p1l451t2399r496b2431],
25	]	NN	O	]	dep	13	SENT_34	[p1l451t2399r496b2431],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l451t2399r496b2431],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_35	[p1l513t2399r576b2425],
2	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	3	SENT_35	[p1l593t2405r671b2425],
3	recent	JJ	O	recent	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l688t2404r791b2425],
4	epidemic	JJ	O	epidemic	amod	5	SENT_35	[p1l807t2399r956b2434],
5	reemergences	NNS	O	reemergence	nsubjpass	7	SENT_35	[p1l974t2408r1198b2434],
6	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	7	SENT_35	[p1l188t2453r265b2470],
7	documented	VBN	O	document	rcmod	3	SENT_35	[p1l290t2444r493b2470],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l519t2445r549b2469],
9	Kinshasa	NNP	LOCATION	Kinshasa	prep_in	7	SENT_35	[p1l574t2444r718b2470],
10	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	9	SENT_35	[p1l743t2444r856b2476],
11	50,000	CD	NUMBER	50,000	num	13	SENT_35	[p1l743t2444r856b2476],
12	estimated	VBN	O	estimate	amod	13	SENT_35	[p1l881t2444r1039b2470],
13	cases	NNS	O	case	dobj	7	SENT_35	[p1l1064t2453r1143b2470],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1168t2445r1199b2469],
15	1999-2000	CD	DATE	1999-2000	num	16	SENT_35	[p1l192t2490r372b2522],
16	)	CD	NUMBER	)	prep_in	13	SENT_35	[p1l192t2490r372b2522],
17	[	NN	O	[	dep	25	SENT_35	[p1l391t2490r437b2522],
18	6	CD	NUMBER	6	num	19	SENT_35	[p1l391t2490r437b2522],
19	]	NN	O	]	dep	17	SENT_35	[p1l391t2490r437b2522],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l391t2490r437b2522],
21	Indonesia	NNP	LOCATION	Indonesia	appos	19	SENT_35	[p1l453t2490r614b2516],
22	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	21	SENT_35	[p1l631t2490r824b2522],
23	2001-2003	CD	DATE	2001-2003	dep	25	SENT_35	[p1l631t2490r824b2522],
24	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	25	SENT_35	[p1l631t2490r824b2522],
25	[	NN	O	[	dep	66	SENT_35	[p1l843t2488r888b2522],
26	7	CD	NUMBER	7	num	27	SENT_35	[p1l843t2488r888b2522],
27	]	NN	O	]	dep	25	SENT_35	[p1l843t2488r888b2522],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l843t2488r888b2522],
29	the	DT	O	the	det	32	SENT_35	[p1l907t2490r956b2516],
30	Indian	NNP	LOCATION	Indian	nn	32	SENT_35	[p1l972t2490r1078b2516],
31	Ocean	NNP	LOCATION	Ocean	nn	32	SENT_35	[p1l1095t2490r1199b2516],
32	islands	NNS	O	island	dep	53	SENT_35	[p1l190t2536r298b2562],
33	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l319t2536r354b2562],
34	Mayotte	NNP	PERSON	Mayotte	nn	38	SENT_35	[p1l371t2537r510b2571],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l371t2537r510b2571],
36	Mauritius	NNP	LOCATION	Mauritius	appos	38	SENT_35	[p1l531t2537r695b2567],
37	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l531t2537r695b2567],
38	Reunion	NNP	O	Reunion	prep_of	32	SENT_35	[p1l716t2536r863b2567],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l716t2536r863b2567],
40	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l885t2536r944b2562],
41	the	DT	O	the	det	43	SENT_35	[p1l965t2536r1014b2562],
42	Seychelles	NNP	LOCATION	Seychelles	nn	43	SENT_35	[p1l1035t2536r1198b2571],
43	(	NN	O	(	dep	53	SENT_35	[p1l190t2579r322b2613],
44	270,000	CD	NUMBER	270,000	num	45	SENT_35	[p1l190t2579r322b2613],
45	cases	NNS	O	case	dep	43	SENT_35	[p1l341t2590r420b2607],
46	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l439t2582r469b2606],
47	2005-2006	CD	DATE	2005-2006	prep_in	45	SENT_35	[p1l488t2581r659b2608],
48	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l677t2582r708b2606],
49	La	NNP	O	La	nn	50	SENT_35	[p1l725t2582r765b2607],
50	Reunion	NNP	O	Reunion	prep_in	45	SENT_35	[p1l782t2581r921b2607],
51	island	NN	O	island	dep	53	SENT_35	[p1l939t2581r1044b2613],
52	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	51	SENT_35	[p1l939t2581r1044b2613],
53	[	NN	O	[	dep	66	SENT_35	[p1l1065t2581r1121b2613],
54	5	CD	NUMBER	5	number	55	SENT_35	[p1l1065t2581r1121b2613],
55	]	CD	NUMBER	]	num	56	SENT_35	[p1l1065t2581r1121b2613],
56	)	NN	O	)	dep	53	SENT_35	[p1l1065t2581r1121b2613],
57	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1065t2581r1121b2613],
58	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1140t2581r1199b2607],
59	India	NNP	LOCATION	India	conj_and	56	SENT_35	[p1l189t2627r273b2653],
60	(	CD	NUMBER	(	number	64	SENT_35	[p1l287t2628r343b2659],
61	1.4	CD	NUMBER	1.4	number	64	SENT_35	[p1l287t2628r343b2659],
62	to	TO	O	to	dep	64	SENT_35	[p1l357t2632r387b2653],
63	6.5	CD	NUMBER	6.5	number	64	SENT_35	[p1l401t2627r446b2653],
64	million	CD	NUMBER	million	dep	59	SENT_35	[p1l459t2627r575b2653],
65	estimated	VBN	O	estimate	amod	66	SENT_35	[p1l588t2627r745b2653],
66	cases	NNS	O	case	dep	3	SENT_35	[p1l759t2636r838b2653],
67	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l852t2628r882b2652],
68	2006-2007	CD	DATE	2006-2007	num	70	SENT_35	[p1l896t2624r1079b2659],
69	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	70	SENT_35	[p1l896t2624r1079b2659],
70	[	NN	O	[	prep_in	66	SENT_35	[p1l1095t2627r1198b2659],
71	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	72	SENT_35	[p1l1095t2627r1198b2659],
72	—	NN	O	—	dep	70	SENT_35	[p1l1095t2627r1198b2659],
73	10	CD	NUMBER	10	num	74	SENT_35	[p1l1095t2627r1198b2659],
74	]	NN	O	]	dep	72	SENT_35	[p1l1095t2627r1198b2659],
75	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1095t2627r1198b2659],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_36	[p1l226t2673r288b2699],
2	magnitude	NN	O	magnitude	nsubj	13	SENT_36	[p1l316t2673r489b2708],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l516t2673r551b2699],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_36	[p1l575t2673r624b2699],
5	recent	JJ	O	recent	amod	7	SENT_36	[p1l651t2679r754b2699],
6	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nn	7	SENT_36	[p1l780t2673r900b2699],
7	intrusion	NN	O	intrusion	prep_of	2	SENT_36	[p1l927t2674r1076b2699],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1103t2674r1134b2698],
9	La	NNP	O	La	nn	11	SENT_36	[p1l1160t2674r1199b2699],
10	Reunion	NNP	O	Reunion	nn	11	SENT_36	[p1l189t2719r328b2745],
11	island	NN	O	island	prep_in	7	SENT_36	[p1l350t2719r445b2745],
12	was	VBD	O	be	cop	13	SENT_36	[p1l466t2728r522b2745],
13	unexpected	JJ	O	unexpected	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l544t2719r742b2754],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l544t2719r742b2754],
15	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l764t2719r833b2745],
16	40	CD	PERCENT	40	num	17	SENT_36	[p1l856t2719r924b2748],
17	%	NN	PERCENT	%	prep_with	13	SENT_36	[p1l856t2719r924b2748],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l950t2719r985b2745],
19	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_36	[p1l1005t2719r1054b2745],
20	785,000	CD	NUMBER	785,000	num	21	SENT_36	[p1l1077t2717r1198b2750],
21	inhabitants	NNS	O	inhabitant	prep_of	17	SENT_36	[p1l190t2765r372b2791],
22	being	VBG	O	be	auxpass	23	SENT_36	[p1l392t2765r482b2800],
23	infected	VBN	O	infect	partmod	21	SENT_36	[p1l501t2765r633b2791],
24	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l653t2766r683b2790],
25	2005-2006	CD	DATE	2005-2006	prep_in	23	SENT_36	[p1l703t2765r882b2792],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l703t2765r882b2792],

1	This	DT	O	this	nsubj	5	SENT_37	[p1l903t2765r972b2791],
2	was	VBD	O	be	cop	5	SENT_37	[p1l991t2774r1046b2791],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_37	[p1l1067t2765r1116b2791],
4	ﬁrst	JJ	O	ﬁrst	amod	5	SENT_37	[p1l1136t2765r1199b2791],
5	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l189t2810r309b2836],
6	epidemic	JJ	O	epidemic	amod	5	SENT_37	[p1l323t2810r471b2845],
7	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l486t2811r517b2835],
8	a	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_37	[p1l531t2819r547b2836],
9	country	NN	O	country	prep_in	6	SENT_37	[p1l560t2815r687b2845],
10	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l699t2810r769b2836],
11	an	DT	O	a	det	15	SENT_37	[p1l783t2819r821b2836],
12	occidental	JJ	O	occidental	amod	15	SENT_37	[p1l835t2810r1003b2836],
13	health	NN	O	health	nn	15	SENT_37	[p1l1017t2810r1117b2836],
14	care	NN	O	care	nn	15	SENT_37	[p1l1132t2819r1199b2836],
15	environment	NN	O	environment	prep_with	9	SENT_37	[p1l189t2857r408b2882],
16	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l189t2857r408b2882],

1	Severe	JJ	O	severe	amod	2	SENT_38	[p1l422t2856r527b2882],
2	forms	NNS	O	form	nsubjpass	7	SENT_38	[p1l540t2856r633b2882],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l645t2856r680b2882],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_38	[p1l690t2856r739b2882],
5	disease	NN	O	disease	prep_of	2	SENT_38	[p1l752t2856r864b2882],
6	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	7	SENT_38	[p1l876t2865r953b2882],
7	reported	VBN	O	report	dep	14	SENT_38	[p1l966t2856r1117b2891],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l966t2856r1117b2891],
9	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1129t2856r1199b2882],
10	about	RB	O	about	quantmod	11	SENT_38	[p1l189t2902r282b2928],
11	250	CD	NUMBER	250	num	13	SENT_38	[p1l298t2902r352b2929],
12	fatal	JJ	O	fatal	amod	13	SENT_38	[p1l369t2902r439b2928],
13	cases	NNS	O	case	prep_with	7	SENT_38	[p1l456t2911r535b2928],
14	(	VBP	O	(	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l552t2902r802b2937],
15	corresponding	VBG	O	correspond	xcomp	14	SENT_38	[p1l552t2902r802b2937],
16	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l818t2907r848b2928],
17	one	CD	NUMBER	one	num	18	SENT_38	[p1l865t2911r923b2928],
18	death	NN	O	death	prep_to	15	SENT_38	[p1l940t2902r1029b2928],
19	per	IN	O	per	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l1046t2911r1100b2937],
20	1,000	CD	NUMBER	1,000	num	21	SENT_38	[p1l1118t2902r1198b2933],
21	infections	NNS	O	infection	prep_per	18	SENT_38	[p1l190t2948r361b2980],
22	)	CD	NUMBER	)	number	23	SENT_38	[p1l190t2948r361b2980],
23	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	21	SENT_38	[p1l390t2948r454b2980],
24	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	25	SENT_38	[p1l390t2948r454b2980],
25	]	NN	O	]	nsubj	14	SENT_38	[p1l390t2948r454b2980],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l390t2948r454b2980],

1	Clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	2	SENT_39	[p1l482t2948r606b2974],
2	cases	NNS	O	case	nsubj	10	SENT_39	[p1l632t2957r719b2979],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l632t2957r719b2979],
4	rarely	RB	O	rarely	advmod	7	SENT_39	[p1l747t2948r840b2983],
5	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l866t2957r902b2974],
6	never	RB	O	never	advmod	7	SENT_39	[p1l927t2957r1017b2974],
7	described	VBN	O	describe	partmod	2	SENT_39	[p1l1042t2948r1199b2974],
8	before	IN	O	before	prep	7	SENT_39	[p1l189t2993r302b3024],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l189t2993r302b3024],
10	include	VBP	O	include	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l321t2993r440b3019],
11	lymphopenia	NN	O	lymphopenia	dobj	10	SENT_39	[p1l459t2993r681b3028],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l459t2993r681b3028],
13	severe	JJ	O	severe	amod	15	SENT_39	[p1l700t3002r800b3019],
14	dermatological	JJ	O	dermatological	amod	15	SENT_39	[p1l818t2993r1063b3028],
15	lesions	NNS	O	lesion	appos	11	SENT_39	[p1l1081t2993r1198b3024],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l1081t2993r1198b3024],
17	)	IN	O	)	amod	11	SENT_39	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	2	SENT_40	[p1l288t3093r352b3116],
2	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l367t3092r511b3123],
3	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	4	SENT_40	[p1l526t3091r528b3124],
4	www	NN	O	www	dobj	2	SENT_40	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
5	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_41	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	dep	1	SENT_41	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	[	NN	O	[	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l1279t1902r1371b1934],
2	41,12	CD	NUMBER	41,12	num	3	SENT_42	[p1l1279t1902r1371b1934],
3	]	NN	O	]	dep	1	SENT_42	[p1l1279t1902r1371b1934],
4	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l1279t1902r1371b1934],

1	Many	JJ	O	many	amod	2	SENT_43	[p1l1398t1903r1486b1937],
2	factors	NNS	O	factor	nsubj	4	SENT_43	[p1l1511t1902r1621b1928],
3	may	MD	O	may	aux	4	SENT_43	[p1l1647t1911r1712b1937],
4	explain	VB	O	explain	_	0	SENT_43	[p1l1737t1902r1856b1937],
5	why	WRB	O	why	advmod	9	SENT_43	[p1l1881t1902r1944b1937],
6	this	DT	O	this	det	7	SENT_43	[p1l1971t1902r2027b1928],
7	virus	NN	O	virus	nsubj	9	SENT_43	[p1l2052t1903r2129b1928],
8	recently	RB	DATE	recently	advmod	9	SENT_43	[p1l2156t1902r2287b1937],
9	spread	VBN	O	spread	advcl	4	SENT_43	[p1l1277t1950r1384b1985],
10	so	RB	O	so	advmod	11	SENT_43	[p1l1403t1959r1434b1976],
11	efficiently	RB	O	efficiently	advmod	9	SENT_43	[p1l1454t1950r1622b1985],
12	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_43	[p1l1454t1950r1622b1985],

1	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nsubj	3	SENT_44	[p1l1642t1950r1762b1976],
2	probably	RB	O	probably	advmod	3	SENT_44	[p1l1780t1950r1925b1985],
3	reached	VBD	O	reach	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1944t1950r2072b1976],
4	La	NNP	O	La	nn	5	SENT_44	[p1l2090t1951r2130b1976],
5	Reunion	NNP	O	Reunion	dobj	3	SENT_44	[p1l2147t1950r2286b1976],
6	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1277t1998r1325b2024],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_44	[p1l1342t1998r1391b2024],
8	first	JJ	ORDINAL	first	amod	9	SENT_44	[p1l1408t1998r1472b2024],
9	time	NN	O	time	prep_for	5	SENT_44	[p1l1489t1999r1568b2029],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1489t1999r1568b2029],
11	encountering	VBG	O	encounter	partmod	3	SENT_44	[p1l1586t1999r1806b2033],
12	a	DT	O	a	det	16	SENT_44	[p1l1823t2007r1839b2024],
13	nonimmune	JJ	O	nonimmune	amod	16	SENT_44	[p1l1856t1999r2055b2024],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l2073t1998r2132b2024],
15	sensitive	JJ	O	sensitive	amod	16	SENT_44	[p1l2149t1999r2286b2024],
16	population	NN	O	population	dobj	11	SENT_44	[p1l1277t2046r1465b2081],
17	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1277t2046r1465b2081],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_45	[p1l1492t2046r1554b2072],
2	mosquitoes	NNS	O	mosquito	nsubj	3	SENT_45	[p1l1581t2047r1765b2081],
3	involved	VBN	O	involve	dep	23	SENT_45	[p1l1793t2046r1929b2072],
4	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1957t2047r1987b2071],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_45	[p1l2015t2046r2064b2072],
6	local	JJ	O	local	amod	7	SENT_45	[p1l2090t2046r2166b2072],
7	transmission	NN	O	transmission	prep_in	3	SENT_45	[p1l2193t2051r2286b2072, p1l1277t2095r1400b2120],
8	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	11	SENT_45	[p1l1416t2094r1453b2126],
9	A.	NN	O	a.	nn	11	SENT_45	[p1l1416t2094r1453b2126],
10	albopictm	NN	O	albopictm	nn	11	SENT_45	[p1l1469t2094r1622b2129],
11	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	23	SENT_45	[p1l1469t2094r1622b2129],
12	are	VBP	O	be	cop	23	SENT_45	[p1l1638t2103r1687b2120],
13	abundant	JJ	O	abundant	amod	23	SENT_45	[p1l1703t2094r1858b2120],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1874t2094r1933b2120],
15	likely	JJ	O	likely	amod	23	SENT_45	[p1l1948t2094r2033b2129],
16	present	JJ	DATE	present	amod	23	SENT_45	[p1l2049t2099r2170b2129],
17	a	DT	O	a	dep	18	SENT_45	[p1l2185t2103r2201b2120],
18	high	JJ	O	high	amod	23	SENT_45	[p1l2216t2094r2286b2129],
19	vectorial	JJ	O	vectorial	amod	23	SENT_45	[p1l1276t2142r1417b2168],
20	capacity	NN	O	capacity	nn	23	SENT_45	[p1l1434t2143r1567b2177],
21	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	22	SENT_45	[p1l1585t2142r1649b2174],
22	13	CD	NUMBER	13	num	23	SENT_45	[p1l1585t2142r1649b2174],
23	]	NN	O	]	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1585t2142r1649b2174],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1585t2142r1649b2174],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_46	[p1l1665t2142r1728b2168],
2	circulating	VBG	O	circulate	amod	4	SENT_46	[p1l1744t2142r1920b2177],
3	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nn	4	SENT_46	[p1l1935t2142r2055b2168],
4	strains	NNS	O	strain	nsubj	8	SENT_46	[p1l2070t2143r2176b2168],
5	might	MD	O	might	aux	8	SENT_46	[p1l2193t2142r2287b2177],
6	have	VB	O	have	aux	8	SENT_46	[p1l1276t2190r1349b2216],
7	also	RB	O	also	advmod	8	SENT_46	[p1l1378t2190r1438b2216],
8	acquired	VBN	O	acquire	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l1466t2190r1609b2225],
9	particular	JJ	O	particular	amod	11	SENT_46	[p1l1637t2190r1800b2225],
10	replication	NN	O	replication	nn	11	SENT_46	[p1l1827t2190r2006b2225],
11	properties	NNS	O	property	dobj	8	SENT_46	[p1l2034t2191r2212b2225],
12	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l2034t2191r2212b2225],

1	An	DT	O	a	det	4	SENT_47	[p1l2239t2190r2286b2215],
2	extensive	JJ	O	extensive	amod	4	SENT_47	[p1l1277t2239r1426b2264],
3	genome	NN	O	genome	nn	4	SENT_47	[p1l1449t2247r1577b2273],
4	analysis	NN	O	analysis	nsubj	14	SENT_47	[p1l1601t2238r1723b2273],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l1747t2238r1782b2264],
6	recent	JJ	O	recent	amod	8	SENT_47	[p1l1802t2243r1904b2264],
7	clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	8	SENT_47	[p1l1927t2238r2043b2264],
8	isolates	NNS	O	isolate	prep_of	4	SENT_47	[p1l2067t2238r2184b2264],
9	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l2207t2238r2287b2264],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_47	[p1l1278t2286r1327b2312],
11	Indian	NNP	LOCATION	Indian	nn	13	SENT_47	[p1l1354t2286r1461b2312],
12	Ocean	NNP	LOCATION	Ocean	nn	13	SENT_47	[p1l1489t2286r1594b2312],
13	outbreak	NN	O	outbreak	prep_from	8	SENT_47	[p1l1621t2286r1768b2312],
14	identiﬁed	VBD	O	identiﬁed	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l1796t2286r1954b2312],
15	unique	JJ	O	unique	amod	17	SENT_47	[p1l1981t2287r2095b2321],
16	molecular	JJ	O	molecular	amod	17	SENT_47	[p1l2123t2286r2287b2312],
17	features	NNS	O	feature	dobj	14	SENT_47	[p1l1277t2334r1406b2360],
18	when	WRB	O	when	advmod	29	SENT_47	[p1l1432t2334r1518b2360],
19	compared	VBN	O	compare	csubj	29	SENT_47	[p1l1545t2334r1708b2369],
20	to	TO	O	to	pcomp	19	SENT_47	[p1l1736t2339r1766b2360],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	25	SENT_47	[p1l1795t2334r1844b2360],
22	few	JJ	O	few	amod	25	SENT_47	[p1l1870t2334r1925b2360],
23	previously	RB	DATE	previously	advmod	24	SENT_47	[p1l1952t2334r2119b2369],
24	available	JJ	O	available	amod	25	SENT_47	[p1l2145t2334r2286b2360],
25	sequences	NNS	O	sequence	pobj	20	SENT_47	[p1l1277t2392r1439b2418],
26	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l1454t2383r1533b2409],
27	laboratory-adapted	JJ	O	laboratory-adapted	amod	28	SENT_47	[p1l1548t2383r1864b2418],
28	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_from	25	SENT_47	[p1l1879t2384r1989b2409],
29	[	VBP	O	[	advcl	14	SENT_47	[p1l2007t2383r2052b2415],
30	5	CD	NUMBER	5	number	31	SENT_47	[p1l2007t2383r2052b2415],
31	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	29	SENT_47	[p1l2007t2383r2052b2415],
32	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l2007t2383r2052b2415],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_48	[p1l2067t2384r2101b2408],
2	particular	JJ	O	particular	pobj	1	SENT_48	[p1l2116t2383r2286b2418],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_48	[p1l2116t2383r2286b2418],

1	Editor	NNP	O	Editor	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l1277t2500r1361b2521],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l1277t2500r1361b2521],
3	Michael	NNP	PERSON	Michael	nn	5	SENT_49	[p1l1378t2500r1469b2521],
4	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	5	SENT_49	[p1l1485t2501r1501b2521],
5	Buchmeier	NNP	PERSON	Buchmeier	dep	1	SENT_49	[p1l1519t2500r1652b2525],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l1519t2500r1652b2525],
7	The	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_49	[p1l1668t2500r1713b2521],
8	Scripps	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Scripps	nn	10	SENT_49	[p1l1730t2501r1815b2527],
9	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	nn	10	SENT_49	[p1l1834t2500r1939b2521],
10	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	appos	5	SENT_49	[p1l1957t2501r2061b2525],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l1957t2501r2061b2525],
12	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	13	SENT_49	[p1l2079t2500r2157b2521],
13	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	appos	5	SENT_49	[p1l2176t2501r2247b2521],
14	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l2264t2500r2289b2521],
15	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	13	SENT_49	[p1l1276t2534r1373b2554],

1	Received	VBN	O	receive	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l1277t2591r1391b2612],
2	February	NNP	DATE	February	nsubj	13	SENT_50	[p1l1404t2591r1509b2618],
3	9	CD	DATE	9	num	2	SENT_50	[p1l1521t2593r1539b2616],
4	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l1521t2593r1539b2616],
5	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	2	SENT_50	[p1l1551t2593r1615b2616],
6	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l1551t2593r1615b2616],
7	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	amod	2	SENT_50	[p1l1626t2591r1745b2618],
8	May	NNP	DATE	May	tmod	7	SENT_50	[p1l1758t2592r1807b2618],
9	14	CD	DATE	14	num	8	SENT_50	[p1l1820t2593r1852b2616],
10	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l1820t2593r1852b2616],
11	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	8	SENT_50	[p1l1863t2593r1927b2616],
12	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l1863t2593r1927b2616],
13	Published	VBN	O	publish	dep	1	SENT_50	[p1l1939t2591r2066b2612],
14	June	NNP	DATE	June	tmod	13	SENT_50	[p1l2077t2592r2133b2612],
15	29	CD	DATE	29	num	14	SENT_50	[p1l2145t2593r2178b2616],
16	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l2145t2593r2178b2616],
17	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	14	SENT_50	[p1l2191t2593r2248b2612],

1	Copyright	NN	O	copyright	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l1276t2650r1411b2677],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l1276t2650r1411b2677],
3	©	CD	NUMBER	©	num	4	SENT_51	[p1l1421t2651r1441b2672],
4	2007	CD	DATE	2007	dep	1	SENT_51	[p1l1451t2652r1508b2671],
5	Sourisseau	NNP	O	Sourisseau	dep	4	SENT_51	[p1l1517t2651r1644b2671],
6	et	FW	O	et	nn	7	SENT_51	[p1l1654t2654r1676b2671],
7	al.	FW	O	al.	dep	4	SENT_51	[p1l1685t2650r1710b2671],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l1685t2650r1710b2671],

1	Abbreviations	NNS	O	abbreviation	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1276t2807r1465b2828],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1276t2807r1465b2828],
3	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	dep	1	SENT_53	[p1l1474t2808r1553b2832],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1474t2808r1553b2832],
5	chikungunya	NN	O	chikungunya	nn	6	SENT_53	[p1l1563t2807r1718b2834],
6	virus	NN	O	virus	appos	3	SENT_53	[p1l1727t2808r1789b2832],
7	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1727t2808r1789b2832],
8	CPE	NNP	ORGANIZATION	CPE	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1798t2808r1849b2832],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1798t2808r1849b2832],
10	cytopathic	JJ	O	cytopathic	amod	11	SENT_53	[p1l1858t2807r1984b2834],
11	effect	NN	O	effect	appos	8	SENT_53	[p1l1994t2807r2067b2832],
12	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1994t2807r2067b2832],
13	DC	NN	ORGANIZATION	dc	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l2077t2808r2116b2832],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l2077t2808r2116b2832],
15	dendritic	JJ	O	dendritic	amod	16	SENT_53	[p1l2125t2807r2232b2828],
16	cell	NN	O	cell	appos	13	SENT_53	[p1l2241t2807r2287b2832],
17	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l2241t2807r2287b2832],
18	Dyn	NNP	O	Dyn	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2841r1353b2867],
19	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	20	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2841r1353b2867],
20	2	CD	NUMBER	2	dep	18	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2841r1353b2867],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2841r1353b2867],
22	dynamin-2	NN	O	dynamin-2	appos	18	SENT_53	[p1l1364t2840r1499b2867],
23	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1364t2840r1499b2867],
24	IFN	NN	ORGANIZATION	ifn	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1512t2841r1554b2865],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1512t2841r1554b2865],
26	interferon	NN	O	interferon	appos	24	SENT_53	[p1l1567t2840r1691b2865],
27	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1567t2840r1691b2865],
28	mAb	NN	O	mab	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1703t2840r1765b2865],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1703t2840r1765b2865],
30	monoclonal	JJ	O	monoclonal	amod	31	SENT_53	[p1l1778t2840r1919b2861],
31	antibody	NN	O	antibody	appos	28	SENT_53	[p1l1931t2840r2044b2867],
32	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1931t2840r2044b2867],
33	moi	FW	O	moi	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l2056t2841r2106b2865],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l2056t2841r2106b2865],
35	multiplicity	NN	O	multiplicity	appos	33	SENT_53	[p1l2119t2840r2253b2867],
36	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l2264t2840r2288b2861],
37	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_of	35	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2874r1388b2899],
38	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2874r1388b2899],
39	PBMC	NN	O	pbmc	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1402t2875r1476b2899],
40	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1402t2875r1476b2899],
41	peripheral	JJ	O	peripheral	amod	44	SENT_53	[p1l1490t2874r1611b2901],
42	blood	NN	O	blood	nn	44	SENT_53	[p1l1626t2874r1694b2895],
43	mononuclear	JJ	O	mononuclear	amod	44	SENT_53	[p1l1709t2874r1869b2895],
44	cell	NN	O	cell	appos	39	SENT_53	[p1l1882t2874r1927b2899],
45	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1882t2874r1927b2899],
46	pi	NN	O	pi	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1941t2875r1967b2901],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1941t2875r1967b2901],
48	post	NN	O	post	nn	50	SENT_53	[p1l1982t2874r2155b2901],
49	—	NN	O	—	nn	50	SENT_53	[p1l1982t2874r2155b2901],
50	infection	NN	O	infection	appos	46	SENT_53	[p1l1982t2874r2155b2901],
51	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1982t2874r2155b2901],
52	RRV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	RRV	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l2169t2875r2220b2899],
53	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l2169t2875r2220b2899],
54	Ross	NNP	LOCATION	Ross	nn	56	SENT_53	[p1l2234t2875r2286b2895],
55	River	NNP	LOCATION	River	nn	56	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2908r1335b2928],
56	virus	NN	O	virus	appos	52	SENT_53	[p1l1346t2908r1408b2932],
57	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1346t2908r1408b2932],
58	SD	NN	O	sd	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1420t2908r1457b2932],
59	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1420t2908r1457b2932],
60	standard	JJ	O	standard	amod	61	SENT_53	[p1l1470t2907r1574b2928],
61	deviation	NN	O	deviation	appos	58	SENT_53	[p1l1587t2907r1705b2932],
62	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1587t2907r1705b2932],
63	SFV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	SFV	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1717t2908r1766b2932],
64	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1717t2908r1766b2932],
65	Semliki	NNP	LOCATION	Semliki	nn	67	SENT_53	[p1l1778t2907r1862b2928],
66	Forest	NNP	LOCATION	Forest	nn	67	SENT_53	[p1l1876t2908r1948b2928],
67	virus	NN	O	virus	appos	63	SENT_53	[p1l1960t2908r2022b2932],
68	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1960t2908r2022b2932],
69	shRNA	NN	O	shrna	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l2034t2907r2118b2932],
70	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l2034t2907r2118b2932],
71	short	JJ	O	short	amod	73	SENT_53	[p1l2131t2907r2191b2928],
72	hairpin	NN	O	hairpin	nn	73	SENT_53	[p1l2204t2907r2285b2934],
73	RNA	NN	O	rna	appos	69	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2941r1333b2965],
74	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1277t2941r1333b2965],
75	SINV	NNP	O	SINV	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1345t2941r1405b2965],
76	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1345t2941r1405b2965],
77	Sindbis	NNP	O	Sindbis	nn	78	SENT_53	[p1l1417t2940r1503b2961],
78	virus	NN	O	virus	appos	75	SENT_53	[p1l1515t2941r1577b2965],
79	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1515t2941r1577b2965],
80	TC	NNP	O	TC	nn	82	SENT_53	[p1l1587t2941r1679b2965],
81	|	NNP	O	|	nn	82	SENT_53	[p1l1587t2941r1679b2965],
82	D50	NNP	O	D50	dep	3	SENT_53	[p1l1587t2941r1679b2965],
83	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1587t2941r1679b2965],
84	tissue	NN	O	tissue	nn	85	SENT_53	[p1l1691t2941r1759b2961],
85	culture	NN	O	culture	appos	82	SENT_53	[p1l1771t2940r1855b2961],
86	infectious	JJ	O	infectious	amod	87	SENT_53	[p1l1867t2940r1983b2961],
87	dose	NN	O	dose	dep	85	SENT_53	[p1l1995t2940r2051b2961],
88	50	CD	NUMBER	50	num	87	SENT_53	[p1l2063t2942r2091b2961],

1	E-mail	NN	O	e-mail	_	0	SENT_55	[p1l1907t2997r1985b3018],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_55	[p1l1907t2997r1985b3018],
3	schwartz@pasteur.fr	NN	O	schwartz@pasteur.fr	nn	4	SENT_55	[p1l1997t2997r2240b3024],
4	changes	NNS	O	change	nsubjpass	12	SENT_55	[p2l189t1440r316b1475],
5	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l331t1440r362b1465],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_55	[p2l376t1440r425b1466],
7	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	10	SENT_55	[p2l438t1440r510b1466],
8	envelope	NN	O	envelope	nn	10	SENT_55	[p2l524t1440r669b1475],
9	glycoprotein	NN	O	glycoprotein	nn	10	SENT_55	[p2l683t1440r890b1475],
10	E1	NN	O	e1	prep_in	4	SENT_55	[p2l902t1440r940b1465],
11	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	12	SENT_55	[p2l955t1449r1031b1466],
12	observed	VBN	O	observe	dep	1	SENT_55	[p2l1046t1440r1198b1471],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l1046t1440r1198b1471],
14	potentially	RB	O	potentially	advmod	15	SENT_55	[p2l189t1486r365b1521],
15	affecting	VBG	O	affect	ccomp	12	SENT_55	[p2l380t1486r523b1521],
16	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	17	SENT_55	[p2l536t1486r608b1512],
17	fusion	NN	O	fusion	dobj	15	SENT_55	[p2l623t1486r731b1517],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l623t1486r731b1517],
19	assembly	NN	O	assembly	appos	17	SENT_55	[p2l747t1486r898b1521],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l747t1486r898b1521],
21	andlor	NN	O	andlor	nn	22	SENT_55	[p2l914t1486r1019b1512],
22	tropism	NN	O	tropism	appos	19	SENT_55	[p2l1034t1486r1168b1521],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_55	[p2l1034t1486r1168b1521],

1	There	EX	O	there	expl	2	SENT_56	[p2l226t1532r323b1558],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l345t1532r367b1558],
3	a	DT	O	a	det	5	SENT_56	[p2l389t1541r406b1558],
4	critical	JJ	O	critical	amod	5	SENT_56	[p2l426t1532r539b1558],
5	lack	NN	O	lack	nsubj	2	SENT_56	[p2l561t1532r624b1558],
6	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l646t1532r680b1558],
7	knowledge	NN	O	knowledge	prep_of	5	SENT_56	[p2l698t1532r871b1567],
8	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l893t1541r934b1558],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_56	[p2l956t1532r1006b1558],
10	biology	NN	O	biology	prep_on	7	SENT_56	[p2l1027t1532r1147b1567],
11	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1168t1532r1202b1558],
12	CHIKV	NN	LOCATION	chikv	prep_of	10	SENT_56	[p2l189t1579r317b1610],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l189t1579r317b1610],
14	contrasting	VBG	O	contrast	partmod	5	SENT_56	[p2l343t1579r531b1614],
15	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l554t1579r624b1605],
16	related	JJ	O	related	amod	18	SENT_56	[p2l649t1579r763b1605],
17	model	NN	O	model	nn	18	SENT_56	[p2l788t1579r889b1605],
18	alphaviruses	NNS	O	alphavirus	prep_with	14	SENT_56	[p2l914t1579r1116b1614],
19	like	IN	O	like	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1141t1579r1199b1605],
20	Sindbis	JJ	O	sindbis	amod	21	SENT_56	[p2l189t1625r307b1651],
21	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_like	14	SENT_56	[p2l328t1625r406b1651],
22	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	24	SENT_56	[p2l429t1625r544b1658],
23	SINV	NN	O	sinv	nn	24	SENT_56	[p2l429t1625r544b1658],
24	)	NN	O	)	dep	21	SENT_56	[p2l429t1625r544b1658],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l429t1625r544b1658],
26	Semliki	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Semliki	nn	27	SENT_56	[p2l567t1625r687b1651],
27	Forest	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Forest	conj_and	21	SENT_56	[p2l707t1626r809b1651],
28	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	31	SENT_56	[p2l829t1625r908b1651],
29	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	31	SENT_56	[p2l930t1625r1025b1658],
30	SFV	NN	ORGANIZATION	sfv	nn	31	SENT_56	[p2l930t1625r1025b1658],
31	)	NN	O	)	dep	27	SENT_56	[p2l930t1625r1025b1658],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l930t1625r1025b1658],
33	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l1047t1625r1106b1651],
34	Ross	NNP	LOCATION	Ross	nn	35	SENT_56	[p2l1127t1626r1198b1651],
35	River	NNP	LOCATION	River	conj_and	21	SENT_56	[p2l189t1671r276b1697],
36	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	39	SENT_56	[p2l288t1671r366b1697],
37	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	39	SENT_56	[p2l382t1672r485b1704],
38	RRV	NN	ORGANIZATION	rrv	nn	39	SENT_56	[p2l382t1672r485b1704],
39	)	NN	O	)	dep	35	SENT_56	[p2l382t1672r485b1704],
40	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l382t1672r485b1704],
41	this	DT	O	this	nsubj	43	SENT_56	[p2l501t1671r557b1697],
42	probably	RB	O	probably	advmod	43	SENT_56	[p2l572t1671r717b1706],
43	reﬂects	VBZ	O	reﬂects	parataxis	2	SENT_56	[p2l732t1671r848b1697],
44	the	DT	O	the	det	45	SENT_56	[p2l864t1671r913b1697],
45	fact	NN	O	fact	dobj	43	SENT_56	[p2l927t1671r987b1697],
46	that	IN	O	that	complm	48	SENT_56	[p2l1002t1671r1065b1697],
47	CHIKV	NNP	O	CHIKV	nsubj	48	SENT_56	[p2l1080t1671r1200b1697],
48	has	VBZ	O	have	ccomp	43	SENT_56	[p2l188t1717r240b1743],
49	mostly	RB	O	mostly	advmod	50	SENT_56	[p2l253t1717r359b1752],
50	afﬂicted	JJ	O	afﬂicted	amod	51	SENT_56	[p2l371t1717r503b1743],
51	persons	NNS	O	person	dobj	48	SENT_56	[p2l516t1726r640b1752],
52	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l654t1717r684b1742],
53	developing	VBG	O	develop	amod	54	SENT_56	[p2l697t1717r876b1752],
54	countries	NNS	O	country	prep_in	51	SENT_56	[p2l888t1717r1048b1743],
55	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_56	[p2l888t1717r1048b1743],

1	Alphaviruses	NNS	O	alphavirus	nsubjpass	3	SENT_57	[p2l1060t1717r1198b1752, p2l189t1772r270b1789],
2	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	3	SENT_57	[p2l289t1772r339b1789],
3	enveloped	VBN	O	envelop	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l358t1763r533b1798],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l358t1763r533b1798],
5	single-stranded	JJ	O	single-stranded	amod	10	SENT_57	[p2l553t1763r810b1798],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l553t1763r810b1798],
7	positive	JJ	O	positive	amod	10	SENT_57	[p2l830t1763r956b1798],
8	polarity	NN	O	polarity	nn	10	SENT_57	[p2l975t1763r1103b1798],
9	RNA	NN	O	rna	nn	10	SENT_57	[p2l1121t1763r1199b1789],
10	viruses	NNS	O	virus	dobj	3	SENT_57	[p2l188t1809r303b1835],
11	[	VBP	O	[	rcmod	10	SENT_57	[p2l331t1809r378b1841],
12	2	CD	NUMBER	2	number	13	SENT_57	[p2l331t1809r378b1841],
13	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	11	SENT_57	[p2l331t1809r378b1841],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l331t1809r378b1841],

1	Alphaviruses	NNS	O	alphavirus	nsubj	2	SENT_58	[p2l404t1809r621b1844],
2	attach	VBP	O	attach	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l648t1809r751b1835],
3	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l777t1814r808b1835],
4	poorly	RB	O	poorly	advmod	5	SENT_58	[p2l835t1809r944b1844],
5	characterized	VBN	O	characterize	amod	6	SENT_58	[p2l970t1809r1199b1835],
6	receptors	NNS	O	receptor	prep_to	2	SENT_58	[p2l189t1861r342b1891],
7	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l356t1865r397b1882],
8	many	JJ	O	many	amod	11	SENT_58	[p2l410t1865r497b1891],
9	different	JJ	O	different	amod	11	SENT_58	[p2l510t1856r654b1882],
10	cell	NN	O	cell	nn	11	SENT_58	[p2l666t1856r721b1882],
11	types	NNS	O	type	prep_on	6	SENT_58	[p2l734t1861r815b1891],
12	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l829t1856r860b1881],
13	various	JJ	O	various	amod	14	SENT_58	[p2l872t1856r989b1882],
14	species	NNS	O	species	prep_in	11	SENT_58	[p2l1002t1856r1123b1891],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l1002t1856r1123b1891],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_59	[p2l1136t1856r1199b1882],
2	E1	NN	O	e1	nn	4	SENT_59	[p2l188t1902r225b1927],
3	spike	NN	O	spike	nn	4	SENT_59	[p2l236t1902r319b1937],
4	protein	NN	O	protein	nsubj	5	SENT_59	[p2l327t1902r449b1937],
5	drives	VBZ	O	drive	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l457t1902r552b1928],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_59	[p2l562t1902r611b1928],
7	fusion	NN	O	fusion	nn	8	SENT_59	[p2l619t1902r720b1928],
8	process	NN	O	process	dobj	5	SENT_59	[p2l728t1911r856b1937],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l728t1911r856b1937],
10	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l866t1902r925b1928],
11	E2	NN	O	e2	nsubj	12	SENT_59	[p2l932t1902r971b1929],
12	interacts	VBZ	O	interact	conj_and	5	SENT_59	[p2l980t1902r1121b1928],
13	with	IN	O	with	mark	16	SENT_59	[p2l1129t1902r1199b1928],
14	cellular	JJ	O	cellular	amod	15	SENT_59	[p2l189t1948r311b1974],
15	receptors	NNS	O	receptor	nsubj	16	SENT_59	[p2l319t1953r472b1983],
16	[	VBP	O	[	advcl	12	SENT_59	[p2l484t1948r596b1980],
17	14,15	CD	NUMBER	14,15	number	18	SENT_59	[p2l484t1948r596b1980],
18	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	16	SENT_59	[p2l484t1948r596b1980],
19	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l484t1948r596b1980],

1	Individual	JJ	O	individual	amod	2	SENT_60	[p2l606t1948r773b1974],
2	viruses	NNS	O	virus	nsubj	3	SENT_60	[p2l781t1948r892b1974],
3	have	VBP	O	have	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l901t1948r974b1974],
4	different	JJ	O	different	acomp	3	SENT_60	[p2l984t1948r1135b1979],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l984t1948r1135b1979],
6	but	CC	O	but	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1145t1948r1199b1974],
7	wide	JJ	O	wide	amod	8	SENT_60	[p2l188t1994r263b2020],
8	tropism	NN	O	tropism	nsubj	16	SENT_60	[p2l289t1994r424b2029],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l289t1994r424b2029],
10	accounting	VBG	O	account	partmod	8	SENT_60	[p2l450t1994r633b2029],
11	somewhat	RB	O	somewhat	advmod	10	SENT_60	[p2l656t1994r819b2020],
12	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l843t1994r892b2020],
13	different	JJ	O	different	amod	15	SENT_60	[p2l915t1994r1060b2020],
14	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	15	SENT_60	[p2l1085t1994r1198b2020],
15	patterns	NNS	O	pattern	prep_for	10	SENT_60	[p2l189t2045r323b2075],
16	[	VBP	O	[	conj_but	3	SENT_60	[p2l344t2040r389b2072],
17	2	CD	NUMBER	2	number	18	SENT_60	[p2l344t2040r389b2072],
18	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	16	SENT_60	[p2l344t2040r389b2072],
19	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l344t2040r389b2072],

1	Viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	2	SENT_61	[p2l407t2040r488b2066],
2	entry	NN	O	entry	nsubj	4	SENT_61	[p2l506t2045r591b2075],
3	generally	RB	O	generally	advmod	4	SENT_61	[p2l609t2040r757b2075],
4	occurs	VBZ	O	occur	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l775t2049r879b2066],
5	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l898t2040r1028b2075],
6	receptormediated	JJ	O	receptormediated	amod	7	SENT_61	[p2l1047t2045r1198b2075, p2l189t2086r341b2112],
7	endocytosis	NN	O	endocytosis	prep_through	4	SENT_61	[p2l355t2086r551b2121],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l355t2086r551b2121],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l566t2086r625b2112],
10	fusion	NN	O	fusion	nsubj	12	SENT_61	[p2l638t2086r739b2112],
11	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	12	SENT_61	[p2l753t2086r775b2112],
12	dependent	JJ	O	dependent	conj_and	4	SENT_61	[p2l789t2086r964b2121],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l978t2086r1013b2112],
14	endosomal	JJ	O	endosomal	amod	16	SENT_61	[p2l1023t2086r1199b2112],
15	acidiﬁcation	NN	O	acidiﬁcation	nn	16	SENT_61	[p2l189t2133r398b2159],
16	[	NN	O	[	prep_of	12	SENT_61	[p2l425t2133r551b2165],
17	16	CD	NUMBER	16	number	18	SENT_61	[p2l425t2133r551b2165],
18	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	16	SENT_61	[p2l425t2133r551b2165],
19	19	CD	NUMBER	19	num	20	SENT_61	[p2l425t2133r551b2165],
20	]	NN	O	]	dep	18	SENT_61	[p2l425t2133r551b2165],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l425t2133r551b2165],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l576t2134r611b2158],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_62	[p2l637t2133r688b2159],
3	19605	CD	NUMBER	19605	prep_in	7	SENT_62	[p2l716t2133r812b2164],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l716t2133r812b2164],
5	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nsubjpass	7	SENT_62	[p2l839t2133r961b2159],
6	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	7	SENT_62	[p2l985t2142r1042b2159],
7	used	VBN	O	use	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1067t2133r1142b2159],
8	to	TO	O	to	aux	9	SENT_62	[p2l1168t2138r1198b2159],
9	stimulate	VB	O	stimulate	xcomp	7	SENT_62	[p2l189t2179r340b2205],
10	type	NN	O	type	nn	12	SENT_62	[p2l366t2184r434b2214],
11	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	12	SENT_62	[p2l458t2180r470b2204],
12	interferon	NN	O	interferon	dobj	9	SENT_62	[p2l495t2179r665b2205],
13	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	16	SENT_62	[p2l691t2180r772b2212],
14	IFN	NN	O	ifn	nn	16	SENT_62	[p2l691t2180r772b2212],
15	)	NN	O	)	nn	16	SENT_62	[p2l691t2180r772b2212],
16	production	NN	O	production	nsubj	31	SENT_62	[p2l798t2179r984b2214],
17	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1008t2179r1089b2205],
18	chick	NN	O	chick	nn	19	SENT_62	[p2l1114t2179r1199b2205],
19	embryo	NN	O	embryo	prep_from	16	SENT_62	[p2l189t2225r391b2260],
20	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	19	SENT_62	[p2l189t2225r391b2260],
21	like	IN	O	like	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l189t2225r391b2260],
22	ﬁbroblasts	NNS	O	ﬁbroblasts	prep_like	16	SENT_62	[p2l409t2225r578b2251],
23	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	24	SENT_62	[p2l598t2225r710b2257],
24	20,21	CD	NUMBER	20,21	num	25	SENT_62	[p2l598t2225r710b2257],
25	]	NN	O	]	dep	22	SENT_62	[p2l598t2225r710b2257],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l598t2225r710b2257],
27	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l730t2225r789b2251],
28	IFN	NN	ORGANIZATION	ifn	conj_and	22	SENT_62	[p2l807t2226r867b2251],
29	most	RBS	O	most	advmod	30	SENT_62	[p2l886t2230r964b2251],
30	likely	JJ	O	likely	amod	28	SENT_62	[p2l981t2225r1067b2260],
31	plays	VBZ	O	play	rcmod	12	SENT_62	[p2l1085t2225r1164b2260],
32	a	DT	O	a	det	34	SENT_62	[p2l1184t2234r1200b2251],
33	prominent	JJ	O	prominent	amod	34	SENT_62	[p2l189t2271r365b2306],
34	role	NN	O	role	dobj	31	SENT_62	[p2l383t2271r445b2297],
35	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l464t2271r494b2296],
36	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	37	SENT_62	[p2l511t2271r583b2297],
37	clearance	NN	O	clearance	prep_in	34	SENT_62	[p2l601t2271r754b2297],
38	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l773t2271r832b2297],
39	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	40	SENT_62	[p2l850t2271r962b2297],
40	pathogenesis	NN	O	pathogenesis	prep_in	34	SENT_62	[p2l980t2271r1198b2306],
41	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l980t2271r1198b2306],

1	Prior	JJ	O	prior	amod	2	SENT_63	[p2l189t2317r274b2343],
2	studies	NNS	O	study	nsubj	9	SENT_63	[p2l285t2317r396b2343],
3	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l408t2317r488b2343],
4	the	DT	DATE	the	det	5	SENT_63	[p2l501t2317r551b2343],
5	1960s	CD	DATE	1960s	prep_from	2	SENT_63	[p2l566t2317r652b2343],
6	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l666t2322r696b2343],
7	1980s	CD	DATE	1980s	prep_to	5	SENT_63	[p2l712t2317r798b2343],
8	have	VBP	O	have	aux	9	SENT_63	[p2l810t2317r883b2343],
9	demonstrated	VBN	O	demonstrate	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l896t2317r1123b2343],
10	that	IN	O	that	complm	12	SENT_63	[p2l1136t2317r1199b2343],
11	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nsubj	12	SENT_63	[p2l189t2363r309b2389],
12	replicates	VBZ	O	replicate	ccomp	9	SENT_63	[p2l326t2363r482b2398],
13	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l499t2363r530b2388],
14	various	JJ	O	various	amod	17	SENT_63	[p2l546t2363r663b2389],
15	nonhuman	JJ	O	nonhuman	amod	17	SENT_63	[p2l681t2363r858b2389],
16	cell	NN	O	cell	nn	17	SENT_63	[p2l875t2363r929b2389],
17	lines	NNS	O	line	nsubj	41	SENT_63	[p2l946t2363r1028b2394],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l946t2363r1028b2394],
19	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l1045t2363r1200b2398],
20	Vero	NNP	LOCATION	Vero	nn	21	SENT_63	[p2l188t2411r268b2436],
21	cells	NNS	O	cell	prep_including	41	SENT_63	[p2l286t2410r362b2441],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l286t2410r362b2441],
23	chick	NN	O	chick	nn	25	SENT_63	[p2l380t2410r465b2436],
24	embryo	NN	O	embryo	nn	25	SENT_63	[p2l482t2410r605b2445],
25	ﬁbroblast	NN	O	ﬁbroblast	appos	21	SENT_63	[p2l622t2410r856b2436],
26	—	CD	NUMBER	—	nsubj	37	SENT_63	[p2l622t2410r856b2436],
27	like	IN	O	like	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l622t2410r856b2436],
28	cells	NNS	O	cell	nn	32	SENT_63	[p2l874t2410r950b2441],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l874t2410r950b2441],
30	BHK21	NN	O	bhk21	dep	32	SENT_63	[p2l968t2410r1093b2441],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l968t2410r1093b2441],
32	L929	NN	O	l929	prep_like	26	SENT_63	[p2l1111t2410r1198b2441],
33	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l1111t2410r1198b2441],
34	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l189t2456r249b2482],
35	Hep-2	NN	O	hep-2	nn	36	SENT_63	[p2l273t2456r374b2491],
36	cells	NNS	O	cell	conj_and	32	SENT_63	[p2l400t2456r468b2482],
37	[	VBP	O	[	rcmod	25	SENT_63	[p2l495t2456r620b2488],
38	22-25	CD	NUMBER	22-25	num	39	SENT_63	[p2l495t2456r620b2488],
39	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	37	SENT_63	[p2l495t2456r620b2488],
40	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l495t2456r620b2488],
41	inducing	VBG	O	induce	prepc_in	12	SENT_63	[p2l646t2456r791b2491],
42	generally	RB	O	generally	advmod	52	SENT_63	[p2l814t2456r964b2491],
43	a	DT	O	a	det	52	SENT_63	[p2l989t2465r1005b2482],
44	signiﬁcant	JJ	O	signiﬁcant	amod	52	SENT_63	[p2l1029t2456r1199b2491],
45	cytopathic	JJ	O	cytopathic	amod	52	SENT_63	[p2l189t2502r359b2537],
46	effect	NN	O	effect	nn	52	SENT_63	[p2l372t2502r463b2528],
47	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	52	SENT_63	[p2l475t2502r564b2535],
48	CPE	NNP	ORGANIZATION	CPE	nn	52	SENT_63	[p2l475t2502r564b2535],
49	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	52	SENT_63	[p2l475t2502r564b2535],
50	[	NN	O	[	nn	52	SENT_63	[p2l579t2502r624b2534],
51	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	52	SENT_63	[p2l579t2502r624b2534],
52	]	NN	O	]	dobj	41	SENT_63	[p2l579t2502r624b2534],
53	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l579t2502r624b2534],

1	To	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l637t2503r680b2528],
2	our	PRP$	O	we	poss	3	SENT_64	[p2l693t2511r750b2528],
3	knowledge	NN	O	knowledge	prep_to	17	SENT_64	[p2l760t2502r941b2537],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l760t2502r941b2537],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	6	SENT_64	[p2l955t2502r1005b2528],
6	interaction	NN	O	interaction	nsubjpass	17	SENT_64	[p2l1017t2502r1199b2528],
7	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l189t2548r224b2574],
8	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	prep_of	6	SENT_64	[p2l234t2548r354b2574],
9	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l365t2548r436b2574],
10	human	JJ	O	human	amod	12	SENT_64	[p2l448t2548r561b2574],
11	primary	JJ	O	primary	amod	12	SENT_64	[p2l574t2548r705b2583],
12	cells	NNS	O	cell	prep_with	8	SENT_64	[p2l718t2548r786b2574],
13	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	17	SENT_64	[p2l799t2548r850b2574],
14	not	RB	O	not	neg	17	SENT_64	[p2l864t2553r918b2574],
15	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	17	SENT_64	[p2l930t2548r1008b2574],
16	extensively	RB	O	extensively	advmod	17	SENT_64	[p2l1021t2548r1199b2583],
17	characterized	VBN	O	characterize	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l189t2594r417b2620],
18	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l189t2594r417b2620],

1	Here	RB	O	here	advmod	4	SENT_65	[p2l433t2595r522b2625],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l433t2595r522b2625],
3	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	4	SENT_65	[p2l537t2603r579b2620],
4	report	VBP	O	report	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l596t2599r700b2629],
5	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l715t2603r756b2620],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_65	[p2l772t2594r821b2620],
7	replication	NN	O	replication	nn	8	SENT_65	[p2l838t2594r1017b2629],
8	characteristics	NNS	O	characteristic	prep_on	4	SENT_65	[p2l1032t2594r1198b2620, p2l189t2641r267b2667],
9	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l291t2641r350b2667],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_65	[p2l373t2641r422b2667],
11	tropism	NN	O	tropism	conj_and	8	SENT_65	[p2l446t2641r573b2676],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l595t2641r629b2667],
13	clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	15	SENT_65	[p2l649t2641r765b2667],
14	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nn	15	SENT_65	[p2l788t2641r908b2667],
15	strains	NNS	O	strain	prep_of	11	SENT_65	[p2l930t2641r1036b2667],
16	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l1058t2641r1138b2667],
17	La	NNP	O	La	nn	19	SENT_65	[p2l1159t2642r1200b2667],
18	Réunion	NNP	O	Réunion	nn	19	SENT_65	[p2l189t2687r332b2713],
19	island	NN	O	island	prep_from	4	SENT_65	[p2l358t2687r457b2713],
20	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l482t2687r543b2713],
21	provide	VB	O	provide	conj_and	4	SENT_65	[p2l569t2687r698b2722],
22	a	DT	O	a	det	24	SENT_65	[p2l724t2696r740b2713],
23	general	JJ	O	general	amod	24	SENT_65	[p2l765t2687r889b2722],
24	insight	NN	O	insight	dobj	21	SENT_65	[p2l915t2687r1029b2722],
25	into	IN	O	into	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l1054t2687r1121b2713],
26	the	DT	O	the	det	27	SENT_65	[p2l1148t2687r1199b2713],
27	interaction	NN	O	interaction	prep_into	21	SENT_65	[p2l189t2733r371b2759],
28	between	IN	O	between	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l382t2733r517b2759],
29	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	prep_between	27	SENT_65	[p2l529t2733r649b2759],
30	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l661t2733r720b2759],
31	its	PRP$	O	its	poss	33	SENT_65	[p2l732t2733r767b2759],
32	human	JJ	O	human	amod	33	SENT_65	[p2l779t2733r892b2759],
33	host	NN	O	host	prep_between	27	SENT_65	[p2l903t2733r979b2759],
34	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l903t2733r979b2759],

1	Results	NNS	O	result	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l190t2831r326b2863],

1	Analysis	NN	O	analysis	nsubjpass	8	SENT_67	[p2l188t2896r326b2935],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l343t2896r378b2927],
3	CHIKV	NNP	O	CHIKV	nn	4	SENT_67	[p2l392t2897r497b2927],
4	Replication	NN	O	replication	prep_of	1	SENT_67	[p2l515t2896r703b2934],
5	Virtually	RB	O	virtually	advmod	6	SENT_67	[p2l225t2947r371b2982],
6	nothing	NN	O	nothing	tmod	8	SENT_67	[p2l399t2947r528b2982],
7	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	8	SENT_67	[p2l555t2947r577b2973],
8	known	VBN	O	know	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l605t2947r714b2973],
9	about	IN	O	about	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l742t2947r835b2973],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_67	[p2l864t2947r914b2973],
11	interactions	NNS	O	interaction	prep_about	8	SENT_67	[p2l942t2947r1139b2973],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l1168t2947r1202b2973],
13	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	prep_of	11	SENT_67	[p2l189t2993r309b3019],
14	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l328t2993r398b3019],
15	human	JJ	O	human	amod	16	SENT_67	[p2l417t2993r530b3019],
16	cells	NNS	O	cell	prep_with	8	SENT_67	[p2l550t2993r626b3019],
17	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l550t2993r626b3019],

1	We	PRP	O	we	nsubj	3	SENT_68	[p2l646t2994r698b3019],
2	thus	RB	O	thus	advmod	3	SENT_68	[p2l719t2993r785b3019],
3	designed	VBD	O	design	_	0	SENT_68	[p2l806t2993r949b3028],
4	various	JJ	O	various	amod	5	SENT_68	[p2l968t2993r1085b3019],
5	assays	NNS	O	assay	dobj	3	SENT_68	[p2l1106t3002r1198b3028],

1	z	SYM	O	z	dep	3	SENT_69	[p2l188t3077r261b3136],
2	2T	NN	O	2t	nn	3	SENT_69	[p2l188t3077r261b3136],
3	PLoS	NN	O	plo	dep	4	SENT_69	[p2l288t3093r352b3116],
4	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l367t3092r511b3123],
5	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	6	SENT_69	[p2l526t3091r528b3124],
6	www	NN	O	www	dobj	4	SENT_69	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_70	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_70	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l543t3092r882b3123],
4	to	TO	O	to	aux	5	SENT_70	[p2l1278t211r1308b232],
5	study	VB	O	study	infmod	3	SENT_70	[p2l1331t206r1416b241],
6	CHIKV	NN	O	chikv	nn	7	SENT_70	[p2l1438t206r1558b232],
7	replication	NN	O	replication	dobj	5	SENT_70	[p2l1580t206r1759b241],
8	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l1781t206r1812b231],
9	cell	NN	O	cell	nn	10	SENT_70	[p2l1834t206r1888b232],
10	cultures	NNS	O	culture	prep_in	5	SENT_70	[p2l1910t206r2048b232],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l1910t206r2048b232],

1	Four	CD	NUMBER	four	num	3	SENT_71	[p2l2070t207r2149b232],
2	clinical	JJ	O	clinical	amod	3	SENT_71	[p2l2170t206r2286b232],
3	strains	NNS	O	strain	nsubjpass	25	SENT_71	[p2l1277t252r1383b278],
4	(	RB	O	(	advmod	5	SENT_71	[p2l1402t252r1537b285],
5	isolated	VBN	O	isolate	partmod	3	SENT_71	[p2l1402t252r1537b285],
6	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l1554t252r1634b278],
7	patients	NNS	O	patient	prep_from	5	SENT_71	[p2l1651t252r1781b287],
8	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l1798t252r1878b278],
9	La	NNP	O	La	nn	11	SENT_71	[p2l1894t253r1935b278],
10	Réunion	NNP	O	Réunion	nn	11	SENT_71	[p2l1951t252r2109b285],
11	)	NN	O	)	prep_from	7	SENT_71	[p2l1951t252r2109b285],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l1951t252r2109b285],
13	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l2127t252r2175b278],
14	which	WDT	O	which	rel	19	SENT_71	[p2l2191t252r2287b278],
15	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_71	[p2l1278t298r1327b324],
16	genome	NN	O	genome	nsubjpass	19	SENT_71	[p2l1338t307r1466b333],
17	has	VBZ	O	have	aux	19	SENT_71	[p2l1477t298r1528b324],
18	been	VBN	O	be	auxpass	19	SENT_71	[p2l1539t298r1617b324],
19	sequenced	VBN	O	sequence	rcmod	3	SENT_71	[p2l1628t298r1798b333],
20	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	21	SENT_71	[p2l1812t298r1857b330],
21	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	22	SENT_71	[p2l1812t298r1857b330],
22	]	NN	O	]	dobj	19	SENT_71	[p2l1812t298r1857b330],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l1812t298r1857b330],
24	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	25	SENT_71	[p2l1868t307r1944b324],
25	analyzed	VBN	O	analyze	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l1956t298r2103b333],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l1956t298r2103b333],

1	CHIKV-21	NN	O	chikv-21	nn	4	SENT_72	[p2l2115t298r2284b325],
2	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1277t343r1336b369],
3	CHIKV-27	NN	MISC	chikv-27	conj_and	1	SENT_72	[p2l1355t340r1526b370],
4	strains	NNS	O	strain	nsubjpass	6	SENT_72	[p2l1545t343r1651b369],
5	were	VBD	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_72	[p2l1670t352r1746b369],
6	isolated	VBN	O	isolate	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1766t343r1899b374],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1766t343r1899b374],
8	respectively	RB	O	respectively	advmod	6	SENT_72	[p2l1919t343r2118b378],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1919t343r2118b378],
10	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l2137t343r2217b369],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_72	[p2l2237t343r2286b369],
12	serum	NN	O	serum	nn	15	SENT_72	[p2l1277t398r1376b415],
13	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1399t389r1458b415],
14	cerebrospinal	JJ	O	cerebrospinal	nn	15	SENT_72	[p2l1481t389r1705b424],
15	ﬂuid	NN	O	ﬂuid	prep_from	6	SENT_72	[p2l1728t389r1802b415],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1825t389r1860b415],
17	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	18	SENT_72	[p2l1881t394r1937b415],
18	newborns	NNS	O	newborn	prep_of	15	SENT_72	[p2l1961t389r2118b415],
19	suffering	VBG	O	suffer	partmod	18	SENT_72	[p2l2141t389r2287b424],
20	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1276t435r1356b461],
21	encephalopathy	NN	O	encephalopathy	prep_from	19	SENT_72	[p2l1378t435r1645b470],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1378t435r1645b470],
23	whereas	IN	O	whereas	mark	27	SENT_72	[p2l1668t435r1797b461],
24	CHIKV-49	NN	O	chikv-49	nsubj	27	SENT_72	[p2l1820t435r1991b461],
25	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l2014t435r2073b461],
26	CHIKV-115	NN	MISC	chikv-115	nsubj	27	SENT_72	[p2l2096t435r2286b461],
27	came	VBD	O	come	advcl	6	SENT_72	[p2l1277t489r1360b506],
28	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1382t480r1462b506],
29	two	CD	NUMBER	two	num	31	SENT_72	[p2l1484t485r1540b506],
30	young	JJ	O	young	amod	31	SENT_72	[p2l1562t489r1662b515],
31	adults	NNS	O	adult	prep_from	27	SENT_72	[p2l1683t480r1779b506],
32	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1800t480r1870b506],
33	a	DT	O	a	det	35	SENT_72	[p2l1893t489r1909b506],
34	classical	JJ	O	classical	amod	35	SENT_72	[p2l1930t480r2059b506],
35	form	NN	O	form	prep_with	27	SENT_72	[p2l2081t480r2161b506],
36	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l2183t480r2218b506],
37	the	DT	O	the	det	41	SENT_72	[p2l2237t480r2286b506],
38	disease	NN	O	disease	nn	41	SENT_72	[p2l1277t526r1389b552],
39	[	NN	O	[	nn	41	SENT_72	[p2l1407t526r1452b558],
40	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	41	SENT_72	[p2l1407t526r1452b558],
41	]	NN	O	]	prep_of	35	SENT_72	[p2l1407t526r1452b558],
42	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_72	[p2l1407t526r1452b558],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_73	[p2l1468t526r1530b552],
2	four	CD	NUMBER	four	num	3	SENT_73	[p2l1545t526r1615b552],
3	strains	NNS	O	strain	nsubj	6	SENT_73	[p2l1629t526r1735b552],
4	were	VBD	O	be	cop	6	SENT_73	[p2l1750t535r1826b552],
5	genetically	RB	O	genetically	advmod	6	SENT_73	[p2l1842t526r2016b561],
6	close	RB	O	close	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l2031t526r2117b557],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l2031t526r2117b557],
8	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l2132t526r2203b552],
9	only	RB	O	only	quantmod	10	SENT_73	[p2l2218t526r2287b561],
10	one	CD	NUMBER	one	num	13	SENT_73	[p2l1277t581r1335b598],
11	polymorphic	JJ	O	polymorphic	amod	13	SENT_73	[p2l1358t572r1567b607],
12	residue	NN	O	residue	nn	13	SENT_73	[p2l1590t572r1707b598],
13	(	NN	O	(	prep_with	6	SENT_73	[p2l1731t573r1771b605],
14	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l1731t573r1771b605],
15	codon	NN	O	codon	nn	17	SENT_73	[p2l1792t572r1893b598],
16	226	CD	NUMBER	226	num	17	SENT_73	[p2l1916t572r1981b604],
17	)	NN	O	)	prep_at	13	SENT_73	[p2l1916t572r1981b604],
18	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l2004t572r2035b597],
19	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_73	[p2l2058t572r2107b598],
20	E1	NN	O	e1	nn	21	SENT_73	[p2l2129t572r2166b597],
21	glycoprotein	NN	O	glycoprotein	prep_in	17	SENT_73	[p2l2191t572r2286b607, p2l1277t617r1398b652],
22	[	CD	NUMBER	[	number	23	SENT_73	[p2l1420t617r1465b649],
23	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	24	SENT_73	[p2l1420t617r1465b649],
24	]	NN	O	]	dep	21	SENT_73	[p2l1420t617r1465b649],
25	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_73	[p2l1420t617r1465b649],
