1	OPEN	NN	MISC	open	nn	3	SENT_1	[p1l242t131r323b155],
2	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	3	SENT_1	[p1l333t112r365b162],
3	ACCESS	NNP	O	ACCESS	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l372t131r484b155],
4	Freely	RB	O	freely	advmod	5	SENT_1	[p1l501t130r590b162],
5	available	JJ	O	available	amod	7	SENT_1	[p1l597t130r731b155],
6	online	JJ	O	online	amod	7	SENT_1	[p1l739t130r832b155],
7	PLUS	NNS	O	plus	dep	3	SENT_1	[p1l2004t111r2118b153],
8	PATHOGENS	NNS	O	pathogen	dep	7	SENT_1	[p1l2129t130r2308b154],

1	Varicellovirus	NNP	O	Varicellovirus	nn	2	SENT_2	[p1l243t240r729b300],
2	UL49	NN	O	ul49	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l765t243r1003b300],
3	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	num	4	SENT_2	[p1l765t243r1003b300],
4	Proteins	NNS	O	protein	nsubj	6	SENT_2	[p1l1041t240r1332b300],
5	Differentially	RB	O	differentially	advmod	6	SENT_2	[p1l1368t239r1836b317],
6	Affect	VB	O	affect	rcmod	2	SENT_2	[p1l1866t239r2078b300],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_2	[p1l2109t240r2225b300],
8	Function	NN	O	function	dobj	6	SENT_2	[p1l248t331r556b391],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l593t330r665b391],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_2	[p1l692t331r808b391],
11	Transporter	NNP	O	Transporter	nn	12	SENT_2	[p1l839t334r1261b407],
12	Associated	NNP	O	Associated	prep_of	8	SENT_2	[p1l1292t331r1676b391],
13	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1711t331r1865b391],
14	Antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	15	SENT_2	[p1l1900t331r2182b408],
15	Processing	NN	O	processing	prep_with	6	SENT_2	[p1l248t422r648b499],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l248t422r648b499],
17	TAP	NN	O	tap	appos	15	SENT_2	[p1l679t424r819b481],

1	Danijela	NNP	PERSON	Danijela	nn	2	SENT_3	[p1l245t551r405b590],
2	Koppers	NNP	PERSON	Koppers	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l424t543r760b589],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l424t543r760b589],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l424t543r760b589],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l424t543r760b589],

1	La	NNP	O	La	nsubj	4	SENT_5	[p1l424t543r760b589],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	4	SENT_5	[p1l424t543r760b589],
3	ic	JJ	O	ic	amod	4	SENT_5	[p1l424t543r760b589],
4	”“	NN	O	”“	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l424t543r760b589],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l424t543r760b589],
6	Marieke	NNP	PERSON	Marieke	nn	9	SENT_5	[p1l778t551r936b582],
7	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	nn	9	SENT_5	[p1l952t552r989b582],
8	Verweij	NNP	PERSON	Verweij	nn	9	SENT_5	[p1l1004t543r1205b590],
9	”	NN	O	”	appos	4	SENT_5	[p1l1004t543r1205b590],
10	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1004t543r1205b590],
11	Andrea	NNP	PERSON	Andrea	nn	13	SENT_5	[p1l1222t551r1365b582],
12	D.	NNP	PERSON	D.	nn	13	SENT_5	[p1l1384t553r1423b582],
13	Lipinskaz	NNP	PERSON	Lipinskaz	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l1440t544r1633b589],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1440t544r1633b589],
15	Ying	NNP	PERSON	Ying	nn	16	SENT_5	[p1l1649t551r1738b590],
16	Wang3	NNP	PERSON	Wang3	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l1755t544r1897b590],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1755t544r1897b590],
18	Edwin	NNP	PERSON	Edwin	nn	20	SENT_5	[p1l1916t551r2033b582],
19	Quinten	NNP	PERSON	Quinten	nn	20	SENT_5	[p1l2051t544r2240b586],
20	‘	NNP	PERSON	‘	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l2051t544r2240b586],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l2051t544r2240b586],
22	Eric	NNP	PERSON	Eric	nn	24	SENT_5	[p1l245t609r315b640],
23	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	24	SENT_5	[p1l330t611r369b640],
24	Reits4	NNP	PERSON	Reits4	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l387t603r510b644],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l387t603r510b644],
26	Joachim	NNP	PERSON	Joachim	nn	27	SENT_5	[p1l526t609r687b640],
27	Kochs	NNP	PERSON	Kochs	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l707t603r832b644],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l707t603r832b644],
29	Sandra	NNP	PERSON	Sandra	nn	30	SENT_5	[p1l850t609r986b640],
30	Loch5	NNP	PERSON	Loch5	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l1005t603r1126b644],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1005t603r1126b644],
32	Marisa	NNP	PERSON	Marisa	nn	35	SENT_5	[p1l1144t609r1273b640],
33	Marcondes	NNP	PERSON	Marcondes	nn	35	SENT_5	[p1l1291t609r1508b640],
34	Rezende	NNP	PERSON	Rezende	nn	35	SENT_5	[p1l1526t603r1722b644],
35	‘	NNP	O	‘	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l1526t603r1722b644],
36	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1526t603r1722b644],
37	Franz	NNP	PERSON	Franz	nn	38	SENT_5	[p1l1740t611r1848b640],
38	Dauss	NNP	PERSON	Dauss	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l1865t603r1991b644],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1865t603r1991b644],
40	Krystyna	NNP	PERSON	Krystyna	nn	41	SENT_5	[p1l2010t611r2181b648],
41	Bienkowska-Szewczykz	NNP	PERSON	Bienkowska-Szewczykz	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l245t661r715b706],
42	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l245t661r715b706],
43	Nikolaus	NNP	PERSON	Nikolaus	nn	44	SENT_5	[p1l733t667r904b698],
44	Osterrieder7	NNP	PERSON	Osterrieder7	appos	9	SENT_5	[p1l921t661r1203b702],
45	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l921t661r1203b702],
46	8	CD	NUMBER	8	dep	44	SENT_5	[p1l921t661r1203b702],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l921t661r1203b702],
48	Thomas	NNP	PERSON	Thomas	nn	50	SENT_5	[p1l1219t667r1375b698],
49	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	nn	50	SENT_5	[p1l1392t668r1428b698],
50	Mettenleiter9	NNP	PERSON	Mettenleiter9	appos	4	SENT_5	[p1l1445t661r1718b702],
51	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1445t661r1718b702],
52	Mirjam	NNP	PERSON	Mirjam	nn	55	SENT_5	[p1l1736t667r1872b706],
53	H.	NNP	PERSON	H.	nn	55	SENT_5	[p1l1892t669r1930b698],
54	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	55	SENT_5	[p1l1948t669r1994b698],
55	Heemskerk	NNP	PERSON	Heemskerk	appos	4	SENT_5	[p1l2011t661r2279b702],
56	‘	CD	NUMBER	‘	number	57	SENT_5	[p1l2011t661r2279b702],
57	°	CD	NUMBER	°	dep	55	SENT_5	[p1l2011t661r2279b702],
58	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l2011t661r2279b702],
59	Robert	NNP	PERSON	Robert	nn	60	SENT_5	[p1l245t725r376b756],
60	Tampés	NNP	PERSON	Tampés	appos	4	SENT_5	[p1l389t719r554b763],
61	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l389t719r554b763],
62	Jacques	NNP	PERSON	Jacques	nn	65	SENT_5	[p1l567t727r723b763],
63	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	65	SENT_5	[p1l736t727r765b756],
64	Neefjes	NNP	PERSON	Neefjes	nn	65	SENT_5	[p1l780t719r973b764],
65	“	NN	O	“	appos	4	SENT_5	[p1l780t719r973b764],
66	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l780t719r973b764],
67	Shafiqul	NNP	PERSON	Shafiqul	nn	69	SENT_5	[p1l988t725r1149b763],
68	I.	NNP	PERSON	I.	nn	69	SENT_5	[p1l1166t727r1186b756],
69	Chowdhury3	NNP	PERSON	Chowdhury3	appos	4	SENT_5	[p1l1200t719r1459b764],
70	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1200t719r1459b764],
71	Maaike	NNP	PERSON	Maaike	nn	72	SENT_5	[p1l1474t725r1615b756],
72	E.	NNP	PERSON	E.	appos	4	SENT_5	[p1l1630t727r1662b756],
73	Ressing	VBG	PERSON	ress	rcmod	72	SENT_5	[p1l1677t719r1855b764],
74	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1677t719r1855b764],
75	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l1677t719r1855b764],
76	Frans	NNP	PERSON	Frans	nn	79	SENT_5	[p1l1871t727r1977b756],
77	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	79	SENT_5	[p1l1990t727r2029b756],
78	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	79	SENT_5	[p1l2044t727r2090b756],
79	Rijsewijks	NNP	PERSON	Rijsewijks	appos	4	SENT_5	[p1l2105t719r2307b764],
80	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l2105t719r2307b764],
81	Emmanuel	NNP	PERSON	Emmanuel	nn	85	SENT_5	[p1l245t783r450b814],
82	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	85	SENT_5	[p1l467t785r496b814],
83	H.	NNP	PERSON	H.	nn	85	SENT_5	[p1l514t785r552b814],
84	J.	NNP	PERSON	J.	nn	85	SENT_5	[p1l567t785r596b814],
85	Wiertz	NNP	PERSON	Wiertz	poss	87	SENT_5	[p1l611t777r775b814],
86	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l611t777r775b814],
87	*	NN	O	*	dobj	4	SENT_5	[p1l611t777r775b814],

1	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	2	SENT_6	[p1l245t852r254b871],
2	Center	NN	O	center	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l265t851r345b871],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l354t850r379b871],
4	Infectious	JJ	O	infectious	amod	5	SENT_6	[p1l387t850r503b871],
5	Diseases	NNS	O	disease	prep_of	2	SENT_6	[p1l514t851r614b871],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l623t850r667b871],
7	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	prep_of	2	SENT_6	[p1l679t851r824b877],
8	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l833t850r858b871],
9	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	nn	10	SENT_6	[p1l866t850r957b871],
10	Microbiology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Microbiology	prep_of	7	SENT_6	[p1l968t850r1131b877],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l968t850r1131b877],
12	Leiden	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Leiden	nn	15	SENT_6	[p1l1142t850r1220b871],
13	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	nn	15	SENT_6	[p1l1232t851r1350b877],
14	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	nn	15	SENT_6	[p1l1360t850r1451b871],
15	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1461t851r1546b875],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1461t851r1546b875],
17	Leiden	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Leiden	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1557t850r1642b875],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1557t850r1642b875],
19	The	DT	LOCATION	the	det	20	SENT_6	[p1l1650t850r1695b871],
20	Netherlands	NNP	LOCATION	Netherlands	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1705t850r1856b875],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1705t850r1856b875],
22	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	23	SENT_6	[p1l1866t852r1881b871],
23	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1889t851r2034b877],
24	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2043t850r2068b871],
25	Molecular	JJ	ORGANIZATION	molecular	amod	26	SENT_6	[p1l2076t850r2194b871],
26	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	prep_of	23	SENT_6	[p1l2202t850r2308b877],
27	,	,	ORGANIZATION	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2202t850r2308b877],
28	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l244t893r363b919],
29	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l374t892r398b913],
30	Gdansk	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Gdansk	prep_of	28	SENT_6	[p1l408t892r502b917],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l408t892r502b917],
32	Gdansk	NNP	LOCATION	Gdansk	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l514t892r608b917],
33	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l514t892r608b917],
34	Poland	NNP	LOCATION	Poland	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l621t892r709b917],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l621t892r709b917],
36	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	37	SENT_6	[p1l721t894r735b913],
37	Department	NN	ORGANIZATION	department	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l744t893r889b919],
38	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l901t892r925b913],
39	Diagnostic	JJ	ORGANIZATION	diagnostic	amod	40	SENT_6	[p1l936t893r1063b919],
40	Medicine/Pathobiology	NN	ORGANIZATION	medicine/pathobiology	prep_of	37	SENT_6	[p1l1075t892r1363b919],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1075t892r1363b919],
42	College	NNP	ORGANIZATION	College	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1374t892r1464b919],
43	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1476t892r1501b913],
44	Veterinaw	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Veterinaw	nn	45	SENT_6	[p1l1510t893r1633b919],
45	Medicine	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medicine	prep_of	42	SENT_6	[p1l1645t892r1759b917],
46	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1645t892r1759b917],
47	Kansas	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Kansas	nn	49	SENT_6	[p1l1773t893r1852b913],
48	State	NNP	ORGANIZATION	State	nn	49	SENT_6	[p1l1864t893r1924b913],
49	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1937t893r2060b919],
50	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1937t893r2060b919],
51	Manhattan	NNP	LOCATION	Manhattan	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l2073t892r2209b917],
52	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2073t892r2209b917],
53	Kansas	NNP	LOCATION	Kansas	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l2222t893r2308b917],
54	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2222t893r2308b917],
55	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	nn	56	SENT_6	[p1l244t934r322b955],
56	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l336t935r407b955],
57	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l420t934r444b955],
58	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	prep_of	56	SENT_6	[p1l455t935r558b959],
59	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l455t935r558b959],
60	4Department	NN	O	4department	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l571t935r740b961],
61	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l752t934r777b955],
62	Cell	NN	O	cell	nn	63	SENT_6	[p1l787t934r829b955],
63	Biology	NNP	O	Biology	prep_of	60	SENT_6	[p1l844t934r932b961],
64	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l944t934r988b955],
65	Histology	NNP	O	Histology	conj_and	63	SENT_6	[p1l1002t934r1121b961],
66	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1002t934r1121b961],
67	Academic	NNP	O	Academic	nn	69	SENT_6	[p1l1133t934r1252b955],
68	Medical	NNP	O	Medical	nn	69	SENT_6	[p1l1265t934r1356b955],
69	Centre	NNP	O	Centre	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1369t935r1454b959],
70	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1369t935r1454b959],
71	Amsterdam	NNP	LOCATION	Amsterdam	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1467t934r1613b959],
72	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1467t934r1613b959],
73	The	DT	LOCATION	the	det	74	SENT_6	[p1l1624t934r1669b955],
74	Netherlands	NNP	LOCATION	Netherlands	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1682t934r1833b959],
75	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1682t934r1833b959],
76	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	78	SENT_6	[p1l1846t935r1967b955],
77	|	NN	O	|	nn	78	SENT_6	[p1l1846t935r1967b955],
78	nstitute	NN	O	nstitute	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l1846t935r1967b955],
79	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1979t934r2004b955],
80	Biochemistw	NNP	LOCATION	Biochemistw	prep_of	78	SENT_6	[p1l2015t934r2175b961],
81	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2015t934r2175b961],
82	Biocenter	NNP	O	Biocenter	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l2189t935r2308b959],
83	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l2189t935r2308b959],
84	Goethe	NNP	PERSON	Goethe	appos	2	SENT_6	[p1l243t975r461b1002],
85	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l243t975r461b1002],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l243t975r461b1002],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l243t975r461b1002],

1	University	NNP	O	University	nn	10	SENT_8	[p1l243t975r461b1002],
2	Frankfurt	NNP	LOCATION	Frankfurt	nn	10	SENT_8	[p1l472t975r586b1000],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l472t975r586b1000],
4	Frankfurt/Main	NNP	O	Frankfurt/Main	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l598t975r782b1000],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l598t975r782b1000],
6	Germany	NNP	LOCATION	Germany	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l793t976r907b1002],
7	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l793t976r907b1002],
8	6Virus	NNP	O	6Virus	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l919t976r999b996],
9	Discovery	NNP	O	Discovery	nn	10	SENT_8	[p1l1011t976r1127b1002],
10	Unit	NNP	O	Unit	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1138t976r1192b1000],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1138t976r1192b1000],
12	ASG	NNP	ORGANIZATION	ASG	appos	10	SENT_8	[p1l1203t975r1367b1002],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l1203t975r1367b1002],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1203t975r1367b1002],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l1203t975r1367b1002],

1	Le	NNP	O	Le	nn	3	SENT_10	[p1l1203t975r1367b1002],
2	|	NNP	O	|	nn	3	SENT_10	[p1l1203t975r1367b1002],
3	ystad	NN	O	ystad	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1203t975r1367b1002],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1203t975r1367b1002],
5	Lelystad	NNP	LOCATION	Lelystad	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1379t975r1482b1002],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1379t975r1482b1002],
7	The	DT	LOCATION	the	det	8	SENT_10	[p1l1492t975r1536b996],
8	Netherlands	NNP	LOCATION	Netherlands	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1548t975r1699b1000],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1548t975r1699b1000],
10	7	CD	NUMBER	7	num	11	SENT_10	[p1l1710t977r1725b996],
11	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1733t976r1878b1002],
12	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1889t975r1914b996],
13	Microbiology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Microbiology	prep_of	11	SENT_10	[p1l1923t975r2082b1002],
14	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2092t975r2136b996],
15	Immunology	NNP	O	Immunology	prep_of	11	SENT_10	[p1l2149t975r2308b1002],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2149t975r2308b1002],
17	College	NNP	O	College	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l243t1016r333b1043],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l344t1016r369b1037],
19	Veterinary	JJ	O	veterinary	amod	20	SENT_10	[p1l377t1017r501b1043],
20	Medicine	NN	O	medicine	prep_of	17	SENT_10	[p1l512t1016r626b1041],
21	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l512t1016r626b1041],
22	Cornell	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Cornell	nn	23	SENT_10	[p1l637t1016r721b1037],
23	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l734t1017r858b1043],
24	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l734t1017r858b1043],
25	Ithaca	NNP	LOCATION	Ithaca	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l871t1016r947b1041],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l871t1016r947b1041],
27	New	NNP	LOCATION	New	nn	28	SENT_10	[p1l959t1017r1012b1037],
28	York	NNP	LOCATION	York	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1023t1016r1081b1041],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1023t1016r1081b1041],
30	United	NNP	LOCATION	United	nn	31	SENT_10	[p1l1094t1016r1172b1037],
31	States	NNPS	LOCATION	States	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1184t1017r1255b1037],
32	of	IN	LOCATION	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1267t1016r1292b1037],
33	America	NNP	LOCATION	America	prep_of	31	SENT_10	[p1l1301t1017r1404b1041],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1301t1017r1404b1041],
35	8	CD	NUMBER	8	num	36	SENT_10	[p1l1416t1018r1431b1037],
36	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1439t1017r1537b1037],
37	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1547t1016r1581b1037],
38	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	prep_for	36	SENT_10	[p1l1591t1016r1696b1043],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1591t1016r1696b1043],
40	Berlin	NNP	LOCATION	Berlin	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1709t1016r1780b1041],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1709t1016r1780b1041],
42	Germany	NNP	LOCATION	Germany	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1792t1017r1907b1043],
43	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1792t1017r1907b1043],
44	9	CD	NUMBER	9	num	45	SENT_10	[p1l1918t1018r1933b1037],
45	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l1941t1017r2039b1037],
46	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2050t1016r2075b1037],
47	Molecular	JJ	ORGANIZATION	molecular	amod	48	SENT_10	[p1l2085t1016r2202b1037],
48	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	prep_of	45	SENT_10	[p1l2214t1016r2308b1043],
49	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l2214t1016r2308b1043],
50	Friedrich	NNP	PERSON	Friedrich	appos	3	SENT_10	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],
51	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],

1	Loeff	NNP	PERSON	Loeff	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_12	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],
3	er	NN	O	er	dep	1	SENT_12	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],
4	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],

1	Institut	NNP	O	Institut	nn	3	SENT_14	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l244t1058r549b1083],
3	Greifswa	NNP	PERSON	Greifswa	dep	10	SENT_14	[p1l559t1058r749b1079],
4	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_14	[p1l559t1058r749b1079],
5	d	NN	O	d	dep	3	SENT_14	[p1l559t1058r749b1079],
6	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	5	SENT_14	[p1l559t1058r749b1079],
7	|	NN	O	|	nn	8	SENT_14	[p1l559t1058r749b1079],
8	nse	NN	O	nse	dep	10	SENT_14	[p1l559t1058r749b1079],
9	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	10	SENT_14	[p1l559t1058r749b1079],
10	Riems	NNS	O	riem	dep	43	SENT_14	[p1l761t1059r836b1083],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l761t1059r836b1083],
12	Germany	NNP	LOCATION	Germany	appos	10	SENT_14	[p1l846t1059r961b1085],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l846t1059r961b1085],
14	10	CD	NUMBER	10	num	17	SENT_14	[p1l973t1060r1004b1079],
15	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	nn	17	SENT_14	[p1l1012t1059r1156b1085],
16	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	amod	17	SENT_14	[p1l1166t1058r1191b1079],
17	Hematology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Hematology	appos	10	SENT_14	[p1l1200t1058r1353b1085],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1200t1058r1353b1085],
19	Leiden	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Leiden	nn	22	SENT_14	[p1l1364t1058r1442b1079],
20	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	nn	22	SENT_14	[p1l1454t1059r1572b1085],
21	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	nn	22	SENT_14	[p1l1582t1058r1673b1079],
22	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	appos	10	SENT_14	[p1l1684t1059r1769b1083],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1684t1059r1769b1083],
24	Leiden	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Leiden	appos	10	SENT_14	[p1l1781t1058r1865b1083],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1781t1058r1865b1083],
26	The	DT	LOCATION	the	det	27	SENT_14	[p1l1874t1058r1918b1079],
27	Netherlands	NNP	LOCATION	Netherlands	appos	10	SENT_14	[p1l1929t1058r2080b1083],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1929t1058r2080b1083],
29	11	CD	NUMBER	11	num	30	SENT_14	[p1l2092t1060r2118b1079],
30	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	appos	10	SENT_14	[p1l2131t1059r2276b1085],
31	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l2286t1058r2310b1079],
32	Tumor	NN	ORGANIZATION	tumor	nn	33	SENT_14	[p1l242t1101r322b1121],
33	Biology	NN	ORGANIZATION	biology	prep_of	30	SENT_14	[p1l334t1100r428b1127],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l334t1100r428b1127],
35	The	DT	O	the	det	40	SENT_14	[p1l439t1100r483b1121],
36	Netherlands	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Netherlands	nn	40	SENT_14	[p1l496t1100r640b1121],
37	Cancer	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Cancer	nn	40	SENT_14	[p1l652t1101r735b1121],
38	Institute	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Institute	nn	40	SENT_14	[p1l747t1101r851b1125],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l747t1101r851b1125],
40	Amsterdam	NNP	LOCATION	Amsterdam	appos	10	SENT_14	[p1l863t1100r1008b1125],
41	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l863t1100r1008b1125],
42	The	DT	LOCATION	the	det	43	SENT_14	[p1l1019t1100r1064b1121],
43	Netherlands	NNPS	LOCATION	Netherlands	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1076t1100r1221b1121],

1	Abstract	JJ	O	abstract	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l308t1216r475b1247],

1	Cytotoxic	JJ	MISC	cytotoxic	amod	5	SENT_16	[p1l309t1283r454b1317],
2	T	NN	O	t	nn	5	SENT_16	[p1l469t1282r697b1317],
3	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	5	SENT_16	[p1l469t1282r697b1317],
4	|	NN	O	|	nn	5	SENT_16	[p1l469t1282r697b1317],
5	ymphocytes	NNS	O	ymphocyte	nsubj	6	SENT_16	[p1l469t1282r697b1317],
6	play	VBP	O	play	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l714t1282r777b1317],
7	an	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_16	[p1l791t1290r826b1309],
8	important	JJ	O	important	amod	9	SENT_16	[p1l844t1283r998b1316],
9	role	NN	O	role	nsubj	29	SENT_16	[p1l1014t1282r1071b1309],
10	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1087t1283r1112b1309],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_16	[p1l1128t1282r1178b1309],
12	protection	NN	O	protection	prep_in	9	SENT_16	[p1l1195t1283r1354b1316],
13	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1371t1283r1482b1317],
14	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	15	SENT_16	[p1l1497t1282r1559b1309],
15	infections	NNS	O	infection	prep_against	12	SENT_16	[p1l1576t1282r1733b1314],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1576t1282r1733b1314],
17	which	WDT	O	which	dobj	19	SENT_16	[p1l1748t1282r1839b1309],
18	they	PRP	O	they	nsubj	19	SENT_16	[p1l1855t1282r1924b1317],
19	detect	VBP	O	detect	rcmod	9	SENT_16	[p1l1939t1282r2036b1309],
20	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l2051t1282r2176b1317],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_16	[p1l2192t1282r2242b1309],
22	recognition	NN	O	recognition	prep_through	19	SENT_16	[p1l310t1324r485b1358],
23	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l500t1323r532b1350],
24	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	22	SENT_16	[p1l542t1323r742b1350],
25	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	24	SENT_16	[p1l542t1323r742b1350],
26	derived	VBN	O	derive	partmod	24	SENT_16	[p1l542t1323r742b1350],
27	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	dobj	26	SENT_16	[p1l758t1323r898b1357],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l758t1323r898b1357],
29	presented	VBN	O	present	ccomp	6	SENT_16	[p1l913t1323r1066b1357],
30	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1082t1324r1106b1350],
31	the	DT	O	the	det	32	SENT_16	[p1l1120t1323r1170b1350],
32	context	NN	O	context	prep_in	29	SENT_16	[p1l1184t1328r1300b1350],
33	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1313t1323r1345b1350],
34	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	35	SENT_16	[p1l1356t1324r1429b1350],
35	class	NN	O	class	prep_of	32	SENT_16	[p1l1443t1323r1513b1350],
36	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	37	SENT_16	[p1l1527t1325r1531b1350],
37	molecules	NNS	O	molecule	dobj	29	SENT_16	[p1l1547t1323r1701b1350],
38	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1715t1328r1743b1350],
39	the	DT	O	the	det	40	SENT_16	[p1l1755t1323r1805b1350],
40	surface	NN	O	surface	prep_at	37	SENT_16	[p1l1819t1323r1928b1350],
41	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1941t1323r1973b1350],
42	the	DT	O	the	det	44	SENT_16	[p1l1983t1323r2033b1350],
43	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	44	SENT_16	[p1l2047t1323r2170b1350],
44	cell	NN	O	cell	prep_of	40	SENT_16	[p1l2185t1323r2242b1350],
45	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l2185t1323r2242b1350],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_17	[p1l307t1365r364b1392],
2	transporter	NN	O	transporter	nsubj	3	SENT_17	[p1l387t1370r561b1399],
3	associated	VBN	O	associate	dep	10	SENT_17	[p1l583t1365r743b1392],
4	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l767t1365r833b1392],
5	antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	6	SENT_17	[p1l858t1366r974b1400],
6	processing	NN	O	processing	prep_with	3	SENT_17	[p1l999t1366r1163b1400],
7	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	9	SENT_17	[p1l1190t1366r1267b1397],
8	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	9	SENT_17	[p1l1190t1366r1267b1397],
9	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	10	SENT_17	[p1l1190t1366r1267b1397],
10	plays	VBZ	O	play	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1293t1365r1369b1400],
11	an	DT	O	a	det	13	SENT_17	[p1l1392t1373r1427b1392],
12	essential	JJ	O	essential	amod	13	SENT_17	[p1l1452t1365r1583b1392],
13	role	NN	O	role	dobj	10	SENT_17	[p1l1609t1365r1665b1392],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1689t1366r1714b1392],
15	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	16	SENT_17	[p1l1739t1366r1812b1392],
16	class	NN	O	class	prep_in	13	SENT_17	[p1l1835t1365r1905b1392],
17	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	16	SENT_17	[p1l1930t1365r2100b1392],
18	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l1930t1365r2100b1392],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1930t1365r2100b1392],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l1930t1365r2100b1392],

1	restricted	JJ	O	restricted	amod	3	SENT_19	[p1l1930t1365r2100b1392],
2	antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	3	SENT_19	[p1l2125t1366r2241b1400],
3	presentation	NN	O	presentation	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l310t1407r513b1440],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l310t1407r513b1440],
5	as	IN	O	as	dep	3	SENT_19	[p1l524t1414r554b1433],
6	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	8	SENT_19	[p1l565t1408r625b1433],
7	imports	NNS	O	import	nn	8	SENT_19	[p1l637t1407r755b1440],
8	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	pobj	5	SENT_19	[p1l767t1406r901b1440],
9	into	IN	O	into	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l913t1407r972b1433],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_19	[p1l983t1406r1033b1433],
11	ER	NN	O	er	prep_into	8	SENT_19	[p1l1045t1408r1087b1438],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1045t1408r1087b1438],
13	where	WRB	O	where	advmod	21	SENT_19	[p1l1098t1406r1194b1433],
14	peptide	NN	O	peptide	nn	15	SENT_19	[p1l1207t1406r1325b1440],
15	loading	NN	O	loading	nsubj	21	SENT_19	[p1l1338t1406r1451b1441],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1464t1406r1496b1433],
17	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	18	SENT_19	[p1l1505t1407r1578b1433],
18	class	NN	O	class	prep_of	15	SENT_19	[p1l1590t1406r1660b1433],
19	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	20	SENT_19	[p1l1673t1408r1676b1433],
20	molecules	NNS	O	molecule	dep	18	SENT_19	[p1l1690t1406r1845b1433],
21	takes	VBZ	O	take	dep	3	SENT_19	[p1l1856t1406r1935b1433],
22	place	NN	O	place	dobj	21	SENT_19	[p1l1948t1406r2035b1440],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l1948t1406r2035b1440],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l2048t1408r2073b1433],
2	this	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_20	[p1l2085t1406r2139b1433],
3	study	NN	O	study	prep_in	43	SENT_20	[p1l2151t1406r2242b1441],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l2151t1406r2242b1441],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_20	[p1l308t1448r358b1475],
6	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	8	SENT_20	[p1l372t1450r473b1475],
7	.5	NN	NUMBER	.5	nn	8	SENT_20	[p1l372t1450r473b1475],
8	proteins	NNS	O	protein	nsubjpass	43	SENT_20	[p1l488t1449r613b1482],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l625t1448r657b1475],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_20	[p1l666t1448r716b1475],
11	varicelloviruses	NNS	O	varicellovirus	prep_of	8	SENT_20	[p1l727t1448r962b1475],
12	bovine	JJ	O	bovine	amod	25	SENT_20	[p1l976t1448r1080b1475],
13	herpesvirus	NN	O	herpesvirus	nn	25	SENT_20	[p1l1094t1448r1270b1482],
14	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	25	SENT_20	[p1l1285t1451r1293b1475],
15	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	25	SENT_20	[p1l1312t1449r1433b1480],
16	BHV	NNP	O	BHV	nn	25	SENT_20	[p1l1312t1449r1433b1480],
17	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	25	SENT_20	[p1l1312t1449r1433b1480],
18	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	25	SENT_20	[p1l1312t1449r1433b1480],
19	)	NN	O	)	nn	25	SENT_20	[p1l1312t1449r1433b1480],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1312t1449r1433b1480],
21	pseudorabies	NN	O	pseudoraby	dep	25	SENT_20	[p1l1446t1448r1653b1482],
22	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	25	SENT_20	[p1l1665t1449r1737b1475],
23	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	25	SENT_20	[p1l1750t1449r1836b1480],
24	PRV	NN	O	prv	nn	25	SENT_20	[p1l1750t1449r1836b1480],
25	)	NN	O	)	rcmod	11	SENT_20	[p1l1750t1449r1836b1480],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1750t1449r1836b1480],
27	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1849t1448r1905b1475],
28	equine	JJ	O	equine	amod	29	SENT_20	[p1l1918t1449r2024b1482],
29	herpesvirus	NN	O	herpesvirus	prep_of	8	SENT_20	[p1l2037t1448r2213b1482],
30	1	CD	NUMBER	1	number	33	SENT_20	[p1l2228t1451r2236b1475],
31	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l309t1489r365b1516],
32	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	35	SENT_20	[p1l381t1492r399b1516],
33	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	35	SENT_20	[p1l416t1490r511b1521],
34	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	nn	35	SENT_20	[p1l416t1490r511b1521],
35	—	NN	O	—	dep	11	SENT_20	[p1l416t1490r511b1521],
36	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	35	SENT_20	[p1l416t1490r511b1521],
37	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l533t1489r589b1516],
38	EHV	NN	O	ehv	prep_of	8	SENT_20	[p1l608t1490r708b1521],
39	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	40	SENT_20	[p1l608t1490r708b1521],
40	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	41	SENT_20	[p1l608t1490r708b1521],
41	)	NN	O	)	dep	38	SENT_20	[p1l608t1490r708b1521],
42	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	43	SENT_20	[p1l725t1497r771b1516],
43	characterized	VBN	O	characterize	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l787t1489r993b1516],
44	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1010t1497r1040b1516],
45	members	NNS	O	member	prep_as	43	SENT_20	[p1l1057t1489r1201b1516],
46	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1218t1489r1250b1516],
47	a	DT	O	a	det	49	SENT_20	[p1l1263t1497r1278b1516],
48	novel	JJ	O	novel	amod	49	SENT_20	[p1l1296t1489r1377b1516],
49	class	NN	O	class	prep_of	45	SENT_20	[p1l1395t1489r1465b1516],
50	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1481t1489r1513b1516],
51	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	54	SENT_20	[p1l1526t1489r1588b1516],
52	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	54	SENT_20	[p1l1606t1490r1733b1516],
53	evasion	NN	O	evasion	nn	54	SENT_20	[p1l1750t1490r1865b1516],
54	proteins	NNS	O	protein	prep_of	49	SENT_20	[p1l1883t1490r2017b1523],
55	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1883t1490r2017b1523],

1	These	DT	O	these	det	4	SENT_21	[p1l2032t1489r2122b1516],
2	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	4	SENT_21	[p1l2140t1491r2241b1516],
3	.5	NN	NUMBER	.5	nn	4	SENT_21	[p1l2140t1491r2241b1516],
4	proteins	NNS	O	protein	nsubj	5	SENT_21	[p1l310t1532r435b1565],
5	interfere	VBP	O	interfere	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l449t1531r578b1558],
6	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l591t1531r657b1558],
7	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	8	SENT_21	[p1l672t1532r744b1558],
8	class	NN	O	class	prep_with	5	SENT_21	[p1l757t1531r827b1558],
9	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	11	SENT_21	[p1l842t1533r845b1558],
10	antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	11	SENT_21	[p1l859t1532r975b1566],
11	presentation	NN	O	presentation	dobj	5	SENT_21	[p1l991t1532r1184b1565],
12	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1200t1531r1236b1566],
13	blocking	VBG	O	block	prepc_by	11	SENT_21	[p1l1249t1531r1379b1566],
14	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_21	[p1l1393t1531r1442b1558],
15	supply	NN	O	supply	dobj	13	SENT_21	[p1l1455t1531r1558b1566],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1570t1531r1601b1558],
17	antigenic	JJ	O	antigenic	amod	18	SENT_21	[p1l1611t1532r1754b1566],
18	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	prep_of	15	SENT_21	[p1l1768t1531r1901b1565],
19	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1913t1531r2038b1566],
20	inhibition	NN	O	inhibition	prep_through	13	SENT_21	[p1l2053t1531r2199b1558],
21	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l2213t1531r2245b1558],
22	TAP	NN	O	tap	prep_of	20	SENT_21	[p1l307t1574r375b1599],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l307t1574r375b1599],

1	BHV	NNP	O	BHV	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l390t1574r489b1604],
2	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	1	SENT_22	[p1l390t1574r489b1604],
3	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	1	SENT_22	[p1l390t1574r489b1604],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l390t1574r489b1604],
5	PRV	NN	O	prv	dep	1	SENT_22	[p1l504t1574r568b1604],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l504t1574r568b1604],
7	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l581t1572r637b1599],
8	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	conj_and	3	SENT_22	[p1l652t1574r737b1599],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l652t1574r737b1599],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l652t1574r737b1599],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l652t1574r737b1599],

1	I	PRP	O	I	nsubj	9	SENT_24	[p1l652t1574r737b1599],
2	recombinant	JJ	O	recombinant	amod	3	SENT_24	[p1l756t1572r954b1599],
3	viruses	NNS	O	virus	dep	1	SENT_24	[p1l966t1573r1071b1599],
4	lacking	VBG	O	lack	partmod	1	SENT_24	[p1l1085t1572r1191b1607],
5	UL49	NN	O	ul49	dobj	4	SENT_24	[p1l1206t1574r1308b1599],
6	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	num	5	SENT_24	[p1l1206t1574r1308b1599],
7	no	DT	O	no	dep	8	SENT_24	[p1l1323t1580r1360b1599],
8	longer	JJR	O	longer	advmod	4	SENT_24	[p1l1374t1572r1473b1607],
9	interfere	VBP	O	interfere	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1485t1572r1615b1599],
10	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1627t1572r1693b1599],
11	peptide	NN	O	peptide	nn	12	SENT_24	[p1l1708t1572r1826b1606],
12	transport	NN	O	transport	prep_with	9	SENT_24	[p1l1838t1577r1988b1606],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l1838t1577r1988b1606],

1	Combined	VBN	O	combine	prep	19	SENT_25	[p1l2001t1572r2161b1599],
2	with	IN	O	with	pcomp	1	SENT_25	[p1l2175t1572r2241b1599],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	4	SENT_25	[p1l308t1614r358b1641],
4	observation	NN	O	observation	pobj	2	SENT_25	[p1l370t1614r551b1641],
5	that	IN	O	that	complm	12	SENT_25	[p1l564t1614r625b1641],
6	the	DT	O	the	nsubj	12	SENT_25	[p1l636t1614r686b1641],
7	individually	RB	O	individually	advmod	8	SENT_25	[p1l698t1614r875b1649],
8	expressed	VBN	O	express	partmod	6	SENT_25	[p1l886t1614r1039b1648],
9	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	11	SENT_25	[p1l1053t1616r1155b1641],
10	.5	NN	NUMBER	.5	nn	11	SENT_25	[p1l1053t1616r1155b1641],
11	proteins	NNS	O	protein	dobj	8	SENT_25	[p1l1169t1615r1294b1648],
12	block	VBP	O	block	dep	4	SENT_25	[p1l1307t1614r1390b1641],
13	TAP	NN	O	tap	dobj	12	SENT_25	[p1l1398t1616r1459b1641],
14	as	RB	O	as	advmod	15	SENT_25	[p1l1470t1622r1500b1641],
15	well	RB	O	well	advmod	12	SENT_25	[p1l1511t1614r1580b1646],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1511t1614r1580b1646],
17	these	DT	O	these	det	18	SENT_25	[p1l1592t1614r1675b1641],
18	data	NNS	O	datum	nsubj	19	SENT_25	[p1l1687t1614r1752b1641],
19	indicate	VBP	O	indicate	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1766t1614r1887b1641],
20	that	IN	O	that	complm	26	SENT_25	[p1l1898t1614r1960b1641],
21	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nsubj	26	SENT_25	[p1l1972t1616r2074b1641],
22	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	num	21	SENT_25	[p1l1972t1616r2074b1641],
23	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	26	SENT_25	[p1l2087t1615r2107b1641],
24	the	DT	O	the	det	26	SENT_25	[p1l2118t1614r2168b1641],
25	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	26	SENT_25	[p1l2179t1614r2241b1641],
26	factor	NN	O	factor	ccomp	19	SENT_25	[p1l308t1655r398b1682],
27	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	30	SENT_25	[p1l415t1655r477b1682],
28	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	30	SENT_25	[p1l497t1656r517b1682],
29	both	DT	O	both	preconj	30	SENT_25	[p1l537t1655r607b1682],
30	necessary	JJ	O	necessary	rcmod	26	SENT_25	[p1l629t1663r778b1690],
31	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l796t1655r852b1682],
32	sufficient	JJ	O	sufficient	rcmod	26	SENT_25	[p1l873t1655r1013b1682],
33	to	TO	O	to	aux	34	SENT_25	[p1l1031t1660r1062b1682],
34	abolish	VB	O	abolish	xcomp	30	SENT_25	[p1l1081t1655r1190b1682],
35	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	36	SENT_25	[p1l1209t1657r1269b1682],
36	function	NN	O	function	dobj	34	SENT_25	[p1l1287t1655r1416b1682],
37	during	IN	O	during	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1436t1655r1536b1690],
38	productive	JJ	O	productive	amod	39	SENT_25	[p1l1558t1655r1724b1689],
39	infection	NN	O	infection	prep_during	34	SENT_25	[p1l1744t1655r1877b1682],
40	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l1899t1655r1935b1690],
41	these	DT	O	these	det	42	SENT_25	[p1l1953t1655r2036b1682],
42	viruses	NNS	O	virus	prep_by	34	SENT_25	[p1l2054t1656r2167b1682],
43	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l2054t1656r2167b1682],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_26	[p1l2185t1655r2242b1682],
2	mechanisms	NNS	O	mechanism	nsubj	26	SENT_26	[p1l310t1697r501b1724],
3	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l517t1697r642b1732],
4	which	WDT	O	which	rel	24	SENT_26	[p1l659t1697r750b1724],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_26	[p1l767t1697r817b1724],
6	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	8	SENT_26	[p1l835t1699r937b1724],
7	.5	NN	NUMBER	.5	nn	8	SENT_26	[p1l835t1699r937b1724],
8	proteins	NNS	O	protein	nsubj	24	SENT_26	[p1l955t1698r1081b1731],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1098t1697r1129b1724],
10	BHV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	BHV	prep_of	8	SENT_26	[p1l1144t1699r1244b1729],
11	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	12	SENT_26	[p1l1144t1699r1244b1729],
12	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	10	SENT_26	[p1l1144t1699r1244b1729],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1144t1699r1244b1729],
14	PRV	NN	O	prv	conj_and	10	SENT_26	[p1l1262t1699r1327b1729],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1262t1699r1327b1729],
16	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	nn	17	SENT_26	[p1l1345t1699r1443b1729],
17	—	NN	O	—	conj_and	10	SENT_26	[p1l1345t1699r1443b1729],
18	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	17	SENT_26	[p1l1345t1699r1443b1729],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1345t1699r1443b1729],
20	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1459t1697r1515b1724],
21	EHV	NN	O	ehv	conj_and	10	SENT_26	[p1l1534t1699r1625b1724],
22	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	23	SENT_26	[p1l1534t1699r1625b1724],
23	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	21	SENT_26	[p1l1534t1699r1625b1724],
24	block	NN	O	block	rcmod	2	SENT_26	[p1l1642t1697r1725b1724],
25	TAP	NN	O	tap	dobj	24	SENT_26	[p1l1739t1699r1799b1724],
26	exhibit	VBP	O	exhibit	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l1816t1697r1921b1724],
27	surprising	JJ	O	surprising	amod	28	SENT_26	[p1l1937t1698r2087b1732],
28	diversity	NN	O	diversity	dobj	26	SENT_26	[p1l2105t1697r2242b1732],
29	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l2105t1697r2242b1732],

1	BHV	NNP	O	BHV	nsubj	7	SENT_27	[p1l310t1740r397b1765],
2	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	1	SENT_27	[p1l310t1740r397b1765],
3	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	6	SENT_27	[p1l310t1740r397b1765],
4	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	6	SENT_27	[p1l416t1740r518b1765],
5	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	num	6	SENT_27	[p1l416t1740r518b1765],
6	targets	NNS	O	target	dep	1	SENT_27	[p1l531t1743r638b1773],
7	TAP	VBP	O	tap	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l649t1740r710b1765],
8	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l722t1738r764b1765],
9	proteasomal	JJ	O	proteasomal	amod	10	SENT_27	[p1l777t1738r968b1772],
10	degradation	NN	O	degradation	prep_for	7	SENT_27	[p1l982t1738r1179b1773],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l982t1738r1179b1773],
12	whereas	IN	O	whereas	mark	22	SENT_27	[p1l1191t1738r1319b1765],
13	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	nsubj	22	SENT_27	[p1l1333t1740r1418b1765],
14	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	15	SENT_27	[p1l1333t1740r1418b1765],
15	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	13	SENT_27	[p1l1333t1740r1418b1765],
16	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1436t1738r1492b1765],
17	EHV	NN	O	ehv	conj_and	13	SENT_27	[p1l1507t1740r1598b1765],
18	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	19	SENT_27	[p1l1507t1740r1598b1765],
19	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	17	SENT_27	[p1l1507t1740r1598b1765],
20	UL49	NN	O	ul49	dep	19	SENT_27	[p1l1611t1740r1713b1765],
21	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	num	20	SENT_27	[p1l1611t1740r1713b1765],
22	interfere	VBP	O	interfere	advcl	7	SENT_27	[p1l1727t1738r1856b1765],
23	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l1868t1738r1934b1765],
24	the	DT	O	the	det	25	SENT_27	[p1l1948t1738r1997b1765],
25	binding	NN	O	binding	prep_with	22	SENT_27	[p1l2011t1738r2128b1773],
26	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l2142t1738r2173b1765],
27	ATP	NN	O	atp	prep_of	25	SENT_27	[p1l2183t1740r2242b1765],
28	to	TO	O	to	aux	29	SENT_27	[p1l308t1785r339b1807],
29	TAP	VB	O	tap	xcomp	22	SENT_27	[p1l351t1782r419b1807],
30	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_27	[p1l351t1782r419b1807],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l433t1782r458b1807],
2	contrast	NN	O	contrast	prep_in	11	SENT_28	[p1l472t1785r604b1812],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l472t1785r604b1812],
4	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	5	SENT_28	[p1l616t1782r676b1807],
5	stability	NN	O	stability	conj_and	2	SENT_28	[p1l690t1780r810b1815],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l822t1780r878b1807],
7	ATP	NN	O	atp	nn	8	SENT_28	[p1l891t1782r950b1807],
8	recruitment	NN	O	recruitment	conj_and	2	SENT_28	[p1l965t1781r1145b1807],
9	are	VBP	O	be	auxpass	11	SENT_28	[p1l1158t1788r1204b1807],
10	not	RB	O	not	neg	11	SENT_28	[p1l1218t1785r1269b1807],
11	affected	VBN	O	affect	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1281t1780r1404b1807],
12	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1420t1780r1456b1815],
13	PRV	NN	O	prv	nn	14	SENT_28	[p1l1469t1782r1527b1807],
14	UL49	NN	O	ul49	agent	11	SENT_28	[p1l1541t1782r1651b1812],
15	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	num	14	SENT_28	[p1l1541t1782r1651b1812],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1541t1782r1651b1812],
17	although	IN	O	although	mark	19	SENT_28	[p1l1664t1780r1802b1815],
18	it	PRP	O	it	nsubj	19	SENT_28	[p1l1818t1781r1836b1807],
19	has	VBZ	O	have	advcl	11	SENT_28	[p1l1849t1780r1899b1807],
20	the	DT	O	the	det	21	SENT_28	[p1l1911t1780r1961b1807],
21	capacity	NN	O	capacity	dobj	19	SENT_28	[p1l1974t1781r2101b1815],
22	to	TO	O	to	aux	23	SENT_28	[p1l2113t1785r2144b1807],
23	arrest	VB	O	arrest	infmod	21	SENT_28	[p1l2157t1785r2243b1807],
24	the	DT	O	the	det	26	SENT_28	[p1l308t1821r358b1848],
25	peptide	NN	O	peptide	nn	26	SENT_28	[p1l374t1821r493b1855],
26	transporter	NN	O	transporter	dobj	23	SENT_28	[p1l507t1826r681b1855],
27	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l696t1822r721b1848],
28	a	DT	O	a	det	32	SENT_28	[p1l737t1829r752b1848],
29	trans	JJ	O	trans	amod	32	SENT_28	[p1l767t1821r1183b1855],
30	|	NN	O	|	nn	32	SENT_28	[p1l767t1821r1183b1855],
31	ocation	NN	O	ocation	nn	32	SENT_28	[p1l767t1821r1183b1855],
32	—	NN	O	—	prep_in	23	SENT_28	[p1l767t1821r1183b1855],
33	incompetent	JJ	O	incompetent	amod	34	SENT_28	[p1l767t1821r1183b1855],
34	state	NN	O	state	nsubjpass	11	SENT_28	[p1l1198t1826r1279b1853],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1198t1826r1279b1853],
36	a	DT	O	a	det	37	SENT_28	[p1l1294t1829r1309b1848],
37	property	NN	O	property	appos	34	SENT_28	[p1l1326t1826r1459b1856],
38	shared	VBN	O	share	partmod	37	SENT_28	[p1l1473t1821r1574b1848],
39	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1590t1821r1656b1848],
40	the	DT	O	the	det	42	SENT_28	[p1l1672t1821r1722b1848],
41	BHV	NNP	O	BHV	nn	42	SENT_28	[p1l1738t1823r1825b1848],
42	—	NN	O	—	prep_with	38	SENT_28	[p1l1738t1823r1825b1848],
43	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	42	SENT_28	[p1l1738t1823r1825b1848],
44	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l1845t1821r1901b1848],
45	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	nn	46	SENT_28	[p1l1919t1823r2003b1848],
46	—	NN	O	—	conj_and	42	SENT_28	[p1l1919t1823r2003b1848],
47	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	48	SENT_28	[p1l1919t1823r2003b1848],
48	UL49	NN	O	ul49	tmod	38	SENT_28	[p1l2026t1823r2136b1848],
49	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	dep	48	SENT_28	[p1l2026t1823r2136b1848],
50	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_28	[p1l2026t1823r2136b1848],

1	Taken	VBN	O	take	partmod	6	SENT_29	[p1l2150t1821r2241b1848],
2	together	RB	O	together	advmod	1	SENT_29	[p1l308t1863r450b1898],
3	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l308t1863r450b1898],
4	these	DT	O	these	det	5	SENT_29	[p1l463t1863r547b1890],
5	results	NNS	O	result	nsubj	6	SENT_29	[p1l561t1863r659b1890],
6	classify	VBP	O	classify	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l673t1863r781b1898],
7	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_29	[p1l792t1863r842b1890],
8	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	11	SENT_29	[p1l857t1865r959b1890],
9	.5	NN	NUMBER	.5	nn	11	SENT_29	[p1l857t1865r959b1890],
10	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	11	SENT_29	[p1l973t1871r1049b1898],
11	products	NNS	O	product	dobj	6	SENT_29	[p1l1064t1863r1200b1897],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1213t1863r1245b1890],
13	BHV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	BHV	prep_of	11	SENT_29	[p1l1257t1865r1357b1895],
14	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	13	SENT_29	[p1l1257t1865r1357b1895],
15	1	CD	NUMBER	1	tmod	6	SENT_29	[p1l1257t1865r1357b1895],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1257t1865r1357b1895],
17	PRV	NN	O	prv	appos	15	SENT_29	[p1l1371t1865r1436b1895],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1371t1865r1436b1895],
19	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	appos	17	SENT_29	[p1l1451t1865r1549b1895],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_29	[p1l1451t1865r1549b1895],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1451t1865r1549b1895],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_30	[p1l1451t1865r1549b1895],

1	I	PRP	O	I	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1451t1865r1549b1895],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1451t1865r1549b1895],
3	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1562t1863r1618b1890],
4	EHV	NN	O	ehv	conj_and	1	SENT_31	[p1l1634t1865r1725b1890],
5	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	6	SENT_31	[p1l1634t1865r1725b1890],
6	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	1	SENT_31	[p1l1634t1865r1725b1890],
7	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1738t1871r1768b1890],
8	members	NNS	O	member	prep_as	6	SENT_31	[p1l1782t1863r1926b1890],
9	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1940t1863r1971b1890],
10	a	DT	O	a	det	12	SENT_31	[p1l1982t1871r1997b1890],
11	novel	JJ	O	novel	amod	12	SENT_31	[p1l2012t1863r2093b1890],
12	family	NN	O	family	prep_of	8	SENT_31	[p1l2107t1863r2201b1898],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l2213t1863r2245b1890],
14	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	17	SENT_31	[p1l308t1904r370b1931],
15	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	17	SENT_31	[p1l387t1905r514b1931],
16	evasion	NN	O	evasion	nn	17	SENT_31	[p1l530t1905r645b1931],
17	proteins	NNS	O	protein	prep_of	12	SENT_31	[p1l662t1905r795b1938],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l662t1905r795b1938],
19	inhibiting	VBG	O	inhibit	partmod	1	SENT_31	[p1l811t1904r957b1939],
20	TAP	NN	O	tap	dobj	19	SENT_31	[p1l972t1906r1032b1931],
21	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1047t1904r1172b1939],
22	a	DT	O	a	det	23	SENT_31	[p1l1188t1912r1203b1931],
23	variety	NN	O	variety	prep_through	19	SENT_31	[p1l1218t1905r1322b1939],
24	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1336t1904r1368b1931],
25	mechanisms	NNS	O	mechanism	prep_of	1	SENT_31	[p1l1381t1904r1580b1931],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_31	[p1l1381t1904r1580b1931],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l278t2009r396b2030],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l278t2009r396b2030],
3	Koppers	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Koppers	dep	1	SENT_32	[p1l411t2009r571b2036],
4	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_32	[p1l411t2009r571b2036],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l411t2009r571b2036],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_33	[p1l411t2009r571b2036],

1	La	NNP	O	La	nn	4	SENT_34	[p1l411t2009r571b2036],
2	|	NNP	O	|	nn	4	SENT_34	[p1l411t2009r571b2036],
3	ic	NN	O	ic	nn	4	SENT_34	[p1l411t2009r571b2036],
4	D	NN	O	d	nsubj	28	SENT_34	[p1l586t2010r608b2034],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l586t2010r608b2034],
6	Verweij	NNP	O	Verweij	nn	7	SENT_34	[p1l621t2010r709b2036],
7	MC	NNP	O	MC	appos	4	SENT_34	[p1l724t2010r768b2034],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l724t2010r768b2034],
9	Lipinska	NNP	LOCATION	Lipinska	nn	10	SENT_34	[p1l783t2009r878b2036],
10	AD	NN	O	ad	appos	4	SENT_34	[p1l892t2010r933b2034],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l892t2010r933b2034],
12	Wang	NNP	PERSON	Wang	nn	13	SENT_34	[p1l947t2010r1015b2036],
13	Y	NN	PERSON	y	appos	4	SENT_34	[p1l1030t2010r1050b2034],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1030t2010r1050b2034],
15	Quinten	NNP	PERSON	Quinten	nn	16	SENT_34	[p1l1063t2010r1160b2033],
16	E	NNP	PERSON	E	appos	4	SENT_34	[p1l1175t2010r1192b2034],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1175t2010r1192b2034],
18	et	FW	O	et	appos	4	SENT_34	[p1l1206t2013r1229b2030],
19	al.	FW	O	al.	nn	20	SENT_34	[p1l1242t2009r1267b2030],
20	(	FW	O	(	dep	18	SENT_34	[p1l1281t2010r1354b2034],
21	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	26	SENT_34	[p1l1281t2010r1354b2034],
22	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	26	SENT_34	[p1l1281t2010r1354b2034],
23	Varicellovirus	NNP	O	Varicellovirus	nn	26	SENT_34	[p1l1368t2009r1527b2030],
24	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	26	SENT_34	[p1l1542t2010r1621b2030],
25	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	num	26	SENT_34	[p1l1542t2010r1621b2030],
26	Proteins	NNS	O	protein	dep	4	SENT_34	[p1l1637t2010r1733b2030],
27	Differentially	RB	O	differentially	advmod	28	SENT_34	[p1l1748t2009r1900b2036],
28	Affect	VB	O	affect	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l1913t2009r1984b2030],
29	the	DT	O	the	det	30	SENT_34	[p1l1997t2009r2036b2030],
30	Function	NN	O	function	dobj	28	SENT_34	[p1l2050t2010r2154b2030],
31	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l2169t2009r2194b2030],
32	the	DT	O	the	det	34	SENT_34	[p1l2205t2009r2244b2030],
33	Transporter	NNP	O	Transporter	nn	34	SENT_34	[p1l277t2043r418b2069],
34	Associated	NNP	O	Associated	prep_of	30	SENT_34	[p1l429t2042r557b2063],
35	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l570t2042r621b2063],
36	Antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	37	SENT_34	[p1l634t2043r728b2069],
37	Processing	NN	O	processing	prep_with	28	SENT_34	[p1l742t2043r875b2069],
38	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l742t2043r875b2069],
39	TAP	NN	O	tap	appos	37	SENT_34	[p1l886t2043r939b2063],
40	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_34	[p1l886t2043r939b2063],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_35	[p1l952t2043r1008b2063],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1021t2042r1104b2069],
3	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	4	SENT_35	[p1l1116t2043r1167b2067],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_35	[p1l1116t2043r1167b2067],
5	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	6	SENT_35	[p1l1116t2043r1167b2067],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_35	[p1l1116t2043r1167b2067],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1116t2043r1167b2067],
8	eI000080	NN	O	ei000080	dep	2	SENT_35	[p1l1179t2044r1301b2063],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_35	[p1l1179t2044r1301b2063],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],
2	:10.1371	CD	NUMBER	:10.1371	dep	1	SENT_36	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],
3	/	:	O	/	punct	5	SENT_36	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],
4	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	5	SENT_36	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],
5	|	NN	O	|	dep	2	SENT_36	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_36	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_37	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],

1	I000080	NNP	O	I000080	nn	2	SENT_38	[p1l1313t2042r1720b2069],
2	Editor	NNP	O	Editor	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l279t2094r370b2115],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l279t2094r370b2115],
4	Bill	NNP	PERSON	Bill	nn	5	SENT_38	[p1l382t2094r414b2115],
5	Sugden	NNP	PERSON	Sugden	dep	2	SENT_38	[p1l427t2094r524b2121],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l427t2094r524b2121],
7	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	appos	5	SENT_38	[p1l537t2095r656b2121],
8	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l667t2094r692b2115],
9	Wisconsin	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Wisconsin	prep_of	7	SENT_38	[p1l701t2094r939b2119],
10	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_38	[p1l701t2094r939b2119],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l701t2094r939b2119],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_39	[p1l701t2094r939b2119],

1	Madison	NNP	O	Madison	nn	4	SENT_40	[p1l701t2094r939b2119],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l701t2094r939b2119],
3	United	NNP	ORGANIZATION	United	appos	4	SENT_40	[p1l953t2094r1031b2115],
4	States	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	States	nsubj	7	SENT_40	[p1l1044t2095r1115b2115],
5	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1127t2094r1151b2115],
6	America	NNP	ORGANIZATION	America	prep_of	4	SENT_40	[p1l1161t2095r1258b2115],
7	Received	VBD	O	receive	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l279t2146r401b2167],
8	July	NNP	DATE	July	nsubj	19	SENT_40	[p1l413t2146r460b2173],
9	24	CD	DATE	24	num	8	SENT_40	[p1l471t2148r504b2171],
10	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l471t2148r504b2171],
11	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	8	SENT_40	[p1l516t2148r580b2171],
12	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l516t2148r580b2171],
13	Accepted	JJ	O	accepted	amod	8	SENT_40	[p1l591t2146r720b2173],
14	April	NNP	DATE	April	tmod	13	SENT_40	[p1l732t2146r787b2173],
15	28	CD	DATE	28	num	14	SENT_40	[p1l799t2148r832b2171],
16	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l799t2148r832b2171],
17	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	14	SENT_40	[p1l844t2148r908b2171],
18	;	:	O	;	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l844t2148r908b2171],
19	Published	VBN	O	publish	ccomp	7	SENT_40	[p1l921t2146r1056b2167],
20	May	NNP	DATE	May	tmod	19	SENT_40	[p1l1069t2147r1118b2173],
21	30	CD	DATE	30	num	20	SENT_40	[p1l1129t2148r1162b2171],
22	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l1129t2148r1162b2171],
23	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	24	SENT_40	[p1l1175t2148r1232b2167],
24	Copyright	NN	O	copyright	dobj	19	SENT_40	[p1l278t2198r425b2225],
25	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l278t2198r425b2225],
26	©	CD	NUMBER	©	num	27	SENT_40	[p1l437t2200r457b2219],
27	2008	CD	DATE	2008	dep	24	SENT_40	[p1l469t2200r526b2219],
28	Koppers	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Koppers	dep	27	SENT_40	[p1l538t2198r698b2225],
29	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_40	[p1l538t2198r698b2225],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l538t2198r698b2225],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_41	[p1l538t2198r698b2225],

1	La	NNP	O	La	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l538t2198r698b2225],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	1	SENT_42	[p1l538t2198r698b2225],
3	ic	JJ	O	ic	dep	1	SENT_42	[p1l538t2198r698b2225],
4	et	FW	O	et	nn	5	SENT_42	[p1l709t2202r732b2219],
5	al.	FW	O	al.	dep	3	SENT_42	[p1l742t2198r767b2219],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_42	[p1l742t2198r767b2219],

1	Funding	NNP	O	Funding	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l279t2283r401b2310],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l279t2283r401b2310],
3	This	DT	O	this	det	4	SENT_44	[p1l409t2283r457b2304],
4	work	NN	O	work	nsubjpass	6	SENT_44	[p1l466t2283r526b2304],
5	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_44	[p1l535t2290r580b2304],
6	supported	VBN	O	support	dep	1	SENT_44	[p1l590t2283r714b2310],
7	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l725t2283r753b2310],
8	a	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_44	[p1l762t2290r774b2304],
9	grant	NN	O	grant	agent	6	SENT_44	[p1l784t2287r847b2310],
10	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l856t2283r912b2304],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_44	[p1l922t2283r961b2304],
12	Dutch	JJ	ORGANIZATION	dutch	amod	15	SENT_44	[p1l972t2283r1042b2304],
13	Diabetes	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Diabetes	nn	15	SENT_44	[p1l1054t2283r1157b2304],
14	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	nn	15	SENT_44	[p1l1168t2283r1273b2304],
15	Foundation	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Foundation	prep_from	9	SENT_44	[p1l1285t2283r1422b2304],
16	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	15	SENT_44	[p1l1433t2284r1464b2308],
17	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1433t2284r1464b2308],
18	DKL	NNP	O	DKL	prep_to	15	SENT_44	[p1l1475t2284r1535b2308],
19	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	18	SENT_44	[p1l1475t2284r1535b2308],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1475t2284r1535b2308],
21	a	DT	O	a	det	25	SENT_44	[p1l1544t2290r1556b2304],
22	FEBS	NNP	O	FEBS	nn	25	SENT_44	[p1l1567t2284r1623b2304],
23	Collaborative	NNP	O	Collaborative	nn	25	SENT_44	[p1l1632t2283r1791b2304],
24	Experimental	JJ	O	experimental	amod	25	SENT_44	[p1l1802t2283r1958b2310],
25	Scholarship	NN	O	scholarship	appos	15	SENT_44	[p1l1969t2283r2107b2310],
26	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l2116t2283r2149b2304],
27	Central	NNP	O	Central	nn	30	SENT_44	[p1l2158t2283r2243b2304],
28	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l278t2316r322b2337],
29	Eastern	NNP	LOCATION	Eastern	nn	30	SENT_44	[p1l333t2317r418b2337],
30	Europe	NNP	LOCATION	Europe	prep_for	25	SENT_44	[p1l430t2317r514b2343],
31	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	30	SENT_44	[p1l524t2317r555b2341],
32	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l524t2317r555b2341],
33	ADL	NNP	ORGANIZATION	ADL	prep_to	30	SENT_44	[p1l564t2317r628b2341],
34	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	33	SENT_44	[p1l564t2317r628b2341],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l564t2317r628b2341],
36	grant	NN	O	grant	nn	37	SENT_44	[p1l637t2320r700b2343],
37	no.	NN	O	no.	appos	15	SENT_44	[p1l711t2323r746b2337],
38	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	39	SENT_44	[p1l756t2318r768b2337],
39	P048	NN	O	p048	dep	37	SENT_44	[p1l779t2317r841b2337],
40	010	CD	NUMBER	010	number	41	SENT_44	[p1l850t2318r893b2337],
41	30	CD	NUMBER	30	npadvmod	6	SENT_44	[p1l902t2318r930b2337],
42	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l938t2316r994b2337],
43	the	DT	O	the	det	44	SENT_44	[p1l1004t2316r1043b2337],
44	Ministry	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Ministry	prep_from	6	SENT_44	[p1l1053t2317r1148b2343],
45	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1157t2316r1181b2337],
46	Science	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Science	prep_of	44	SENT_44	[p1l1189t2317r1279b2337],
47	and	CC	ORGANIZATION	and	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1288t2316r1331b2337],
48	Education	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Education	conj_and	46	SENT_44	[p1l1343t2316r1461b2337],
49	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1471t2316r1496b2337],
50	Poland	NNP	LOCATION	Poland	prep_of	44	SENT_44	[p1l1504t2316r1585b2337],
51	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	50	SENT_44	[p1l1596t2317r1627b2341],
52	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1596t2317r1627b2341],
53	ADL	NNP	ORGANIZATION	ADL	prep_to	6	SENT_44	[p1l1636t2317r1699b2341],
54	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	53	SENT_44	[p1l1636t2317r1699b2341],
55	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l1636t2317r1699b2341],
56	Public	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Public	nn	60	SENT_44	[p1l1710t2316r1781b2337],
57	Health	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Health	nn	60	SENT_44	[p1l1792t2316r1868b2337],
58	Service	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Service	nn	60	SENT_44	[p1l1879t2317r1963b2337],
59	grant	NN	O	grant	nn	60	SENT_44	[p1l1972t2320r2036b2343],
60	no.	NN	O	no.	appos	53	SENT_44	[p1l2046t2323r2081b2337],
61	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_44	[p1l2046t2323r2081b2337],

1	A	DT	O	a	det	2	SENT_45	[p1l2090t2317r2202b2337],
2	|	NN	O	|	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2090t2317r2202b2337],
3	063048	CD	NUMBER	063048	num	4	SENT_45	[p1l2090t2317r2202b2337],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_45	[p1l2213t2317r2244b2341],
5	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2213t2317r2244b2341],
6	NO	NN	O	no	nn	7	SENT_45	[p1l279t2350r329b2374],
7	)	NN	O	)	prep_to	4	SENT_45	[p1l279t2350r329b2374],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l279t2350r329b2374],
9	USDA	NNP	ORGANIZATION	USDA	nn	10	SENT_45	[p1l341t2350r408b2370],
10	grant	NN	O	grant	appos	7	SENT_45	[p1l418t2353r482b2376],
11	07	CD	NUMBER	07	number	12	SENT_45	[p1l492t2351r686b2370],
12	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	10	SENT_45	[p1l492t2351r686b2370],
13	35204	CD	NUMBER	35204	number	14	SENT_45	[p1l492t2351r686b2370],
14	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	16	SENT_45	[p1l492t2351r686b2370],
15	l7358	NN	O	l7358	nn	16	SENT_45	[p1l492t2351r686b2370],
16	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_45	[p1l697t2350r728b2374],
17	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l697t2350r728b2374],
18	SIC	NNP	O	SIC	prep_to	16	SENT_45	[p1l739t2350r789b2374],
19	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	18	SENT_45	[p1l739t2350r789b2374],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l739t2350r789b2374],
21	EMBO	NNP	O	EMBO	appos	2	SENT_45	[p1l800t2350r870b2370],
22	short	JJ	O	short	amod	25	SENT_45	[p1l881t2349r941b2370],
23	term	NN	O	term	nn	25	SENT_45	[p1l951t2353r1007b2370],
24	fellowship	NN	O	fellowship	nn	25	SENT_45	[p1l1017t2349r1140b2376],
25	ASTF	NN	O	astf	dep	21	SENT_45	[p1l1151t2350r1209b2370],
26	152005	CD	NUMBER	152005	num	27	SENT_45	[p1l1222t2351r1315b2370],
27	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_45	[p1l1327t2350r1358b2374],
28	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1327t2350r1358b2374],
29	JK	NNP	O	JK	nn	30	SENT_45	[p1l1367t2350r1407b2374],
30	)	NNP	O	)	prep_to	27	SENT_45	[p1l1367t2350r1407b2374],
31	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1367t2350r1407b2374],
32	the	DT	O	the	det	35	SENT_45	[p1l1417t2349r1456b2370],
33	Dutch	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Dutch	nn	35	SENT_45	[p1l1467t2349r1537b2370],
34	Cancer	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Cancer	nn	35	SENT_45	[p1l1548t2350r1631b2370],
35	Society	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Society	appos	2	SENT_45	[p1l1641t2350r1727b2376],
36	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	37	SENT_45	[p1l1738t2350r1809b2376],
37	grant	NN	O	grant	dep	35	SENT_45	[p1l1738t2350r1809b2376],
38	UL	NNP	O	UL	dep	2	SENT_45	[p1l1820t2350r1850b2370],
39	2005-3259	CD	DURATION	2005-3259	num	38	SENT_45	[p1l1860t2351r1991b2374],
40	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1860t2351r1991b2374],
41	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2001t2353r2025b2370],
42	MER	NNP	O	MER	prep_to	38	SENT_45	[p1l2036t2350r2087b2370],
43	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2097t2349r2140b2370],
44	EJHJW	NNP	O	EJHJW	prep_to	38	SENT_45	[p1l2153t2350r2244b2374],
45	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	44	SENT_45	[p1l2153t2350r2244b2374],
46	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l2153t2350r2244b2374],
47	the	DT	O	the	det	51	SENT_45	[p1l278t2383r317b2404],
48	M.W.	NNP	ORGANIZATION	M.W.	nn	51	SENT_45	[p1l330t2384r388b2404],
49	Beijerinck	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Beijerinck	nn	51	SENT_45	[p1l402t2383r517b2410],
50	Virology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Virology	nn	51	SENT_45	[p1l528t2383r629b2410],
51	Fund	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Fund	appos	2	SENT_45	[p1l642t2383r701b2404],
52	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l715t2383r740b2404],
53	the	DT	ORGANIZATION	the	det	55	SENT_45	[p1l750t2383r789b2404],
54	Royal	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Royal	nn	55	SENT_45	[p1l803t2383r865b2410],
55	Academy	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Academy	prep_of	51	SENT_45	[p1l879t2383r991b2410],
56	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1004t2383r1029b2404],
57	Arts	NNS	ORGANIZATION	art	prep_of	55	SENT_45	[p1l1039t2384r1086b2404],
58	and	CC	ORGANIZATION	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1099t2383r1142b2404],
59	Sciences	NNPS	ORGANIZATION	Sciences	prep_of	55	SENT_45	[p1l1157t2384r1258b2404],
60	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	2	SENT_45	[p1l1272t2384r1303b2408],
61	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1272t2384r1303b2408],
62	MER	NNP	MISC	MER	prep_to	60	SENT_45	[p1l1317t2384r1381b2408],
63	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	62	SENT_45	[p1l1317t2384r1381b2408],
64	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1317t2384r1381b2408],
65	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1395t2383r1438b2404],
66	the	DT	O	the	det	68	SENT_45	[p1l1452t2383r1491b2404],
67	Netherlands	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Netherlands	nn	68	SENT_45	[p1l1505t2383r1649b2404],
68	Organisation	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Organisation	conj_and	60	SENT_45	[p1l1662t2384r1816b2410],
69	for	IN	ORGANIZATION	for	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l1829t2383r1862b2404],
70	Scientific	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Scientific	nn	74	SENT_45	[p1l1875t2383r1982b2404],
71	Research	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Research	nn	74	SENT_45	[p1l1996t2383r2101b2404],
72	(	NNP	O	(	nn	74	SENT_45	[p1l2116t2383r2167b2408],
73	Vidi	NNP	PERSON	Vidi	nn	74	SENT_45	[p1l2116t2383r2167b2408],
74	grant	NN	O	grant	prep_for	68	SENT_45	[p1l2180t2387r2244b2410],
75	917.76.330	CD	NUMBER	917.76.330	num	74	SENT_45	[p1l278t2418r413b2441],
76	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l278t2418r413b2441],
77	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l424t2420r449b2437],
78	MER	NNP	O	MER	prep_to	2	SENT_45	[p1l461t2417r526b2441],
79	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	78	SENT_45	[p1l461t2417r526b2441],
80	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_45	[p1l461t2417r526b2441],

1	Competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	2	SENT_46	[p1l278t2468r431b2495],
2	Interests	NNS	O	interest	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l444t2469r571b2489],
3	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l444t2469r571b2489],
4	The	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_46	[p1l581t2468r626b2489],
5	authors	NNS	O	author	nsubj	7	SENT_46	[p1l637t2468r728b2489],
6	have	VBP	O	have	aux	7	SENT_46	[p1l741t2468r796b2489],
7	declared	VBN	O	declare	dep	2	SENT_46	[p1l808t2468r910b2489],
8	that	IN	O	that	complm	12	SENT_46	[p1l922t2468r970b2489],
9	no	DT	O	no	det	11	SENT_46	[p1l982t2474r1011b2489],
10	competing	VBG	O	compete	amod	11	SENT_46	[p1l1023t2469r1153b2495],
11	interests	NNS	O	interest	nsubj	12	SENT_46	[p1l1167t2469r1268b2489],
12	exist	VBP	O	exist	ccomp	7	SENT_46	[p1l1279t2469r1339b2489],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_46	[p1l1279t2469r1339b2489],

1	*	NN	O	*	nn	2	SENT_47	[p1l278t2521r289b2531],
2	E	NN	O	e	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l301t2520r379b2541],
3	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	2	SENT_47	[p1l301t2520r379b2541],
4	mai	FW	O	mai	nn	5	SENT_47	[p1l301t2520r379b2541],
5	|	FW	O	|	dep	2	SENT_47	[p1l301t2520r379b2541],
6	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l301t2520r379b2541],
7	wiertz	NN	O	wiertz	dep	2	SENT_47	[p1l390t2520r572b2541],
8	@	IN	O	@	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l390t2520r572b2541],
9	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	10	SENT_47	[p1l390t2520r572b2541],
10	umc	NN	O	umc	prep_@	7	SENT_47	[p1l390t2520r572b2541],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_47	[p1l390t2520r572b2541],

1	n	NN	O	n	_	0	SENT_48	[p1l390t2520r572b2541],
2	|	SYM	O	|	dep	1	SENT_48	[p1l390t2520r572b2541],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l278t2576r291b2589],
2	Current	JJ	DATE	current	amod	3	SENT_49	[p1l303t2572r393b2592],
3	address	NN	O	address	prep_in	28	SENT_49	[p1l405t2571r502b2592],
4	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l405t2571r502b2592],
5	Virus	NN	O	virus	nn	10	SENT_49	[p1l513t2572r572b2592],
6	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l584t2571r627b2592],
7	Stem	NN	O	stem	nn	10	SENT_49	[p1l640t2572r699b2592],
8	Cell	NN	O	cell	nn	10	SENT_49	[p1l712t2571r754b2592],
9	Biology	NNP	O	Biology	nn	10	SENT_49	[p1l768t2571r857b2598],
10	Lab	NNP	O	Lab	dep	3	SENT_49	[p1l869t2571r916b2596],
11	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l869t2571r916b2596],
12	Department	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Department	appos	10	SENT_49	[p1l929t2572r1074b2598],
13	of	IN	ORGANIZATION	of	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l1085t2571r1110b2592],
14	Molecular	JJ	ORGANIZATION	molecular	amod	16	SENT_49	[p1l1120t2571r1238b2592],
15	Cell	NN	ORGANIZATION	cell	nn	16	SENT_49	[p1l1249t2571r1291b2592],
16	Biology	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Biology	prep_of	12	SENT_49	[p1l1305t2571r1399b2598],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l1305t2571r1399b2598],
18	Leiden	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Leiden	nn	21	SENT_49	[p1l1412t2571r1490b2592],
19	University	NNP	ORGANIZATION	University	nn	21	SENT_49	[p1l1503t2572r1622b2598],
20	Medical	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Medical	nn	21	SENT_49	[p1l1633t2571r1724b2592],
21	Center	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Center	nsubj	28	SENT_49	[p1l1737t2572r1822b2596],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l1737t2572r1822b2596],
23	The	DT	O	the	det	24	SENT_49	[p1l1833t2571r1877b2592],
24	Netherlands	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Netherlands	appos	21	SENT_49	[p1l1890t2571r2035b2592],
25	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	24	SENT_49	[p1l278t2625r297b2644],
26	These	DT	O	these	det	27	SENT_49	[p1l308t2623r378b2644],
27	authors	NNS	O	author	dep	24	SENT_49	[p1l390t2623r480b2644],
28	contributed	VBD	O	contribute	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l492t2623r633b2644],
29	equally	RB	O	equally	advmod	28	SENT_49	[p1l646t2623r733b2650],
30	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l743t2627r767b2644],
31	this	DT	O	this	det	32	SENT_49	[p1l779t2623r821b2644],
32	work	NN	O	work	prep_to	28	SENT_49	[p1l833t2623r897b2644],
33	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_49	[p1l833t2623r897b2644],

1	|	RB	O	|	dep	2	SENT_50	[p1l245t2761r490b2792],
2	nt	NNS	O	nt	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l245t2761r490b2792],
3	|	SYM	O	|	dep	7	SENT_50	[p1l245t2761r490b2792],
4	-	:	O	-	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l245t2761r490b2792],
5	oduction	NN	O	oduction	nn	6	SENT_50	[p1l245t2761r490b2792],
6	molecules	NNS	O	molecule	npadvmod	7	SENT_50	[p1l1314t2760r1459b2786],
7	at	IN	O	at	dep	2	SENT_50	[p1l1488t2766r1514b2786],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_50	[p1l1542t2760r1587b2786],
9	surface	NN	O	surface	pobj	7	SENT_50	[p1l1616t2760r1718b2786],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l1748t2760r1780b2786],
11	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	12	SENT_50	[p1l1803t2760r1919b2786],
12	cells	NNS	O	cell	prep_of	9	SENT_50	[p1l1947t2760r2015b2786],
13	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_50	[p1l1947t2760r2015b2786],

1	Herpesviruses	NNS	O	herpesvirus	nsubj	5	SENT_51	[p1l2046t2760r2252b2794],
2	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l2281t2760r2308b2785],
3	particular	JJ	O	particular	prep_in	1	SENT_51	[p1l1313t2803r1459b2837],
4	have	VBP	O	have	aux	5	SENT_51	[p1l1477t2803r1546b2829],
5	acquired	VBN	O	acquire	ccomp	35	SENT_51	[p1l1566t2803r1695b2837],
6	diverse	JJ	O	diverse	amod	7	SENT_51	[p1l1714t2803r1816b2829],
7	mechanisms	NNS	O	mechanism	dobj	5	SENT_51	[p1l1836t2803r2017b2829],
8	to	TO	O	to	aux	9	SENT_51	[p1l2037t2809r2064b2829],
9	inhibit	VB	O	inhibit	xcomp	5	SENT_51	[p1l2084t2803r2180b2829],
10	antigen	NN	O	antigen	dobj	9	SENT_51	[p1l2199t2803r2308b2837],
11	Evolving	VBG	O	evolve	partmod	10	SENT_51	[p1l281t2845r411b2879],
12	under	IN	O	under	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l435t2845r522b2871],
13	the	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_51	[p1l546t2845r591b2871],
14	selective	JJ	O	selective	amod	15	SENT_51	[p1l616t2845r737b2871],
15	pressure	NN	O	pressure	prep_under	11	SENT_51	[p1l762t2854r883b2879],
16	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l909t2845r941b2871],
17	the	DT	O	the	det	20	SENT_51	[p1l960t2845r1005b2871],
18	host	NN	O	host	nn	20	SENT_51	[p1l1030t2845r1090b2871],
19	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	20	SENT_51	[p1l1114t2845r1237b2871],
20	presentation	NN	O	presentation	prep_of	15	SENT_51	[p1l1313t2847r1497b2881],
21	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l1516t2847r1543b2872],
22	the	DT	O	the	det	23	SENT_51	[p1l1562t2847r1607b2873],
23	context	NN	O	context	prep_in	20	SENT_51	[p1l1627t2853r1736b2873],
24	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l1755t2847r1786b2873],
25	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	26	SENT_51	[p1l1800t2847r1888b2873],
26	class	NN	O	class	nn	31	SENT_51	[p1l1909t2847r1974b2873],
27	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	28	SENT_51	[p1l1993t2847r2004b2872],
28	molecules	NNS	O	molecule	dep	26	SENT_51	[p1l2023t2847r2176b2879],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l2023t2847r2176b2879],
30	thereby	RB	O	thereby	advmod	26	SENT_51	[p1l2196t2847r2309b2881],
31	system	NN	O	system	prep_of	23	SENT_51	[p1l243t2895r348b2923],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l243t2895r348b2923],
33	herpesviruses	NNS	O	herpesvirus	nsubj	35	SENT_51	[p1l363t2889r560b2923],
34	have	VBP	O	have	aux	35	SENT_51	[p1l573t2889r642b2915],
35	developed	VBN	O	develop	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l656t2889r807b2923],
36	countermeasures	NNS	O	countermeasure	dobj	35	SENT_51	[p1l820t2895r1071b2915],
37	to	TO	O	to	aux	38	SENT_51	[p1l1084t2895r1111b2915],
38	prevent	VB	O	prevent	xcomp	35	SENT_51	[p1l1125t2895r1238b2923],
39	escaping	VBG	O	escape	xcomp	38	SENT_51	[p1l1314t2890r1442b2924],
40	from	IN	O	from	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l1454t2890r1525b2916],
41	elimination	NN	O	elimination	prep_from	39	SENT_51	[p1l1540t2890r1708b2916],
42	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l1722t2890r1758b2924],
43	CTLs	NNS	O	ctl	prep_by	41	SENT_51	[p1l1772t2890r1857b2916],
44	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	45	SENT_51	[p1l1875t2890r1959b2924],
45	l	NN	O	l	tmod	41	SENT_51	[p1l1875t2890r1959b2924],
46	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	48	SENT_51	[p1l1875t2890r1959b2924],
47	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	48	SENT_51	[p1l1875t2890r1959b2924],
48	]	NN	O	]	dobj	39	SENT_51	[p1l1875t2890r1959b2924],
49	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_51	[p1l1875t2890r1959b2924],

1	recognition	NN	O	recognition	nsubj	21	SENT_52	[p1l243t2933r411b2967],
2	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_52	[p1l431t2933r463b2959],
3	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	4	SENT_52	[p1l478t2933r594b2959],
4	cells	NNS	O	cell	prep_of	1	SENT_52	[p1l614t2933r674b2959],
5	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_52	[p1l694t2933r730b2967],
6	cytotoxic	JJ	O	cytotoxic	amod	7	SENT_52	[p1l748t2933r881b2967],
7	CD8	NN	O	cd8	prep_by	4	SENT_52	[p1l902t2929r990b2959],
8	+	CC	O	+	_	0	SENT_52	[p1l902t2929r990b2959],
9	T	NN	O	t	nn	10	SENT_52	[p1l1009t2933r1033b2958],
10	lymphocytes	NNS	O	lymphocyte	conj_+	4	SENT_52	[p1l1052t2933r1237b2967],
11	Most	JJS	O	most	amod	12	SENT_52	[p1l1351t2935r1427b2961],
12	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	nsubj	13	SENT_52	[p1l1454t2935r1576b2969],
13	presented	VBN	O	present	rcmod	10	SENT_52	[p1l1604t2935r1748b2969],
14	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_52	[p1l1775t2935r1811b2969],
15	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	16	SENT_52	[p1l1838t2935r1926b2961],
16	class	NN	O	class	prep_by	13	SENT_52	[p1l1956t2935r2021b2961],
17	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	18	SENT_52	[p1l2050t2935r2061b2960],
18	molecules	NNS	O	molecule	dep	16	SENT_52	[p1l2089t2935r2234b2961],
19	are	VBP	O	be	cop	21	SENT_52	[p1l2263t2944r2308b2961],
20	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	21	SENT_52	[p1l244t2977r354b3011],
21	CTLs	NNS	O	ctl	_	0	SENT_52	[p1l244t2977r354b3011],
22	)	CD	NUMBER	)	attr	21	SENT_52	[p1l244t2977r354b3011],
23	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_52	[p1l244t2977r354b3011],

1	CTLs	NNS	MISC	ctl	nsubj	2	SENT_53	[p1l382t2977r467b3003],
2	recognize	VBP	O	recognize	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l492t2977r633b3011],
3	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	4	SENT_53	[p1l657t2977r723b3002],
4	antigens	NNS	O	antigen	nsubj	29	SENT_53	[p1l748t2977r870b3011],
5	presented	VBN	O	present	partmod	4	SENT_53	[p1l894t2977r1038b3011],
6	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1063t2986r1090b3003],
7	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	prep_as	5	SENT_53	[p1l1115t2977r1237b3011],
8	transported	VBN	O	transport	partmod	7	SENT_53	[p1l1314t2978r1485b3012],
9	into	IN	O	into	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1504t2978r1560b3004],
10	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_53	[p1l1580t2978r1625b3004],
11	endoplasmic	JJ	O	endoplasmic	amod	16	SENT_53	[p1l1645t2978r1830b3012],
12	reticulum	NN	O	reticulum	nn	16	SENT_53	[p1l1850t2978r1992b3004],
13	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	16	SENT_53	[p1l2012t2978r2077b3012],
14	ER	NN	O	er	nn	16	SENT_53	[p1l2012t2978r2077b3012],
15	)	NN	O	)	nn	16	SENT_53	[p1l2012t2978r2077b3012],
16	lumen	NN	O	luman	prep_into	8	SENT_53	[p1l2097t2978r2190b3004],
17	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l2209t2978r2245b3012],
18	the	DT	O	the	det	19	SENT_53	[p1l2263t2978r2308b3004],
19	bound	VBN	O	bind	prep_by	16	SENT_53	[p1l243t3022r338b3048],
20	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l368t3028r395b3048],
21	major	JJ	O	major	amod	25	SENT_53	[p1l425t3022r513b3056],
22	histocompatibility	NN	O	histocompatibility	nn	25	SENT_53	[p1l542t3022r810b3056],
23	complex	NN	O	complex	nn	25	SENT_53	[p1l838t3022r964b3056],
24	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	25	SENT_53	[p1l994t3022r1100b3056],
25	MHC	NN	O	mhc	prep_to	19	SENT_53	[p1l994t3022r1100b3056],
26	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	19	SENT_53	[p1l994t3022r1100b3056],
27	class	NN	O	class	nn	29	SENT_53	[p1l1131t3022r1196b3048],
28	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	29	SENT_53	[p1l1226t3022r1237b3047],
29	transporter	NN	O	transporter	xcomp	2	SENT_53	[p1l1314t3028r1479b3056],
30	associated	VBN	O	associate	partmod	29	SENT_53	[p1l1499t3022r1648b3048],
31	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1666t3022r1731b3048],
32	antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	33	SENT_53	[p1l1751t3022r1860b3056],
33	processing	NN	O	processing	prep_with	30	SENT_53	[p1l1879t3022r2042b3056],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l1879t3022r2042b3056],
35	TAP	NN	O	tap	appos	33	SENT_53	[p1l2063t3022r2141b3048],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_53	[p1l2063t3022r2141b3048],

1	TAP	NN	O	tap	nsubj	3	SENT_54	[p1l2162t3022r2234b3047],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	3	SENT_54	[p1l2253t3022r2272b3048],
3	a	DT	O	a	_	0	SENT_54	[p1l2293t3031r2309b3047],

1	@	IN	O	@	_	0	SENT_55	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
2	K	NNP	O	K	prep_@	5	SENT_55	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
3	T	NN	O	t	nn	4	SENT_55	[p1l242t3124r316b3183],
4	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nsubj	5	SENT_55	[p1l344t3144r408b3167],
5	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_55	[p1l423t3143r567b3174],
6	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	7	SENT_55	[p1l587t3142r590b3175],
7	www	NN	O	www	dobj	5	SENT_55	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
8	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_55	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_56	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_56	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	dep	11	SENT_56	[p1l610t3143r949b3174],
4	1	CD	DATE	1	num	7	SENT_56	[p1l1271t3145r1278b3167],
5	May	NNP	DATE	May	nn	7	SENT_56	[p1l1674t3144r1730b3174],
6	2008	CD	DATE	2008	num	7	SENT_56	[p1l1742t3145r1807b3167],
7	|	NNP	O	|	dep	3	SENT_56	[p1l1828t3142r1830b3175],
8	Volume	NN	O	volume	dep	11	SENT_56	[p1l1850t3143r1955b3167],
9	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	8	SENT_56	[p1l1973t3145r1989b3167],
10	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	11	SENT_56	[p1l2009t3142r2011b3175],
11	Issue	NN	O	issue	_	0	SENT_56	[p1l2033t3144r2099b3167],
12	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	14	SENT_56	[p1l2118t3145r2131b3167],
13	|	NN	O	|	nn	14	SENT_56	[p1l2152t3142r2155b3175],
14	e1000080	NN	O	e1000080	dep	11	SENT_56	[p1l2175t3145r2308b3167],

1	Author	NN	O	author	nn	2	SENT_57	[p2l280t269r419b300],
2	Summary	NN	O	summary	_	0	SENT_57	[p2l436t270r625b308],

1	Herpesviruses	NNS	O	herpesvirus	nsubj	2	SENT_58	[p2l282t339r495b372],
2	have	VBP	O	have	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l518t338r589b365],
3	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_58	[p2l610t338r660b365],
4	conspicuous	JJ	O	conspicuous	amod	5	SENT_58	[p2l681t339r874b372],
5	property	NN	O	property	dobj	2	SENT_58	[p2l897t343r1030b373],
6	that	IN	O	that	complm	8	SENT_58	[p2l1050t338r1112b365],
7	they	PRP	O	they	nsubj	8	SENT_58	[p2l1132t338r1201b373],
8	persist	VBP	O	persist	dep	5	SENT_58	[p2l282t380r381b413],
9	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l393t379r436b406],
10	life	NN	O	life	prep_for	8	SENT_58	[p2l450t379r493b406],
11	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l508t380r532b406],
12	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_58	[p2l546t379r596b406],
13	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	14	SENT_58	[p2l611t379r734b406],
14	host	NN	O	host	prep_in	10	SENT_58	[p2l750t379r822b406],
15	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_58	[p2l750t379r822b406],

1	This	DT	O	this	nsubj	5	SENT_59	[p2l834t379r896b406],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	5	SENT_59	[p2l910t380r930b406],
3	also	RB	O	also	advmod	5	SENT_59	[p2l944t379r1003b406],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_59	[p2l1016t379r1066b406],
5	case	NN	O	case	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1079t387r1145b406],
6	for	IN	O	for	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1158t379r1201b406],
7	varicelloviruses	NNS	O	varicellovirus	prep_for	5	SENT_59	[p2l280t421r523b453],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l280t421r523b453],
9	a	DT	O	a	det	11	SENT_59	[p2l544t429r559b448],
10	large	JJ	O	large	amod	11	SENT_59	[p2l583t421r657b456],
11	subfamily	NN	O	subfamily	nsubj	27	SENT_59	[p2l679t421r829b456],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l850t421r881b448],
13	herpesviruses	NNS	O	herpesvirus	prep_of	11	SENT_59	[p2l901t421r1111b455],
14	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1132t421r1198b448],
15	representatives	NNS	O	representative	prep_with	13	SENT_59	[p2l282t464r517b497],
16	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l536t464r561b490],
17	humans	NNS	O	human	prep_in	15	SENT_59	[p2l582t463r703b490],
18	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	21	SENT_59	[p2l722t463r855b495],
19	varicella	NN	O	varicellum	nn	21	SENT_59	[p2l722t463r855b495],
20	zoster	NN	O	zoster	nn	21	SENT_59	[p2l873t468r967b490],
21	virus	NN	O	virus	dep	17	SENT_59	[p2l983t464r1055b490],
22	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1073t471r1104b490],
23	VZV	NN	O	vzv	nn	24	SENT_59	[p2l1120t464r1200b495],
24	)	NN	O	)	prep_in	15	SENT_59	[p2l1120t464r1200b495],
25	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l1120t464r1200b495],
26	cattle	NNS	O	cattle	appos	24	SENT_59	[p2l281t504r365b531],
27	(	VBP	O	(	ccomp	5	SENT_59	[p2l380t504r495b536],
28	bovine	JJ	O	bovine	amod	29	SENT_59	[p2l380t504r495b536],
29	herpesvirus	NN	O	herpesvirus	dobj	27	SENT_59	[p2l511t504r687b538],
30	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	29	SENT_59	[p2l704t507r712b531],
31	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l733t512r764b531],
32	BHV-1	NN	O	bhv-1	nn	33	SENT_59	[p2l779t505r889b536],
33	)	NN	O	)	conj_or	29	SENT_59	[p2l779t505r889b536],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l779t505r889b536],
35	pigs	NNS	O	pig	nsubj	36	SENT_59	[p2l904t505r966b539],
36	(	VBP	O	(	ccomp	5	SENT_59	[p2l982t504r1199b538],
37	pseudorabies	NNS	O	pseudoraby	nn	38	SENT_59	[p2l982t504r1199b538],
38	virus	NN	O	virus	dobj	36	SENT_59	[p2l280t547r352b573],
39	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l364t554r395b573],
40	PRV	NN	O	prv	nn	41	SENT_59	[p2l407t547r482b578],
41	)	NN	O	)	dobj	36	SENT_59	[p2l407t547r482b578],
42	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l407t547r482b578],
43	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l493t546r549b573],
44	horses	NNS	O	horse	nsubj	45	SENT_59	[p2l563t546r661b573],
45	(	VBP	O	(	conj_and	5	SENT_59	[p2l674t547r789b580],
46	equine	JJ	O	equine	amod	47	SENT_59	[p2l674t547r789b580],
47	herpesvirus	NN	O	herpesvirus	dobj	45	SENT_59	[p2l802t546r978b580],
48	or	CC	O	or	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l990t554r1021b573],
49	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	nn	50	SENT_59	[p2l1032t548r1093b573],
50	type	NN	O	type	dobj	45	SENT_59	[p2l1103t551r1171b581],
51	1	CD	NUMBER	1	num	54	SENT_59	[p2l1186t549r1194b573],
52	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l280t587r336b614],
53	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	54	SENT_59	[p2l350t588r386b619],
54	)	NN	O	)	dep	47	SENT_59	[p2l350t588r386b619],
55	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l350t588r386b619],
56	among	IN	O	among	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l399t595r507b622],
57	many	JJ	O	many	amod	58	SENT_59	[p2l523t595r607b622],
58	others	NNS	O	other	prep_among	47	SENT_59	[p2l620t587r724b614],
59	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_59	[p2l620t587r724b614],

1	Cytotoxic	JJ	O	cytotoxic	amod	5	SENT_60	[p2l737t588r883b622],
2	T	NN	O	t	nn	5	SENT_60	[p2l895t587r1123b622],
3	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	5	SENT_60	[p2l895t587r1123b622],
4	|	NN	O	|	nn	5	SENT_60	[p2l895t587r1123b622],
5	ymphocytes	NNS	O	ymphocyte	nsubj	6	SENT_60	[p2l895t587r1123b622],
6	play	VBP	O	play	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1138t587r1201b622],
7	an	DT	O	a	det	9	SENT_60	[p2l280t637r315b656],
8	important	JJ	O	important	amod	9	SENT_60	[p2l330t630r484b663],
9	role	NN	O	role	nsubj	29	SENT_60	[p2l498t629r554b656],
10	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l568t630r592b656],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	12	SENT_60	[p2l606t629r656b656],
12	protection	NN	O	protection	prep_in	9	SENT_60	[p2l670t630r829b663],
13	against	IN	O	against	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l843t630r954b664],
14	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	15	SENT_60	[p2l965t629r1028b656],
15	infections	NNS	O	infection	prep_against	12	SENT_60	[p2l1043t629r1200b661],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1043t629r1200b661],
17	which	WDT	O	which	dobj	19	SENT_60	[p2l280t670r371b697],
18	they	PRP	O	they	nsubj	19	SENT_60	[p2l383t670r452b705],
19	detect	VBP	O	detect	rcmod	9	SENT_60	[p2l462t670r560b697],
20	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l570t670r695b705],
21	the	DT	O	the	det	22	SENT_60	[p2l707t670r757b697],
22	recognition	NN	O	recognition	prep_through	19	SENT_60	[p2l770t671r946b705],
23	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l958t670r990b697],
24	virus	NN	O	virus	prep_of	22	SENT_60	[p2l998t670r1198b697],
25	—	CD	NUMBER	—	num	24	SENT_60	[p2l998t670r1198b697],
26	derived	VBN	O	derive	partmod	24	SENT_60	[p2l998t670r1198b697],
27	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	dobj	26	SENT_60	[p2l282t712r423b746],
28	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l282t712r423b746],
29	presented	VBN	O	present	ccomp	6	SENT_60	[p2l455t712r609b746],
30	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l642t713r666b739],
31	the	DT	O	the	det	32	SENT_60	[p2l698t712r748b739],
32	context	NN	O	context	prep_in	29	SENT_60	[p2l779t716r896b739],
33	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l927t712r958b739],
34	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	35	SENT_60	[p2l988t713r1060b739],
35	class	NN	O	class	prep_of	32	SENT_60	[p2l1092t712r1162b739],
36	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	37	SENT_60	[p2l1195t714r1198b739],
37	molecules	NNS	O	molecule	dobj	29	SENT_60	[p2l282t753r436b780],
38	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l469t758r497b780],
39	the	DT	O	the	det	40	SENT_60	[p2l529t753r579b780],
40	surface	NN	O	surface	prep_at	37	SENT_60	[p2l611t753r720b780],
41	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l753t753r785b780],
42	the	DT	O	the	det	44	SENT_60	[p2l814t753r863b780],
43	infected	JJ	O	infected	amod	44	SENT_60	[p2l897t753r1020b780],
44	cell	NN	O	cell	prep_of	40	SENT_60	[p2l1054t753r1112b780],
45	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_60	[p2l1054t753r1112b780],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_61	[p2l1143t753r1199b780],
2	transporter	NN	O	transporter	nsubj	3	SENT_61	[p2l280t799r454b829],
3	associated	VBN	O	associate	dep	10	SENT_61	[p2l466t795r626b822],
4	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l639t795r705b822],
5	antigen	NN	O	antigen	nn	6	SENT_61	[p2l719t796r835b830],
6	processing	NN	O	processing	prep_with	3	SENT_61	[p2l851t796r1015b830],
7	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	9	SENT_61	[p2l1030t796r1108b827],
8	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	9	SENT_61	[p2l1030t796r1108b827],
9	)	NN	O	)	nsubj	10	SENT_61	[p2l1030t796r1108b827],
10	plays	VBZ	O	play	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l1123t795r1199b830],
11	an	DT	O	a	det	13	SENT_61	[p2l280t844r315b863],
12	essential	JJ	O	essential	amod	13	SENT_61	[p2l333t836r464b863],
13	role	NN	O	role	dobj	10	SENT_61	[p2l483t836r539b863],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l556t837r581b863],
15	this	DT	O	this	det	16	SENT_61	[p2l598t836r652b863],
16	process	NN	O	process	prep_in	10	SENT_61	[p2l669t844r793b870],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l669t844r793b870],
18	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l809t844r839b863],
19	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	21	SENT_61	[p2l854t838r914b863],
20	imports	NNS	O	import	nn	21	SENT_61	[p2l931t837r1049b870],
21	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	prep_as	10	SENT_61	[p2l1066t836r1199b870],
22	into	IN	O	into	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l281t879r340b905],
23	the	DT	O	the	det	24	SENT_61	[p2l354t878r404b905],
24	compartment	NN	O	compartment	prep_into	10	SENT_61	[p2l418t883r631b912],
25	where	WRB	O	where	advmod	34	SENT_61	[p2l645t878r740b905],
26	peptide	NN	O	peptide	nn	27	SENT_61	[p2l756t878r874b912],
27	loading	NN	O	loading	nsubj	34	SENT_61	[p2l890t878r1003b913],
28	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l1019t878r1051b905],
29	the	DT	O	the	det	31	SENT_61	[p2l1062t878r1111b905],
30	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	31	SENT_61	[p2l1127t879r1199b905],
31	class	NN	O	class	prep_of	27	SENT_61	[p2l281t919r350b946],
32	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	33	SENT_61	[p2l368t921r372b946],
33	molecules	NNS	O	molecule	dep	31	SENT_61	[p2l390t919r545b946],
34	takes	VBZ	O	take	rcmod	24	SENT_61	[p2l561t919r640b946],
35	place	NN	O	place	dobj	34	SENT_61	[p2l657t919r745b953],
36	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_61	[p2l657t919r745b953],

1	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l762t921r786b946],
2	this	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_62	[p2l803t919r858b946],
3	study	NN	O	study	prep_in	6	SENT_62	[p2l874t919r965b954],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l874t919r965b954],
5	we	PRP	O	we	nsubj	6	SENT_62	[p2l981t927r1025b946],
6	show	VBP	O	show	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1042t919r1123b946],
7	that	IN	O	that	complm	28	SENT_62	[p2l1138t919r1200b946],
8	the	DT	O	the	det	11	SENT_62	[p2l280t961r330b988],
9	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	11	SENT_62	[p2l349t963r451b988],
10	.5	NN	NUMBER	.5	nn	11	SENT_62	[p2l349t963r451b988],
11	proteins	NNS	O	protein	nsubj	28	SENT_62	[p2l471t962r596b995],
12	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l615t961r646b988],
13	BHV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	BHV	prep_of	11	SENT_62	[p2l663t963r763b993],
14	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	15	SENT_62	[p2l663t963r763b993],
15	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	13	SENT_62	[p2l663t963r763b993],
16	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l663t963r763b993],
17	PRV	NN	O	prv	prep_of	11	SENT_62	[p2l782t963r847b993],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l782t963r847b993],
19	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	nn	20	SENT_62	[p2l866t963r965b993],
20	—	NN	O	—	appos	17	SENT_62	[p2l866t963r965b993],
21	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	20	SENT_62	[p2l866t963r965b993],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l866t963r965b993],
23	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l982t961r1038b988],
24	EHV	NN	O	ehv	prep_of	11	SENT_62	[p2l1059t963r1149b988],
25	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	26	SENT_62	[p2l1059t963r1149b988],
26	4	CD	NUMBER	4	num	27	SENT_62	[p2l1059t963r1149b988],
27	all	DT	O	all	dep	24	SENT_62	[p2l1167t961r1198b988],
28	block	VBP	O	block	ccomp	6	SENT_62	[p2l282t1002r364b1029],
29	the	DT	O	the	det	30	SENT_62	[p2l374t1002r424b1029],
30	supply	NN	O	supply	dobj	28	SENT_62	[p2l435t1002r538b1037],
31	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l549t1002r580b1029],
32	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	prep_of	30	SENT_62	[p2l590t1002r723b1036],
33	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l734t1002r859b1037],
34	the	DT	O	the	det	35	SENT_62	[p2l871t1002r921b1029],
35	inhibition	NN	O	inhibition	prep_through	28	SENT_62	[p2l933t1002r1079b1029],
36	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1092t1002r1124b1029],
37	TAP	NN	O	tap	prep_of	35	SENT_62	[p2l1131t1004r1200b1034],
38	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l1131t1004r1200b1034],
39	but	CC	O	but	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l282t1044r333b1071],
40	that	IN	O	that	complm	51	SENT_62	[p2l349t1044r411b1071],
41	the	DT	O	the	det	42	SENT_62	[p2l426t1044r476b1071],
42	mechanisms	NNS	O	mechanism	nsubj	51	SENT_62	[p2l494t1044r685b1071],
43	employed	VBN	O	employ	partmod	42	SENT_62	[p2l702t1044r855b1079],
44	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l874t1044r911b1079],
45	these	DT	O	these	det	46	SENT_62	[p2l926t1044r1009b1071],
46	proteins	NNS	O	protein	agent	43	SENT_62	[p2l1027t1045r1152b1078],
47	to	TO	O	to	aux	48	SENT_62	[p2l1168t1049r1199b1071],
48	inhibit	VB	O	inhibit	xcomp	43	SENT_62	[p2l281t1085r379b1112],
49	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	50	SENT_62	[p2l407t1087r467b1112],
50	function	NN	O	function	dobj	48	SENT_62	[p2l497t1085r625b1112],
51	exhibit	VBP	O	exhibit	ccomp	6	SENT_62	[p2l656t1085r761b1112],
52	surprising	JJ	O	surprising	amod	53	SENT_62	[p2l791t1086r941b1120],
53	diversity	NN	O	diversity	dobj	51	SENT_62	[p2l973t1085r1110b1120],
54	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_62	[p2l973t1085r1110b1120],

1	VZV	NN	O	vzv	nn	2	SENT_63	[p2l1138t1087r1201b1112],
2	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nsubj	10	SENT_63	[p2l282t1129r392b1159],
3	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	dep	2	SENT_63	[p2l282t1129r392b1159],
4	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l282t1129r392b1159],
5	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l412t1135r450b1154],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	8	SENT_63	[p2l469t1127r519b1154],
7	other	JJ	O	other	amod	8	SENT_63	[p2l539t1127r622b1154],
8	hand	NN	O	hand	prep_on	2	SENT_63	[p2l642t1127r726b1159],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l642t1127r726b1159],
10	binds	VBZ	O	bind	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l746t1127r829b1154],
11	to	TO	O	to	aux	12	SENT_63	[p2l848t1131r879b1154],
12	TAP	VB	O	tap	xcomp	10	SENT_63	[p2l897t1129r965b1159],
13	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l897t1129r965b1159],
14	but	CC	O	but	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l986t1127r1037b1154],
15	does	VBZ	O	do	aux	17	SENT_63	[p2l1056t1127r1129b1154],
16	not	RB	O	not	neg	17	SENT_63	[p2l1149t1131r1200b1154],
17	interfere	VB	O	interfere	conj_but	10	SENT_63	[p2l281t1168r410b1195],
18	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l429t1168r495b1195],
19	peptide	NN	O	peptide	nn	20	SENT_63	[p2l516t1168r635b1202],
20	transport	NN	O	transport	prep_with	17	SENT_63	[p2l653t1172r803b1202],
21	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_63	[p2l653t1172r803b1202],

1	Our	PRP$	O	we	poss	2	SENT_64	[p2l822t1169r879b1195],
2	study	NN	O	study	nsubj	3	SENT_64	[p2l897t1168r982b1203],
3	classifies	VBZ	O	classify	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1000t1168r1131b1195],
4	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_64	[p2l1150t1168r1200b1195],
5	UL49	NN	O	ul49	nn	7	SENT_64	[p2l282t1212r384b1237],
6	.5	NN	NUMBER	.5	nn	7	SENT_64	[p2l282t1212r384b1237],
7	proteins	NNS	O	protein	dobj	3	SENT_64	[p2l412t1211r538b1244],
8	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l565t1210r596b1237],
9	BHV	NNP	ORGANIZATION	BHV	prep_of	7	SENT_64	[p2l622t1212r722b1242],
10	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	11	SENT_64	[p2l622t1212r722b1242],
11	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	9	SENT_64	[p2l622t1212r722b1242],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l622t1212r722b1242],
13	PRV	NN	O	prv	conj_and	9	SENT_64	[p2l750t1212r815b1242],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l750t1212r815b1242],
15	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	nn	16	SENT_64	[p2l843t1212r941b1242],
16	—	NN	O	—	appos	13	SENT_64	[p2l843t1212r941b1242],
17	1	CD	NUMBER	1	dep	16	SENT_64	[p2l843t1212r941b1242],
18	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l843t1212r941b1242],
19	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l967t1210r1023b1237],
20	EHV	NN	ORGANIZATION	ehv	prep_of	7	SENT_64	[p2l1052t1212r1143b1237],
21	—	CD	NUMBER	—	number	22	SENT_64	[p2l1052t1212r1143b1237],
22	4	CD	NUMBER	4	dep	20	SENT_64	[p2l1052t1212r1143b1237],
23	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1169t1218r1199b1237],
24	members	NNS	O	member	prep_as	3	SENT_64	[p2l282t1251r426b1278],
25	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l453t1251r485b1278],
26	a	DT	O	a	det	28	SENT_64	[p2l509t1259r524b1278],
27	novel	JJ	O	novel	amod	28	SENT_64	[p2l553t1251r634b1278],
28	family	NN	O	family	prep_of	24	SENT_64	[p2l662t1251r756b1286],
29	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l782t1251r814b1278],
30	viral	JJ	O	viral	amod	33	SENT_64	[p2l837t1251r899b1278],
31	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	33	SENT_64	[p2l929t1252r1056b1278],
32	evasion	NN	O	evasion	nn	33	SENT_64	[p2l1083t1252r1198b1278],
33	proteins	NNS	O	protein	prep_of	28	SENT_64	[p2l282t1294r415b1327],
34	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l282t1294r415b1327],
35	inhibiting	VBG	O	inhibit	partmod	3	SENT_64	[p2l431t1293r577b1328],
36	TAP	NN	O	tap	dobj	35	SENT_64	[p2l592t1295r652b1320],
37	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l666t1293r791b1328],
38	a	DT	O	a	det	39	SENT_64	[p2l808t1301r822b1320],
39	variety	NN	O	variety	prep_through	35	SENT_64	[p2l837t1294r941b1328],
40	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l956t1293r987b1320],
41	mechanisms	NNS	O	mechanism	prep_of	39	SENT_64	[p2l1001t1293r1200b1320],
42	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_64	[p2l1001t1293r1200b1320],

1	heterodimer	NN	O	heterodimer	nsubj	17	SENT_65	[p2l243t1426r426b1452],
2	composed	VBN	O	compose	dep	1	SENT_65	[p2l440t1426r589b1460],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l604t1426r636b1452],
4	TAPl	NN	O	tapl	nn	7	SENT_65	[p2l644t1426r729b1451],
5	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l748t1426r804b1452],
6	TAP2	NN	O	tap2	nn	7	SENT_65	[p2l817t1426r905b1453],
7	subunits	NNS	O	subunit	prep_of	2	SENT_65	[p2l921t1426r1042b1452],
8	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l1057t1426r1112b1452],
9	belongs	VBZ	O	belong	conj_and	2	SENT_65	[p2l1126t1426r1237b1460],
10	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l243t1476r270b1496],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	14	SENT_65	[p2l291t1470r336b1496],
12	ATP-binding	JJ	O	atp-binding	amod	14	SENT_65	[p2l357t1470r556b1504],
13	cassette	NN	O	cassette	nn	14	SENT_65	[p2l576t1476r686b1496],
14	family	NN	O	family	prep_to	9	SENT_65	[p2l707t1470r800b1504],
15	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l820t1470r852b1496],
16	transporters	NNS	O	transporter	prep_of	14	SENT_65	[p2l867t1476r1045b1504],
17	[	VBP	O	[	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l1070t1470r1144b1504],
18	5,6	CD	NUMBER	5,6	number	19	SENT_65	[p2l1070t1470r1144b1504],
19	]	CD	NUMBER	]	dobj	17	SENT_65	[p2l1070t1470r1144b1504],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_65	[p2l1070t1470r1144b1504],

1	TAP	NN	O	tap	nsubj	2	SENT_66	[p2l1167t1470r1238b1495],
2	translocates	VBZ	O	translocate	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l243t1514r416b1540],
3	peptides	NNS	O	peptide	dobj	2	SENT_66	[p2l434t1514r556b1548],
4	across	IN	O	across	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l574t1523r662b1540],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	7	SENT_66	[p2l680t1514r725b1540],
6	ER	NN	O	er	nn	7	SENT_66	[p2l744t1514r793b1539],
7	membrane	NN	O	membrane	prep_across	2	SENT_66	[p2l810t1514r971b1540],
8	via	IN	O	via	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l988t1514r1032b1539],
9	a	DT	O	a	det	11	SENT_66	[p2l1050t1523r1066b1539],
10	conformational	JJ	O	conformational	amod	11	SENT_66	[p2l1083t1514r1237b1540, p2l243t1557r326b1583],
11	transition	NN	O	transition	prep_via	7	SENT_66	[p2l338t1557r478b1583],
12	that	WDT	O	that	nsubjpass	14	SENT_66	[p2l490t1557r548b1583],
13	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	14	SENT_66	[p2l559t1557r578b1583],
14	energized	VBN	O	energize	rcmod	11	SENT_66	[p2l590t1557r733b1591],
15	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l744t1557r780b1591],
16	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_66	[p2l790t1557r835b1583],
17	hydrolysis	NN	O	hydrolysis	agent	14	SENT_66	[p2l847t1557r994b1591],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1006t1557r1038b1583],
19	ATP	NN	O	atp	prep_of	17	SENT_66	[p2l1043t1557r1122b1583],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_66	[p2l1043t1557r1122b1583],

1	TAP	NN	O	tap	nsubj	3	SENT_67	[p2l1135t1557r1207b1582],
2	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	3	SENT_67	[p2l1218t1557r1237b1583],
3	part	NN	O	part	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l242t1607r303b1635],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l328t1601r360b1627],
5	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_67	[p2l380t1601r424b1627],
6	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	10	SENT_67	[p2l450t1601r538b1627],
7	class	NN	O	class	nn	10	SENT_67	[p2l565t1601r630b1627],
8	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	10	SENT_67	[p2l655t1601r666b1626],
9	peptide-loading	JJ	O	peptide-loading	amod	10	SENT_67	[p2l691t1601r925b1635],
10	complex	NN	O	complex	prep_of	3	SENT_67	[p2l949t1601r1075b1635],
11	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	13	SENT_67	[p2l1099t1601r1157b1627],
12	also	RB	O	also	advmod	13	SENT_67	[p2l1182t1601r1237b1627],
13	contains	VBZ	O	contain	rcmod	10	SENT_67	[p2l243t1645r365b1671],
14	tapasin	NN	O	tapasin	dobj	13	SENT_67	[p2l378t1645r491b1679],
15	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l378t1645r491b1679],
16	MHC	NN	O	mhc	nn	17	SENT_67	[p2l505t1645r593b1671],
17	class	NN	O	class	conj_and	14	SENT_67	[p2l608t1645r673b1671],
18	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	22	SENT_67	[p2l686t1645r697b1670],
19	heavy	JJ	O	heavy	amod	22	SENT_67	[p2l710t1645r797b1679],
20	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l809t1645r864b1671],
21	light	JJ	O	light	amod	22	SENT_67	[p2l876t1645r942b1679],
22	chains	NNS	O	chain	dep	17	SENT_67	[p2l954t1645r1055b1677],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l954t1645r1055b1677],
24	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l1069t1645r1125b1671],
25	several	JJ	O	several	amod	27	SENT_67	[p2l1137t1645r1237b1671],
26	auxiliary	JJ	O	auxiliary	amod	27	SENT_67	[p2l243t1688r373b1722],
27	proteins	NNS	O	protein	dobj	13	SENT_67	[p2l385t1688r504b1722],
28	including	VBG	O	include	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l519t1688r658b1722],
29	calreticulin	NN	O	calreticulin	prep_including	27	SENT_67	[p2l671t1688r835b1714],
30	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l850t1688r905b1714],
31	ERp57	NN	O	erp57	prep_including	27	SENT_67	[p2l919t1688r1023b1722],
32	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	31	SENT_67	[p2l1043t1688r1173b1722],
33	5,7	CD	NUMBER	5,7	number	34	SENT_67	[p2l1043t1688r1173b1722],
34	—	CD	NUMBER	—	dep	31	SENT_67	[p2l1043t1688r1173b1722],
35	lO	NN	O	lo	dep	34	SENT_67	[p2l1043t1688r1173b1722],
36	]	CD	NUMBER	]	num	35	SENT_67	[p2l1043t1688r1173b1722],
37	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_67	[p2l1043t1688r1173b1722],

1	Several	JJ	O	several	amod	2	SENT_68	[p2l281t1734r389b1760],
2	herpesviruses	NNS	O	herpesvirus	nsubj	4	SENT_68	[p2l408t1734r605b1768],
3	have	VBP	O	have	aux	4	SENT_68	[p2l625t1734r694b1760],
4	acquired	VBN	O	acquire	_	0	SENT_68	[p2l714t1734r844b1768],
5	mechanisms	NNS	O	mechanism	dobj	4	SENT_68	[p2l863t1734r1045b1760],
6	to	TO	O	to	aux	7	SENT_68	[p2l1065t1740r1092b1760],
7	interfere	VB	O	interfere	xcomp	4	SENT_68	[p2l1113t1734r1237b1760],
8	with	IN	O	with	_	0	SENT_68	[p2l242t1777r306b1803],
9	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	10	SENT_68	[p2l324t1777r395b1802],
10	function	NN	O	function	prep_with	7	SENT_68	[p2l411t1777r541b1803],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_68	[p2l411t1777r541b1803],

1	Interestingly	RB	O	interestingly	advmod	8	SENT_69	[p2l560t1777r753b1811],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l560t1777r753b1811],
3	inhibition	NN	O	inhibition	nsubjpass	8	SENT_69	[p2l772t1777r915b1803],
4	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l933t1777r965b1803],
5	TAP	NN	O	tap	nn	6	SENT_69	[p2l977t1777r1048b1802],
6	transport	NN	O	transport	prep_of	3	SENT_69	[p2l1065t1783r1200b1811],
7	is	VBZ	O	be	auxpass	8	SENT_69	[p2l1218t1777r1237b1803],
8	achieved	VBN	O	achieve	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l243t1821r373b1847],
9	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l396t1821r514b1855],
10	different	JJ	O	different	amod	11	SENT_69	[p2l538t1821r662b1847],
11	strategies	NNS	O	strategy	prep_through	8	SENT_69	[p2l686t1821r829b1855],
12	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l686t1821r829b1855],
13	exerted	VBN	O	exert	partmod	11	SENT_69	[p2l854t1821r963b1847],
14	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l986t1821r1022b1855],
15	unique	JJ	O	unique	amod	17	SENT_69	[p2l1043t1821r1145b1855],
16	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	17	SENT_69	[p2l1169t1830r1237b1855],
17	products	NNS	O	product	agent	13	SENT_69	[p2l242t1865r378b1899],
18	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_69	[p2l242t1865r378b1899],

1	Although	IN	O	although	mark	26	SENT_70	[p2l393t1865r532b1899],
2	the	DT	O	the	det	5	SENT_70	[p2l546t1865r590b1891],
3	varicellovirus	NN	O	varicellovirus	nn	5	SENT_70	[p2l603t1865r800b1891],
4	bovine	JJ	O	bovine	amod	5	SENT_70	[p2l814t1865r912b1891],
5	herpesvirus	NN	O	herpesvirus	nsubj	26	SENT_70	[p2l927t1865r1094b1899],
6	1	CD	NUMBER	1	number	7	SENT_70	[p2l1113t1866r1121b1890],
7	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	9	SENT_70	[p2l1139t1865r1237b1899, p2l248t1908r268b1942],
8	BHVl	NN	O	bhvl	nn	9	SENT_70	[p2l1139t1865r1237b1899, p2l248t1908r268b1942],
9	)	NN	O	)	dep	5	SENT_70	[p2l1139t1865r1237b1899, p2l248t1908r268b1942],
10	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l281t1908r336b1934],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	13	SENT_70	[p2l347t1908r392b1934],
12	simplexviruses	NNS	O	simplexvirus	nn	13	SENT_70	[p2l405t1908r617b1942],
13	herpes	NN	O	herpes	nsubj	26	SENT_70	[p2l629t1908r725b1942],
14	simplex	NN	O	simplex	nn	16	SENT_70	[p2l738t1908r850b1942],
15	virus	NN	O	virus	nn	16	SENT_70	[p2l860t1908r931b1934],
16	type	NN	O	type	dep	13	SENT_70	[p2l943t1914r1005b1942],
17	1	CD	NUMBER	1	number	20	SENT_70	[p2l1022t1909r1030b1933],
18	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l1046t1908r1101b1934],
19	2	CD	NUMBER	2	num	21	SENT_70	[p2l1114t1908r1128b1935],
20	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	21	SENT_70	[p2l1142t1908r1237b1942, p2l248t1953r256b1977],
21	HSVl	NN	O	hsvl	dep	16	SENT_70	[p2l1142t1908r1237b1942, p2l248t1953r256b1977],
22	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l276t1952r331b1978],
23	-2	CD	NUMBER	-2	num	24	SENT_70	[p2l347t1952r383b1986],
24	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	13	SENT_70	[p2l347t1952r383b1986],
25	all	DT	O	all	dep	24	SENT_70	[p2l400t1952r434b1977],
26	belong	VBP	O	belong	advcl	34	SENT_70	[p2l449t1952r549b1986],
27	to	TO	O	to	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l564t1958r591b1978],
28	the	DT	O	the	det	29	SENT_70	[p2l607t1952r652b1978],
29	subfamily	NN	O	subfamily	prep_to	26	SENT_70	[p2l669t1952r812b1986],
30	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l827t1952r859b1978],
31	alphaherpesviruses	NNS	O	alphaherpesvirus	prep_of	29	SENT_70	[p2l870t1952r1158b1986],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l870t1952r1158b1986],
33	they	PRP	O	they	nsubj	34	SENT_70	[p2l1175t1952r1238b1986],
34	block	VBP	O	block	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l243t1996r322b2022],
35	TAP	NN	O	tap	dobj	34	SENT_70	[p2l348t1996r419b2021],
36	through	IN	O	through	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l445t1996r563b2030],
37	proteins	NNS	O	protein	prep_through	34	SENT_70	[p2l589t1996r708b2030],
38	that	WDT	O	that	nsubj	39	SENT_70	[p2l735t1996r792b2022],
39	have	VBP	O	have	rcmod	37	SENT_70	[p2l818t1996r887b2022],
40	an	DT	O	a	det	43	SENT_70	[p2l914t2005r949b2021],
41	entirely	RB	O	entirely	advmod	42	SENT_70	[p2l976t1996r1088b2030],
42	different	JJ	O	different	amod	43	SENT_70	[p2l1113t1996r1238b2022],
43	structure	NN	O	structure	dobj	39	SENT_70	[p2l243t2046r373b2066],
44	and	CC	O	and	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l389t2040r445b2066],
45	mode	NN	O	mode	dobj	39	SENT_70	[p2l459t2040r541b2066],
46	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l558t2040r590b2066],
47	action	NN	O	action	prep_of	45	SENT_70	[p2l600t2040r698b2066],
48	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_70	[p2l600t2040r698b2066],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	2	SENT_71	[p2l715t2040r775b2066],
2	inhibition	NN	O	inhibition	nsubj	7	SENT_71	[p2l791t2040r935b2066],
3	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l951t2040r983b2066],
4	TAP	NN	O	tap	prep_of	2	SENT_71	[p2l992t2040r1064b2065],
5	by	IN	O	by	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l1078t2040r1114b2074],
6	BHV-1	NN	O	bhv-1	prep_by	4	SENT_71	[p2l1129t2040r1233b2066],
7	relies	VBZ	O	rely	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l243t2083r318b2109],
8	on	IN	O	on	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l334t2092r370b2109],
9	the	DT	O	the	det	10	SENT_71	[p2l386t2083r430b2109],
10	UL49	NN	O	ul49	prep_on	7	SENT_71	[p2l446t2083r560b2109],
11	.5	CD	NUMBER	.5	number	12	SENT_71	[p2l446t2083r560b2109],
12	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	18	SENT_71	[p2l578t2083r696b2117],
13	Unique	JJ	O	unique	amod	18	SENT_71	[p2l578t2083r696b2117],
14	Long	JJ	O	long	amod	18	SENT_71	[p2l713t2083r791b2117],
15	49.5	CD	NUMBER	49.5	amod	18	SENT_71	[p2l805t2083r877b2117],
16	)	NN	O	)	nn	18	SENT_71	[p2l805t2083r877b2117],
17	gene	NN	O	gene	nn	18	SENT_71	[p2l893t2092r961b2117],
18	product	NN	O	product	dep	10	SENT_71	[p2l976t2083r1101b2117],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l976t2083r1101b2117],
20	a	DT	O	a	det	24	SENT_71	[p2l1118t2092r1133b2108],
21	type	NN	O	type	nn	24	SENT_71	[p2l1148t2089r1210b2117],
22	I	CD	NUMBER	i	num	24	SENT_71	[p2l1226t2083r1237b2108],
23	transmembrane	NN	O	transmembrane	nn	24	SENT_71	[p2l243t2127r478b2153],
24	protein	NN	O	protein	appos	10	SENT_71	[p2l496t2127r603b2161],
25	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l622t2127r654b2153],
26	75	CD	NUMBER	75	num	28	SENT_71	[p2l669t2128r701b2153],
27	amino	NN	O	amino	nn	28	SENT_71	[p2l722t2127r814b2153],
28	acids	NNS	O	acid	prep_of	24	SENT_71	[p2l834t2127r906b2153],
29	[	CD	NUMBER	[	num	31	SENT_71	[p2l928t2127r993b2161],
30	ll	NN	O	ll	nn	31	SENT_71	[p2l928t2127r993b2161],
31	]	NN	O	]	dep	24	SENT_71	[p2l928t2127r993b2161],
32	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_71	[p2l928t2127r993b2161],
