1	Correction	NN	O	correction	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t280r512b317],
3	Dynorphin	NNP	O	Dynorphin	nsubj	4	SENT_1	[p1l534t280r771b327],
4	Activates	VBZ	O	activate	dep	1	SENT_1	[p1l792t280r1000b317],
5	Quorum	NNP	O	Quorum	nsubj	13	SENT_1	[p1l1020t281r1203b322],
6	Sensing	VBG	O	sense	partmod	5	SENT_1	[p1l1226t280r1400b327],
7	Quinolone	NNP	O	Quinolone	nn	8	SENT_1	[p1l1422t280r1657b322],
8	Signaling	NN	O	signaling	dobj	6	SENT_1	[p1l1678t280r1887b327],
9	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1909t280r1947b316],
10	Pseudomonas	FW	O	pseudomonas	nn	11	SENT_1	[p1l263t340r571b377],
11	aeruginosa	FW	O	aeruginosa	prep_in	6	SENT_1	[p1l590t340r838b387],
12	Olga	NNP	PERSON	Olga	nn	13	SENT_1	[p1l263t412r333b447],
13	Zaborina	NNP	PERSON	Zaborina	xcomp	4	SENT_1	[p1l349t412r494b444],
14	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l349t412r494b444],
15	Francois	NNP	PERSON	Francois	nn	16	SENT_1	[p1l510t413r636b439],
16	Lepine	NNP	PERSON	Lepine	dep	53	SENT_1	[p1l652t413r762b446],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l652t413r762b446],
18	Gaoping	NNP	PERSON	Gaoping	nn	19	SENT_1	[p1l777t413r907b447],
19	Xiao	NNP	PERSON	Xiao	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l923t413r997b444],
20	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l923t413r997b444],
21	Vesta	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Vesta	nn	22	SENT_1	[p1l1011t414r1093b439],
22	Valuckaite	NNP	ORGANIZATION	Valuckaite	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l1108t412r1274b444],
23	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1108t412r1274b444],
24	Yimei	NNP	PERSON	Yimei	nn	25	SENT_1	[p1l1289t413r1373b439],
25	Chen	NNP	PERSON	Chen	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l1389t412r1476b444],
26	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1389t412r1476b444],
27	Terry	NNP	PERSON	Terry	nn	28	SENT_1	[p1l1490t414r1568b447],
28	Li	NNP	PERSON	Li	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l1584t413r1614b444],
29	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1584t413r1614b444],
30	Mae	NNP	PERSON	Mae	nn	31	SENT_1	[p1l1630t414r1693b439],
31	Ciancio	NNP	PERSON	Ciancio	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l1707t413r1827b444],
32	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1707t413r1827b444],
33	Alex	NNP	PERSON	Alex	nn	34	SENT_1	[p1l1843t412r1908b439],
34	Zaborin	NNP	PERSON	Zaborin	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l1922t412r2049b444],
35	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1922t412r2049b444],
36	Elaine	NNP	PERSON	Elaine	nn	38	SENT_1	[p1l265t458r353b485],
37	O.	NNP	PERSON	O.	nn	38	SENT_1	[p1l368t459r399b485],
38	Petrof	NNP	PERSON	Petrof	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l416t458r514b490],
39	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l416t458r514b490],
40	Jerrold	NNP	PERSON	Jerrold	nn	42	SENT_1	[p1l528t458r632b485],
41	R.	NNP	PERSON	R.	nn	42	SENT_1	[p1l650t460r674b485],
42	Turner	NNP	PERSON	Turner	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l688t460r797b490],
43	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l688t460r797b490],
44	Laurence	NNP	PERSON	Laurence	nn	46	SENT_1	[p1l814t460r952b485],
45	G.	NNP	PERSON	G.	nn	46	SENT_1	[p1l967t459r997b485],
46	Rahme	NNP	PERSON	Rahme	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l1013t458r1125b490],
47	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1013t458r1125b490],
48	Eugene	NNP	PERSON	Eugene	nn	49	SENT_1	[p1l1142t460r1256b493],
49	Chang	NNP	PERSON	Chang	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l1271t458r1378b493],
50	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l1271t458r1378b493],
51	John	NNP	PERSON	John	appos	16	SENT_1	[p1l1392t458r1465b485],
52	C.	NNP	PERSON	C.	dep	53	SENT_1	[p1l1481t459r1508b485],
53	Alverdy	NNP	PERSON	Alverdy	dep	59	SENT_1	[p1l1523t458r1640b493],
54	doi	FW	O	doi	dep	53	SENT_1	[p1l264t529r319b556],
55	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l264t529r319b556],
56	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	dep	54	SENT_1	[p1l337t529r797b564],
57	/	:	O	/	punct	59	SENT_1	[p1l337t529r797b564],
58	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	59	SENT_1	[p1l337t529r797b564],
59	|	NN	O	|	dep	13	SENT_1	[p1l337t529r797b564],
60	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_1	[p1l337t529r797b564],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	npadvmod	25	SENT_2	[p1l337t529r797b564],
2	.0030035	CD	NUMBER	.0030035	num	1	SENT_2	[p1l337t529r797b564],
3	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l265t601r289b626],
4	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	5	SENT_2	[p1l305t600r376b626],
5	Pathogens	NN	O	pathogen	prep_in	25	SENT_2	[p1l390t599r554b634],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l390t599r554b634],
7	vol	NN	O	vol	nsubjpass	25	SENT_2	[p1l569t599r613b626],
8	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	7	SENT_2	[p1l630t601r654b631],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l630t601r654b631],
10	issue	NN	O	issue	appos	7	SENT_2	[p1l670t600r744b626],
11	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	10	SENT_2	[p1l759t601r783b626],
12	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l759t601r783b626],
13	One	CD	NUMBER	one	dep	10	SENT_2	[p1l263t671r326b697],
14	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l341t670r373b697],
15	the	DT	O	the	det	16	SENT_2	[p1l384t670r434b697],
16	authors	NNS	O	author	prep_of	13	SENT_2	[p1l449t670r573b702],
17	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l449t670r573b702],
18	Dr.	NNP	O	Dr.	nn	21	SENT_2	[p1l590t672r630b697],
19	Elaine	NNP	PERSON	Elaine	nn	21	SENT_2	[p1l647t670r736b697],
20	O.	NNP	PERSON	O.	nn	21	SENT_2	[p1l750t671r781b697],
21	Petrof	NNP	PERSON	Petrof	appos	16	SENT_2	[p1l798t670r896b702],
22	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l798t670r896b702],
23	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	25	SENT_2	[p1l911t678r969b697],
24	incorrectly	RB	O	incorrectly	advmod	25	SENT_2	[p1l985t670r1147b705],
25	listed	VBN	O	list	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1162t670r1241b697],
26	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1257t678r1288b697],
27	Elaine	NNP	PERSON	Elaine	nn	28	SENT_2	[p1l1304t670r1393b697],
28	Petroff	NNP	PERSON	Petroff	prep_as	25	SENT_2	[p1l1409t670r1518b697],
29	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_2	[p1l1409t670r1518b697],

1	This	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_3	[p1l338t736r395b757],
2	correction	NN	O	correction	nn	3	SENT_3	[p1l408t737r551b758],
3	note	NN	O	note	nsubjpass	6	SENT_3	[p1l565t741r623b758],
4	may	MD	O	may	aux	6	SENT_3	[p1l637t744r691b765],
5	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_3	[p1l703t736r734b757],
6	found	VBN	O	find	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l746t736r827b757],
7	online	NN	O	online	dep	6	SENT_3	[p1l839t736r925b757],
8	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l938t741r962b758],
9	doi	FW	O	doi	prep_at	6	SENT_3	[p1l975t736r1023b757],
10	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l975t736r1023b757],
11	10.1371	CD	NUMBER	10.1371	num	13	SENT_3	[p1l1039t734r1443b765],
12	[	NN	O	[	nn	13	SENT_3	[p1l1039t734r1443b765],
13	iournal	NN	O	iournal	dep	6	SENT_3	[p1l1039t734r1443b765],
14	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_3	[p1l1039t734r1443b765],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1039t734r1443b765],
2	.0030067	CD	NUMBER	.0030067	dep	1	SENT_4	[p1l1039t734r1443b765],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_4	[p1l1039t734r1443b765],

1	Published	VBN	O	publish	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l338t771r471b792],
2	May	NNP	DATE	May	tmod	1	SENT_5	[p1l483t772r538b800],
3	25	CD	DATE	25	num	2	SENT_5	[p1l551t771r587b797],
4	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l551t771r587b797],
5	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	2	SENT_5	[p1l601t769r669b794],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_5	[p1l601t769r669b794],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l338t807r456b829],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l338t807r456b829],
3	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	1	SENT_6	[p1l471t805r551b834],
4	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	6	SENT_6	[p1l471t805r551b834],
5	)	NN	O	)	nn	6	SENT_6	[p1l471t805r551b834],
6	Correction	NN	O	correction	dep	3	SENT_6	[p1l564t807r720b829],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l564t807r720b829],
8	Dynorphin	NN	MISC	dynorphin	nsubj	9	SENT_6	[p1l734t807r883b836],
9	activates	VBZ	O	activate	dep	1	SENT_6	[p1l896t808r1011b829],
10	quorum	NN	O	quorum	dobj	9	SENT_6	[p1l1025t815r1133b836],
11	sensing	VBG	O	sense	partmod	10	SENT_6	[p1l1146t808r1245b836],
12	quinolone	NN	O	quinolone	nn	13	SENT_6	[p1l1258t807r1396b836],
13	signaling	NN	O	signaling	dobj	11	SENT_6	[p1l1409t807r1531b836],
14	in	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1543t808r1568b828],
15	Pseudomonas	FW	O	pseudomonas	nn	16	SENT_6	[p1l1580t807r1740b828],
16	twrug	FW	O	twrug	prep_in	11	SENT_6	[p1l1752t808r1887b836],
17	"	``	O	"	punct	16	SENT_6	[p1l1752t808r1887b836],
18	ino	NN	O	ino	dep	16	SENT_6	[p1l1752t808r1887b836],
19	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_6	[p1l1752t808r1887b836],

1	s	NNS	O	s	poss	5	SENT_7	[p1l1752t808r1887b836],
2	'	POS	O	'	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1752t808r1887b836],
3	a.	NN	O	a.	nn	5	SENT_7	[p1l1752t808r1887b836],
4	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	5	SENT_7	[p1l1901t807r1970b829],
5	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l1983t807r2078b836],
6	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	7	SENT_7	[p1l2090t807r2145b834],
7	(	NN	O	(	dep	5	SENT_7	[p1l2090t807r2145b834],
8	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	9	SENT_7	[p1l2090t807r2145b834],
9	)	NN	O	)	dep	5	SENT_7	[p1l2090t807r2145b834],
10	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l2090t807r2145b834],
11	e67	NN	O	e67	dep	5	SENT_7	[p1l2159t805r2211b828],
12	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_7	[p1l2159t805r2211b828],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	nn	3	SENT_8	[p1l338t840r790b871],
2	:10.137	FW	O	:10.137	nn	3	SENT_8	[p1l338t840r790b871],
3	l	NN	O	l	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l338t840r790b871],
4	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	5	SENT_8	[p1l338t840r790b871],
5	journal	NN	O	journal	dep	3	SENT_8	[p1l338t840r790b871],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_8	[p1l338t840r790b871],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_9	[p1l338t840r790b871],
2	.0030067	CD	NUMBER	.0030067	num	1	SENT_9	[p1l338t840r790b871],

1	Correction	NN	O	correction	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l264t1007r512b1044],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l264t1007r512b1044],
3	Population	NNP	O	Population	nn	4	SENT_10	[p1l534t1007r779b1053],
4	Genomics	NNP	O	Genomics	dep	12	SENT_10	[p1l800t1007r1020b1044],
5	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1040t1006r1086b1044],
6	the	DT	O	the	det	9	SENT_10	[p1l1103t1007r1176b1044],
7	Immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	9	SENT_10	[p1l1198t1009r1381b1044],
8	Evasion	NN	O	evasion	nn	9	SENT_10	[p1l1403t1007r1573b1044],
9	(	NN	O	(	prep_of	4	SENT_10	[p1l1596t1008r1696b1049],
10	var	NN	O	var	dep	12	SENT_10	[p1l1596t1008r1696b1049],
11	)	CD	NUMBER	)	num	10	SENT_10	[p1l1596t1008r1696b1049],
12	Genes	NNS	O	gene	dep	23	SENT_10	[p1l1716t1008r1854b1044],
13	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l1873t1006r1919b1044],
14	Plasmodium	NN	O	plasmodium	nn	18	SENT_10	[p1l263t1067r535b1104],
15	falciparum	NN	O	falciparum	nn	18	SENT_10	[p1l555t1066r792b1113],
16	Alyssa	NNP	PERSON	Alyssa	nn	18	SENT_10	[p1l263t1140r357b1175],
17	E.	NNP	PERSON	E.	nn	18	SENT_10	[p1l374t1142r396b1167],
18	Barry	NNP	PERSON	Barry	prep_of	12	SENT_10	[p1l412t1142r496b1175],
19	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l412t1142r496b1175],
20	Aleksandra	NNP	PERSON	Aleksandra	nn	22	SENT_10	[p1l511t1140r680b1167],
21	Le	NNP	PERSON	Le	nn	22	SENT_10	[p1l697t1140r895b1175],
22	|	NNP	O	|	appos	18	SENT_10	[p1l697t1140r895b1175],
23	iwa	NN	O	iwa	dep	1	SENT_10	[p1l697t1140r895b1175],
24	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_10	[p1l697t1140r895b1175],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l697t1140r895b1175],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_11	[p1l697t1140r895b1175],

1	Sytek	NNP	PERSON	Sytek	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l697t1140r895b1175],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l697t1140r895b1175],
3	Livingston	NNP	PERSON	Livingston	nn	4	SENT_12	[p1l912t1141r1069b1175],
4	Tavul	NNP	PERSON	Tavul	appos	1	SENT_12	[p1l1084t1140r1174b1172],
5	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1084t1140r1174b1172],
6	Heather	NNP	PERSON	Heather	nn	7	SENT_12	[p1l1190t1140r1313b1167],
7	lmrie	NN	O	lmrie	appos	1	SENT_12	[p1l1328t1141r1411b1172],
8	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1328t1141r1411b1172],
9	Florence	NNP	LOCATION	Florence	nn	10	SENT_12	[p1l1427t1140r1558b1167],
10	Migot	NNP	LOCATION	Migot	appos	1	SENT_12	[p1l1574t1140r1787b1175],
11	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_12	[p1l1574t1140r1787b1175],

1	—	NN	O	—	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1574t1140r1787b1175],
2	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_13	[p1l1574t1140r1787b1175],

1	Nabias	NNP	PERSON	Nabias	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1574t1140r1787b1175],
2	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1574t1140r1787b1175],
3	Stuart	NNP	PERSON	Stuart	nn	5	SENT_14	[p1l1802t1141r1893b1167],
4	M.	NNP	PERSON	M.	nn	5	SENT_14	[p1l1909t1142r1943b1167],
5	Brown	NNP	PERSON	Brown	appos	1	SENT_14	[p1l1959t1142r2064b1172],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l1959t1142r2064b1172],
7	Gil	NNP	PERSON	Gil	nn	8	SENT_14	[p1l263t1186r301b1213],
8	Mcvean	NNP	PERSON	Mcvean	appos	1	SENT_14	[p1l318t1188r447b1218],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l318t1188r447b1218],
10	Karen	NNP	PERSON	Karen	nn	12	SENT_14	[p1l464t1188r548b1213],
11	P.	NNP	PERSON	P.	nn	12	SENT_14	[p1l566t1188r589b1213],
12	Day	NNP	PERSON	Day	appos	8	SENT_14	[p1l606t1188r663b1221],
13	doi	FW	O	doi	dep	1	SENT_14	[p1l264t1256r786b1291],
14	:10.1371	CD	NUMBER	:10.1371	dep	13	SENT_14	[p1l264t1256r786b1291],
15	/	:	O	/	punct	17	SENT_14	[p1l264t1256r786b1291],
16	journa	NN	O	journa	nn	17	SENT_14	[p1l264t1256r786b1291],
17	|	NN	O	|	dep	14	SENT_14	[p1l264t1256r786b1291],
18	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_14	[p1l264t1256r786b1291],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	npadvmod	20	SENT_15	[p1l264t1256r786b1291],
2	.0030034	CD	NUMBER	.0030034	num	1	SENT_15	[p1l264t1256r786b1291],
3	In	IN	O	in	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l265t1329r289b1354],
4	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	5	SENT_15	[p1l305t1328r376b1354],
5	Pathogens	NNS	O	pathogen	prep_in	20	SENT_15	[p1l390t1327r555b1362],
6	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l390t1327r555b1362],
7	volume	NN	O	volume	nsubjpass	20	SENT_15	[p1l569t1327r685b1354],
8	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	7	SENT_15	[p1l700t1329r724b1359],
9	,	,	O	,	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l700t1329r724b1359],
10	issue	NN	O	issue	appos	7	SENT_15	[p1l740t1328r814b1354],
11	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	10	SENT_15	[p1l830t1329r853b1354],
12	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l830t1329r853b1354],
13	The	DT	O	the	det	15	SENT_15	[p1l262t1397r319b1424],
14	seventh	JJ	ORDINAL	seventh	amod	15	SENT_15	[p1l334t1397r454b1424],
15	author	NN	O	author	poss	17	SENT_15	[p1l470t1397r594b1424],
16	's	POS	O	's	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l470t1397r594b1424],
17	name	NN	O	name	dep	10	SENT_15	[p1l611t1405r695b1424],
18	was	VBD	O	be	auxpass	20	SENT_15	[p1l710t1405r768b1424],
19	incorrectly	RB	O	incorrectly	advmod	20	SENT_15	[p1l784t1397r946b1432],
20	listed	VBN	O	list	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l961t1397r1040b1424],
21	as	IN	O	as	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1056t1405r1086b1424],
22	Gilean	NNP	PERSON	Gilean	nn	25	SENT_15	[p1l1101t1397r1196b1424],
23	A.	NNP	PERSON	A.	nn	25	SENT_15	[p1l1212t1399r1240b1424],
24	V.	NNP	PERSON	V.	nn	25	SENT_15	[p1l1255t1399r1282b1424],
25	McVean	NNP	PERSON	McVean	prep_as	20	SENT_15	[p1l1298t1399r1427b1424],
26	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_15	[p1l1298t1399r1427b1424],

1	The	DT	O	the	det	3	SENT_16	[p1l1440t1397r1497b1424],
2	correct	JJ	O	correct	amod	3	SENT_16	[p1l1512t1402r1619b1424],
3	name	NN	O	name	nsubj	6	SENT_16	[p1l1635t1405r1720b1424],
4	is	VBZ	O	be	cop	6	SENT_16	[p1l1736t1398r1756b1424],
5	Gil	NNP	PERSON	Gil	nn	6	SENT_16	[p1l1771t1397r1808b1424],
6	Mcvean	NNP	PERSON	Mcvean	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1825t1399r1954b1424],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_16	[p1l1825t1399r1954b1424],

1	This	DT	O	this	det	3	SENT_17	[p1l338t1463r395b1484],
2	correction	NN	O	correction	nn	3	SENT_17	[p1l408t1464r551b1485],
3	note	NN	O	note	nsubjpass	6	SENT_17	[p1l565t1468r623b1485],
4	may	MD	O	may	aux	6	SENT_17	[p1l637t1471r691b1492],
5	be	VB	O	be	auxpass	6	SENT_17	[p1l703t1463r734b1484],
6	found	VBN	O	find	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l746t1463r827b1484],
7	online	NN	O	online	dep	6	SENT_17	[p1l839t1463r925b1484],
8	at	IN	O	at	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l938t1468r962b1485],
9	doi	FW	O	doi	nn	10	SENT_17	[p1l975t1461r1433b1492],
10	:10.137	FW	O	:10.137	prep_at	6	SENT_17	[p1l975t1461r1433b1492],
11	lﬁournal	NN	O	lﬁournal	dep	10	SENT_17	[p1l975t1461r1433b1492],
12	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_17	[p1l975t1461r1433b1492],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l975t1461r1433b1492],
2	.0030070	CD	NUMBER	.0030070	dep	1	SENT_18	[p1l975t1461r1433b1492],
3	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_18	[p1l975t1461r1433b1492],

1	Published	VBN	O	publish	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l338t1499r471b1520],
2	May	NNP	DATE	May	tmod	1	SENT_19	[p1l483t1500r538b1528],
3	25	CD	DATE	25	num	2	SENT_19	[p1l551t1499r587b1525],
4	,	,	DATE	,	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l551t1499r587b1525],
5	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	2	SENT_19	[p1l601t1497r669b1522],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_19	[p1l601t1497r669b1522],

1	Citation	NNP	O	Citation	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l338t1534r456b1556],
2	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l338t1534r456b1556],
3	(	CD	NUMBER	(	dep	1	SENT_20	[p1l472t1533r553b1561],
4	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	6	SENT_20	[p1l472t1533r553b1561],
5	)	NN	O	)	nn	6	SENT_20	[p1l472t1533r553b1561],
6	Correction	NN	O	correction	dep	3	SENT_20	[p1l568t1534r723b1556],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l568t1534r723b1556],
8	Population	NNP	O	Population	nn	9	SENT_20	[p1l739t1534r889b1563],
9	genomics	NNS	O	genomic	dep	1	SENT_20	[p1l904t1535r1030b1563],
10	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1046t1534r1075b1555],
11	the	DT	O	the	det	17	SENT_20	[p1l1087t1534r1128b1556],
12	immune	JJ	O	immune	amod	17	SENT_20	[p1l1143t1535r1254b1555],
13	evasion	NN	O	evasion	nn	17	SENT_20	[p1l1269t1535r1369b1555],
14	(	NN	O	(	nn	17	SENT_20	[p1l1385t1535r1440b1561],
15	var	NN	O	var	nn	17	SENT_20	[p1l1385t1535r1440b1561],
16	)	NN	O	)	nn	17	SENT_20	[p1l1385t1535r1440b1561],
17	genes	NNS	O	gene	prep_of	9	SENT_20	[p1l1455t1541r1528b1563],
18	of	IN	O	of	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1543t1534r1572b1555],
19	Pla	NN	O	plum	prep_of	17	SENT_20	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],
20	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_20	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],

1	vm	NN	O	vm	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],
2	(	CD	NUMBER	(	number	3	SENT_21	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],
3	)	CD	NUMBER	)	dep	1	SENT_21	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],
4	dium_falL	NN	O	dium_fall	nn	6	SENT_21	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],
5	'	''	O	'	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],
6	iparum	NN	O	iparum	dep	3	SENT_21	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_21	[p1l1583t1534r1880b1563],

1	PLoS	NN	O	plo	nn	2	SENT_22	[p1l1896t1534r1965b1556],
2	Pathog	NN	O	pathog	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l1980t1534r2075b1563],
3	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	4	SENT_22	[p1l2089t1534r2144b1561],
4	(	NN	O	(	dep	2	SENT_22	[p1l2089t1534r2144b1561],
5	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	6	SENT_22	[p1l2089t1534r2144b1561],
6	)	NN	O	)	dep	2	SENT_22	[p1l2089t1534r2144b1561],
7	:	:	O	:	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l2089t1534r2144b1561],
8	e70	NN	O	e70	dep	2	SENT_22	[p1l2159t1533r2211b1555],
9	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_22	[p1l2159t1533r2211b1555],

1	doi	FW	O	doi	nn	3	SENT_23	[p1l338t1568r790b1598],
2	:10.137	FW	O	:10.137	nn	3	SENT_23	[p1l338t1568r790b1598],
3	l	NN	O	l	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l338t1568r790b1598],
4	(	CD	NUMBER	(	num	5	SENT_23	[p1l338t1568r790b1598],
5	journal	NN	O	journal	dep	3	SENT_23	[p1l338t1568r790b1598],
6	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_23	[p1l338t1568r790b1598],

1	ppat	NN	O	ppat	_	0	SENT_24	[p1l338t1568r790b1598],
2	.0030070	CD	NUMBER	.0030070	num	1	SENT_24	[p1l338t1568r790b1598],

1	@w	NN	O	@w	nsubj	4	SENT_25	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
2	+	CC	O	+	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l188t3077r261b3136],
3	PLoS	NN	O	plo	conj_+	1	SENT_25	[p1l288t3093r352b3116],
4	Pathogens	VBD	O	pathogen	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l367t3092r511b3123],
5	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	6	SENT_25	[p1l526t3091r528b3124],
6	www	NN	O	www	dobj	4	SENT_25	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
7	.	.	O	.	_	0	SENT_25	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],

1	p	NN	O	p	nn	3	SENT_26	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
2	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	3	SENT_26	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
3	ospathogens.org	NN	O	ospathogens.org	dep	11	SENT_26	[p1l543t3092r882b3123],
4	0690	CD	DATE	0690	num	7	SENT_26	[p1l1205t3094r1270b3116],
5	May	NNP	DATE	May	nn	7	SENT_26	[p1l1700t3093r1756b3123],
6	2007	CD	DATE	2007	num	7	SENT_26	[p1l1768t3094r1833b3116],
7	|	NNP	O	|	dep	3	SENT_26	[p1l1848t3091r1851b3124],
8	Volume	NN	O	volume	dep	11	SENT_26	[p1l1865t3092r1971b3116],
9	3	CD	NUMBER	3	num	8	SENT_26	[p1l1984t3094r1997b3116],
10	|	NN	O	|	nn	11	SENT_26	[p1l2013t3091r2016b3124],
11	Issue	NN	O	issue	dep	16	SENT_26	[p1l2032t3093r2098b3116],
12	5	CD	NUMBER	5	num	14	SENT_26	[p1l2111t3094r2124b3116],
13	|	NN	O	|	nn	14	SENT_26	[p1l2140t3091r2143b3124],
14	e67	NN	O	e67	dep	11	SENT_26	[p1l2158t3094r2206b3116],
15	|	CD	NUMBER	|	num	16	SENT_26	[p1l2221t3091r2223b3124],
16	e70	NN	O	e70	_	0	SENT_26	[p1l2238t3094r2286b3116],

